<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/91-122</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1991</YYYY><MM>1</MM><DD>31</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>17</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">HERITAGE RAILWAY STATIONS PROTECTION ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Heritage Railway Stations Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting Heritage Railway Stations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1991-170 </OrderNumber><Date><YYYY> 1991</YYYY><MM>1</MM><DD>31</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of the Environment, pursuant to section 9 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Heritage Railway Stations Protection Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-91-122_e_hq_6163">*</FootnoteRef>, is pleased hereby to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting heritage railway stations</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fn_SOR-91-122_e_hq_6163" placement="page" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>R.S., c. 52 (4th Supp.)</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Heritage Railway Stations Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Heritage Railway Stations Protection Act</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Minister</DefinedTermEn> means the Minister of the Environment. (<DefinedTermFr>ministre</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Public Notice</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The public notice referred to in section 6 of the Act shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>be published once in at least one newspaper of general circulation in the municipality in which the heritage railway station is situated;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>be posted in a prominent location at the heritage railway station for a period of not less than 15 days; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>be sent to</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the municipal authority for the area in which the heritage railway station is situated,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the Minister responsible for heritage preservation in the province in which the heritage railway station is situated, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>the Canadian Parks Service of the Department of the Environment at Ottawa, Ontario.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The public notice referred to in subsection (1) shall set out</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the name of the owner of the heritage railway station, the name of the heritage railway station and the address of the heritage railway station;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a description of the planned activity and the date on which it is intended that the activity begin;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the name, title, business address and business phone number of the official of the railway company responsible for the planned activity;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the date the railway company intends to file the application;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>a statement to the effect that any person objecting to the planned activity may, within 60 days after the application is filed, serve on the Minister a notice of objection in the form of a letter setting out the reasons for the objection and any relevant facts and that the person shall send a copy of the notice of objection to the railway company; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>the Minister’s address for service of a notice of objection.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/94-363, s. 2(F).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application for Authorization</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>The application for authorization referred to in section 6 of the Act shall include</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the identification of the heritage railway station by name, owner, street address or legal description, and photographs of the heritage railway station showing its current condition;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a description of the planned activity, the date on which it is intended that the activity begin and, in the case of an alteration, any plans, drawings, specifications and photographs that may be applicable;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the dates and locations at which the public notice referred to in section 3 was given and a copy of the notice as published and posted;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the name, title, business address and business phone number of the official of the railway company responsible for the planned activity; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>any other information that the railway company considers pertinent.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>5</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>An application for authorization shall be filed by a railway company within 60 days after the company gives public notice in accordance with section 3.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Where a railway company files an application for authorization after 60 days of giving public notice in accordance with section 3, the Minister may reject the application.</Text></Subsection></Section></Body></Regulation>