<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/62-1</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1961</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>01</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS MARKETING ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Ontario Onion Growers’ Marketing Order</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1961-1820</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1961</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>WHEREAS under the provisions of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Agricultural Products Marketing Act</XRefExternal>, the Governor in Council may by order grant authority in interprovincial and export trade to any board or agency authorized under the law of any province to exercise powers of regulation in relation to the marketing of any agricultural product locally within the province, and for such purposes to exercise all or any powers like the powers exercisable by such board or agency in relation to the marketing of such agricultural product locally within the province;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>AND WHEREAS The Ontario Onion Growers’ Marketing Board is authorized by <XRefExternal reference-type="act">The Farm Products Marketing Act</XRefExternal> of Ontario and the regulations thereunder, to exercise powers of regulation in relation to the marketing of onions locally within the Province of Ontario, and has applied for, and it is deemed advisable to grant to the Board, authority to regulate the marketing of onions outside the Province of Ontario in interprovincial and export trade;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THEREFORE, His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Acting Minister of Agriculture, pursuant to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Agricultural Products Marketing Act</XRefExternal>, is pleased hereby to make the annexed Order.</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Order</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Ontario Onion Growers’ Marketing Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In this Order,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Board</DefinedTermEn> means The Ontario Onion Growers’ Marketing Board established by order of the Lieutenant-Governor of Ontario in Council pursuant to <XRefExternal reference-type="act">The Farm Products Marketing Act</XRefExternal> of Ontario; (<DefinedTermFr>Office</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>onions</DefinedTermEn> means onions produced in Ontario. (<DefinedTermFr>oignons</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>The Board is authorized to regulate the marketing of onions in interprovincial and export trade and for such purposes may, with respect to persons and property situate within the Province of Ontario, exercise all or any powers like the powers exercisable by the Board in relation to the marketing of onions locally within the Province of Ontario under sections 4, 5, 7, 8, 9, 10 and 11 of Regulation 334/61, which Regulation was made by The Farm Products Marketing Board of Ontario pursuant to <XRefExternal reference-type="act">The Farm Products Marketing Act</XRefExternal> of Ontario.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>