<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2000-181</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2000</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>4</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>10</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">DNA IDENTIFICATION ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>DNA Data Bank Advisory Committee Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2000-635 </OrderNumber><Date><YYYY> 2000</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>4</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Solicitor General of Canada, pursuant to section 12 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">DNA Identification Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-2000-181_e_hq_5544">a</FootnoteRef>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">DNA Data Bank Advisory Committee Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fn_SOR-2000-181_e_hq_5544" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 1998, c. 37</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>In these Regulations, “Advisory Committee” means the DNA Data Bank Advisory Committee established by section 2.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>DNA Data Bank Advisory Committee</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>An advisory committee is hereby established, to be known as the DNA Data Bank Advisory Committee, consisting of a Chairperson, a Vice-Chairperson, a representative of the Office of the Privacy Commissioner and up to six other members who may include representatives of the police, legal, scientific and academic communities.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2000-269, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>The members of the Advisory Committee shall be appointed by the Solicitor General of Canada for a term of not more than five years.</Text></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>A member of the Advisory Committee is eligible for reappointment on the expiry of their term.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Duties of the Advisory Committee</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>The Advisory Committee shall, on its own motion when the Advisory Committee considers it necessary or on the request of the Commissioner, advise the Commissioner on any matter related to the establishment and operation of the national DNA data bank that is referred to in section 3 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">DNA Identification Act</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Annual Report to the Commissioner</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>The Advisory Committee shall report annually to the Commissioner, within three months after the end of each fiscal year, on its activities during that year.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>7</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on the day on which sections 2, 3 and 12 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">DNA Identification Act</XRefExternal>, chapter 37 of the Statutes of Canada, 1998, come into force.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>