<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/93-587</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1993</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>15</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>25</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">EXPORT AND IMPORT PERMITS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Issuance of Certificates Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1993-2087 </OrderNumber><Date><YYYY> 1993</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>15</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Secretary of State for External Affairs, is pleased hereby, pursuant to paragraph 12(c.01)<FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-93-587_e_hq_6269">*</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Export and Import Permits Act</XRefExternal>, to revoke the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Issuance of Certificates Regulations</XRefExternal>, made by Order in Council P.C. 1988-2869 of December 30, 1988<FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-93-587_e_hq_6270">**</FootnoteRef>, and to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations providing for considerations to be taken into account by the Minister in the issuance of certificates under section 9.01 of the Export and Import Permits Act</XRefExternal>, effective on the day on which section 154 of <XRefExternal reference-type="act">An Act to implement the North American Free Trade Agreement</XRefExternal>, being chapter 44 of the Statutes of Canada, 1993, comes into force.</Text><Footnote id="fn_SOR-93-587_e_hq_6269" placement="page" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>S.C. 1993, c. 44, s. 154</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="fn_SOR-93-587_e_hq_6270" placement="page" status="official"><Label>**</Label><Text>SOR/89-45, 1989 <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal> Part II, p. 760</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Section><Label>1</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/99-57, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>apparel goods</DefinedTermEn> means goods provided for in Chapters 61 and 62 in the List of Tariff Provisions set out in the schedule to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal> that are both cut or knit to shape and sewn or otherwise assembled in Canada from fabric or yarn produced or obtained outside the free trade area; (<DefinedTermFr>vêtements</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Canada</DefinedTermEn><Repealed> [Repealed, SOR/99-57, s. 3]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>export development plan</DefinedTermEn> means a plan indicating the intent and ability of an exporter to export from Canada to a specified importer or specified importers in the United States or Mexico a certain volume or value of apparel goods, fabrics and made-up goods or spun yarn, as applicable; (<DefinedTermFr>plan de développement des exportations</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>export performance</DefinedTermEn> means the volume and value of exports from Canada of an exporter to the United States or Mexico of apparel goods, fabrics and made-up goods or spun yarn, as applicable; (<DefinedTermFr>performance à l’exportation</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>exporter</DefinedTermEn> means a person who exports or intends to export from Canada to the United States or Mexico apparel goods, fabrics and made-up goods or spun yarn; (<DefinedTermFr>exportateur</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>fabric and made-up goods</DefinedTermEn> means</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>cotton or man-made fibre fabric and cotton or man-made fibre made-up textile goods provided for in Chapters 52 to 55 in the List of Tariff Provisions set out in the schedule to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal>, excluding goods containing 36 per cent or more by weight of wool or fine animal hair, and in Chapters 58, 60 and 63 of that schedule, that are woven or knit in Canada from yarn produced or obtained outside the free trade area, or knit in Canada from yarn spun in the free trade area from fibre produced or obtained outside the free trade area, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>goods of subheading No. 9404.90 in the List of Tariff Provisions set out in the schedule to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal> that are finished, cut and sewn or otherwise assembled in Canada from fabrics of subheading Nos. 5208.11 to 5208.29, 5209.11 to 5209.29, 5210.11 to 5210.29, 5211.11 to 5211.29, 5212.11, 5212.12, 5212.21, 5212.22, 5407.41, 5407.51, 5407.71, 5407.81, 5407.91, 5408.21, 5408.31, 5512.11, 5512.21, 5512.91, 5513.11 to 5513.19, 5514.11 to 5514.19, 5516.11, 5516.21, 5516.31, 5516.41 or 5516.91 of that schedule that are produced or obtained outside the free trade area; (<DefinedTermFr>tissus et articles confectionnés</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>free trade area</DefinedTermEn> means the area comprising Canada, Mexico and the United States; (<DefinedTermFr>zone de libre-échange</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Mexico</DefinedTermEn> has the same meaning as in section 2.2 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>Mexique</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>spun yarn</DefinedTermEn> means cotton or man-made fibre yarn that is classified under heading Nos. 52.05 to 52.07 or 55.09 to 55.11 in the List of Tariff Provisions set out in the schedule to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal> that is spun in Canada from fibre classified under heading Nos. 52.01 to 52.03 or 55.01 to 55.07 of that schedule and produced or obtained outside the free trade area; (<DefinedTermFr>filé</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>United States</DefinedTermEn> has the same meaning as in section 2.1 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal>. (<DefinedTermFr>États-Unis</DefinedTermFr>) </Text></Definition><HistoricalNote>SOR/98-26, s. 1; SOR/99-57, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Considerations in the Issuance of Certificates</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>The following considerations shall be taken into account by the Minister in the issuance of a certificate under paragraph 9.1(a) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Export and Import Permits Act</XRefExternal>:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the export performance of the exporter, if any, over a recent representative base period;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any export development plan prepared by the exporter;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the degree of demand for certificates;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the potential impact of the issuance or non-issuance of a certificate on the exporter, on the Canadian textile industry or on the Canadian apparel industry; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the effective utilization and preservation of the benefits of NAFTA and any intergovernmental arrangements made thereunder.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/99-57, s. 4.</HistoricalNote></Section></Body></Regulation>