<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/98-4</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1997</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>17</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2010</YYYY><MM>4</MM><DD>13</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Establishment Licensing Fees (Veterinary Drugs) Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1997-1896</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1997</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>17</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Health and the Treasury Board, pursuant to paragraph 19.1(a)<FootnoteRef idref="footnotea_e">a</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Financial Administration Act</XRefExternal> and, considering that it is in the public interest to remit certain debts, pursuant to subsection 23(2.1)<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteb_e">b</FootnoteRef> of that Act, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Establishment Licensing Fees Regulations</XRefExternal> (1056).</Text><Footnote id="footnotea_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 1991, c. 24, s. 6</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="footnoteb_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>b</Label><Text>S.C. 1991, c. 24, s. 7(2)</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Definitions</MarginalNote><Label>1</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The definitions in this subsection apply in these Regulations.</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><MarginalNote><DefinedTermEn>activity</DefinedTermEn></MarginalNote><MarginalNote><DefinedTermFr>activité</DefinedTermFr></MarginalNote><Text><DefinedTermEn>activity</DefinedTermEn> means an activity set out in Table I to section C.01A.008 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Food and Drug Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><MarginalNote><DefinedTermEn>category</DefinedTermEn></MarginalNote><MarginalNote><DefinedTermFr>catégorie</DefinedTermFr></MarginalNote><Text><DefinedTermEn>category</DefinedTermEn> means a category of drugs set out in Table II to section C.01A.008 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Food and Drug Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><MarginalNote><DefinedTermEn>drug</DefinedTermEn></MarginalNote><MarginalNote><DefinedTermFr>drogue</DefinedTermFr></MarginalNote><Text><DefinedTermEn>drug</DefinedTermEn> has the same meaning as in subsection C.01A.001(2) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Food and Drug Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><MarginalNote><DefinedTermEn>establishment licence</DefinedTermEn></MarginalNote><MarginalNote><DefinedTermFr>licence d’établissement</DefinedTermFr></MarginalNote><Text><DefinedTermEn>establishment licence</DefinedTermEn> means a licence issued under section C.01A.008 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Food and Drug Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><MarginalNote><DefinedTermEn>site</DefinedTermEn></MarginalNote><MarginalNote><DefinedTermFr>site</DefinedTermFr></MarginalNote><Text><DefinedTermEn>site</DefinedTermEn> means</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a building specified in an establishment licence and located more than one kilometre from any other building specified in the licence; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>more than one building specified in an establishment licence, all of which are located within one kilometre of each other.</Text></Paragraph></Definition></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Other words and expressions</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Unless the context otherwise requires, all other words and expressions used in these Regulations have the meanings assigned to them by the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Food and Drugs Act</XRefExternal>, the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Food and Drug Regulations</XRefExternal>, the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Controlled Drugs and Substances Act</XRefExternal> or the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Narcotic Control Regulations</XRefExternal>, as the case may be.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Application</MarginalNote><Label>2</Label><Text>These Regulations apply to establishment licences for activities that relate to drugs for veterinary use only, with the exception of those for activities that relate to any <DefinitionRef>active pharmaceutical ingredient</DefinitionRef>, as defined in subsection C.01A.001(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Food and Drug Regulations</XRefExternal>, that is for veterinary use.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2011-84, s. 2; SOR/2017-77, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Fees</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Amount payable</MarginalNote><Label>3</Label><Text>The fee that is payable for an establishment licence is the sum of the fees referred to in sections 4 to 10, as applicable.</Text></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Licence authorizing fabrication</MarginalNote><Label>4</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The fee payable for each site at which one or more activities is authorized by the establishment licence including the fabrication of drugs is the basic fee, set out in column 2 of item 1 of Schedule 1, together with each of the following fees that are applicable:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>if the licence is in respect of more than one category of drugs, the fee set out in column 2 of item 2 of Schedule 1, for each additional category;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>if the licence is in respect of more than one dosage form class, the applicable fee set out in column 2 of item 3 of Schedule 1; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>if the licence is in respect of sterile dosage forms, the fee set out in column 2 of item 4 of Schedule 1.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Importing</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Despite section 6, if importing is authorized by the establishment licence at a site referred to in subsection (1), the fee referred to in paragraph 6(b) is also payable.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Licence authorizing packaging/labelling</MarginalNote><Label>5</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The fee that is payable for each site at which one or more activities is authorized by the establishment licence, including packaging/labelling drugs but not including fabricating drugs, is the basic fee, set out in column 2 of item 1 of Schedule 2, together with each of the following fees that are applicable:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>if the licence is in respect of more than one category of drugs, the fee set out in column 2 of item 2 of Schedule 2, for each additional category; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>if the licence is in respect of more than one dosage form class, the applicable fee set out in column 2 of item 3 of Schedule 2.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Importing</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Despite section 6, if importing is authorized by the establishment licence at a site referred to in subsection (1), the fee referred to in paragraph 6(b) is also payable.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Licence authorizing importation</MarginalNote><Label>6</Label><Text>The fee that is payable for one or more activities authorized by the establishment licence, including importing drugs but not including fabricating or packaging/labelling drugs, is</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for each site where those activities are so authorized, the basic fee, set out in column 2 of item 1 of Schedule 3, together with each of the following fees that are applicable:</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>if the licence is in respect of more than one category of drugs, the fee set out in column 2 of item 2 of Schedule 3, for each additional category, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>if the licence is in respect of more than one dosage form class, the applicable fee set out in column 2 of item 3 of Schedule 3; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each fabricator outside Canada of drugs that are imported, except where a certificate from a Canadian inspector indicating that the fabricator’s buildings, equipment, practices and procedures meet the applicable requirements of Divisions 2 to 4 of Part C of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Food and Drug Regulations</XRefExternal> is provided by the importer, the sum of the following fees that are applicable:</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the fee set out in column 2 of item 4 of Schedule 3, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>if the licence is in respect of more than one dosage form class, for each additional dosage form class, the fee set out in column 2 of item 5 of Schedule 3.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Licence authorizing distribution</MarginalNote><Label>7</Label><Text>The fee that is payable for each site at which one or more activities is authorized by the establishment licence, including distributing drugs as a distributor referred to in paragraph C.01A.003(b) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Food and Drug Regulations</XRefExternal> but not including fabricating, packaging/labelling or importing drugs, is the basic fee, set out in column 2 of item 1 of Schedule 3, together with each of the following fees that are applicable:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>if the licence is in respect of more than one category of drugs, the fee set out in column 2 of item 2 of Schedule 3, for each additional category; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>if the licence is in respect of more than one dosage form class, the applicable fee set out in column 2 of item 3 of Schedule 3.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Drug analysis fee</MarginalNote><Label>8</Label><Text>In addition to the fees referred to in sections 4 to 7, the fee that is payable, if an establishment licence authorizes the holder to fabricate, package/label, import or distribute drugs as a distributor referred to in paragraph C.01A.003(b) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Food and Drug Regulations</XRefExternal>, is for any of those activities, the highest fee set out in column 2 of Schedule 4 that corresponds to drugs described in column 1 of that Schedule</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in respect of which the licence is requested; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>except in the case of an importer, for which the holder of the licence has obtained an identification number (DIN) or a numbered certificate of registration (GP).</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Licence authorizing distribution or wholesaling</MarginalNote><Label>9</Label><Text>The fee that is payable for each site at which one or more activities is authorized by the establishment licence, including distributing drugs as a distributor referred to in paragraph C.01A.003(a) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Food and Drug Regulations</XRefExternal> or wholesaling drugs but not including fabricating, packaging/labelling or importing drugs or distributing drugs as a distributor referred to in paragraph C.01A.003(b) of those Regulations, is a basic fee of $1,500.</Text></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Licence authorizing testing</MarginalNote><Label>10</Label><Text>The fee that is payable for each site at which only the testing of drugs is authorized by the establishment licence is a basic fee of $1,000.</Text></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Remission</MarginalNote><Label>11</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection 13(2), if the total of the fees payable under sections 3 to 10 of these Regulations and the fee payable under section 3 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Licensed Dealers for Controlled Drugs and Narcotics (Veterinary Use) Fees Regulations</XRefExternal> is greater than an amount equal to 1.5% of the applicant’s actual gross revenue from the sale, testing and packaging/labelling of drugs, as well as controlled drugs and narcotics not in dosage form, for the previous calendar year, remission is granted of the difference between those amounts if the applicant provides, with their application for the annual review of their licence, a statement signed by the individual responsible for the applicant’s financial affairs that sets out the actual gross revenue.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Statement — first year of activities</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>If the applicant has not completed their first calendar year of conducting activities under the licence, the applicant shall provide the statement within 90 days after the day on which that year ends in order to be eligible for the remission.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2011-84, s. 3; SOR/2017-77, s. 2(F).</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Timing of payment</MarginalNote><Label>12</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (2), the fee is payable on the day on which the establishment licence is issued or the application for the annual review of the licence is submitted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Timing of deferred payment</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>In the case of an applicant referred to in subsection 11(2), the fee for an application for the annual review of their licence is payable upon the expiry of the 90–day period.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2011-84, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Audited records</MarginalNote><Label>13</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>If the Minister determines that, on the basis of any information available to the Minister, the statement provided under subsection 11(1) is not adequate to determine the actual gross revenue referred to in that subsection, the Minister may require, for the purpose of determining the fee payable or the amount of the remission, the applicant to provide sales records that have been audited by a qualified independent auditor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Omission</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>If the applicant fails to provide the Minister with the audited sales records within 90 days after the day on which the Minister requested those records, the difference between the fee and the amount already paid is immediately payable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Difference payable</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>If the audited sales records establish that the amount already paid is less than the amount payable, the difference between those amounts is immediately payable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Difference remitted</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>If the audited sales records establish that the amount already paid is greater than the amount payable, remission is granted of an amount equal to the difference between those amounts, which the Minister must repay to the applicant.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2011-84, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>14</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2011-84, s. 3]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>15</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2011-84, s. 3]</Repealed></Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Licence Amendments</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Amendment to add sterile dosage forms</MarginalNote><Label>16</Label><Text>If an establishment licence authorizing the holder to carry out one or more activities including fabricating drugs is amended to authorize sterile dosage forms of drugs for the first time at a site, the fee payable for each site at which those forms are so authorized is the basic fee set out in column 2 of item 1 of Schedule 1.</Text></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Amendment to add activity</MarginalNote><Label>17</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>If an establishment licence is amended to add an activity at a site, the fee payable for the amendment to the licence is, for each site at which the activity is added,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>if the amendment authorizes the holder to fabricate drugs, the basic fee set out in column 2 of item 1 of Schedule 1;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>if the amendment authorizes the holder to package/label drugs but the amended licence does not authorize the holder to fabricate drugs, the basic fee set out in column 2 of item 1 of Schedule 2;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>if the amendment authorizes the holder to import drugs but the amended licence does not authorize the holder to fabricate or package/label drugs, the basic fee set out in column 2 of item 1 of Schedule 3;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>if the amendment authorizes the holder to distribute drugs as a distributor referred to in paragraph C.01A.003(b) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Food and Drug Regulations</XRefExternal>, but the amended licence does not authorize the holder to fabricate, package/label or import drugs, the basic fee set out in column 2 of item 1 of Schedule 3; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>if the amendment authorizes the holder to distribute drugs as a distributor referred to in paragraph C.01A.003(a) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Food and Drug Regulations</XRefExternal>, or to wholesale drugs or to carry out both activities, but the amended licence does not authorize the holder to fabricate, package/label or import drugs or distribute drugs as a distributor referred to in paragraph C.01A.003(b) of those Regulations, the basic fee set out in section 9.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Amendment to add category</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (3), if an establishment licence is amended to add a category of drugs for an activity that is authorized by the licence at a site, the fee payable for the amendment to the licence is, for each site at which the category of drugs is added for the authorized activity,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>if the amendment authorizes the holder to fabricate an additional category of drugs, the basic fee set out in column 2 of item 1 of Schedule 1;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>if the amendment authorizes the holder to package/label an additional category of drugs, the basic fee set out in column 2 of item 1 of Schedule 2;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>if the amendment authorizes the holder to import an additional category of drugs, the basic fee set out in column 2 of item 1 of Schedule 3;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>if the amendment authorizes the holder to distribute an additional category of drugs as a distributor referred to in paragraph C.01A.003(b) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Food and Drug Regulations</XRefExternal>, the basic fee set out in column 2 of item 1 of Schedule 3;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>if the amendment authorizes the holder to distribute an additional category of drugs as a distributor referred to in paragraph C.01A.003(a) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Food and Drug Regulations</XRefExternal>, or to wholesale an additional category of drugs, the basic fee set out in section 9; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>if the amendment authorizes the holder to test an additional category of drugs, the basic fee set out in section 10.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Included categories</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>If an establishment licence is amended to add a category of drugs in respect of more than one activity referred to in paragraphs (2)(a) to (f), the fee payable under subsection (2) is the highest applicable fee for those activities.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Fee exemption</MarginalNote><Label>18</Label><Text>If a remission has been granted under section 11 or 13, no fee is payable under section 16 or 17 for the amendment of the establishment licence.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2011-84, s. 4.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Time of payment</MarginalNote><Label>19</Label><Text>The fees determined in accordance with sections 16 and 17 are payable on the day on which the amended licence is issued.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Suspended Licences</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Fee for reinstated licence</MarginalNote><Label>20</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (2), if an establishment licence has been suspended by the Minister of Health in respect of any or all matters indicated in subsection C.01A.008(2) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Food and Drug Regulations</XRefExternal>, the fee payable for a reinstated licence is</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>if it authorizes the holder to carry out one or more activities, including fabricating drugs, for each site in respect of which the matter is reinstated, the basic fee set out in column 2 of item 1 of Schedule 1;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>if it authorizes the holder to carry out one or more activities, including packaging/labelling drugs but not including fabricating drugs, for each site in respect of which the matter is reinstated, the basic fee set out in column 2 of item 1 of Schedule 2;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>if it authorizes the holder to carry out one or more activities, including importing drugs but not including fabricating or packaging/labelling drugs, for each site in respect of which the matter is reinstated, the basic fee set out in column 2 of item 1 of Schedule 3;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>if it authorizes the holder to carry out one or more activities, including distributing drugs as a distributor referred to in paragraph C.01A.003(b) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Food and Drug Regulations</XRefExternal>, but not including fabricating, packaging/labelling or importing drugs, for each site in respect of which the matter is reinstated, the basic fee set out in column 2 of item 1 of Schedule 3;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>if it authorizes the holder to carry out one or more activities, including distributing drugs as a distributor referred to in paragraph C.01A.003(a) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Food and Drug Regulations</XRefExternal> or wholesaling drugs but not including fabricating, packaging/labelling or importing drugs or distributing drugs as a distributor referred to in paragraph C.01A.003(b) of those Regulations, for each site in respect of which the matter is reinstated, the basic fee set out in section 9; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>if it authorizes the holder only to test drugs, for each site in respect of which the matter is reinstated, the basic fee set out in section 10.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Remission</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>If a remission has been granted under section 11 or 13, the fee payable for a reinstated establishment licence is the lesser of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the fee determined in accordance with section 11 or 13, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the fee determined in accordance with subsection (1).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Time of payment</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The fee determined in accordance with this section is payable on the day on which the establishment licence is reinstated.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2011-84, s. 5.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Transitional Provisions</TitleText></Heading><Section type="transitional"><MarginalNote>Licence issued before coming into force</MarginalNote><Label>21</Label><Text>Despite section 11, the fees determined in accordance with sections 3 to 10 and subsection 13(2) are payable on January 1, 1998, if an establishment licence is issued before that date.</Text></Section><Section type="transitional"><MarginalNote>Application for a reduction</MarginalNote><Label>22</Label><Subsection type="transitional"><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Despite subsection 12(2), if an application for an establishment licence is submitted before January 1, 1998, an application for a fee reduction may be submitted no later than 60 days after the day of the coming into force of these Regulations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection type="transitional"><MarginalNote>Remission</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>If a person has paid the total fee referred to in subsection 12(1) at the time an application for a fee reduction is submitted within the period referred to in subsection (1), the Minister of Health shall grant a remission to the applicant of an amount equal to the difference between</Text><Paragraph type="transitional"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in the case of an application under section 13, an amount equal to the difference between</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the sum of the fees paid pursuant to subsection 12(1), and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the total fee payable pursuant to subsection 13(2); and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph type="transitional"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the case of an application under section 14, an amount equal to the difference between</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the sum of the fees paid pursuant to subsection 12(1), and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the sum of the fees payable pursuant to paragraph 14(3)(a).</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section type="transitional"><MarginalNote>Coming into force</MarginalNote><Label>23</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on January 1, 1998.</Text></Section></Body><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 1</Label><OriginatingRef>(Sections 4, 16, 17 and 20)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><TableGroup pointsize="9" topmarginspacing="4"><table frame="topbot"><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="60.98*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="306.83*" /><colspec colname="3" colwidth="100.20*" /><thead><row valign="bottom" topdouble="yes" topmarginspacing="4"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" /><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Column 1</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Column 2</entry></row><row valign="bottom" topmarginspacing="6"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1">Item</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1">Description</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1">Fee ($)</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Basic fee</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">6,000</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Each additional category</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1,500</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" morerows="6" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">3</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Dosage form classes:</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top" /></row><row topmarginspacing="0"><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>2 classes</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">3,000</entry></row><row topmarginspacing="0"><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>3 classes</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">6,000</entry></row><row topmarginspacing="0"><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>4 classes</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">7,500</entry></row><row topmarginspacing="0"><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(d)</Label><Text>5 classes</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">9,000</entry></row><row topmarginspacing="0"><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(e)</Label><Text>6 classes</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">10,500</entry></row><row topmarginspacing="0"><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(f)</Label><Text>each additional class</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">600</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">4</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Sterile dosage forms</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">3,000</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Schedule><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 2</Label><OriginatingRef>(Sections 5, 17 and 20)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><TableGroup pointsize="9" topmarginspacing="4"><table frame="topbot"><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="60.94*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="306.36*" /><colspec colname="3" colwidth="100.71*" /><thead><row valign="bottom" topdouble="yes" topmarginspacing="4"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" /><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Column 1</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Column 2</entry></row><row valign="bottom" topmarginspacing="6"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1">Item</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1">Description</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1">Fee ($)</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Basic fee</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">4,000</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Each additional category</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1,000</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" morerows="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">3</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Dosage form classes:</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top" /></row><row topmarginspacing="0"><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>2 classes</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2,000</entry></row><row topmarginspacing="0"><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>3 or more classes</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">3,000</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Schedule><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 3</Label><OriginatingRef>(Sections 6, 7, 17 and 20)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><TableGroup pointsize="9" topmarginspacing="4"><table frame="topbot"><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="62.50*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="304.29*" /><colspec colname="3" colwidth="101.22*" /><thead><row valign="bottom" topdouble="yes" topmarginspacing="4"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" /><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Column 1</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Column 2</entry></row><row valign="bottom" topmarginspacing="6"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1">Item</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1">Description</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1">Fee ($)</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Basic fee</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2,500</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Each additional category</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">625</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" morerows="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">3</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Dosage form classes:</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top" /></row><row topmarginspacing="0"><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>2 classes</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1,250</entry></row><row topmarginspacing="0"><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>3 or more classes</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2,500</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">4</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Each fabricator</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">600</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">5</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Each additional dosage form class for each fabricator</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">300</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Schedule><Schedule bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 4</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 8)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><TableGroup pointsize="9" topmarginspacing="4"><table frame="topbot"><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="0.53*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="1.89*" /><colspec colname="3" colwidth="0.58*" /><thead><row valign="bottom" topdouble="yes" topmarginspacing="4"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" /><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Column 1</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Column 2</entry></row><row valign="bottom" topmarginspacing="6"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Item</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Description</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Fee ($)</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1 to 4</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2011-84, s. 6]</Repealed></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top" /></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">5</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Drugs for veterinary use</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">250</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">6 to 11</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2011-84, s. 7]</Repealed></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top" /></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup><HistoricalNote>SOR/2011-84, ss. 6, 7.</HistoricalNote></Schedule></Regulation>