<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/93-306</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1993</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>8</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>19</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AIRPORT TRANSFER (MISCELLANEOUS MATTERS) ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Designated Employees Pension Protection Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting Pension Protection for Designated Employees</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1993-1216</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1993</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>8</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision language-align="yes" format-ref="indent-0-0" list-item="no"><Text>His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the President of the Treasury Board, pursuant to subsections 5(3) and (4) of the Airport Transfer (Miscellaneous Matters) Act<FootnoteRef idref="footnote1_e">*</FootnoteRef>, is pleased hereby to make the annexed Regulations respecting pension protection for designated employees.</Text><Footnote id="footnote1_e" placement="section" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>S.C. 1992, c. 5</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Designated Employees Pension Protection Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Applicable Enactments</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>Subject to sections 3 and 4, the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Superannuation Act</XRefExternal> and the regulations made under that Act apply to a person who makes an election under paragraph 5(1)(e) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Airport Transfer (Miscellaneous Matters) Act</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>Subsections 12(4), (6) and (7) and 13(2) and (3) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Superannuation Act</XRefExternal> do not apply in respect of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a surviving spouse of a designated employee for an airport who became the spouse of that employee on or after the transfer date for that airport, unless the designated employee had again become a contributor under the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Superannuation Act</XRefExternal>; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a child of a designated employee for an airport who was conceived by, adopted by, or became the stepchild of, a designated employee on or after the transfer date for the airport, unless the designated employee had again become a contributor under the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Superannuation Act</XRefExternal>.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Adapted Provisions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>For the purposes of section 5 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Airport Transfer (Miscellaneous Matters) Act</XRefExternal>,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in subparagraphs 10(9)(b)(i) and (ii) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Superannuation Act</XRefExternal>, the year in which a person ceased to be employed in the Public Service is the year in which the person ceased to be employed by a designated airport authority;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in subsections 12(1) to (3) and (6) to (8) and section 13 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Superannuation Act</XRefExternal>,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the number of years of pensionable service and the number of years of service of a designated employee for an airport includes any period of service with a designated airport authority during the period beginning on the transfer date for the airport and ending on the day preceding the day on which the person ceases to be employed by the designated airport authority, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the day on which a person ceases to be employed in the Public Service is the day on which that person ceases to be employed by a designated airport authority; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>in subsection 69(3) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Superannuation Act</XRefExternal>, the retirement year or retirement month of a person who is a designated employee for an airport is the year or month, as the case may be, in which the transfer date for the airport occurs.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section type="transitional"><Label>5</Label><Text>These Regulations shall be deemed to have come into force on July 1, 1992.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>