<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/80-686</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1980</YYYY><MM>8</MM><DD>27</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2010</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>23</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CANADIAN HUMAN RIGHTS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Immigration Investigation Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting the Manner in Which Complaints Relating to Immigration Will be Investigated</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1980-2259</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1980</YYYY><MM>8</MM><DD>27</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Justice, pursuant to subsection 35(4) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canadian Human Rights Act</XRefExternal>, is pleased hereby to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting the manner in which complaints relating to immigration will be investigated</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Immigration Investigation Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canadian Human Rights Act</XRefExternal>;</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Commission</DefinedTermEn> means the Canadian Human Rights Commission.</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Procedure</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>Where a complaint relating to immigration is received by the Commission against the Canada Employment and Immigration Commission or one of its officers, the Commission shall serve on the Chairman of the Canada Employment and Immigration Commission</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a copy of the complaint;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the name of the investigator designated to investigate the complaint, pursuant to subsection 35(1) of the Act; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a proposed investigation plan</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>identifying relevant documents believed to be in the possession of the Canada Employment and Immigration Commission that are required to be examined by the investigator, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>identifying persons in the employ of the Canada Employment and Immigration Commission who are required to be examined by the investigator,</Text></Subparagraph><ContinuedParagraph><Text>and specifying the days and times at which such documents or persons are required for examination.</Text></ContinuedParagraph></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>An investigation plan shall not require documents or persons to be examined earlier than seven working days from the date the Chairman of the Canada Employment and Immigration Commission was served with a copy of the complaint.</Text></Section><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>The Commission shall also serve a copy of the complaint on any employee of the Canada Employment and Immigration Commission who is identified in the said complaint or who is the person whose actions resulted in the complaint and if that person is required to be examined by the investigator he or she shall not be examined until 48 hours after he or she has been served with a copy of the complaint.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>