<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/86-922</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1986</YYYY><MM>8</MM><DD>27</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2011</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>1</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">RAILWAY SAFETY ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Service Equipment Cars Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting the Movement in Trains of Service Equipment Cars</LongTitle></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="centered" language-align="yes"><Text>CTC 1986-9 RAIL</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>The Canadian Transport Commission, pursuant to section 46 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">National Transportation Act</XRefExternal> and section 227 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Railway Act</XRefExternal>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting the movement in trains of service equipment cars</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Hull, Quebec, in the National Capital Region, August 26, 1986</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Service Equipment Cars Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>marshal</DefinedTermEn> means to assign a car to a specific location in a train, relative to the locomotive or caboose; (<DefinedTermFr>triage</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>service equipment car</DefinedTermEn> means rolling stock used to house employees at work sites, a material car used for transporting railway maintenance-of-way equipment or for railway company purposes if not used in revenue service and wrecking auxiliaries. (<DefinedTermFr>wagon de matériel de service</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Marshalling</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>Subject to sections 4 and 5, a railway company shall marshal occupied service equipment cars other than flangers, plows, spreaders, test cars and business cars</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in the case of a freight train, at the rear end of the train immediately ahead of the caboose; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the case of a mixed freight and passenger train, immediately ahead of any passenger cars.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>No railway company shall marshal</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>an open top trailer being used in piggyback service, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>an open top car other than a car that has permanent bulkheads and that is loaded lengthwise with timber, poles, rail, rods or other similar commodities,</Text></Paragraph><ContinuedSectionSubsection><Text>nearer than second from an occupied service equipment car and at least one of the intervening cars shall be a full size steel boxcar or bulkhead type car.</Text></ContinuedSectionSubsection></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>No railway company shall marshal a car containing dangerous goods</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>where a train consists of seven cars or more, nearer than sixth from an occupied service equipment car; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>where a train consists of less than seven cars, other than near the middle of the train but not nearer than second from an occupied service equipment car.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>5</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Where it is necessary to set off service equipment cars at a point where track configuration may require the use of additional measures to ensure the safety of the set-off movement, a railway company may marshall occupied service equipment cars to the front end of a train, immediately behind the locomotive.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Where the cars of a train are marshalled in accordance with subsection (1), the train</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>shall not be moved a distance exceeding 32.18 km (20 miles); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>shall not exceed a speed of 32.18 km (20 miles) per hour at any time.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Lengths</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>A railway company shall restrict a train having 30 or less occupied service equipment cars to not more than 60 cars in total.</Text></Section><Section><Label>7</Label><Text>Where a train has more than 30 occupied service equipment cars, a railway company shall restrict the train to service equipment cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Train Speeds</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>8</Label><Text>No railway company shall permit a train having occupied service equipment cars to exceed a speed of 56.31 km (35 miles) per hour at any time.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Securement</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>9</Label><Text>No railway company shall, move an occupied service equipment car, unless</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>all heavy furniture, appliances and other heavy objects are securely fastened to the structure of the car; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>all tools and equipment are secured in a place isolated from living quarters in the car.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Communication</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>10</Label><Text>A railway company shall, within two years after the date of the coming into force and these Regulations, provide each occupied service equipment car with a means of voice communication with the train crew in other parts of the train or with an emergency brake valve.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Protection in Sidings</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>11</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A railway company shall protect occupied service equipment cars placed in sidings, back tracks or other tracks against other train movements by</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>issuing a train order in accordance with the second sentence of Rule 203 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations No. 0-8, Uniform Code of Operating Rules</XRefExternal> or a Manual Block System Bulletin pursuant to Rule 323 of the said Regulations;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>spiking the switches of back tracks and other tracks; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>where practicable, spiking the switches of sidings.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>No railway company shall permit the coupling to or the moving of occupied service equipment cars until</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the locomotive or train involved in the coupling or moving has come to a stop not more than 12 feet or not less than six feet from the cars to be moved or coupled; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>employees in or about the cars are notified by a member of the train crew that a coupling or moving is to take place.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>No railway company shall cut off occupied service equipment cars while they are in motion or cut off other cars while the other cars are in motion toward occupied service equipment cars.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>12</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>No railway company shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>refill propane cylinders used in occupied service equipment cars on the right-of-way; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>carry spare propane cylinders in occupied service equipment cars.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Where propane cylinders are installed for use in service equipment cars, a railway company shall install</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>an automatic shut-off valve for the supply of fuel from each propane cylinder; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a pilot flame monitoring device to automatically shut off the supply of fuel in the event of pilot flame failure.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section></Body></Regulation>