<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/86-501</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1986</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>1</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>7</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">FOREIGN MISSIONS AND INTERNATIONAL ORGANIZATIONS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Pacific Salmon Commission Privileges and Immunities Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Respecting the Granting of Certain Privileges and Immunities to the Pacific Salmon Commission</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1986-1083 </OrderNumber><Date><YYYY> 1986</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>1</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Whereas on January 28, 1985, the Government of Canada and the Government of the United States of America have signed the Treaty between the Government of Canada and the Government of the United States of America concerning Pacific Salmon;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Whereas on March 18, 1985, the Government of Canada and the Government of the United States of America have exchanged instruments of ratification for the said Treaty;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>And Whereas paragraph II(1) of the said Treaty establishes the Pacific Salmon Commission;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Therefore, Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Secretary of State for External Affairs and with the concurrence of the Minister of Fisheries and Oceans, pursuant to section 3 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Privileges and Immunities (International Organizations) Act</XRefExternal>, is pleased hereby to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Order respecting the granting of certain privileges and immunities to the Pacific Salmon Commission</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Pacific Salmon Commission Privileges and Immunities Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In this Order,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Convention</DefinedTermEn> means the Convention on the Privileges and Immunities of the United Nations; (<DefinedTermFr>Convention</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Organization</DefinedTermEn> means the Pacific Salmon Commission established pursuant to paragraph II(1) of the Treaty between the Government of Canada and the Government of the United States of America concerning Pacific Salmon. (<DefinedTermFr>Organisation</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Privileges and Immunities</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The Organization shall have in Canada the legal capacities of a body corporate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The Organization shall have in Canada, to such extent as may be required for the exercise of its functions in Canada, the privileges and immunities set out in Articles II and III of the Convention.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Representatives of the governments that are Members of the Organization shall have in Canada, to such extent as may be required for the exercise of their functions in Canada, the privileges and immunities set out in Article IV of the Convention.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>All officials of the Organization shall have in Canada, to such extent as may be required for the exercise of their functions in Canada, the privileges and immunities set out in Article V of the Convention.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>All experts performing missions for the Organization shall have in Canada, to such extent as may be required for the exercise of their functions in Canada, the privileges and immunities set out in Article VI of the Convention.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/89-390, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section></Body></Regulation>