<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/97-569</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1997</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>9</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2009</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>23</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CRIMINAL CODE</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>British Columbia Rules of Practice Respecting Reduction in the Number of Years of Imprisonment Without Eligibility for Parole</LongTitle></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The Chief Justice of the Supreme Court of British Columbia, pursuant to subsection 745.64(1)<FootnoteRef idref="footnotea_e">a</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Criminal Code</XRefExternal>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">British Columbia Rules of Practice Respecting Reduction in the Number of Years of Imprisonment Without Eligibility for Parole</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="footnotea_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 1996, c. 34, s. 2(2)</Text></Footnote></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Dated at Vancouver, British Columbia, this 5th day of November, 1997</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><SignatureBlock justification="right" width="14pc"><SignatureName bottommarginspacing="0" justification="left" topmarginspacing="6">Bryan Williams</SignatureName><SignatureTitle justification="left">Chief Justice of the Supreme Court of British Columbia</SignatureTitle></SignatureBlock></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><Label>RULE 7</Label><TitleText>Applications for a Reduction in the Number of Years of Imprisonment Without Eligibility for Parole</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The following definitions apply in Rule 7.</Text><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>applicant</DefinedTermEn> means a person who makes an application and includes, according to the context, counsel acting for that person. (<DefinedTermFr>requérant</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>application</DefinedTermEn> means an application made pursuant to subsection 745.6(1) of the Code. (<DefinedTermFr>demande</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Attorney General</DefinedTermEn> means the Attorney General of British Columbia and includes counsel acting for the Attorney General of British Columbia. (<DefinedTermFr>procureur général</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>district registrar</DefinedTermEn> means the district registrar of the Supreme Court of British Columbia for the Vancouver Judicial District. (<DefinedTermFr>registraire du district</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>judge</DefinedTermEn> means the judge of the Supreme Court of British Columbia designated by the Chief Justice to empanel a jury pursuant to subsection 745.61(5) of the Code in respect of an application. (<DefinedTermFr>juge</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Section><Label>(2)</Label><Text>These Rules come into force on December 1, 1997.</Text></Section><Section><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">British Columbia Rules of Practice Respecting Reduction in the Number of Years of Imprisonment Without Eligibility for Parole</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="footnote1_e">1</FootnoteRef> are repealed.</Text><Footnote id="footnote1_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>1</Label><Text>SOR/92-746</Text></Footnote></Section><Section><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Subrules 1(5) to (10) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Criminal Rules of the Supreme Court of British Columbia</XRefExternal> apply in respect of Rule 7.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Application for Reduction</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>(5)</Label><Text>An application for a reduction in the number of years of imprisonment without eligibility for parole shall be in writing in Form 8 and shall indicate</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the applicant’s full name and date of birth;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the offence and the sentence in respect of which the application is made, the dates of conviction and sentencing and the place of the trial;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the name and place of the institution in which the applicant is detained;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the name and place of each institution in which the applicant has been detained since the time of the applicant’s arrest for the offence that is the subject of the application, and the date of entry into each of those institutions;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>any sentence, in addition to the sentence in respect of which the application is made, that the applicant is serving at the time of the application and the date and place of the imposition of that sentence and the offence in respect of which the sentence was imposed;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>the grounds to be relied on in support of the application;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>the relief sought; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>the applicant’s address for service.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>(6)</Label><Text>An application shall be supported by an affidavit of the applicant in Form 9.</Text></Section><Section><Label>(7)</Label><Text>An application, together with an affidavit referred to in subrule (6), shall be filed with the district registrar.</Text></Section><Section><Label>(8)</Label><Subsection><Label>(a)</Label><Text>Immediately after an application is filed with the district registrar, the applicant shall cause the application to be served on</Text><Paragraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the Solicitor General of Canada;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the Attorney General; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>the officer in charge of the institution in which the applicant is detained.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(b)</Label><Text>Service of an application may be effected by registered mail, in which case it is deemed to have been effected on the seventh day after the day on which the application was mailed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(c)</Label><Text>Proof of service of an application may be established by an affidavit of the person who effected the service.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(d)</Label><Text>Proof of service of an application shall be filed with the district registrar no later than seven days after the day on which the service was effected.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Designation of Judge</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>(9)</Label><Text>A designation of a judge pursuant to subsection 745.61(5) of the Code shall be in writing and shall be filed with the district registrar.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Notice of Preliminary Hearing</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>(10)</Label><Subsection><Label>(a)</Label><Text>On receipt of an application, the judge shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>determine the date and place of the preliminary hearing to be held in connection with the application;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>send a written notice of the date and place of the preliminary hearing to the Attorney General; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>instruct the Attorney General to take the necessary steps to ensure that the applicant is present on the date and at the place determined for the preliminary hearing.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(b)</Label><Text>On receipt of a notice referred to in paragraph (a)(i), the Attorney General shall send a written notice of the date and place of the preliminary hearing by registered mail or by other accepted means of service to</Text><Paragraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the applicant;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the Solicitor General of Canada; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>the officer in charge of the institution in which the applicant is detained.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(c)</Label><Text>A copy of each notice referred to in subrule (b) shall be filed with the district registrar.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Preliminary Hearing</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>(11)</Label><Subsection><Label>(a)</Label><Text>At a preliminary hearing held in connection with an application, the judge shall determine</Text><Paragraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>whether the applicant meets the requirements of subsection 745.6(1) of the Code;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>whether the application meets the requirements of Rule 7;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>the means of presenting evidence;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>whether evidence is to be provided to the other party prior to the date determined for the hearing of the application and, if so, how and when that evidence shall be provided;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(v)</Label><Text>the nature and extent of any cross-examination; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(vi)</Label><Text>the date and place for the hearing of the application.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(b)</Label><Text>At a preliminary hearing, the applicant and the Attorney General shall inform the judge of any evidence they intend to present and of the manner in which they intend to present it.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(c)</Label><Text>The judge may adjourn a preliminary hearing as the judge considers appropriate and resume the preliminary hearing on a date and at a place determined by the judge.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Parole Eligibility Report</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>(12)</Label><Subsection><Label>(a)</Label><Text>At a preliminary hearing, the judge may order that a parole eligibility report in respect of an applicant and having regard to the matters referred to in subsection 745.63(1) of the Code be prepared.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(b)</Label><Text>A parole eligibility report in respect of an applicant shall be prepared by a person designated by the Solicitor General of Canada and shall contain</Text><Paragraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>a summary of the applicant’s social and family background;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>a summary of the applicant’s classification and discipline evaluations;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>a summary of the regular reports of the applicant’s conduct;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>a summary of any psychological and psychiatric assessments that have been made of the applicant; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(v)</Label><Text>any other information relevant to a complete description of the applicant’s character and conduct.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(c)</Label><Text>A parole eligibility report in respect of an applicant may contain any information relevant to the issue of the parole eligibility of the applicant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(d)</Label><Text>Where the judge at a preliminary hearing orders that a parole eligibility report be prepared, the judge shall adjourn the preliminary hearing to allow for the preparation of that report.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(e)</Label><Text>A parole eligibility report shall be filed with the district registrar.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(f)</Label><Text>The district registrar, on receiving a parole eligibility report in respect of an applicant, shall deliver a copy of that report to the applicant and to the Attorney General.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>(13)</Label><Subsection><Label>(a)</Label><Text>The judge, on being informed that a parole eligibility report has been filed, shall notify the applicant and the Attorney General that the preliminary hearing is being resumed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(b)</Label><Text>In setting the date for the resumption of a preliminary hearing, the judge shall allow at least 30 days for the applicant and the Attorney General to study the parole eligibility report.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>(14)</Label><Text>Where the applicant or the Attorney General disputes any part of the parole eligibility report, the applicant or the Attorney General may require the attendance of the author of that report at the preliminary hearing for the purposes of cross-examination.</Text></Section><Section><Label>(15)</Label><Text>In the case of a dispute at a preliminary hearing, the judge shall decide what parts of the parole eligibility report in respect of the applicant and what additional evidence, if any, are to be presented at the hearing of the application.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Hearing of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>(16)</Label><Subsection><Label>(a)</Label><Text>The hearing of an application shall be conducted and the jury shall be empanelled in accordance with Part XX of the Code, with the modification set in out subrule (b) and any other modifications that the circumstances require.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(b)</Label><Text>For the purposes of subrule (a), the applicant and the Attorney General are entitled to the same number of peremptory challenges as they would be entitled to if the applicant were being tried for the offence that is the subject of the application.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>(17)</Label><Text>The judge may at any time make any orders and give any directions that the judge considers necessary for the due hearing and disposition of an application, including orders and directions respecting the sufficiency of an application and the extension or reduction of time periods.</Text></Section><Section><Label>(18)</Label><Text>At the hearing of an application, the judge may, to the extent that the judge considers necessary and desirable, admit as evidence a duly certified transcript of the proceedings at the trial and the sentencing of the applicant for the offence in respect of which the application is made.</Text></Section><Section><Label>(19)</Label><Text>At the hearing of an application, the applicant shall present evidence first and may, if the judge so permits, present rebuttal evidence after the evidence of the Attorney General is presented.</Text></Section><Section><Label>(20)</Label><Text>After the presentation of evidence at the hearing of an application, the applicant, followed by the Attorney General, shall address the jury and the applicant may reply after the address of the Attorney General to the jury.</Text></Section><Section><Label>(21)</Label><Text>The jury at the hearing of an application shall base its decision on the evidence presented to it at the hearing.</Text></Section></Body><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label><Emphasis style="bold">APPENDIX</Emphasis></Label></ScheduleFormHeading><FormGroup><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>FORM 8</Label><OriginatingRef>(Subrule 7(5))</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>CANADA</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" topmarginspacing="6" list-item="no"><Text>PROVINCE OF BRITISH COLUMBIA</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" topmarginspacing="6" list-item="no"><Text>IN THE SUPREME COURT OF BRITISH COLUMBIA</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" topmarginspacing="6" list-item="no"><Text>IN THE MATTER OF <Emphasis style="italic">(give full name of applicant)</Emphasis>, an application for a reduction in the number of years of imprisonment without eligibility for parole pursuant to section 745.6 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Criminal Code</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="centered"><Text><Leader leader="dash" length="4pc" /></Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>To the Honourable Chief Justice of the Supreme Court of British Columbia:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Label>1</Label><Text>I, <Emphasis style="italic">(give full name of applicant)</Emphasis>, born on <Emphasis style="italic">(applicant’s date of birth)</Emphasis> and detained at <Emphasis style="italic">(name and place of the institution)</Emphasis>, hereby apply, pursuant to section 745.6 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Criminal Code</XRefExternal>, for the number of years of imprisonment during which I will not be eligible for parole with respect to the sentence imposed on me on <Emphasis style="italic">(give date of sentencing)</Emphasis> at <Emphasis style="italic">(give place of trial)</Emphasis> to be reduced to <Emphasis style="italic">(give number of years)</Emphasis>.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Label>2</Label><Text>Since my arrest for the offence set out in paragraph 3, I have been detained in the following institutions: <Emphasis style="italic">(Give a COMPLETE list of the names and places of the institutions in which the applicant has been detained and specify the date of entry into each of the institutions)</Emphasis>.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Label>3</Label><Text>The sentence referred to in paragraph 1 was imposed on me for the following offence: <Emphasis style="italic">(Indicate the offence for which the applicant was convicted and give the date of conviction)</Emphasis>.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Label>4</Label><Text>The sentence imposed on me was <Emphasis style="italic">(give a description of the sentence)</Emphasis> and the number of years of imprisonment without eligibility for parole was set at <Emphasis style="italic">(give number of years)</Emphasis>. <Emphasis style="italic">(Indicate whether the sentence has been commuted and, if so, give the date of commutation.)</Emphasis></Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Label>5</Label><Text>In addition to the sentence referred to in paragraph 1, as of the date of this application I am also serving the following sentences: <Emphasis style="italic">(Give a list of any other sentences that the applicant is serving at the time of the application, the date and place of the imposition of the sentence and the offence in respect of which the sentence was imposed)</Emphasis>.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Label>6</Label><Text>In support of my application I am relying on the following grounds: <Emphasis style="italic">(Specify ALL grounds PRECISELY and CONCISELY)</Emphasis>.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Label>7</Label><Text>My address for service is: <Emphasis style="italic">(Give complete address)</Emphasis>.</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Dated at <Leader leader="solid" length="5pc" /> this <Leader leader="solid" length="2pc" /> day of <Leader leader="solid" length="5pc" />, 19<Leader leader="solid" length="1pc" /></Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="right-align" language-align="yes"><Text><FormBlank width="10pc"><Emphasis style="italic">(Signature of applicant)</Emphasis></FormBlank></Text></Provision></FormGroup><FormGroup><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>FORM 9</Label><OriginatingRef>(Subrule 7(6))</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>CANADA</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" topmarginspacing="6" list-item="no"><Text>PROVINCE OF BRITISH COLUMBIA</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" topmarginspacing="6" list-item="no"><Text>IN THE SUPREME COURT OF BRITISH COLUMBIA</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" topmarginspacing="6" list-item="no"><Text>IN THE MATTER of the application</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>of <FormBlank width="20pc"><Emphasis style="italic">(give full name of applicant)</Emphasis></FormBlank></Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>pursuant to section 745.6 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Criminal Code</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision></Provision><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Affidavit of Applicant</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>I, <FormBlank width="15pc"><Emphasis style="italic">(give full name of applicant)</Emphasis></FormBlank>, detained at <FormBlank width="14pc"><Emphasis style="italic">(give name and place of institution)</Emphasis></FormBlank>, in the Province of <Leader leader="solid" length="6pc" />, make oath and say as follows:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Label>1</Label><Text>I am the applicant.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Label>2</Label><Text>The facts set out in the attached application are true.</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision format-ref="right-align" language-align="yes"><Text><FormBlank width="10pc"><Emphasis style="italic">(Signature of applicant)</Emphasis></FormBlank></Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Sworn before me at <Leader leader="solid" length="8pc" /> in the Province of <Leader leader="solid" length="6pc" /> this <Leader leader="solid" length="3pc" /> day of <Leader leader="solid" length="5.5pc" />, 19<Leader leader="solid" length="1pc" /></Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text><FormBlank width="12pc">Commissioner for Oaths</FormBlank></Text></Provision></FormGroup></Schedule></Regulation>