<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en" in-force="yes"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2016-176</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2016</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>22</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2016</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>20</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CANADA CONSUMER PRODUCT SAFETY ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Textile Floor Coverings Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2016-603</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>2016</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Health, pursuant to section 37 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Consumer Product Safety Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_81200-2-TEXTILE_hc">a</FootnoteRef>, makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Textile Floor Coverings Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fn_81200-2-TEXTILE_hc" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 2010, c. 21</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Definitions</MarginalNote><Label>1</Label><Text>The following definitions apply in these Regulations.</Text><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>methenamine tablet test standard</DefinedTermEn> means the Canadian General Standards Board standard CAN/CGSB-4.2 No. 27.6-2015, entitled <XRefExternal reference-type="standard">Textile Test Methods – Flame Resistance — Methenamine Tablet Test for Textile Floor Coverings</XRefExternal>, published in September 2015. (<DefinedTermFr>norme sur l’essai à la tablette de méthénamine</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>removal of non-permanent flame-retardant treatments standard</DefinedTermEn> means the Canadian General Standards Board standard CAN/CGSB-4.2 No. 30.2-M90, entitled <XRefExternal reference-type="standard">Textile Test Methods – Procedure for the Removal of Non-Permanent Flame-Retardant Treatments on Textile Floor Coverings</XRefExternal>, published in January 1990. (<DefinedTermFr>norme sur le mode de suppression des agents ignifuges non permanents</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>sampling plans standard</DefinedTermEn> means the Canadian General Standards Board standard CAN/CGSB-4.155-M88, entitled <XRefExternal reference-type="standard">Flammability of Soft Floor Coverings — Sampling Plans</XRefExternal>, published in April 1988 and reaffirmed in November 2013. (<DefinedTermFr>norme sur les plans d’échantillonnage</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>textile floor covering</DefinedTermEn> does not include a one-of-a-kind or Oriental rug, or an underlay, that is made of textile fibres. (<DefinedTermFr>revêtement de sol textile</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Specifications</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Carpet tile or large textile floor covering — indoor only, or indoor and outdoor</MarginalNote><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The cumulative number of specimen failures that occur when a textile floor covering that is intended for indoor use only, or indoor and outdoor use, and that is either a carpet tile or has a surface area greater than 2.16 m<Sup>2</Sup> or a linear dimension greater than 1.8 m is tested in accordance with subsection (4) or (5), must not be equal to or greater than the number set out in the last column of Table 1, entitled <XRefExternal reference-type="standard">Normal Sequential Sampling Plan</XRefExternal>, to the sampling plans standard.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Carpet tile or large textile floor covering — outdoor only</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A textile floor covering that is intended for outdoor use only and that is either a carpet tile or has a surface area greater than 2.16 m<Sup>2</Sup> or a linear dimension greater than 1.8 m must, at the time it is advertised or sold, have a label that carries the following warning if the cumulative number of specimen failures that occur when it is tested in accordance with subsection (4) or (5) is equal to or greater than the number set out in the last column of Table 1, entitled <XRefExternal reference-type="standard">Normal Sequential Sampling Plan</XRefExternal>, to the sampling plans standard:</Text><Provision format-ref="centered" language-align="yes" pointsize="8"><Text>Caution — Flammable — Do not use in locations exposed to open flame or sources of intense heat. Do not use indoors.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="centered" language-align="yes" pointsize="8"><Text><Language xml:lang="fr">Attention — Inflammable — Tenir éloigné de la flamme ou d’une source de chaleur intense. Ne pas utiliser à l’intérieur.</Language></Text></Provision></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Small textile floor covering — indoor only, indoor and outdoor, or outdoor only</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>A textile floor covering that is intended for indoor use only, indoor and outdoor use or outdoor use only and that has a surface area equal to or less than 2.16 m<Sup>2</Sup> and linear dimensions that are all equal to or less than 1.8 m must, at the time it is advertised or sold, have a label that carries the warning set out in subsection (2) or the following warning if the cumulative number of specimen failures that occur when it is tested in accordance with subsection (4) or (5) is equal to or greater than the number set out in the last column of Table 1, entitled <XRefExternal reference-type="standard">Normal Sequential Sampling Plan</XRefExternal>, to the sampling plans standard:</Text><Provision format-ref="centered" language-align="yes" pointsize="8"><Text>Caution — Flammable — Do not use in locations exposed to open flame or sources of intense heat.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="centered" language-align="yes" pointsize="8"><Text><Language xml:lang="fr">Attention — Inflammable — Tenir éloigné de la flamme ou d’une source de chaleur intense.</Language></Text></Provision></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Test — not treated with flame retardant</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>A textile floor covering that has not been treated with a flame retardant must be tested using a sample that consists of 48 specimens, in accordance with the following:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the <XRefExternal reference-type="standard">Normal Sequential Sampling Plan</XRefExternal> set out in the sampling plans standard; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the methenamine tablet test standard.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Test — treated with flame retardant</MarginalNote><Label>(5)</Label><Text>A textile floor covering that has been treated with a flame retardant must be tested using a sample that consists of 48 specimens, in accordance with the following:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the removal of non-permanent flame-retardant treatments standard;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the <XRefExternal reference-type="standard">Normal Sequential Sampling Plan</XRefExternal> set out in the sampling plans standard; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the methenamine tablet test standard.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Labelling</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Presentation</MarginalNote><Label>3</Label><Text>The warnings referred to in subsections 2(2) and (3) must be clearly and prominently displayed and be</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>printed in letters that are easily legible and of equal size and prominence; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>set apart from any other information or visual images on the label.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Packaged textile floor covering</MarginalNote><Label>4</Label><Text>In the case of a textile floor covering that is packaged, the required label must be on its package, unless the label is affixed to the textile floor covering itself and it is packaged in such a manner that the warning is clearly visible to the consumer.</Text></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Importation</MarginalNote><Label>5</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A person may import a textile floor covering that is not labelled in accordance with these Regulations if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>it is imported solely for the purpose of resale;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>on or before the date of the importation, the person sends to the inspector referred to in subsection (2) a notice containing the following information:</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>a statement to the effect that they are the importer,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the date and place of the importation,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>the nature and quantity of the textile floor covering being imported, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>the address of the premises where the textile floor covering will be labelled in accordance with these Regulations; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>prior to reselling the textile floor covering, they notify the inspector in writing that it has been labelled in accordance with these Regulations.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Inspector</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>For the purpose of subsection (1), the notice must be sent to the inspector who is located at the place where the textile floor covering is to be labelled in accordance with these Regulations or, if there is no inspector, to the inspector who is located nearest to that place.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Repeal</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>[Repeal]</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section type="transitional"><MarginalNote>Registration</MarginalNote><Label>7</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on the day on which they are registered.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>