<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/94-123</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1994</YYYY><MM>1</MM><DD>20</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2011</YYYY><MM>8</MM><DD>25</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AERONAUTICS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Peterborough Airport Zoning Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting Zoning at Peterborough Airport</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1994-98</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1994</YYYY><MM>1</MM><DD>20</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Whereas, pursuant to section 5.5 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Aeronautics Act</XRefExternal>, a copy of the proposed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting zoning at Peterborough Airport</XRefExternal>, substantially in the form set out in the schedule hereto, was published in two successive issues of the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal> Part I on March 2nd and 9th, 1991, and in two successive issues of the <Emphasis style="italic">Peterborough Examiner</Emphasis> on April 5th and 12th, 1991, and a reasonable opportunity was thereby afforded to interested persons to make representations to the Minister of Transport with respect thereto;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Therefore, His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Transport, pursuant to section 5.4 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Aeronautics Act</XRefExternal>, is pleased hereby to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting zoning at Peterborough Airport</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Peterborough Airport Zoning Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>airport</DefinedTermEn> means the Peterborough Airport, in the Townships of Cavan, North Monaghan, South Monaghan and Otonabee, County of Peterborough, in the Province of Ontario; (<DefinedTermFr>aéroport</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>airport reference point</DefinedTermEn> means the point described in Part I of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>point de repère de l’aéroport</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>approach surfaces</DefinedTermEn> means the imaginary inclined planes that extend upward and outward from each end of a strip, which planes are more particularly described in Part II of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>surfaces d’approche</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>outer surface</DefinedTermEn> means an imaginary plane located above and in the immediate vicinity of the airport, which plane is more particularly described in Part III of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>surface extérieure</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>strip</DefinedTermEn> means the rectangular portion of the landing area of the airport, including the runway, prepared for the take-off and landing of aircraft in a particular direction, which portion is more particularly described in Part IV of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>bande</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>transitional surfaces</DefinedTermEn> means the imaginary inclined planes that extend upward and outward from the lateral limits of a strip and its approach surfaces, which planes are more particularly described in Part V of the schedule. (<DefinedTermFr>surfaces de transition</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>For the purposes of these Regulations, the elevation of the airport reference point is 190.3 m above sea level.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>These Regulations apply to all land, including public road allowances, that is adjacent to or in the vicinity of the airport, which land is more particularly described in Part VI of the schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>No person shall erect or construct, on any land to which these Regulations apply, any building, structure or object or any addition to any existing building, structure or object, the highest point of which will exceed in elevation at the location of that point</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the approach surfaces;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the outer surface; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the transitional surfaces.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Aeronautical Facilities</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>No owner or lessee of any land to which these Regulations apply shall permit any part of that land to be used or developed in a manner that causes interference with any signals or communications to and from any aircraft or to and from any facilities used to provide services relating to aeronautics.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Natural Growth</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>Where an object of natural growth that is on any land to which these Regulations apply grows to a height that exceeds in elevation at the location of the object any of the surfaces referred to in section 4, the Minister may require that the owner or lessee of the land remove the excessive growth.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Disposal of Waste</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>7</Label><Text>No owner or lessee of any land to which these Regulations apply shall permit any part of that land to be used for the disposal of any waste that is edible by or attractive to birds.</Text></Section></Body><Schedule bilingual="no" spanlanguages="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label><OriginatingRef>(Sections 2 and 3)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><Heading level="1"><Label>PART I</Label><TitleText>Description of the Airport Reference Point</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The airport reference point shown on Peterborough Airport Zoning Plan No. 15-006 89-43, Sheet 5, dated December 29, 1989, is a point which may be located by:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>COMMENCING at the easterly end of runway 09-27;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE westerly along the centreline of said runway a distance of 450.76 m to a point;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE southerly and perpendicular to the said runway centreline a distance of 95.14 m to the airport reference point which point has the six degree Universal Transverse Mercator co-ordinates of N 4 900 575.39 and E 710 707.05.</Text></Provision></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART II</Label><TitleText>Description of the Approach Surfaces</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The approach surfaces, shown on Peterborough Airport Zoning Plan No. 15-006 89-43, Sheets 4, 5 and 6, dated December 29, 1989 are planes abutting each end of the strip associated with runway 09-27, and are described as follows:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>an inclined plane abutting the end of the strip associated with the approach to runway 09 having a ratio of l m measured vertically to 40 m measured horizontally rising to an imaginary horizontal line drawn at right angles to the projected centre line of the strip and distant 1 800 m measured horizontally from the end of the strip; the outer ends of the imaginary horizontal line being 345 m from the projected centre line; said imaginary horizontal line being 45 m above the elevation at the end of the strip; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>an inclined plane abutting the end of the strip associated with the approach to runway 27 having a ratio of l m measured vertically to 40 m measured horizontally rising to an imaginary horizontal line drawn at right angles to the projected centre line of the strip and distant 1 764 m measured horizontally from the end of the strip; the outer ends of the imaginary horizontal line being 339.6 m from the projected centre line; said imaginary horizontal line being 44.1 m above the elevation at the end of the strip.</Text></Provision></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART III</Label><TitleText>Description of the Outer Surface</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The outer surface, shown on Peterborough Airport Zoning Plan No. 15-006 89-43, Sheets 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8 and 9, dated December 29, 1989, is an imaginary plane established at a constant elevation of 45 m above the elevation of the airport reference point, except that, where that plane is less than 9 m above the surface of the ground, the outer surface is located at 9 m above the surface of the ground.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART IV</Label><TitleText>Description of the Strip</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The strip associated with runway 09-27, shown on Peterborough Airport Zoning Plan No. 15-006 89-43, Sheet 5, dated December 29, 1989, is 150 m in width, 75 m being on each side of the centre line of the runway and 1 644.36 m in length.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART V</Label><TitleText>Description of Each Transitional Surface</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Each transitional surface, shown on Peterborough Airport Zoning Plan No. 15-006 89-43, Sheets 4, 5 and 6, dated December 29, 1989, is an inclined plane rising at a ratio of 1 m measured vertically to 7 m measured horizontally at right angles to the centre line and projected centre line of the strip, extending upward and outward from the lateral limits of the strip and its approach surfaces to an intersection with the outer surface.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART VI</Label><TitleText>Description of the Lands to Which These Regulations Apply</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The outer boundary of the land to which these Regulations apply, shown on Peterborough Airport Zoning Plan No. 15-006 89-43, Sheets 1 to 4 and 6 to 9 dated December 29, 1989, is described as follows:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>ALL AND SINGULAR those certain parcels or tracts of land situate, lying and being in the Townships of Cavan, North Monaghan, South Monaghan and Otonabee, all in the County of Peterborough.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>COMMENCING at the northeast corner of Lot 23, Concession 10, Township of Cavan;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE westerly along the northerly limit of Lot 23 and Lot 22, Concession 10, Township of Cavan to the northwest corner of Lot 22, Concession 10;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE southerly along the westerly boundary of the said Lot 22, to the southwest corner of the said Lot 22, Concession 10;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE southerly in a straight line across the road allowance between Concessions 9 and 10, to the northwest corner of Lot 22, Concession 9, Township of Cavan;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE southerly along the westerly limit of Lot 22, Concession 9, Township of Cavan, to the southwest corner thereof;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE southerly in a straight line across the road allowance between Concessions 8 and 9, Township of Cavan, to the northwest corner of Lot 22, Concession 8;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE southerly along the westerly limit of the said Lot 22, Concession 8, to the southwest corner thereof;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE easterly along the southerly limit of Lot 22 and Lot 23, Concession 8, to the southeast corner of Lot 23, Concession 8;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE easterly on the production of the southerly limit of Lot 23, Concession 8, Township of Cavan, in a straight line across the road allowance between the Township of Cavan and the Township of North Monaghan to its intersection with the westerly limit of Lot 1, Concession 7, Township of North Monaghan;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE southerly along the said westerly limit of Lot 1, Concession 7, Township of North Monaghan, to the southwest corner thereof;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE southerly in a straight line across the road allowance between the Townships of North Monaghan and South Monaghan, to the northwest corner of Lot 1, Concession 6, Township of South Monaghan;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE southerly along the westerly limit of Lot 1, Concession 6, Township of South Monaghan, to the southwest corner thereof;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE easterly along the southerly limit of the said Lot 1 and Lot 2, Concession 6, to the southeast corner of Lot 2, Concession 6, Township of South Monaghan;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE southerly in a straight line across the road allowance between Concessions 5 and 6, to the northwest corner of Lot 3, Concession 5, Township of South Monaghan;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE southerly along the westerly limit of the said Lot 3, Concession 5, to the southwest corner thereof;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE easterly along the southerly limit of Lots 3, 4 and 5, Concession 5, Township of South Monaghan to the southeast corner of said Lot 5, Concession 5;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE northerly along the easterly limit of said Lot 5 to the north westerly corner of Lot 6, Concession 5, Township of South Monaghan;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE northerly across the Otonabee River in a straight line to the southwest corner of Lot 13, Concession 18, Township of Otonabee;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE easterly along the southerly limit of said Lot 13 to the southeast corner thereof;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE easterly in a straight line across the road allowance between Concessions 17 and 18, Township of Otonabee to the southwest corner of said Lot 13, Concession 17;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE easterly along the southerly limit of the West Half of Lot 13, Concession 17, to the southeast corner of the said West Half of Lot 13, Concession 17;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE easterly along the southerly limit of the said East Half of Lot 13, Concession 17 to the southeast corner of the said East Half of Lot 13, Concession 17;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE easterly in a straight line across the road allowance between Concessions 16 and 17, Township of Otonabee to the southwest corner of Lot 13, Concession 16, Township of Otonabee;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE easterly along the southerly limit of the West Half of Lot 13, Concession 16, to the southeast corner thereof;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE northerly along the line between the East and West Halves of the said Lot 13, Concession 16, to the northwest corner of the East Half of the said Lot 13, Concession 16;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE easterly along the northerly limit of the East Half of said Lot 13, Concession 16, to the northeast corner thereof;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE northerly along the easterly limit of Lot 14, Concession 16, to the northeast corner of the said Lot 14, Concession 16;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE easterly in a straight line across the road allowance between Concessions 15 and 16, to the southwest corner of Lot 15, Concession 15, Township of Otonabee;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE easterly along the southerly limit of the said Lot 15, Concession 15, to its intersection with the line between the East and West Halves of the said Lot 15, Concession 15;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE northerly along the line between the East and West Halves of the said Lot 15, Concession 15, to the northeast corner of the West Half of the said Lot 15, Concession 15;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE northerly along the line between the East and West Halves of Lot 16, Concession 15 to its intersection with the northerly limit of the said Lot 16, Concession 15;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE northerly in a straight line across the road allowance between Lots 16 and 17, to the southwest corner of the East Half of Lot 17, Concession 15;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE easterly along the southerly limit of the East Half of the said Lot 17, Concession 15, to the southeast corner of the said Lot 17, Concession 15;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE northerly along the easterly limit of Lot 17, Lot 18, Lot 19 and Lot 20, Concession 15, Township of Otonabee, to the northeast corner of the said Lot 20, Concession 15;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE westerly along the northerly limit of Lot 20, Concession 15, to the southwest corner of the East Half of Lot 21, Concession 15;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE northerly along the westerly limit of the East Half of the said Lot 21, Concession 15, to the northwest corner of the said East Half of Lot 21, Concession 15;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE northerly in a straight line across the road allowance between Lots 21 and 22, to the southwest corner of the East Half of Lot 22, Concession 15, Township of Otonabee;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE northerly along the westerly limit of the East Half of the said Lot 22, Concession 15, to the northeast corner of the West Half of the said Lot 22, Concession 15;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE westerly along the northerly limit of the West Half of the said Lot 22, Concession 15, to the northwest corner thereof;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE westerly in a straight line across the road allowance between Concessions 15 and 16, to the northeast corner of Lot 22, Concession 16, Township of Otonabee;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE northerly along the easterly limit of Lot 23, Concession 16, to the northeast corner thereof;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE northeasterly across the Otonabee River in a straight line to the southeast corner of Lot 10, Concession 10, Township of North Monaghan;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE northerly along the easterly limit of Lot 10, Concession 10, part in the Township of North Monaghan, and part in the City of Peterborough to the northeasterly corner of the said Lot 10;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE westerly along the northerly limit of the said Lot 10, to the northwest corner thereof;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE westerly along the northerly limit of Lot 9, Lot 8 and Lot 7, Concession 10, formerly Township of North Monaghan, now City of Peterborough, to the northwest corner of the said Lot 7, Concession 10;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE westerly in a straight line across the road allowance between Lots 6 and 7, to the northeast corner of Lot 6, Concession 10, formerly Township of North Monaghan, now City of Peterborough;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE westerly along the northerly limit of the said Lot 6, Concession 10, part in the City of Peterborough, and part in the Township of North Monaghan, to the northwest corner of the said Lot 6;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE westerly along the northerly limit of Lot 5, Lot 4, Lot 3 and Lot 2, Concession 10, Township of North Monaghan, to the northwest corner of the said Lot 2;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE southerly along the westerly limit of the said Lot 2 to the southwest corner of the said Lot 2;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE southerly in a straight line across the road allowance between Concessions 9 and 10, Township of North Monaghan, to the northeast corner of Lot 1, Concession 9, Township of North Monaghan;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE westerly along the northerly limit of the said Lot 1, Concession 9, to the northwest corner of said Lot 1;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE westerly on the production of the northerly limit of Lot 1, Concession 9, Township of North Monaghan, across the road allowance between the Townships of North Monaghan and Cavan to its intersection with the easterly limit of Lot 23, Concession 10, Township of Cavan;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE northerly along the said easterly limit of Lot 23, Concession 10, Township of Cavan, to the point of commencement.</Text></Provision></Provision><HistoricalNote>SOR/94-375, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Schedule></Regulation>