<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2001-493</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2001</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>8</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>1</MM><DD>4</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">INDIAN ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Property Assessment and Taxation (Railway Right-of-Way) Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2001-2081 </OrderNumber><Date><YYYY> 2001</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>8</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Whereas the taxation of property interests within reserves is an important element of self-government;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Whereas, to facilitate the implementation of property taxation on reserve land, the First Nations set out in Schedule 1 to the annexed Regulations wish to provide railway companies occupying reserve land with levels of property taxation that are predictable and comparable to levels of property taxation under provincial laws, and have requested that the Governor in Council make those Regulations;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>And whereas the Indian Taxation Advisory Board was established by Canada to, among other things, advise and assist the Minister of Indian Affairs and Northern Development on policy issues related to section 83 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Indian Act</XRefExternal>, to foster harmony between taxation by First Nations and taxation by other authorities and to ensure compliance with the principles of equity, natural justice and fairness;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Therefore, Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Indian Affairs and Northern Development, pursuant to subsection 83(5)<FootnoteRef idref="footnotea_e">a</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Indian Act</XRefExternal>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Property Assessment and Taxation (Railway Right-of-Way) Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="footnotea_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>R.S., c. 17 (4th Supp.), s. 10(3)</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Definitions</MarginalNote><Label>1</Label><Text>The following definitions apply in these Regulations.</Text><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Indian Act</XRefExternal>. (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>adjacent area</DefinedTermEn>, in respect of a First Nation, means the incorporated or unincorporated area bordering a majority of those reserves of the First Nation that contain right-of-way areas. (<DefinedTermFr>zone adjacente</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>adjustment factor</DefinedTermEn> means the adjustment factor set out in the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Adjustment Factors Relating to the Valuation of Railway Corporation Property Regulation</XRefExternal>, B.C. Reg. 324/96, as amended from time to time. (<DefinedTermFr>facteur de rajustement</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>band council</DefinedTermEn> means the council of a First Nation. (<DefinedTermFr>conseil de bande</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>by-law</DefinedTermEn> means a by-law made under subsection 83(1) of the Act. (<DefinedTermFr>règlement administratif</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Canadian Pacific Railway Company</DefinedTermEn> includes any successor to the Canadian Pacific Railway Company. (<DefinedTermFr>Compagnie de chemin de fer Canadien Pacifique</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>fibre optic improvements</DefinedTermEn> means fibre optic fibres, sheaths, wrapping, conduits, cables and other related improvements. (<DefinedTermFr>équipement de fibres optiques</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>First Nation</DefinedTermEn> means an Indian band set out in column 1 of Schedule 1. (<DefinedTermFr>première nation</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>incorporated area</DefinedTermEn> means an area incorporated as a municipality under the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Local Government Act</XRefExternal> of British Columbia. (<DefinedTermFr>zone constituée</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>property</DefinedTermEn> means a right-of-way, any other right or interest in lands, or improvements. (<DefinedTermFr>propriété</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>provincial taxation laws</DefinedTermEn> means the laws and regulations of the Province of British Columbia respecting property taxation, including the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Assessment Act</XRefExternal>, the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Adjustment Factors Relating to the Valuation of Railway Corporation Property Regulation</XRefExternal>, the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Hospital District Act</XRefExternal>, the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">School Act</XRefExternal>, the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Local Government Act</XRefExternal> and the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Taxation (Rural Area) Act</XRefExternal>, as amended from time to time. (<DefinedTermFr>lois fiscales provinciales</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>right-of-way area</DefinedTermEn>, in respect of a First Nation set out in column 1 of Schedule 1, means the lands described in column 2. (<DefinedTermFr>zone d’emprise</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>track in place</DefinedTermEn> has the same meaning as <DefinedTermEn>track in place of a railway corporation</DefinedTermEn> in subsection 21(15) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Assessment Act</XRefExternal> of British Columbia, as amended from time to time. (<DefinedTermFr>voie ferrée existante</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><HistoricalNote>SOR/2016-91, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Application</MarginalNote><Label>2</Label><Text>These Regulations apply to by-laws made by a band council in respect of taxation of property in a right-of-way area.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Taxation By-laws</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>First Nations Tax Commission review</MarginalNote><Label>3</Label><Text>A band council shall refer a draft of each by-law proposed to be made in respect of taxation of property in a right-of-way area to the First Nations Tax Commission for review and recommendations prior to making the by-law.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2007-278, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Determination of assessable value</MarginalNote><Label>4</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (2), a by-law in respect of taxation of property in a right-of-way area shall provide that an assessor must determine the assessable value of the following types of property using the assessment rates, adjustments, exceptions, inclusions and exclusions that would be applied if the property were subject to provincial taxation laws:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>track in place of a railway company, including fibre optic improvements;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>rights-of-way for track referred to in paragraph (a);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>bridges of a railway company;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>fibre optic improvements of a non-railway company;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>utility systems of a non-railway company, including pipeline, cable, telephone, power, sewer, gas and related facilities; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>other improvements lawfully located in a right-of-way area.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Adjustment factors</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Adjustment factors do not apply to the determination of assessable values of property under a by-law.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2007-278, s. 2(F).</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Maximum tax rates for railway companies</MarginalNote><Label>5</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (3), the tax rate for a taxation year established under a by-law enacted by a First Nation set out in column 1 of Schedule 2 in respect of property of a railway company in a right-of-way area shall not exceed the rate equal to the sum of the products, determined for each of the tax bases set out in column 2, of</Text><FormulaGroup><Formula><FormulaText>A × B</FormulaText></Formula><FormulaConnector>where</FormulaConnector><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>A</FormulaTerm><Text>is the tax rate established for that taxation year under provincial taxation laws for that tax base; and</Text></FormulaDefinition><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>B</FormulaTerm><Text>is the adjustment factor for that tax base.</Text></FormulaDefinition></FormulaGroup></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Maximum tax rates for non-railway companies</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (3), the tax rate for a taxation year established under a by-law enacted by a First Nation set out in column 1 of Schedule 2 in respect of improvements of a company other than a railway company in a right-of-way area shall not exceed the rate equal to the sum of the tax rates, established for that taxation year under provincial taxation laws, for the tax bases set out in column 2.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Exemptions and inclusions</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>A tax rate referred to in subsection (1) or (2) shall incorporate the same exemptions, exceptions, inclusions and exclusions that would be applicable to the property if the property were subject to the provincial taxation laws applicable to the adjacent area.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Adjustment factors</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>For the purposes of subsection (1), the adjustment factors applicable to the determination of tax rates for the Boothroyd Indian Band, Cook’s Ferry Indian Band, Little Shuswap Lake Indian Band, Nicomen Indian Band, Siska Indian Band and Skuppah Indian Band shall be the adjustment factors that apply to property in incorporated areas.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2003-373, s. 1; SOR/2004-66, s. 1; SOR/2007-278, s. 3; SOR/2008-265, s. 1; SOR/2016-91, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Coming into force date</MarginalNote><Label>6</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on the day on which they are registered.</Text></Section></Body><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 1</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 1)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><TableGroup pointsize="7" rowbreak="yes" spanmarginalnotecol="yes" topmarginspacing="10"><table frame="all"><title>Right-of-Way Areas</title><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="53.52*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="105.50*" /><colspec colname="3" colwidth="309.05*" /><thead><row topdouble="yes" topmarginspacing="4"><entry morerows="1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Item</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 1</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 2</entry></row><row topmarginspacing="4"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">First Nation</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Description of Right-of-way Area</entry></row></thead><tbody><row topmarginspacing="4"><entry colname="1" morerows="1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">1</entry><entry namest="2" nameend="3" morerows="1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top"><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2008-265, s. 2]</Repealed></entry></row><row topmarginspacing="4"><entry /></row><row topmarginspacing="4"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">1.01</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">Boothroyd Indian Band</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>In the Province of British Columbia In Yale Division of Yale District In Speyum Indian Reserve No. 3</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Firstly, all those lands shown as Parcel 1 on a Registration Plan of Railway Right of Way Area prepared by Mr. D.G. Fenning C.L.S., B.C.L.S. in May 2001 and recorded in the Canada Lands Surveys Records in Ottawa under number RSBC 3325R.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Containing an area of 32.0 hectares more or less, save and except all mines and minerals, whether precious or base, solid, liquid or gaseous.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Secondly, all those lands shown as Parcel 2, being the travelled portion of the Chaumox Road within the Railway Right of Way Area as shown on the plan prepared by Mr. D.G. Fenning C.L.S., B.C.L.S. in May 2001 and recorded in the Canada Lands Surveys Records in Ottawa under number RSBC 3325R.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Containing an area of 1.75 hectares more or less, save and except all mines and minerals, whether precious or base, solid, liquid or gaseous.</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>In the Province of British Columbia In Yale Division of Yale District In Chukcheetso Indian Reserve No.7</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>All those lands shown on a Registration Plan of Railway Right of Way Area, including the roads within that Railway Right of Way, as shown on a plan prepared by Mr. D.G. Fenning C.L.S., B.C.L.S. in May 2001 and recorded in the Canada Lands Surveys Records in Ottawa under number RSBC 3315R.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Containing 11.11 hectares more or less, save and except all mines and minerals, whether precious or base, solid, liquid or gaseous.</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row topmarginspacing="4"><entry colname="1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">1.1</entry><entry namest="2" nameend="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top"><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2008-265, s. 3]</Repealed></entry></row><row topmarginspacing="4"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">2</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">Cook’s Ferry Indian Band</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>In the Province of British Columbia In Yale Division of Yale District In Kumcheen Indian Reserve No. 1</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>All those lands shown on a Registration Plan of Railway Right of Way Area prepared by Mr. D.G. Fenning C.L.S., B.C.L.S. in May 2001 and recorded in the Canada Lands Surveys Records in Ottawa under number RSBC 3312R.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Containing 2.22 hectares more or less, save and except all mines and minerals, whether precious or base, solid, liquid or gaseous.</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>In the Province of British Columbia In Yale Division of Yale District In Spences Bridge Indian Reserve No. 4</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>All those lands shown on a Registration Plan of Railway Right of Way Area prepared by Mr. Edward Eaton C.L.S., B.C.L.S. in May 2001 and recorded in the Canada Lands Surveys Records in Ottawa under number RSBC 3322R.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Containing 0.45 hectares more or less, save and except all mines and minerals, whether precious or base, solid, liquid or gaseous.</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>In the Province of British Columbia In Yale Division of Yale District In Lower Shawniken Indian Reserve No. 4A</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>All those lands shown on a Registration Plan of Railway Right of Way Area prepared by Mr. Edward Eaton C.L.S., B.C.L.S. in May 2001 and recorded in the Canada Lands Surveys Records in Ottawa under number RSBC 3321R.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Containing 11.9 hectares more or less, save and except all mines and minerals, whether precious or base, solid, liquid or gaseous.</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(d)</Label><Text>In the Province of British Columbia In Yale Division of Yale District In Pemynoos Indian Reserve No. 9</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>All those lands shown on a Registration Plan of Railway Right of Way Area prepared by Mr. Edward Eaton C.L.S., B.C.L.S. in May 2001 and recorded in the Canada Lands Surveys Records in Ottawa under number RSBC 3320R.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Containing 51 hectares more or less, save and except all mines and minerals, whether precious or base, solid, liquid or gaseous.</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(e)</Label><Text>In the Province of British Columbia In Yale Division of Yale District In Pokheitsk Indian Reserve No. 10</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>All those lands shown on a Registration Plan of Railway Right of Way Area prepared by Mr. Edward Eaton C.L.S., B.C.L.S. in May 2001 and recorded in the Canada Lands Surveys Records in Ottawa under number RSBC 3319R.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Containing 4.48 hectares more or less, save and except all mines and minerals, whether precious or base, solid, liquid or gaseous.</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(f)</Label><Text>In the Province of British Columbia In Yale Division of Yale District In Spatsum Indian Reserve No. 11 xxx</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>All those lands shown on a Registration Plan of Railway Right of Way Area prepared by Mr. Edward Eaton C.L.S., B.C.L.S. in May 2001 and recorded in the Canada Lands Surveys Records in Ottawa under number RSBC 3317R.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Containing 4.92 hectares more or less, save and except all mines and minerals, whether precious or base, solid, liquid or gaseous.</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(g)</Label><Text>In the Province of British Columbia In Yale Division of Yale District In Spatsum Indian Reserve No. 11A</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>All those lands shown on a Registration Plan of Railway Right of Way Area prepared by Mr. Edward Eaton C.L.S., B.C.L.S. in May 2001 and recorded in the Canada Lands Surveys Records in Ottawa under number RSBC 3318R.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Containing 9.18 hectares more or less, save and except all mines and minerals, whether precious or base, solid, liquid or gaseous.</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row topmarginspacing="4"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">2.1</entry><entry namest="2" nameend="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top"><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2016-91, s. 3]</Repealed></entry></row><row topmarginspacing="4"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">2.11</entry><entry namest="2" nameend="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top"><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2007-278, s. 5]</Repealed></entry></row><row topmarginspacing="4"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">2.2</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">Little Shuswap Lake Indian Band</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>In the Province of British Columbia In Kamloops Division of Yale District</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Firstly: All of those lands within Chum Creek Indian Reserve No. 2 shown as the Canadian Pacific Railway Right of Way on Plan RR1398 recorded in the Canada Lands Surveys Records in Ottawa. A copy of the said plan is deposited in the Kamloops Land Title Office under number 31. Save and except Lot 40 on Plan 3700R recorded in the Canada Lands Surveys Records in Ottawa. Said lands containing about 9.670 hectares (23.89 acres).</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Secondly: All of those lands within Chum Creek Indian Reserve No. 2 shown as Lots 38, 39 and 44 on Plan 88122 recorded in the Canada Lands Surveys Records in Ottawa. Said lands containing about 4.383 hectares (10.83 acres).</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Said lands containing together about 14.053 hectares (34.72 acres).</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>In the Province of British Columbia In Kamloops Division of Yale District</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Firstly: All of those lands within North Bay Indian Reserve No. 5 shown as Lots 52, 53 and 54 on Plan RSBC 3698R recorded in the Canada Lands Surveys Records at Ottawa. Said lands containing about 7.30 hectares (18.04 acres).</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Secondly: All of those lands within North Bay Indian Reserve No. 5 shown as Block C on Plan A592 deposited in the Kamloops Land Title Office; a copy of the said plan is recorded in the Canada Lands Surveys Records at Ottawa under number RR1148A. Said lands containing about 0.915 hectares (2.26 acres).</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Said lands containing together about 8.215 hectares (20.30 acres).</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row topmarginspacing="4"><entry colname="1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">3. and 3.01</entry><entry namest="2" nameend="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top"><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2008-265, s. 4]</Repealed></entry></row><row topmarginspacing="4"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">3.1</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">Nicomen Indian Band</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>In the Province of British Columbia In Yale Division of Yale District</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>All those lands within Nicomen Indian Reserve No. 1 shown as Canadian Pacific Railway on Plan RR2006 recorded in the Canada Lands Surveys Records in Ottawa. A copy of the said plan is deposited in the Kamloops Land Title Office under number M287. Said lands containing about 11.84 hectares (29.26 acres).</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>In the Province of British Columbia In Kamloops Division of Yale District</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Firstly: All those lands within Sackum Indian Reserve No. 3 shown as part of the Canadian Pacific Railway Right of Way on Plan RR2006 recorded in the Canada Lands Surveys Records in Ottawa. A copy of the said plan is deposited in the Kamloops Land Title Office under number M287. Said lands containing about 3.16 hectares (7.80 acres).</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Secondly: All those lands within Gulada Indian Reserve No. 3A shown as part of the Canadian Pacific Railway Right of Way on Plan RR2006 recorded in the Canada Lands Surveys Records in Ottawa. A copy of the said plan is deposited in the Land Title Office at Kamloops under number M287. Said lands containing about 0.32 hectares (0.80 acres).</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row topmarginspacing="4"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">4</entry><entry namest="2" nameend="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top"><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2007-278, s. 6]</Repealed></entry></row><row topmarginspacing="4"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">4.1</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">Siska Indian Band</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>In the Province of British Columbia In Kamloops Division of Yale District</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Firstly: All those lands within Zacht Indian Reserve No. 5 shown as the Canadian Pacific Railway on Plan RR2006 recorded in the Canada Lands Surveys Records in Ottawa. A copy of the said plan is deposited in the Land Title Office at Kamloops under number M287. Said lands containing about 0.032 hectares (0.08 acres).</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Secondly: All those lands within Nahamanak Indian Reserve No. 7 shown as part of the Canadian Pacific Railway Right of Way on Plan RR1153 recorded in the Canada Lands Surveys Records in Ottawa. Said lands containing about 36.22 hectares (89.51 acres).</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Thirdly: All those lands within Siska Flat Indian Reserve No. 5A shown as part of the Canadian Pacific Railway Right of Way on Plan RSBC 3699R in the Canada Lands Surveys Records in Ottawa. Said lands containing about 1.65 hectares (4.08 acres).</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row topmarginspacing="4"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">5</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">Skuppah Indian Band</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="1" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>In the Province of British Columbia In Yale Division of Yale District In Inklyuhkinatko Indian Reserve No. 2</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>All those lands shown on a Registration Plan of Railway Right of Way Area prepared by Mr. D.G. Fenning C.L.S., B.C.L.S. in May 2001 and recorded in the Canada Lands Surveys Records in Ottawa under number RSBC 3323R.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Containing 22.0 hectares more or less, save and except all mines and minerals, whether precious or base, solid, liquid or gaseous.</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>In the Province of British Columbia In Yale Division of Yale District In Skuppah Indian Reserve No. 2A</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>All those lands shown on a Registration Plan of Railway Right of Way Area prepared by Mr. D.G. Fenning C.L.S., B.C.L.S. in May 2001 and recorded in the Canada Lands Surveys Records in Ottawa under number RSBC 3324R.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Containing 4.74 hectares more or less, save and except all mines and minerals, whether precious or base, solid, liquid or gaseous.</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>In the Province of British Columbia In Yale Division of Yale District In Skuppah Indian Reserve No. 4</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>All those lands shown on a Registration Plan of Railway Right of Way Area prepared by Mr. D.G. Fenning C.L.S., B.C.L.S. in May 2001 and recorded in the Canada Lands Surveys Records in Ottawa under number RSBC 3314R.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Containing 7.17 hectares more or less, save and except all mines and minerals, whether precious or base, solid, liquid or gaseous.</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup><HistoricalNote>SOR/2003-373, ss. 2 to 4; SOR/2004-66, ss. 2 to 5; SOR/2007-278, ss. 4(E), 5, 6; SOR/2008-265, ss. 2 to 4; SOR/2016-91, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Schedule><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 2</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 5)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><TableGroup pointsize="7" rowbreak="yes" spanmarginalnotecol="yes" topmarginspacing="10"><table frame="all"><title>Determination of First Nations’ Tax Rates for Companies with Class 2 Property in Right-of-Way Areas</title><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="55.00*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="112.63*" /><colspec colname="3" colwidth="300.38*" /><thead><row topdouble="yes" topmarginspacing="4"><entry morerows="1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Item</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 1</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 2</entry></row><row topmarginspacing="4"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">First Nation</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Tax Base for Adjacent Area</entry></row></thead><tbody><row topmarginspacing="4"><entry colname="1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">1</entry><entry namest="2" nameend="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top"><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2008-265, s. 5]</Repealed></entry></row><row topmarginspacing="4"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">1.01</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">Boothroyd Indian Band</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(i)</Label><Text>Basic School</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>Provincial Rural</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>Fraser Valley Hospital</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>Area “A” Fraser Valley Regional District</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(v)</Label><Text>B.C. Assessment</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(vi)</Label><Text>Municipal Finance Authority</Text></Provision></entry></row><row topmarginspacing="4"><entry colname="1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">1.1</entry><entry namest="2" nameend="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top"><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2008-265, s. 6]</Repealed></entry></row><row topmarginspacing="4"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">2</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">Cook’s Ferry Indian Band</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(i)</Label><Text>Basic School</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>Provincial Rural</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>Thompson Hospital</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>Thompson-Nicola Hospital</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(v)</Label><Text>Area “I” Thompson-Nicola Regional District</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(vi)</Label><Text>B.C. Assessment</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(vii)</Label><Text>Municipal Finance Authority</Text></Provision></entry></row><row topmarginspacing="4"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">2.1</entry><entry namest="2" nameend="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top"><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2016-91, s. 4]</Repealed></entry></row><row topmarginspacing="4"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">2.11</entry><entry namest="2" nameend="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top"><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2007-278, s. 8]</Repealed></entry></row><row topmarginspacing="4"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">2.2</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">Little Shuswap Lake Indian Band</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(i)</Label><Text>Basic School</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>Provincial Rural</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>Area “C” Columbia Shuswap Regional District</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>North Okanagan - Columbia Shuswap Hospital</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(v)</Label><Text>Columbia Shuswap Hospital</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(vi)</Label><Text>Okanagan Regional Library</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(vii)</Label><Text>Tapp/Sun’brae Fire</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(viii)</Label><Text>B.C. Assessment</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(ix)</Label><Text>Municipal Finance Authority</Text></Provision></entry></row><row topmarginspacing="4"><entry colname="1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">3. and 3.01</entry><entry namest="2" nameend="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top"><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2008-265, s. 7]</Repealed></entry></row><row topmarginspacing="4"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">3.1</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">Nicomen Indian Band</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(i)</Label><Text>Basic School</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>Provincial Rural</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>Thompson Hospital</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>Thompson-Nicola Hospital</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(v)</Label><Text>Area “I” Thompson-Nicola Regional District</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(vi)</Label><Text>B.C. Assessment</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(vii)</Label><Text>Municipal Finance Authority</Text></Provision></entry></row><row topmarginspacing="4"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">4</entry><entry namest="2" nameend="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top"><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2007-278, s. 9]</Repealed></entry></row><row topmarginspacing="4"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">4.1</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">Siska Indian Band</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(i)</Label><Text>Basic School</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>Provincial Rural</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>Thompson Hospital</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>Thompson-Nicola Hospital</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(v)</Label><Text>Area “I” Thompson-Nicola Regional District</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(vi)</Label><Text>TV Rebroadcast</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(vii)</Label><Text>B.C. Assessment</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(viii)</Label><Text>Municipal Finance Authority</Text></Provision></entry></row><row topmarginspacing="4"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">5</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">Skuppah Indian Band</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(i)</Label><Text>Basic School</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>Provincial Rural</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>Thompson Hospital</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>Thompson-Nicola Hospital</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(v)</Label><Text>Area “I” Thompson-Nicola Regional District</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(vi)</Label><Text>TV Rebroadcast</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(vii)</Label><Text>B.C. Assessment</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(viii)</Label><Text>Municipal Finance Authority</Text></Provision></entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup><HistoricalNote>SOR/2003-373, ss. 5 to 7; SOR/2004-66, ss. 6 to 9; SOR/2007-278, ss. 7(E), 8, 9; SOR/2008-265, ss. 5 to 7; SOR/2016-91, s. 4.</HistoricalNote></Schedule></Regulation>