<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/96-143</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1996</YYYY><MM>3</MM><DD>12</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2011</YYYY><MM>4</MM><DD>12</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Veterinary Drug Evaluation Fees Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Prescribing the Fees to be Paid for a Veterinary Drug Submission Evaluation Service Provided by or on Behalf of Her Majesty in Right of Canada</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1996-295 </OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1996</YYYY><MM>3</MM><DD>12</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of National Health and Welfare and the Treasury Board, pursuant to paragraph 19(1)(a)<FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-96-143_e_hq_4709">*</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Financial Administration Act</XRefExternal>, is pleased hereby to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations prescribing the fees to be paid for a veterinary drug submission evaluation service provided by or on behalf of Her Majesty in right of Canada</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fn_SOR-96-143_e_hq_4709" placement="page" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>S.C. 1991, c. 24, s. 6</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Veterinary Drug Evaluation Fees Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>All words and expressions used in these Regulations have the meanings assigned to them by the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Food and Drugs Act</XRefExternal> or the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Food and Drug Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>These Regulations apply only in respect of drugs for veterinary use.</Text></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>These Regulations do not apply in respect of a drug for veterinary use for which a submission, supplement or application referred to in any of sections 5 to 11 was filed on or before March 31, 1995.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>New Drug Submission</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>Every person who includes, in a new drug submission referred to in section C.08.002 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Food and Drug Regulations</XRefExternal>, one or more components set out in column I of an item of Schedule I shall pay the applicable fee set out in column II of that item for the screening and examination of each component.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Supplement to a New Drug Submission</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>Every person who includes, in a supplement to a new drug submission referred to in section C.08.003 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Food and Drug Regulations</XRefExternal>, one or more components set out in column I of an item of Schedule II shall pay the applicable fee set out in column II of that item for the screening and examination of each component.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Abbreviated New Drug Submission and Supplement to an Abbreviated New Drug Submission</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>7</Label><Text>Every person who includes, in an abbreviated new drug submission or a supplement to an abbreviated new drug submission referred to in section C.08.002 or C.08.003 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Food and Drug Regulations</XRefExternal>, one or more components set out in column I of an item of Schedule III shall pay the applicable fee set out in column II of that item for the screening and examination of each component.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Drug Identification Number (Din)</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>8</Label><Text>Every person who includes, in an application for a drug identification number referred to in section C.01.014.1 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Food and Drug Regulations</XRefExternal>, one or more components set out in column I of an item of Schedule IV shall pay the applicable fee set out in column II of that item for the screening and examination of each component.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Preclinical New Drug Submission</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>9</Label><Text>Every person who includes, in a preclinical new drug submission referred to in section C.08.005 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Food and Drug Regulations</XRefExternal>, one or more components set out in column I of an item of Schedule V shall pay the applicable fee set out in column II of that item for the screening and examination of each component.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Experimental Studies Certificate</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>10</Label><Text>Every person who includes, in an application for an experimental studies certificate referred to in section C.08.014 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Food and Drug Regulations</XRefExternal>, one or more components set out in column I of an item of Schedule VI shall pay the applicable fee set out in column II of that item for the screening and examination of each component.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Emergency Drug Sale</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>11</Label><Text>Every person who includes, in an application for a letter of authorization referred to in section C.08.010 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Food and Drug Regulations</XRefExternal>, one or more components set out in column I of an item of Schedule VII shall pay the applicable fee set out in column II of that item for the screening and examination of each component.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Submission, Supplement or Application Filed on or After April 1, 1996</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>12</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>This section applies in respect of a submission, supplement or application referred to in any of sections 5 to 11 that is filed on or after April 1, 1996.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Where the sum of the fees for components included in a submission, supplement or application is $10,000 or less, the fee for each component is payable at the time that the submission, supplement or application is filed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Where the sum of the fees for components included in a submission, supplement or application is more than $10,000, the fee for each component is payable as follows:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>10% of the fee for the component at the time that the submission, supplement or application is filed;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>40% of the fee for the component on receipt of a notice from the Minister or Director stating that the submission, supplement or application has been accepted for examination; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>50% of the fee for the component on receipt of a notice from the Minister or Director stating that the examination of the component has been completed.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Submission, Supplement or Application Filed Before April 1, 1996</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>13</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>This section applies in respect of a submission, supplement or application referred to in any of sections 5 to 11 where</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>it was filed during the period beginning on April 1, 1995 and ending on March 31, 1996; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>as of April 1, 1996, the screening of the submission, supplement or application has not begun.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Where the sum of the fees for components included in a submission, supplement or application is $10,000 or less, the fee for each component is payable on receipt of a notice from the Minister or Director stating that the submission, supplement or application has been screened.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Where the sum of the fees for components included in a submission, supplement or application is more than $10,000, the fee for each component is payable as follows:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>10% of the fee for the component on receipt of a notice from the Minister or Director stating that the submission, supplement or application has been screened;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>40% of the fee for the component on receipt of a notice from the Minister or Director stating that the submission, supplement or application has been accepted for examination; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>50% of the fee for the component on receipt of a notice from the Minister or Director stating that the examination of the component has been completed.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>14</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>This section applies in respect of a submission, supplement or application referred to in any of sections 5 to 11 where</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>it was filed during the period beginning on April 1, 1995 and ending on March 31, 1996; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>as of April 1, 1996, the screening of the submission, supplement or application has begun but is not completed, or the submission, supplement or application has been screened and accepted for examination but one or more of the components included in it are not yet under examination.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Notwithstanding sections 5 to 11, the fee payable for the examination of each component not yet under examination as of April 1, 1996 is 90% of the applicable fee set out in the relevant schedule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Where the sum of the fees for components that are included in a submission, supplement or application and that are not yet under examination is $10,000 or less, the fee for each such component is payable on the later of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>April 1, 1996, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the date of receipt of a notice from the Minister or Director stating that the submission, supplement or application has been screened and accepted for examination.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Where the sum of the fees for components that are included in a submission, supplement or application and that are not yet under examination is more than $10,000, the fee for each such component is payable as follows:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>50% of the fee for the component on the later of</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>April 1, 1996, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the date of receipt of a notice from the Minister or Director stating that the submission, supplement or application has been screened and accepted for examination; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>50% of the fee for the component on receipt of a notice from the Minister or Director stating that the examination of the component has been completed.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>15</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>This section applies in respect of each component included in a submission, supplement or application referred to in any of sections 5 to 11 where</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the submission, supplement or application was filed during the period beginning on April 1, 1995 and ending on March 31, 1996; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>as of April 1, 1996, the component is still under examination.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Notwithstanding sections 5 to 11, the fee payable for the examination of each component that is included in a submission, supplement or application and that is still under examination is</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>where 25% or more but less than 50% of the component remains to be examined, 15% of the applicable fee set out in the relevant schedule;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>where 50% or more but less than 75% of the component remains to be examined, 40% of the applicable fee set out in the relevant schedule; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>where 75% or more of the component remains to be examined, 65% of the applicable fee set out in the relevant schedule.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The fee for each component still under examination is payable as follows:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>50% of that fee on receipt of a notice from the Minister or Director stating the percentage of the component that remains to be examined; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>50% of that fee on receipt of a notice from the Minister or Director stating that the examination of the component has been completed.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Reduction of Fees</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>16</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>In this section, <DefinedTermEn>fee verification period</DefinedTermEn>, in respect of a drug for which an application is made under this section, means the period beginning on the date that the drug is first sold in Canada and ending three years after that date.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A person who files a submission, supplement or application referred to in any of sections 5 to 7 may apply to the Minister or Director, as the case may be, for a reduction in the fee payable for each component included in the submission, supplement or application.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The Minister or Director shall grant an application made under subsection (2) where</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the Minister or Director has reasonable grounds to believe that, during the fee verification period, the applicant’s revenue from sales in Canada of the drug to which the submission, supplement or application relates will be less than 10 times the sum of the applicable fees calculated in accordance with sections 5 to 7, 14 and 15; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the applicant submits with the application a fee for processing the application in the amount of $1,000.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Notwithstanding sections 5 to 7, 14 and 15, where the Minister or Director grants an application made under subsection (2), the fee payable for the components included in the submission, supplement or application is the lesser of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the sum of the applicable fees calculated in accordance with sections 5 to 7, 14 and 15, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the greater of</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>10% of the applicant’s anticipated revenue from sales of the drug in Canada during the fee verification period, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>10% of the applicant’s actual revenue from sales of the drug in Canada during the fee verification period, as verified by audited sales records for the drug.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>The fee calculated in accordance with subsection (4) is payable as follows:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>10% of the applicant’s anticipated revenue from sales of the drug in Canada during the fee verification period is payable at the times and in the manner set out in sections 12 to 15, as applicable; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the balance, if any, is payable 60 days after the day on which the fee verification period ends.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>17</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on April 1, 1996.</Text></Section></Body><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE I</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 5)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><TableGroup pointsize="9" topmarginspacing="4"><Caption position="over">NEW DRUG SUBMISSION</Caption><table frame="topbot"><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="49.37*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="314.79*" /><colspec colname="3" colwidth="103.92*" /><thead><row topdouble="yes"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top" /><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column I</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column II</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Item</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Component</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Fee</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Efficacy and safety data (in the intended species) to support a single route of administration, dosage form and indication in one animal species. (In the case of an antiparasitic drug, several indications in one food animal species.)</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">$15,980</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Efficacy and safety data (in the intended species) to support a single route of administration and dosage form for an antiparasitic drug in one non-food animal species.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">9,680</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">3</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Efficacy and safety data (in the intended species) to support a single route of administration, dosage form and indication in two animal species, or a single route of administration, dosage form and two indications in one animal species.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">23,240</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">4</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Efficacy and safety data (in the intended species) to support a growth promotion or production enhancement indication in one animal species.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">31,470</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">5</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Comparative (pharmacodynamic, clinical or bioavailability) data to support an additional route of administration.<FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-96-143_e_hq_4710">1</FootnoteRef></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2,900</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">6</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Comparative (pharmacodynamic, clinical or bioavailability) data to support each additional strength.<FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-96-143_e_hq_4711">2</FootnoteRef></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">480</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">7</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">For food-producing animals, toxicity, metabolism and residue depletion studies to establish an acceptable daily intake with a safety factor of 1,000, a maximum residue limit and a withdrawal period for a single dosage form, dosage and route of administration in one species.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">21,790</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">8</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">For food-producing animals, toxicity, metabolism and residue depletion studies to establish an acceptable daily intake with a safety factor of less than 1,000, a maximum residue limit and a withdrawal period for a single dosage form, dosage and route of administration in one species.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">29,050</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">9</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">For food-producing animals, residue depletion studies to establish a withdrawal period for an additional dosage form, dosage or route of administration.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2,900</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">10</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">For food-producing animals (once an acceptable daily intake with a safety factor of 1,000 or less has been established), metabolism and residue depletion studies to establish a maximum residue limit and a withdrawal period for a single dosage form, dosage and route of administration in an additional species.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">14,520</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">11</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Chemistry and manufacturing data for a non-compendial medicinal ingredient of a drug.<FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-96-143_e_hq_4712">3</FootnoteRef></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">4,840</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">12</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Chemistry and manufacturing data to support one strength of a single dosage form.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">4,840</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">13</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Chemistry and manufacturing data to support an additional strength of a single dosage form submitted at the same time as item 12.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2,420</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">14</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Documentation to support a change of manufacturer.<FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-96-143_e_hq_4713">4</FootnoteRef></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">250</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table><Footnote id="fn_SOR-96-143_e_hq_4710" placement="table" status="official"><Label>1</Label><Text>This is in addition to a route of administration referred to in item 1, 2 or 3.</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="fn_SOR-96-143_e_hq_4711" placement="table" status="official"><Label>2</Label><Text>One study to support strengths may be included with a new drug submission, under item 1, 2 or 3, without payment of the fee set out in item 6.</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="fn_SOR-96-143_e_hq_4712" placement="table" status="official"><Label>3</Label><Text>A medicinal ingredient that has been evaluated, within the last three years, in another submission to which reference is made is not required to be re-evaluated.</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="fn_SOR-96-143_e_hq_4713" placement="table" status="official"><Label>4</Label><Text>This item applies only where a new drug submission does not include any of the components set out in items 1 to 13.</Text></Footnote></TableGroup></Schedule><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE II</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 6)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><TableGroup pointsize="9" topmarginspacing="4"><Caption position="over">SUPPLEMENT TO A NEW DRUG SUBMISSION</Caption><table frame="topbot"><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="49.36*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="313.73*" /><colspec colname="3" colwidth="104.91*" /><thead><row topdouble="yes"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top" /><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column I</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column II</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Item</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Component</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Fee</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Efficacy data to support an additional indication in one animal species.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">$12,590</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Efficacy and safety data (in the intended species) to support a single route of administration and dosage form for an antiparasitic drug in one non-food animal species.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">9,680</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">3</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Efficacy and safety data (in the intended species) to support an indication in another animal species.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">15,980</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">4</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Efficacy and safety data (in the intended species) to support a single route of administration, dosage form and indication in two animal species, or a single route of administration and dosage form and two indications in one animal species.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">23,240</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">5</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Efficacy and safety data (in the intended species) to support a growth promotion or production enhancement indication in one animal species.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">31,470</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">6</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Efficacy and safety data (in the intended species) to support the concurrent use of two drugs approved for the same animal species.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">7,740</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">7</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Comparative (pharmacodynamic, clinical or bioavailability) data to support an additional route of administration.<FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-96-143_e_hq_4714">1</FootnoteRef></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2,900</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">8</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Comparative (pharmacodynamic, clinical or bioavailability) data to support each additional strength.<FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-96-143_e_hq_4715">2</FootnoteRef></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">480</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">9</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">For food-producing animals, residue depletion studies to establish a new withdrawal period for a change in the dosage or route of administration of an approved dosage form in one species.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2,900</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">10</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">For food-producing animals, metabolism and residue depletion studies to establish a maximum residue limit and a withdrawal period for a single dosage and route of administration of an approved dosage form in an additional species.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">14,520</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">11</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">For food-producing animals, toxicity studies to support a change of an established acceptable daily intake, maximum residue limit and withdrawal period.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">7,260</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">12</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">For the concurrent use of two drugs in a species of food-producing animals, residue depletion studies to determine if an extension to existing withdrawal periods is required.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">5,810</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">13</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Chemistry and manufacturing data to support a change in the source of a medicinal ingredient or its manufacturing process.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">4,840</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">14</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Chemistry and manufacturing data to support a change in formulation or dosage form.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2,420</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">15</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Chemistry and manufacturing data to support a change in packaging or in the sterilization process.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1,930</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">16</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Chemistry and manufacturing data to support an extension of the expiry dating.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1,450</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">17</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Chemistry and manufacturing data to support the concurrent use of two drugs.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1,450</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">18</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Chemistry and manufacturing data to support a change in the manufacturing site for parenteral dosage forms.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">480</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">19</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Documentation to support a change to the name of a manufacturer or the brand name of a drug.<FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-96-143_e_hq_4716">3</FootnoteRef></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">250</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table><Footnote id="fn_SOR-96-143_e_hq_4714" placement="table" status="official"><Label>1</Label><Text>This is in addition to a route of administration referred to in item 2 or 4.</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="fn_SOR-96-143_e_hq_4715" placement="table" status="official"><Label>2</Label><Text>One study to support strengths may be included with a supplement to a new drug submission, under item 1, 2 or 3, without payment of the fee set out in item 8.</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="fn_SOR-96-143_e_hq_4716" placement="table" status="official"><Label>3</Label><Text>This item applies only where a supplement to a new drug submission does not include any of the components set out in items 1 to 18.</Text></Footnote></TableGroup></Schedule><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE III</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 7)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><TableGroup pointsize="9" topmarginspacing="4"><Caption position="over" pointsize="9">ABBREVIATED NEW DRUG SUBMISSION AND SUPPLEMENT TO AN ABBREVIATED NEW DRUG SUBMISSION</Caption><table frame="topbot"><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="48.82*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="306.37*" /><colspec colname="3" colwidth="112.81*" /><thead><row topdouble="yes"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top" /><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column I</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column II</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Item</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Component</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Fee</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Any applicable component listed in Schedule II.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">See Schedule II</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Comparative (pharmacodynamic, clinical or bioavailability) data to support a single route of administration and dosage form.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">$2,900</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">3</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">For food-producing animals, residue depletion studies to confirm that the withdrawal period(s) for each species falls within the conditions of use for the Canadian reference product.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2,900</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">4</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Chemistry and manufacturing data for a non-compendial medicinal ingredient of a drug.<FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-96-143_e_hq_4717">1</FootnoteRef></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">4,840</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">5</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Chemistry and manufacturing data to support a single dosage form.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">4,840</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" morerows="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">6</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Documentation to support</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">250</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">(a) a change of manufacturer, in the case of an abbreviated new drug submission; or</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" /></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">(b) a change to the name of a manufacturer or the brand name of a drug, in the case of a supplement to an abbreviated new drug submission.<FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-96-143_e_hq_4718">2</FootnoteRef></entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" /></row></tbody></tgroup></table><Footnote id="fn_SOR-96-143_e_hq_4717" placement="table" status="official"><Label>1</Label><Text>A medicinal ingredient that has been evaluated, within the last three years, in another submission to which reference is made is not required to be re-evaluated.</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="fn_SOR-96-143_e_hq_4718" placement="table" status="official"><Label>2</Label><Text>This item applies only where an abbreviated new drug submission or a supplement to an abbreviated new drug submission does not include any of the components set out in items 1 to 5.</Text></Footnote></TableGroup></Schedule><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE IV</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 8)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><TableGroup pointsize="9" topmarginspacing="4"><Caption position="over">DIN APPLICATION</Caption><table frame="topbot"><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="48.86*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="315.17*" /><colspec colname="3" colwidth="103.88*" /><thead><row topdouble="yes"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top" /><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column I</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column II</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Item</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Component</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Fee</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Information, other than that referred to in item 2, to support an application for a DIN, including the submission of labelling material for a second review, if required.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">$720</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Published references or other data.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">500</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">3</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Documentation to support a change of manufacturer, a change to the name of a manufacturer or a change to the brand name of a drug.<FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-96-143_e_hq_4719">1</FootnoteRef><Sup>1</Sup></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">250</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table><Footnote id="fn_SOR-96-143_e_hq_4719" placement="table" status="official"><Label>1</Label><Text>This item applies only where a DIN application does not include either of the components set out in item 1 or 2.</Text></Footnote></TableGroup></Schedule><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE V</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 9)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><TableGroup pointsize="9" topmarginspacing="4"><Caption position="over" pointsize="9">PRECLINICAL NEW DRUG SUBMISSION</Caption><table frame="topbot"><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="48.87*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="314.74*" /><colspec colname="3" colwidth="104.41*" /><thead><row topdouble="yes"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top" /><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column I</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column II</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Item</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Component</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Fee</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Efficacy and safety data (in the intended species) and protocol to support the conduct of clinical studies relative to a single dosage form, route of administration and indication in one species.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">$4,840</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Efficacy data and protocol to support the conduct of clinical studies relative to a single route of administration and indication with a dosage form for which a notice of compliance has been issued for use in the species to be treated.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">3,870</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">3</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">For food-producing animals, toxicity, metabolism and residue depletion studies to establish a temporary acceptable daily intake, a maximum residue limit and a withdrawal period for a single dosage form, dosage and route of administration in one species.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">14,520</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">4</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">For food-producing animals, toxicity, metabolism and residue depletion studies to establish an acceptable daily intake with a safety factor of 1,000, a maximum residue limit and a withdrawal period for a single dosage form, dosage and route of administration in one species.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">21,790</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">5</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">For food-producing animals, toxicity, metabolism and residue depletion studies to establish an acceptable daily intake with a safety factor of less than 1,000, a maximum residue limit and a withdrawal period for a single dosage form, dosage and route of administration in one species.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">29,050</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">6</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">For food-producing animals (once an acceptable daily intake with a safety factor of 1,000 or less has been established), metabolism studies to establish a withdrawal period for a single dosage form, dosage and route of administration in an additional species.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">7,260</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">7</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Chemistry and manufacturing data to support a single dosage form containing a non-compendial medicinal ingredient.<FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-96-143_e_hq_4720">1</FootnoteRef><Sup>1</Sup></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">4,840</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">8</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Chemistry and manufacturing data to support a single dosage form containing a compendial medicinal ingredient.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2,420</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table><Footnote id="fn_SOR-96-143_e_hq_4720" placement="table" status="official"><Label>1</Label><Text>A medicinal ingredient that has been evaluated, within the last three years, in another submission to which reference is made is not required to be re-evaluated. In that case, the fee for item 8 would apply.</Text></Footnote></TableGroup></Schedule><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE VI</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 10)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><TableGroup pointsize="9" topmarginspacing="4"><Caption position="over">EXPERIMENTAL STUDIES CERTIFICATE</Caption><table frame="topbot"><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="48.87*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="314.22*" /><colspec colname="3" colwidth="104.91*" /><thead><row topdouble="yes"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top" /><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column I</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column II</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Item</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Component</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Fee</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Information and material to support the issuance of an experimental studies certificate for a drug to be administered to a non-food-producing animal.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">$960</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Information and material to support the issuance of an experimental studies certificate whose protocol is the same as that for a previously authorized experimental studies certificate for a drug to be administered to a non-food-producing animal.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">480</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">3</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Information and material to support the issuance of an experimental studies certificate for a drug to be administered to a food-producing animal.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2,900</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">4</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Information and material to support the issuance of an experimental studies certificate whose protocol is the same as that for a previously authorized experimental studies certificate for a drug to be administered to a food-producing animal.</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">480</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Schedule><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE VII</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 11)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><TableGroup pointsize="9" topmarginspacing="4"><Caption position="over">EMERGENCY DRUG SALE</Caption><table frame="topbot"><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.32*" /><colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.02*" /><colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.67*" /><thead><row topdouble="yes"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top" /><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column I</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column II</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Item</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Component</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Fee</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">1</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Information and material to support the sale of a drug to be used in the emergency treatment of a non-food-producing animal.</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">$50</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">2</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Information and material to support the sale of a drug to be used in the emergency treatment of a food-producing animal.</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">100</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Schedule></Regulation>