<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/85-846</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1985</YYYY><MM>8</MM><DD>29</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2017</YYYY><MM>4</MM><DD>4</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CANADIAN OWNERSHIP AND CONTROL DETERMINATION ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Canadian Ownership and Control Determination Forms Order, 1985</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Respecting the Form and Manner in which an Application for a Certificate under the Canadian Ownership and Control Determination Act Shall be Filed on or After August 29, 1985 and the Information and Documentation that is to be Contained in or to Accompany that Application</LongTitle></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>The Minister of Energy, Mines and Resources, pursuant to the definition “prescribed” in subsection 35(1) and to subsection 38(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canadian Ownership and Control Determination Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-85-846_e_hq_3775">*</FootnoteRef>, hereby revokes the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Canadian Ownership and Control Determination Forms Order, 1984</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-85-846_e_hq_3776">**</FootnoteRef> and makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Order respecting the form and manner in which an application for a certificate under the Canadian Ownership and Control Determination Act shall be filed on or after August 29, 1985 and the information and documentation that is to be contained in or to accompany that application</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fn_SOR-85-846_e_hq_3775" placement="page" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>S.C. 1980-81-82-83, c. 107</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="fn_SOR-85-846_e_hq_3776" placement="page" status="official"><Label>**</Label><Text>SOR/84-412, 1984 <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal> Part II, p. 2312</Text></Footnote></Provision><Provision first-line-indent="1"><Text>Ottawa, August 16, 1985</Text><SignatureBlock justification="right" width="16pc"><SignatureName justification="right">PAT CARNEY</SignatureName><SignatureTitle justification="right"><Emphasis style="italic">Minister of Energy, Mines and Resources</Emphasis></SignatureTitle></SignatureBlock></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Canadian Ownership and Control Determination Forms Order, 1985</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>In this Order,</Text><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Annex</DefinedTermEn> means an annex set out in Schedule II; (<DefinedTermFr>appendice</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canadian Ownership and Control Determination Act</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>class of capitalization</DefinedTermEn> means a class of formal equity within the meaning of the Regulations read without regard to section 6 thereof or a class of forward equity; (<DefinedTermFr>catégorie de capitalisation</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Form</DefinedTermEn> means a form set out in Schedule I; (<DefinedTermFr>formule</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Regulations</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Canadian Ownership and Control Determination Regulations, 1984</XRefExternal>. (<DefinedTermFr>Règlement</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>All other words and expressions have the same meaning as in the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canadian Ownership and Control Determination Act</XRefExternal> and the Regulations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Where any provision of this Order provides for the making of an application in a particular Form, the application may be made in that Form or in the form of a letter or other appropriate form, but, in any case, the application shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>include the information indicated in the Form;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>include or be accompanied by any other information or documentation required by this Order to be included in or to accompany the application; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>be certified as indicated in the Form.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application of Order</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>This Order applies to all applications filed on or after August 29, 1985.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Applications by Individuals</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>An application by an individual shall be in Form A-I.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Applications by Small Applicants</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>An application by a small applicant shall be in Form A-S.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Applications by Other Applicants</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>Subject to sections 7 and 8, an application by an entity that is not a small applicant shall be in Form A.</Text></Section><Section><Label>7</Label><Text>An application by a corporation that makes an election pursuant to subsection 30(7) of the Regulations may be in Form A-AML instead of Form A.</Text></Section><Section><Label>8</Label><Text>An application by an entity that meets the requirements specified in Form A-C may be in Form A-C instead of Form A.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Additional Information</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>9</Label><Text>An application by a cooperative corporation that by reason of paragraph 12(1)(g) of the Regulations is considered to have a Canadian ownership rate of 100 per cent shall include or be accompanied by the information indicated in Annex 1 and the certificate set out in that Annex completed as indicated therein.</Text></Section><Section><Label>10</Label><Text>An application by a life insurance company shall include or be accompanied by the information indicated in Annex 2.</Text></Section><Section><Label>11</Label><Text>An application by a mutual company, other than a life insurance company, shall include or be accompanied by the information indicated in Annex 3.</Text></Section><Section><Label>12</Label><Text>Subject to section 9, an application by</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>an entity that by reason of subsection 12(1) of the Regulations is considered to have a Canadian ownership rate of 100 per cent, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>an entity referred to in subsection 16(5) of the Regulations,</Text></Paragraph><ContinuedSectionSubsection><Text>shall include or be accompanied by such of the information indicated in Annex 4 as is relevant and the relevant certificate set out in that Annex completed as indicated therein.</Text></ContinuedSectionSubsection></Section><Section><Label>13</Label><Text>Where, in the case of any application, any of the following information, namely,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a description of each class of capitalization,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a summary of nominee client information,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a summary of measured block information,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a summary of the beneficial Canadian ownership calculation for each class of formal equity measured,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>a summary of the Canadian ownership rate calculation,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>any other information that is relevant in determining the Canadian ownership rate of the applicant, including, but not limited to, the following:</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>information identifying a class of capitalization,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>information relating to the exclusion of a class of capitalization from measurement,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>information regarding the beneficiaries of a trust,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>information relating to the status of an investor as a primary investor, as a secondary investor or as an investor equity-related to an applicant,</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><ContinuedSectionSubsection><Text>is required in respect of the applicant or an investor in the applicant in order to make, in accordance with the Act and Regulations, a determination of the Canadian ownership rate of the applicant for the purposes of the application, such information shall be included in the application in respect of the applicant or investor, as the case may be.</Text></ContinuedSectionSubsection></Section><Section><Label>14</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Where, with respect to an application that includes or is accompanied by the information required by Form A or Form A-AML, it is relevant to determine the Canadian ownership rate or control status of the applicant, the application shall be accompanied by such of the following documentation as is relevant in the making of that determination:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a copy of</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>every prospectus filed by or on behalf of the applicant with a securities regulatory authority, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>every other offering document,</Text></Subparagraph><ContinuedParagraph><Text>pursuant to which securities were issued by the applicant on or after October 28, 1980;</Text></ContinuedParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a copy of the financial statements of the applicant for its most recently completed fiscal period, if the applicant is required to measure its Canadian ownership rate; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a copy of that portion of the unit holders list of the applicant and of any unit holders list of an investor in the applicant that shows all entries therein that have a number of units equal to or exceeding 10 per cent of the measured block threshold for each class of formal equity of the applicant or the investor, as the case may be, the beneficial Canadian ownership rate of which is calculated in accordance with section 25 of the Regulations.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Where an applicant makes an application in Form A-S or an application that includes or is accompanied by the information indicated in that Form, the application may include or be accompanied by one copy of financial statements that show the assets that would be included in making a determination of the applicant’s total assets pursuant to section 9 of the Regulations.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>15</Label><Text>Where, pursuant to section 39 of the Act, an application is made by a person for a certificate stating the person’s Canadian ownership rate and control status or for a certificate stating the person’s control status, the application shall include or be accompanied by such information and documentation as are required in order to determine the control status of the person.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Filing</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>16</Label><Text>An application shall be filed by sending it by mail or delivering it to the Central Registry of the Petroleum Incentives Administration in the City of Calgary or the City of Ottawa.</Text></Section></Body><Schedule bilingual="no" spanlanguages="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE I</Label><TitleText>(Forms)</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>GRAPHICS ARE NOT DISPLAYED, SEE SOR/85-846, PP. 3813 TO 3825</Text></Provision></Schedule><Schedule bilingual="no" spanlanguages="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE II</Label><TitleText>(Annexes)</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>GRAPHICS ARE NOT DISPLAYED, SEE SOR/85-846, PP. 3826 TO 3833</Text></Provision></Schedule></Regulation>