<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2001-258</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2001</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>12</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>6</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">TERRITORIAL LANDS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Order Authorizing Federal Employees to Acquire Interests in Certain Lands in the Northwest Territories (Order No. 1, 2001)</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2001-1240 </OrderNumber><Date><YYYY> 2001</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>12</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Indian Affairs and Northern Development, pursuant to paragraph 29(1)(a) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Territorial Lands Act</XRefExternal>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Order Authorizing Federal Employees to Acquire Interests in Certain Lands in the Northwest Territories (Order No. 1, 2001)</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Purpose</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>The purpose of this Order is to authorize certain employees of the Government of Canada to acquire an interest in territorial lands in the Northwest Territories.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Authorization</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>The employee of the Government of Canada named in the schedule is hereby authorized to acquire an interest in territorial lands in the Northwest Territories as described in the schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>This Order comes into force on the day on which it is registered.</Text></Section></Body><Schedule bilingual="no" spanlanguages="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label></ScheduleFormHeading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Mary-Ann Doering, of the City of Yellowknife, in the Northwest Territories, an employee with the Legal Surveys Division, Department of Natural Resources, has applied to lease with the option to purchase, for seasonal recreational purposes, a parcel of land located in the Madeline Lake Cottage Subdivision, in Quad 85 J/9, in the Northwest Territories, as outlined in red on a sketch plan on file 33-1-12 in the Land and Water Management Division of the Department of Indian Affairs and Northern Development at Ottawa, saving and excepting therefrom and reserving thereout all mines and minerals, including hydrocarbons, whether solid, liquid or gaseous and the right to work them.</Text></Provision></Schedule></Regulation>