<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/96-337</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1996</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>3</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2015</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>12</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CANADA TRANSPORTATION ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Railway Third Party Liability Insurance Coverage Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1996-1063</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY> 1996</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>3</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="centered" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Order No. 1996-R-275</TitleText></Heading></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Pursuant to subsection 92(3) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Transportation Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="footnotea_e">a</FootnoteRef>, the Canadian Transportation Agency hereby makes the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Railway Third Party Liability Insurance Coverage Regulations</XRefExternal> in accordance with the schedule hereto.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>July 2, 1996</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Transport, pursuant to subsection 36(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Transportation Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="footnotea_e">a</FootnoteRef>, hereby approves the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Railway Third Party Liability Insurance Coverage Regulations</XRefExternal>, made by the Canadian Transportation Agency.</Text><Footnote id="footnotea_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 1996, c. 10</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>The definitions in this section apply in these Regulations.</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Transportation Act</XRefExternal>. (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>applicant</DefinedTermEn> means a person who makes an application to the Agency for a certificate of fitness or for the variation of a certificate. (<DefinedTermFr>demandeur</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>deductible</DefinedTermEn> means the amount of risk for which an applicant retains financial responsibility under an insurance contract. (<DefinedTermFr>franchise</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>insurer</DefinedTermEn> means an insurance company that provides third party liability insurance coverage to an applicant and includes an insurance company that is wholly owned by the parties it insures. (<DefinedTermFr>assureur</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>named perils pollution</DefinedTermEn> means risks that are set out in an insurance contract that are associated with seepage or pollution or contamination resulting from but not limited to collision, overturning, derailment, upset, hostile fire, lightning or explosion or other railway related accidents. (<DefinedTermFr>risques de pollution désignés</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>self-insurance</DefinedTermEn> means self-insured retention and deductible. (<DefinedTermFr>autoassurance</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>self-insured retention</DefinedTermEn> means the amount of risk for which an applicant takes financial responsibility, outside of an insurance contract. (<DefinedTermFr>affectation pour autoassurance</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>third party liability insurance coverage</DefinedTermEn> means financial compensation provided for in a contract entered into between an applicant and an insurer, or in the case of self-insurance, financial compensation provided by the applicant, in respect of the following matters arising out of an applicant’s proposed construction or operation of a railway, including a proposed temporary construction or operation of a railway resulting from unforeseen or exceptional circumstances:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>third party bodily injury or death, including injury or death to passengers,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>third party property damage, excluding damage to cargo, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>named perils pollution. (<DefinedTermFr>assurance responsabilité civile</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>These Regulations apply to any person proposing to</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>construct a railway; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>operate a railway either over and on their own railway or over and on the railway of another railway company, including operating over and on a portion of the railway of another railway company.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Determination of Adequate Third Party Liability Insurance Coverage</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>Third party liability insurance coverage is adequate if there is</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>sufficient insurance, including self-insurance, to compensate for the following matters that may arise out of an applicant’s proposed construction or operation of a railway, including a proposed temporary construction or operation of a railway resulting from unforeseen or exceptional circumstances:</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>third party bodily injury or death, including injury or death to passengers,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>third party property damage, excluding damage to cargo, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>named perils pollution;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a written confirmation provided to the Agency by the applicant that the applicant has fully disclosed to the insurer the nature and extent of the proposed construction or operation of the railway and any associated third party liability risks; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>full disclosure to the Agency by the applicant of the amount of self-insured retention and of the third party liability risks that may arise from the proposed construction or operation of the railway.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>In determining whether third party liability insurance coverage is adequate, the Agency shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>examine the risks associated with the proposed construction or operation of the railway by considering information that is provided by the applicant, including</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>passenger ridership,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>passenger and freight train miles,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>volume of railway traffic,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>class and volume of dangerous goods transported by rail,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(v)</Label><Text>types of population areas served,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(vi)</Label><Text>number of level crossings,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(vii)</Label><Text>speed of trains,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(viii)</Label><Text>train crew training,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ix)</Label><Text>method of train control, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(x)</Label><Text>overall safety record of the applicant; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the case of self-insurance, assess the financial capability of the applicant to sustain the level of self-insurance, on the basis of the following information provided by the applicant:</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the three most recent annual financial reports that have been filed with the Agency pursuant to section 344 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Railway Act</XRefExternal>, as that section read immediately before the coming into force of the Act, or with the Minister of Transport in accordance with any applicable regulations made pursuant to section 50 of the Act,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>where the applicant does not file the reports referred to in subparagraph (i), audited financial statements for the three most recent complete fiscal years, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>where the applicant does not have the information referred to in subparagraph (i) or (ii), other financial information that establishes the applicant’s financial capability to sustain the self-insurance.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Section></Body></Regulation>