<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en" in-force="yes"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2012-152</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2012</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>26</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2012</YYYY><MM>8</MM><DD>15</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CANADA GRAIN ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Wheat and Barley Research, Market Development and Technical Assistance Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2012-997</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>2012</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>26</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Agriculture and Agri-Food, pursuant to section 83.2<FootnoteRef idref="fn_81000-2-1129-E_hq_12070">a</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Grain Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_81000-2-1129-E_hq_12071">b</FootnoteRef>, makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations Respecting Research, Market Development and Technical Assistance (Wheat and Barley)</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fn_81000-2-1129-E_hq_12070" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 2011, c. 25, s. 27</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="fn_81000-2-1129-E_hq_12071" placement="page" status="official"><Label>b</Label><Text>R.S., c. G-10</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>In these Regulations, <DefinedTermEn>Commission</DefinedTermEn> means the Alberta Barley Commission.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>These Regulations apply to wheat and barley grown in Manitoba, Saskatchewan and Alberta and the Peace River District of British Columbia.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Responsible Agency</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>The Commission is the agency to which amounts are to be remitted under section 83.1 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Grain Act</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Deductions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Any person required to issue a cash purchase ticket under the Act must collect a deduction of the following amounts:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>$0.48 per tonne for wheat; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>$0.56 per tonne for barley except in the case of barley grown in Alberta for which the amount to be collected is $0.04 per tonne.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The amounts that are deducted must be remitted to the Commission within 30 days from the end of the month in which they are collected along with a report that indicates the amounts deducted in respect of wheat and barley from each producer.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Refunds of Amounts Deducted</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Any producer may make an application for a refund from the Commission of any amount that was deducted under subsection 4(1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The application must be in the appropriate form supplied by the Commission, be signed and dated and contain the producer’s name, mailing address and telephone number.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The application may be made once every crop year and must be submitted by July 31 of that crop year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The Commission must remit the refund not later than 90 days after the end of the crop year.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2013-123, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Annual Reports</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>The Commission must provide an annual report to the Minister of Agriculture and Agri-Food not later than 120 days after the end of the crop year that contains the following information in respect of wheat and of barley:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the total amounts of deductions;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the total amounts paid for research activities into new and improved varieties of wheat and of barley, the recipients of the funds and a description of those activities;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the total amounts paid for the promotion of the marketing and use of wheat and of barley, the recipients of the funds and a description of those activities;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the total amounts paid for technical assistance relating to the use of wheat and of barley, the recipients of the funds and a description of the technical assistance activities;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the total amounts of refunds; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>details of the administrative costs.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2013-123, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>7</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on August 1, 2012.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>