<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/89-501</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1989</YYYY><MM>10</MM><DD>19</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>20</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CANADIAN ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION ACT, 1999</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Concentration of Phosphorus in Certain Cleaning Products Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1989-2098</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1989</YYYY><MM>10</MM><DD>19</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of the Environment, pursuant to subsection 50(2) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canadian Environmental Protection Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="footnote1_e">*</FootnoteRef>, is pleased hereby to revoke the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Phosphorus Concentration Control Regulations</XRefExternal>, C.R.C., c. 393, and to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting the concentration of phosphorus in laundry detergents</XRefExternal>, in substitution therefor.</Text><Footnote id="footnote1_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label> *</Label><Text>S.C. 1988, c. 22</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Section><Label>1</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2009-178, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Prescribed Nutrients</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>For the purpose of paragraph 118(1)(a) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canadian Environmental Protection Act, 1999</XRefExternal>, phosphorus and its compounds thereof are nutrients.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2000-106, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Laundry Detergents</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>The concentration of phosphorus in any household laundry detergent must not exceed 1.1% by weight expressed as phosphorus pentoxide or 0.5% by weight expressed as elemental phosphorus.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2009-178, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>The concentration of phosphorus in any commercial or industrial laundry detergent must not exceed 5% by weight expressed as phosphorus pentoxide or 2.2% by weight expressed as elemental phosphorus.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2009-178, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Household Dish-washing Compounds</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>The concentration of phosphorus in any household dish-washing compound must not exceed 1.1% by weight expressed as phosphorus pentoxide or 0.5% by weight expressed as elemental phosphorus.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2009-178, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Household Cleaners</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>The concentration of phosphorus in any household cleaner, other than a laundry detergent, dish-washing compound, metal cleaner or de-greasing compound, must not exceed 1.1% by weight expressed as phosphorus pentoxide or 0.5% by weight expressed as elemental phosphorus.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2009-178, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Accredited Laboratory</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>7</Label><Text>For the purposes of these Regulations, the concentration of phosphorus must be determined by a laboratory that is accredited under the International Organization for Standardization standard ISO/IEC 17025:2005, entitled <XRefExternal reference-type="standard">General requirements for the competence of testing and calibration laboratories</XRefExternal>, as amended from time to time, and whose accreditation includes the analysis of phosphorus within its scope of testing.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2009-178, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Record Keeping</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>8</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Every person who, during any year, manufactures for use or sale in Canada or imports any laundry detergent, household dish-washing compound or household cleaner within the meaning of section 6 containing phosphorus must maintain records containing the following:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>respecting the manufacture for use or sale</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the brand name of each laundry detergent, household dish-washing compound or household cleaner containing phosphorus,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the name and civic address of the principal place of business of the manufacturer,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>the quantity of each of the cleaning products shipped from each manufacturing plant; and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>the name and civic address of the recipient of each cleaning product that was shipped or sold;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>respecting the import</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the brand name of each laundry detergent, household dish-washing compound or household cleaner containing phosphorus,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the name and civic address of the principal place of business of the importer,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>the port of entry where each cleaning product is imported,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>the name and civic address of the sender of each cleaning product,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(v)</Label><Text>the date of import,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(vi)</Label><Text>the Harmonized Commodity Description and Coding System number for the cleaning product that is imported, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(vii)</Label><Text>the importer number for the shipment of the cleaning product that is imported.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The records must be kept for a period of five years after the day on which the records are made, at the person’s principal place of business in Canada or at any other place in Canada where they can be inspected. If the records are kept at any place other than the person’s principal place of business, the person must provide the Minister with the civic address of the place where they are kept.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2009-178, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section></Body></Regulation>