<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2000-211</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2000</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>31</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>20</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">NUCLEAR SAFETY AND CONTROL ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Canadian Nuclear Safety Commission Rules of Procedure</LongTitle></Identification><Order><Provision language-align="yes" format-ref="indent-0-0" list-item="no"><Text>Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Natural Resources, pursuant to section 44 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Nuclear Safety and Control Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="footnotea_e">a</FootnoteRef>, hereby approves the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Canadian Nuclear Safety Commission Rules of Procedure</XRefExternal>, made by the Canadian Nuclear Safety Commission on May 31, 2000.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Footnote id="footnotea_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 1997, c. 9</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The definitions in this subrule apply in these Rules.</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Nuclear Safety and Control Act</XRefExternal>. (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>intervenor</DefinedTermEn> means a person who is permitted to intervene at a public hearing under rule 19. (<DefinedTermFr>intervenant</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>participant</DefinedTermEn> means a party or intervenor. (<DefinedTermFr>participant</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>party</DefinedTermEn> means</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in relation to a licence application, the applicant;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in relation to a licence renewal, suspension, amendment, revocation or replacement, the licensee;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>in relation to a matter being heard by the Commission in the public interest under the Act, and if these Rules do not otherwise set out who the parties are, any person whom the Commission names as party in the proceeding;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>in relation to the review by the Commission of an order of an inspector or a designated officer, a person who is named in or subject to the order;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>in relation to an appeal made to the Commission under subsection 43(1) of the Act, the appellant;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>in relation to a rehearing and redetermination under subsection 43(2) of the Act, any of the persons referred to in that subsection; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>in relation to a redetermination on the Commission's own initiative under subsection 43(3) of the Act, any of the persons referred to in subsection 43(2) of the Act. (<DefinedTermFr>partie</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Secretary</DefinedTermEn> means the Secretary of the Commission. (<DefinedTermFr>secrétaire</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>For greater certainty, "document" includes information stored by electronic means.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 1</Label><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Application, Officers and Employees of the Commission, Quorum</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>This Part applies in respect of the following proceedings:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>an opportunity to be heard provided by a designated officer under subsection 39(1) of the Act;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>an opportunity to be heard provided by the Commission under subsection 40(1) of the Act;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>proceedings conducted by the Commission on its own initiative under subsection 40(3) of the Act;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a public hearing in relation to a licensing matter that is held by the Commission under paragraph 40(5)(a) of the Act;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>a public hearing in relation to any matter within the Commission's jurisdiction that is held by the Commission under paragraph 40(5)(b) of the Act;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>an appeal made to the Commission pursuant to subsection 43(1) of the Act;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>a rehearing by the Commission under subsection 43(2) of the Act;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>a redetermination by the Commission under subsection 43(3) of the Act; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>a public hearing conducted by the Commission under section 46 of the Act.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The Commission or a designated officer, as the case may be, may permit or require officers and employees of the Commission to participate in a proceeding under these Rules in such manner, including presenting information and submissions orally or in writing, questioning participants and responding to questions and submissions, as will enable the Commission or designated officer to determine the matter in a fair, informal and expeditious manner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>For the purposes of proceedings before the Commission or a panel of the Commission under these Rules, the number of members of the Commission or a panel that constitutes a quorum shall be:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>three members for a proceeding before the Commission;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>one panel member for a proceeding before a panel of one member or two members;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>two panel members for a proceeding before a panel of three or four members; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>three panel members for a proceeding before a panel of more than four members.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Varying Rules</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The Commission or, where applicable, a designated officer may vary or supplement any of these Rules, in order to ensure that a proceeding be dealt with as informally and expeditiously as the circumstances and the considerations of fairness permit.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Any procedural matter that arises in the course of a proceeding that is not provided for in these Rules shall be dealt with by the Commission or, where applicable, a designated officer as informally and expeditiously as the circumstances and the considerations of fairness permit.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Defect in Form or Procedure</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>No proceeding is invalid, in whole or part, by reason only of a defect in form or failure to follow a procedure that is set out in these Rules, where the defect or failure does not result in any material harm to a relevant interest.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2007-208, s. 26(F).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Waiver of Rules</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Any participant may waive any procedural right that is granted to the participant under these Rules.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>In the absence of proof to the contrary, where any participant fails to take advantage of a procedural right granted under these Rules, the participant is deemed to have waived that right.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Time Limits</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>Where these Rules indicate that a time limit is to be specified in an order of the Commission or a designated officer, or a notice of the Commission, the time limit specified shall provide for as informal and expeditious a proceeding as the circumstances and the considerations of fairness permit.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Transmitting Documents</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>7</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Unless otherwise provided by these Rules, any giving, sending, notifying, serving or filing that is required or permitted under these Rules may be done</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>by hand, ordinary mail, registered mail or courier;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>by facsimile, if the recipient is able to receive the information in that manner; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>by any other method that is agreed to by the recipient.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A document that is sent by facsimile must include the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the name, address and telephone and facsimile numbers of the sender;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the date and time of the transmission;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the total number of pages transmitted;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the name, address and telephone and facsimile numbers of the recipient; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the name, address and telephone and facsimile numbers of a person to contact if transmission problems occur.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Filing</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>8</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subrule (2), a document that is required to be filed under these Rules shall be filed at the office of the Secretary.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>During a proceeding, a document may be filed with the presiding member of the Commission or the designated officer who is hearing the matter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>In the absence of proof to the contrary, the date of filing is the date on which the document is received by the Commission or designated officer, as indicated</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>by the date stamped on the document by an employee of the Commission, in the case of a document that is filed in accordance with paragraph 7(1)(a); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>by the date that appears on the covering page of the facsimile as processed by the receiving facsimile machine of the Commission, in the case of a document that is filed by facsimile.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Service</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>9</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Where a document is required under these Rules to be served personally, the service shall be made</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>on an individual, by leaving a copy of the document with the individual or the individual’s authorized representative or, if there is no such representative, with any other person who appears to be an adult occupant of the place of service and who agrees to accept service;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the case of a partnership or other non-incorporated association of persons, by leaving a copy of the document with a person whom the partnership or association has designated to the Commission as its representative for the matter in question or, if there is no such person, with any other person who appears to manage or be in control of a place of business operated by the partnership or association and who agrees to accept service; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>on a corporation, by leaving a copy of the document with an officer, director or agent of the corporation, any employee of the corporation who is at a place of business of the corporation and who is responsible for the management of the place of business or, if there is no such person, with any other person at a place of business of the corporation who appears to manage or be in control of the place of business and who agrees to accept service.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A document that is served by ordinary or registered mail shall be served at the address where mail is ordinarily received, as found on the most recent document filed with the Commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The date of service of a document is</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>where the document is served personally, the date of delivery;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>where the document is served by ordinary mail, the date that is 10 days after mailing unless there is information that shows that the date is other than 10 days after mailing, in which case the date of service is the date so shown; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>where the document is served by electronic transmission, the date of receipt that appears on the facsimile or electronic version of the document as processed by the recipient's facsimile or computer.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Where these Rules require a document to be served, the Commission or designated officer, as the case may be, may, in the interests of a fair, informal and expeditious consideration of the matter, require proof of service to be filed with the Commission or designated officer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>Proof of service of any document may be made by showing</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>an acknowledgment of service signed by or on behalf of the person served; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>an affidavit of service stating the name of the person who served the document and the date, place and manner of service.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2007-208, s. 27.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Notice</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>10</Label><Text>Information that is not given in accordance with these Rules is considered to have been properly given where it is shown that the information or its substance came, within the required time limit, to the attention of the person to whom it was to be given.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Official Languages</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>11</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subrule (2), all documents given to the Commission or a designated officer must be in at least one official language.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A person may give a document in a language other than an official language if, at the same time, the person gives a translation of the document in at least one official language, and an affidavit of the translator attesting to the accuracy of the translation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Where the original of a document referred to in subrule (2) is required to be served, the translation and affidavit must also be served, and at the same time as the service of the original document.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Confidentiality</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>12</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subrule (2), in any proceeding, the Commission or a designated officer, as the case may be, may take measures referred to in subrule (3) to protect information if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the information involves national or nuclear security;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the information is confidential information of a financial, commercial, scientific, technical, personal or other nature that is treated consistently as confidential and the person affected has not consented to the disclosure; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>disclosure of the information is likely to endanger the life, liberty or security of a person.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The Commission or the designated officer may take the measures referred to in subrule (3) if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>protection of the information outweighs in importance the public interest in public hearings and disclosure of evidence; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the measures are designed so as not to affect the public nature of the proceeding except to the extent necessary to adequately protect the information.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The measures that the Commission or designated officer may take include requiring that</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the proceeding or part of the proceeding take place in private, to the exclusion of members of the public, other than the parties and their counsel or agent;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the publication of information given to the Commission or designated officer be restricted or prohibited; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the disclosure of information given or received by the Commission or designated officer be prohibited or restricted to some or all of the parties and intervenors, or their counsel or agent, if any.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2007-208, s. 28.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Summonses</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>13</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>In the case of a public hearing that is conducted by the Commission, a participant may request the Commission to issue a summons by submitting a request in writing before the start of the hearing or an oral request at the hearing, but in any case as soon as the circumstances giving rise to the request become known to the participant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The request for a summons shall set out</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the reasons for the summons;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>how any information, record or thing to be produced by the person to be summoned is relevant to the matter; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>why the person to be summoned is the appropriate person to produce the information, record or thing.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>A summons shall be served directly on the person to be summoned at least seven days before the day on which the person is required to attend the public hearing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>A person who has been summoned to a public hearing shall attend at the time and day specified and every day of the hearing, unless the Commission directs that the person must only attend on certain days, or that the presence of the person is no longer required.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>Where a public hearing is adjourned and the day for its reconvening is not disclosed at the time of the adjournment, the Commission must notify the person who is under summons of the date of the reconvening</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>at least five days before the person summoned is to re-attend; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>where the Commission has given less than five days notice of the reconvening, within such notice period as is fair and reasonable in the circumstances.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2007-208, s. 29.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Adjournments</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>14</Label><Text>The Commission or a designated officer, as the case may be, on the request of a participant or on their own initiative, may adjourn a proceeding, on such terms and conditions as the Commission or the designated officer considers necessary in the interests of a fair, informal and expeditious consideration of the matter.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Record</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>15</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The Commission shall keep a record of the following in respect of every proceeding:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any document that initiated the proceeding;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any notice given by the Commission or a designated officer;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>any documentary evidence, written submission or other material filed with the Commission or a designated officer;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>any final decision of the Commission or a designated officer, including reasons in any case where reasons were given;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>any transcript of the proceeding that is made by the Commission or a designated officer; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>any other relevant information that the Commission or a designated officer directs to be placed on the record.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Subject to any measures taken under rule 12, the record kept under subrule (1) shall be open to the participants and the public.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2007-208, s. 30(F).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 2</Label><TitleText>Public Hearings</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>16</Label><Text>This Part applies in respect of a public hearing that the Commission holds</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>under paragraph 40(5)(a) of the Act, in relation to an application for the issuance, renewal, suspension, amendment, revocation or replacement of a licence; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>under paragraph 40(5)(b) of the Act, in relation to any other matter within the Commission's jurisdiction.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Notice of Public Hearing</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>17</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Where the Commission holds a public hearing on any matter under this Part, it may hold the hearing on one or more days and in one or more places.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The Commission shall give notice of a public hearing to the parties at least 60 days before the start of the hearing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The Commission shall also give a notice to the public at least 60 days before the start of the hearing in any manner that the Commission considers will most likely result in the notice coming to the attention of persons interested in the matter being considered.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The notices referred to in subrules (2) and (3) shall include</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a description of the matter being heard;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>where the Commission proposes to hold the public hearing on one day, the date, time and place of the hearing;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>where the Commission proposes to hold the public hearing on more than one day, the dates, times and places, if known, of the public hearing;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the requirement that parties who intend to participate in the hearing must so notify the Commission in accordance with rule 18;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the manner in which persons may request to intervene, as set out in rule 19; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>the names and addresses of persons to whom copies of any information and submissions filed or to be filed with the Commission, for consideration at the hearing, must be sent.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2007-208, s. 31(F).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Participation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>18</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A party who intends to appear at a public hearing shall file with the Commission, at least 30 days before the start of the hearing, a notice that includes</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a statement of the party's intention to appear and, where the party will be represented by counsel or an agent, the name, address and telephone and facsimile numbers of the counsel or agent; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a copy of the documentary information and written submission that the party will present to the Commission at the hearing, and a list of any witnesses proposed by the party.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>There shall be filed with the Commission, at least 30 days before the start of a public hearing, a copy of the documentary information and written submission that the officers and employees of the Commission will present to the Commission at the hearing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Where a public hearing comprises two hearing days, any documentary information and written submission filed under subrule (1) or (2) shall be considered by the Commission on each of those hearing days, and the parties and their witnesses shall attend on each of those hearing days unless the Commission directs otherwise in the interests of a fair, informal and expeditious consideration of the matter.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Intervention</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>19</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Where a request to intervene at a public hearing is filed with the Commission in accordance with subrules (2) and (3), the Commission, subject to these Rules, may permit the following persons to participate as intervenors at the hearing in the manner and to the extent that the Commission considers will enable it to determine the matter before it in a fair, informal and expeditious manner:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a person who has an interest in the matter being heard; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a person who has expertise in the matter or information that may be useful to the Commission in coming to a decision.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Where the notice of public hearing given under this Part indicates one hearing day, the request to intervene must be filed with the Commission by the filing date specified in the notice.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Where the notice of public hearing given under this Part indicates two hearing days, the request to intervene must be filed with the Commission at least 30 days before the second hearing day.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The request to intervene shall include</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the name, address and telephone and facsimile numbers of the requester;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>where the requester intends to be represented by counsel or an agent, the name, address and telephone and facsimile numbers of the counsel or agent;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a description of how the requester meets at least one of the conditions for intervening set out in subrule (1) and;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a statement setting out whether the requester wishes to intervene by way of written submission only or by way of written submission and oral presentation, and a copy of the information and submission.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>Where a public hearing comprises two hearing days, any written submission and oral presentation of a person permitted to intervene at the public hearing shall be considered by the Commission on the second hearing day.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Requests for Rulings</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>20</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>At any time before the start of a public hearing, a participant may file a request with the Commission for a ruling on a particular issue by setting out the issue and the reasons for the ruling that is sought.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>At the same time that a request for a ruling is filed with the Commission, the participant making the request must serve a copy of it</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>on the other participants, if any; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>where the participant is opposing a request to intervene, on the person requesting permission to intervene.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>At any time during the public hearing, a participant may make an oral request to the Commission for a ruling on a particular issue by explaining the issue and the reasons for the ruling that is sought.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The Commission shall give its decision in relation to the request for a ruling after the Commission has provided the relevant persons an opportunity to present their views on the request.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Presentation of Information and Submissions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>21</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>During a public hearing, the Commission, subject to these Rules, may permit each participant to present information and submissions on the subject-matter orally or in writing, and may permit participants to question one another and any witnesses, and to respond to any submissions, in any manner and sequence that will enable the Commission to determine the matter before it in a fair, informal and expeditious manner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A person who makes an oral presentation at a public hearing must have complied with the documentary filing requirements of rule 18 or 19, as the case may be.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>A person who has filed documentary material with the Commission under rule 18 may, no later than seven days before the start of the public hearing, file documentary material to the extent necessary to supplement or amend the material originally filed.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2007-208, s. 32.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Decision</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>22</Label><Text>The Commission shall give notice of its decision in respect of the matter that has been the subject of a public hearing by sending a copy of the decision to the participants.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 3</Label><TitleText>Opportunity to Be Heard by Commission</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>23</Label><Text>This Part applies in respect of an opportunity to be heard that is given by the Commission under subsection 40(1) of the Act, where Part 2 does not apply.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Notice</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>24</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The Commission shall notify each party of the party's opportunity to be heard.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The notice shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>set out the subject-matter of the opportunity to be heard;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>set out the time limits for filing submissions and information with the Commission; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>set out the name and address of any person to whom copies of any information and written submissions must be sent, and the time limits for sending them.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The Commission shall conduct the opportunity to be heard orally, by written submissions or in any other manner that will enable the Commission to determine the questions before it in a fair, informal and expeditious manner.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Decision of Commission</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>25</Label><Text>The Commission shall give notice of its decision in respect of the matter that has been the subject of an opportunity to be heard under this Part by sending a copy of the decision to the parties and any other persons who intervened in the proceeding.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 4</Label><TitleText>Opportunity to Be Heard by Designated Officer — Licensing Matters</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>26</Label><Text>This Part applies in respect of an opportunity to be heard referred to in subsection 39(1) of the Act that is given by a designated officer</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in considering an application for a licence under paragraph 37(2)(c) of the Act; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>before renewing, suspending, amending, revoking or replacing a licence, or refusing to renew, suspend, amend, revoke or replace a licence under paragraph 37(2)(d) of the Act.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Notice</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>27</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The designated officer shall notify each party of their opportunity to be heard in respect of a licensing matter referred to in rule 26.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The notice shall set out</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the subject-matter of the opportunity to be heard;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the time limits for filing submissions and information with the designated officer; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the name and address of any person to whom copies of any information and written submissions must be sent, and the time limits for sending them.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The designated officer shall conduct the opportunity to be heard orally, by written submissions or in any other manner that will enable the designated officer to determine the questions before him or her in a fair, informal and expeditious manner.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Decision of Designated Officer</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>28</Label><Text>The designated officer shall give notice of the decision in respect of the matter that has been heard under this Part by sending a copy of the decision to the parties and any other persons who intervened in the proceeding.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 5</Label><TitleText>Licence Appeal or Redetermination</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>29</Label><Text>Rule 30 applies in respect of the following licensing matters that may be the subject of an appeal or rehearing and redetermination by the Commission under subsection 43(1) or (2) of the Act, as the case may be:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a refusal of a designated officer to issue, renew, suspend, amend, revoke or replace a licence;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a term or condition of a licence issued by a designated officer;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a renewal, suspension, amendment, revocation or replacement, by a designated officer, of a licence;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a decision of the Commission not to issue a licence;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>a decision of the Commission not to renew, suspend, amend, revoke or replace a licence;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>any term or condition of a licence issued, renewed, suspended or amended by the Commission; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>a suspension, amendment, revocation or replacement, by the Commission, of a licence.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Notice of Appeal or Redetermination</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>30</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>An appeal or an application for a rehearing and redetermination may be made by sending to the Commission a notice that includes</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a reference to the paragraph of subsection 43(1) or (2) of the Act under which the appeal or application is being made;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a reference to the licence that is the subject of the appeal or application;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the grounds for the appeal or application, including, in the case of an appeal, a statement of how the appellant is directly affected by the decision being appealed;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a statement of the action that the appellant or applicant submits that the Commission should take under subsection 43(4) of the Act;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>a statement indicating whether or not the appellant or applicant intends to present new evidence;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>a description of the manner in which the appellant or applicant proposes to participate in the proceeding;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>the name, address and telephone and facsimile numbers of the appellant or applicant; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>a statement indicating whether the appellant or applicant intends to be represented by counsel or an agent and, if so, the name, address and telephone and facsimile numbers of the counsel or agent.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>After receiving a notice of appeal or rehearing and redetermination, the Commission shall determine whether its consideration will be by way of public hearing under paragraph 40(5)(b) of the Act or written submissions or by another manner that will enable the Commission to determine the matter before it in a fair, informal and expeditious manner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>After determining the manner in which the appeal or rehearing and redetermination will be considered, the Commission shall send the appellant or applicant and any other participant a notice that includes</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the manner in which the appeal or rehearing and redetermination will be considered and a description of the manner in which the appellant or applicant and any other participant may present information, evidence and submissions to the Commission;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the date, place and time limit for giving or presenting information and submissions and requesting information; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the names and addresses of the persons to whom copies of the information and written submissions must be sent.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Redetermination on Commission's Own Initiative</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>31</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>This rule and rule 32 apply in respect of a redetermination by the Commission, on its own initiative, of any decision or order or term or condition of a licence, under subsection 43(3) of the Act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Where the Commission proposes to make a redetermination referred to in subrule (1), the Commission shall send a notice of redetermination to those persons who were participants in the matter being redetermined.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The notice of redetermination shall include the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the basis for the proposed redetermination;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a statement of the powers that the Commission might exercise under subsection 43(4) of the Act;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a statement of whether the Commission intends to redetermine the matter by way of public hearing or written submissions or by another manner that will enable the Commission to determine the matter before it in a fair, informal and expeditious manner;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a description of the manner in which a party and any other person participating may present information, evidence and submissions to the Commission;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the date, place and time limits for giving or presenting information and written submissions; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>the names and addresses of the persons to whom copies of the information and written submissions must be sent.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Decision</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>32</Label><Text>The Commission shall give notice of its decision in respect of the matter that has been the subject of an appeal or rehearing and redetermination by sending a copy of the decision to the parties and any other person who intervened in the proceedings.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 6</Label><TitleText>Orders of Inspectors and Designated Officers</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Making of Orders</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>33</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Before making an order under section 35 or paragraph 37(2)(f) of the Act, an inspector or a designated officer, as the case may be, shall inform, either orally or in writing, the person to whom the order is given of its nature and the basis for it, as well as any proposed time limit for compliance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The inspector or designated officer shall give the order referred to in subrule (1) in writing.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Proceedings to Confirm, Amend, Revoke or Replace an Order</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>34</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>As soon as practicable and, in any event, not later than 10 days after an inspector or a designated officer, as the case may be, gives an order under subrule 33(2), the inspector or designated officer shall refer it to the Commission for confirmation, amendment, revocation or replacement in accordance with subsection 35(3) or 37(6) of the Act, as the case may be.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Where the Commission acts under subsection 35(3) of the Act or a designated officer is authorized by the Commission to act under paragraph 37(2)(g) of the Act, the Commission or designated officer, as the case may be, shall notify the persons named in or subject to the order of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>their opportunity to be heard under paragraph 39(1)(c) or 40(1)(c) or (d) of the Act, as the case may be; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the requirement that those persons who intend to present information and submissions in respect of the order so notify the Commission or designated officer within 10 days after receipt of the notice.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>As soon as practicable after receiving a notice referred to in paragraph (2)(b), the Commission or designated officer shall notify the person giving the notice</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>of the manner in which and time when the person may be heard; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>of the format in which the information and submissions are required to be filed with the Commission or designated officer and sent to other parties and the time limits for filing and sending the information and submissions, as well as the names and addresses of the other parties.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>A decision by the Commission or designated officer, as the case may be, to confirm, amend, revoke or replace an order shall be in writing and must be sent, within 10 days after being made, to the persons who are named in or subject to the decision, and to any other persons who intervened in the proceeding.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2007-208, s. 33.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Appeal or Redetermination of an Order</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>35</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>This rule and rule 36 apply in respect of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>an appeal, under subsection 43(1) of the Act, of a confirmation, amendment, revocation or replacement, by a designated officer, of an order of an inspector; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a rehearing and redetermination, by the Commission,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>under paragraph 43(2)(e) of the Act, of an order of the Commission, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>under paragraph 43(2)(f) of the Act, of a confirmation, amendment, revocation or replacement by the Commission, of an order of an inspector or a designated officer.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>An appeal or an application for a redetermination referred to in subrule (1) may be made by sending to the Commission a notice that includes the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a reference to the paragraph of subsection 43(1) or (2) of the Act under which the appeal or application is being made;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a reference to the order that is the subject of the appeal or application;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the grounds for the appeal or application, including, in the case of an appeal, a statement showing how the appellant is directly affected by the order being appealed;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a statement of the action that the appellant or applicant submits that the Commission should take under subsection 43(4) of the Act;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>a statement indicating whether or not the appellant or applicant wishes to present new evidence;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>a description of the manner in which the appellant or applicant proposes to participate in the proceeding;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>the name, address and telephone and facsimile numbers of the appellant or applicant; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>a statement indicating whether the appellant or applicant intends to be represented by counsel or an agent and, if so, the name, address and telephone and facsimile numbers of the counsel or agent.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>After receiving the information referred to in subrule (2), the Commission shall decide whether the appeal or redetermination will be by way of public hearing under paragraph 40(5)(b) of the Act or written submissions or by another manner that will enable the Commission to determine the matter before it in a fair, informal and expeditious manner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>After determining the manner in which the appeal or redetermination will be considered, the Commission shall send to the appellant or applicant and to those persons who were participants in the proceeding related to the order being appealed or redetermined, a notice that includes</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a description of the manner in which the redetermination will be considered and a description of the manner in which the appellant or applicant and any other participant may present information, evidence and submissions to the Commission;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the date, place and time limits for giving or presenting information and submissions; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the names and addresses of the persons to whom copies of the information and written submissions must be sent.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Decision</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>36</Label><Text>The Commission shall give notice of its decision in respect of the matter that has been the subject of appeal or rehearing and redetermination by sending a copy of the decision to the parties and to any other persons who intervened in the proceeding.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 7</Label><TitleText>Hearing for Contaminated Places</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Notice of Public Hearing</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>37</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Where the Commission proposes, under subsection 46(1) of the Act, to conduct a public hearing in respect of contamination by a radioactive nuclear substance at any place, the Commission shall send a notice of public hearing, at least 60 days before the beginning of the hearing, to</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the owner and the occupant of the place; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any person who has a right to, or interest in, the place, where the right or interest is set out in the registry of the land registry office or other office where title to the land in which the place is located is recorded.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The Commission shall also give a notice to the public at least 60 days before the start of the public hearing in any manner that the Commission considers will most likely result in the notice coming to the attention of persons interested in the matter being considered.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The notices referred to in subrules (1) and (2) shall include, where applicable, the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the Commission's reasons for believing that there is contamination in excess of the prescribed limit by a radioactive nuclear substance at the place;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the date, time and place of the public hearing;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the requirement that persons referred to in paragraph (1)(a) or (b) who intend to participate in the hearing must so notify the Commission in accordance with rule 18;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the manner in which persons may request to intervene, as set out in rule 19;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the actions the Commission may take, following the hearing, under subsections 46(2) and (3) of the Act; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>the names and addresses of persons to whom copies of any information and written submissions filed or to be filed with the Commission, for consideration at the hearing, must be sent.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2007-208, s. 34(F).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText> Determination</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>38</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The Commission shall send a written notice of its determination to the persons referred to in subrule 37(1) in respect of the matter that was the subject of the public hearing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Where the Commission determines that there is contamination in excess of the prescribed limit, the notice shall include</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a description and the amount of the contamination that is present at the place;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a statement that a notice of contamination will be filed in accordance with subsection 46(2) of the Act; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>where the Commission intends to issue an order to reduce the level of contamination in accordance with subsection 46(3) of the Act, a statement to that effect, or, where an order has already been issued, a copy of the order.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Notice of Contamination</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>39</Label><Text>A notice of contamination referred to in subsection 46(2) of the Act shall include a description of the place that is the subject of the notice and a description of the contamination that is present at the place.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Notice of Order</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>40</Label><Text>An order in relation to the contamination of a place that is made by the Commission under subsection 46(3) of the Act shall be sent to those persons to whom a notice of contamination was sent and shall include the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a description of the place that is the subject of the order and of the contamination that is present at that place;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a description of the particular prescribed measures that are required to be taken to reduce the level of contamination; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>any time limit for complying with the order.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 8</Label><TitleText>Hearing where Place No Longer Contaminated</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Notice of Public Hearing</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>41</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Where the Commission intends, under subsection 46(4) of the Act, to conduct a public hearing to determine whether contamination by a radioactive nuclear substance at any place is no longer present, the Commission shall send a notice of public hearing, at least 60 days before the beginning of the hearing, to</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the owner and the occupant of the place;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any person who has a right to, or interest in, the place, where the right or interest is set out in the registry of the land registry office or other office where title to the land in which the place is located is recorded; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>any other person to whom a notice of public hearing was sent under subrule 37(1).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The notice shall include, where applicable, the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the Commission's reasons for believing that there no longer is contamination in excess of the prescribed limit by a radioactive nuclear substance at the place;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the time limits for filing information and written submissions with the Commission;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the date, time and place of the public hearing;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the action the Commission may take, following the hearing, pursuant to subsection 46(5) of the Act; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the names and addresses of persons to whom copies of any information and written submissions filed or to be filed with the Commission, for consideration at the hearing, must be sent.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2007-208, s. 35.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Determination</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>42</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The Commission shall send a notice of its determination in respect of a matter that was the subject of the public hearing to the persons referred to in subrule 41(1) within 30 days after making the determination.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The notice shall include, where the Commission determines that there no longer is contamination in excess of the prescribed limit, a description and the amount of the contamination, if any, that is still present at the place.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 9</Label><TitleText>Notice of Emergency Order</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>43</Label><Text>A notice of an emergency order given under subsection 47(2) of the Act shall be sent in accordance with rule 7 to every person named in or subject to it, and shall include</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a copy of the order; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any time limit for complying with the order.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 10</Label><TitleText>Court Orders</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Publication of Facts</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>44</Label><Text>Where a court, pursuant to paragraph 60(1)(c) of the Act, orders an offender to publish the facts relating to a conviction, the offender shall publish them in two editions of any newspaper specified in the order, at an interval of not less than one week and not more than two months between publications.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Notifying Affected Persons</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>45</Label><Text>Where a court, pursuant to paragraph 60(1)(d) of the Act, orders an offender to notify any person who is affected by the offender's conduct of the facts relating to a conviction, the offender shall give notice to the person in accordance with rule 44 or by one of the methods referred to in rule 7, as ordered by the court.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section type="transitional"><Label>46</Label><Text>These Rules come into force on the day on which they are approved by the Governor in Council.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>