<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2005-60</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>3</MM><DD>22</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><LastAmendedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>9</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></LastAmendedDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2006</YYYY><MM>4</MM><DD>27</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">BROADCASTING ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Direction to the CRTC (Reservation of Channels for the Distribution of CPAC)</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2005-380</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>3</MM><DD>22</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Whereas on March 12, 2003, the Government of Canada released a new official languages accountability and coordination framework in which it renewed its commitment to supporting Canada's linguistic duality;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>Whereas the Canadian Public Affairs Channel (CPAC) is a valuable and unique component of the broadcasting system;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>Whereas the Standing Committee on Official Languages and the Standing Committee on Canadian Heritage have recommended that CPAC be made more widely available in both official languages;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>Whereas direct-to-home distribution undertakings are required to provide CPAC in both official languages;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>Whereas the Government of Canada is of the opinion that every effort should be made to ensure that CPAC be made available in both official languages to more cable subscribers;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>Whereas cable broadcasting distribution undertakings who have fewer than 2,000 subscribers may suffer significant financial or competitive difficulties if they are required to distribute CPAC in both official languages;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>Whereas, pursuant to subsection 26(4) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Broadcasting Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="footnotea_e">a</FootnoteRef>, the Minister of Canadian Heritage has consulted with the Canadian Radio-television and Telecommunications Commission with regard to the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Direction to the CRTC (Reservation of Channels for the Distribution of CPAC)</XRefExternal>;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>And whereas the Direction is intended to apply to cable broadcasting distribution undertakings who have 2,000 or more subscribers and who are licensed, or are exempted from licensing, by the Canadian Radio-television and Telecommunications Commission;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>Therefore, Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Canadian Heritage, pursuant to paragraph 26(1)(b) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Broadcasting Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef>a</FootnoteRef>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Direction to the CRTC (Reservation of Channels for the Distribution of CPAC)</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="footnotea_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 1991, c. 11</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Direction</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>The Canadian Radio-television and Telecommunications Commission is hereby directed to require cable broadcasting distribution undertakings who have 2,000 or more subscribers, whether or not they are exempted from licensing by the Commission, to reserve two video channels, one channel for the English-language service and the other for the French-language service, for the distribution of the licensed and exempted programming service provided by the Cable Public Affairs Channel (CPAC). One of the video channels shall be on the basic service.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2005–283, s. 1(E).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section type="transitional"><Label>2</Label><Text>This Order comes into force on the day on which it is registered.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>