<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en" in-force="yes"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2008-222</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>4</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>25</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">WAGE EARNER PROTECTION PROGRAM ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Wage Earner Protection Program Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2008-1317</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>4</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Labour, pursuant to section 41 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Wage Earner Protection Program Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_609937-e_hq_4009">a</FootnoteRef>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Wage Earner Protection Program Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fn_609937-e_hq_4009" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 2005, c. 47, s. 1</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>The following definitions apply in these Regulations.</Text><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Wage Earner Protection Program Act</XRefExternal>. (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Minister</DefinedTermEn> means the Minister of Labour. (<DefinedTermFr>ministre</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Wages</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>The following amounts are prescribed for the purposes of the definition <DefinedTermEn>wages</DefinedTermEn> in subsection 2(1) of the Act:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>gratuities accounted for by the employer;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>disbursements of a travelling salesperson properly incurred in and about the business of a bankrupt or the business of a person subject to a receivership; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>production bonuses and shift premiums.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2016-258, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Termination of Employment</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>An individual’s employment has ended for the purposes of paragraph 5(a) of the Act if it has ended for any of the following reasons:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the individual resigned or retired;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the individual’s employment has terminated; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the term of the individual’s employment has expired.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>2009, c. 2, s. 348.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Controlling Interest</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>For the purpose of paragraph 6(b) of the Act, an individual had a controlling interest in the business of their former employer if the individual owned</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>more than 40% of the voting shares in the business;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a block of voting shares that is large enough such that no one shareholder or coalition of shareholders can block a motion; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>enough shares in the business to control the business’s policy.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Excluded Managers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>For the purpose of paragraph 6(c) of the Act, an individual occupied a managerial position with their former employer if the responsibilities of the individual included making binding</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>financial decisions affecting the business of the former employer; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>decisions with respect to the payment or the non-payment of wages by the former employer.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Offsets</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>The following amounts are prescribed for the purpose of subsection 7(1) of the Act:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any amount that the individual has received after the date of the bankruptcy or the first day on which there was a receiver in relation to the former employer by virtue of his or her rights in respect of the eligible wages; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>an amount equal to 6.82% of the amount determined under that subsection.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>2009, c. 2, s. 349.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>7</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, 2009, c. 2, s. 350]</Repealed></Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Allocation of Payments</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>8</Label><Text>Payments to an individual under the Act are to be allocated in the following order:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>firstly, to wages other than those referred to in paragraphs (b) to (e);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>secondly, to disbursements of a travelling salesperson properly incurred in and about the business of a bankrupt or the business of a person subject to a receivership to the extent referred to in subsections 81.3(3) and 81.4(3) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Bankruptcy and Insolvency Act</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>thirdly, to vacation pay;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>fourthly, to termination pay; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>lastly, to severance pay.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>2009, c. 2, s. 351.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Applications</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>9</Label><Text>An application for payment shall, unless circumstances beyond the control of the applicant justify a longer period, be made within 56 days after the latest of the following days:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the date of the bankruptcy or receivership of the applicant’s former employer,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the day on which the applicant’s employment ends for any of the reasons referred to in section 3, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the day on which the receiver terminates the applicant’s employment.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>2009, c. 2, s. 352; SOR/2016-258, s. 2(E).</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>10</Label><Text>An application shall be made in writing using the form provided by the Minister.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Review</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>11</Label><Text>An applicant shall, unless circumstances beyond the control of the applicant justify a longer period, request a review under section 11 of the Act in writing no more than 30 days after the day on which the applicant is informed of the Minister’s determination of eligibility or ineligibility, as the case may be.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2016-258, s. 3(E).</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>12</Label><Text>The Minister shall notify the applicant in writing of the Minister’s decision.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Appeal</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>13</Label><Text>An appeal to an adjudicator under section 14 of the Act shall, unless circumstances beyond the control of the applicant justify a longer period, be made within 60 days after the day on which the applicant is notified of the Minister’s decision.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2016-258, s. 4(E).</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>14</Label><Text>The appeal shall be made in writing and contain a statement of the grounds of appeal.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Information to Be Provided to the Minister</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>15</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>For the purpose of paragraph 21(1)(d) of the Act, the trustee or receiver shall provide the Minister with the following information in the form provided by the Minister:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the date of bankruptcy or receivership;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the name, address, telephone number, social insurance number, employee number and job title of the individual;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the dates on which wages, other than severance pay or termination pay, were earned and the basis upon which they were calculated;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c.1)</Label><Text>the date on which any employment in respect of which severance pay or termination pay is owing ended;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a statement as to whether or not the individual delivered a proof of claim for wages owing under section 124 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Bankruptcy and Insolvency Act</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the names of the employer’s officers, directors and owners and of the person responsible for the employer’s payroll.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The trustee or receiver shall provide the information within</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>45 days after the date of bankruptcy or after the first day on which there was a receiver in relation to the former employer, as the case may be, unless circumstances beyond the control of the trustee or receiver justify a longer period; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>if the trustee or receiver requests the information under subsection 21(3) or (4) of the Act, 15 days after receiving the information.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>2009, c. 2, s. 353; SOR/2016-258, s. 5(E).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Information to Be Provided to an Individual</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>16</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>For the purpose of paragraph 21(1)(d) of the Act, the trustee or receiver shall provide each individual with the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the date of bankruptcy or receivership;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a statement informing the individual of their requirement under section 124 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Bankruptcy and Insolvency Act</XRefExternal> to deliver a proof of claim for wages owing;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a copy of the information and documents that they provided to the Minister with respect to the individual; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>an application form for the Wage Earner Protection Program.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The trustee or receiver shall provide the information within 45 days after the date of bankruptcy or after the first day on which there was a receiver in relation to the former employer, as the case may be, unless circumstances beyond the control of the trustee or receiver justify a longer period.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>2009, c. 2, s. 354; SOR/2016-258, s. 6.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Duty to Assist — Deadlines</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>17</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A person shall provide information under subsection 21(3) or (4) of the Act within 10 days after the day on which they receive the request unless circumstances beyond the control of the person justify a longer period and the person makes a written request to the Minister for an extension before the 10 days have elapsed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A copy of the request for extension shall also be provided to the trustee or receiver, as the case may be.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2016-258, s. 7.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Fees and Expenses</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>18</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>For the purpose of subsection 22(2) of the Act, the Minister shall, on application by the trustee or receiver, pay the fees and expenses in relation to the performance of their duties under the Act if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the trustee or receiver provides a copy of their final statement of receipts and disbursements for the bankruptcy or receivership;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the final statement of receipts and disbursements for the bankruptcy or receivership shows a deficit;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>no guarantee has been provided by a creditor of the employer in respect of the fees and expenses; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the fees in relation to the performance of duties under section 21 of the Act are equal to at least 10% of the total fees charged for the administration of the bankruptcy or receivership.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The amount payable is equal to the lesser of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the amount of the deficit shown in the final statement of receipts and disbursements, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the amount obtained by adding $600 for the first wage claim to the amount determined by multiplying $35 by the number of subsequent claims.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>19</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>For the purposes of subsection 22(2) of the Act, the Minister shall, on application by the trustee or receiver, pay the fees and expenses for their administration of the estate or property if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the trustee or receiver provides a copy of their final statement of receipts and disbursements for the bankruptcy or receivership;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the final statement of receipts and disbursements for the bankruptcy or receivership shows a deficit;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the amount determined in accordance with the following formula is greater than zero and less than or equal to the value of the rights under sections 81.3 and 81.4 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Bankruptcy and Insolvency Act</XRefExternal>:</Text><FormulaGroup><Formula><FormulaText>X - Y</FormulaText></Formula><FormulaConnector>where</FormulaConnector><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>X</FormulaTerm><Text>is equal to the current assets realized, and</Text></FormulaDefinition><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>Y</FormulaTerm><Text>is the sum of the value of the rights under sections 81.1 and 81.2 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Bankruptcy and Insolvency Act</XRefExternal> and the amounts referred to in subsection 67(3) of that Act that have been deemed to be held in trust; and</Text></FormulaDefinition></FormulaGroup></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the value of the rights under sections 81.3 and 81.4 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Bankruptcy and Insolvency Act</XRefExternal> constitutes the entire value of the property in the possession of the trustee or receiver.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The amount payable is equal to the least of the following amounts, minus any amount paid under section 18:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the sum of</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>95% of the value of current assets realized that are worth less than $2,000,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>50% of the value of current assets realized that are worth between $2,000 and $4,000,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>35% of the value of current assets realized that are worth between $4,000.01 and $10,000,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>5% of the value of current assets realized that are worth $10,000.01 or more, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(v)</Label><Text>the fees and expenses</Text><Clause><Label>(A)</Label><Text>for taking possession of the property, making an inventory and securing and insuring the property,</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(B)</Label><Text>for mail-outs to creditors to advise them of the meeting of creditors and the discharge hearing of the trustee,</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(C)</Label><Text>for the cost of publishing a newspaper notice of the bankruptcy,</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(D)</Label><Text>of the official receiver and the registrar, and</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(E)</Label><Text>for other items that may be allowed by the court on the taxation of the statement of receipts and disbursements to a maximum of $1,000;</Text></Clause></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>if a guarantee has been provided by a creditor of the employer in respect of the fees and expenses, the value of that guarantee; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the value of the rights under sections 81.3 and 81.4 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Bankruptcy and Insolvency Act</XRefExternal>.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label><FootnoteRef idref="fn_Ind154C_hq_4985">*</FootnoteRef>20</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on the day on which the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Wage Earner Protection Program Act</XRefExternal>, as enacted by section 1 of chapter 47 of the Statutes of Canada, 2005, comes into force.</Text><Footnote id="fn_Ind154C_hq_4985" placement="section" status="editorial"><Label>*</Label><Text>[Note: Regulations in force July 7, 2008, <Emphasis style="italic">see</Emphasis> SI/2008-78.]</Text></Footnote></Section></Body><Schedule id="RelatedProvs"><ScheduleFormHeading type="amending"><TitleText>RELATED PROVISIONS</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><RegulationPiece><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — 2009, c. 2, s. 357</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Application</MarginalNote><Label>357</Label><Text>The provisions of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Wage Earner Protection Program Act</XRefExternal> and the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Wage Earner Protection Program Regulations</XRefExternal> as amended by sections <XRefInternal>342</XRefInternal> to <XRefInternal>354</XRefInternal> apply</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in respect of wages owing to an individual by an employer who becomes bankrupt after January 26, 2009; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in respect of wages owing to an individual by an employer any of whose property comes under the possession or control of a receiver within the meaning of subsection 243(2) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Bankruptcy and Insolvency Act</XRefExternal> after January 26, 2009.</Text></Paragraph></Section></RegulationPiece></Schedule></Regulation>