<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/90-774</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1990</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>9</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>9</MM><DD>3</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">HIBERNIA DEVELOPMENT PROJECT ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Hibernia Development Project Offshore Application Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting the Application of Federal Laws and Laws of Newfoundland in the Newfoundland Offshore Area for the Purposes of the Hibernia Development Project Act</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1990-2419 </OrderNumber><Date><YYYY> 1990</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>9</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Whereas the Governor in Council considers that certain modifications or additions to the laws of Newfoundland that apply in the offshore area pursuant to section 8 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Hibernia Development Project Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-90-774_e_hq_5211">*</FootnoteRef> are necessary;</Text><Footnote id="fn_SOR-90-774_e_hq_5211" placement="page" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>S.C. 1990, c. 41</Text></Footnote></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Therefore, His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Energy, Mines and Resources, pursuant to sections 7 and 8 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Hibernia Development Project Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-90-774_e_hq_5211">*</FootnoteRef>, is pleased hereby to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting the application of federal laws and laws of Newfoundland in the Newfoundland offshore area for the purposes of the Hibernia Development Project Act</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Hibernia Development Project Offshore Application Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Federal Laws</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>The prescribed federal laws in relation to the subjects referred to in subsection 7(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Hibernia Development Project Act</XRefExternal> are the Acts of Parliament or the provisions thereof set out in Schedule I, any regulations as defined in section 2 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Interpretation Act</XRefExternal> that are issued, made or established under the authority of those Acts and any rules of law within the jurisdiction of Parliament in relation to those subjects.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Laws of Newfoundland</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>For the purpose of creating, continuing and enforcing, under the laws of Newfoundland that apply in the offshore area by virtue of subsection 8(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Hibernia Development Project Act</XRefExternal>, a security interest in any personal property that is affixed to, rests on or is otherwise in contact with the seabed or subsoil of the submarine areas of the offshore area, those laws shall be read as if that personal property were not a fixture of that seabed or subsoil.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>For the purposes of subsection 8(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Hibernia Development Project Act</XRefExternal>, the Acts of Newfoundland set out in column I of an item of Schedule II shall be read as if they were modified or added to in the manner and to the extent set out in column II of that item.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application of the Interpretation Act (Newfoundland)</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text><XRefExternal reference-type="act">The Interpretation Act</XRefExternal>, R.S.N. 1970, c. 182, applies in respect of all laws of Newfoundland, including the Acts referred to in section 3 as modified or added to pursuant to that section, that, by virtue of subsection 8(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Hibernia Development Project Act</XRefExternal>, apply in the offshore area.</Text></Section></Body><Schedule bilingual="no" spanlanguages="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE I</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 2)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><TableGroup topmarginspacing="4"><table frame="topbot"><tgroup cols="2"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="72.12*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="395.88*" /><thead><row topdouble="yes"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Item</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Act of Parliament or Provisions thereof</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Parts I and V and Schedules VI, VII, VIII and IX of the Bank Act, R.S.C., 1985, c. B-1</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Bankruptcy and Insolvency Act, R.S.C., 1985, c. B-3</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">3</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Bills of Exchange Act, R.S.C., 1985, c. B-4</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">4</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Interest Act, R.S.C., 1985, c. I-15</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup><HistoricalNote> 1992, c. 27, s. 90.</HistoricalNote></Schedule><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE II</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 3)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><TableGroup pointsize="8" topmarginspacing="4"><table frame="topbot"><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="72.46*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="193.31*" /><colspec colname="3" colwidth="202.22*" /><thead><row topdouble="yes"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" /><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Column I</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Column II</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Item</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Act of Newfoundland</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Modifications or Additions</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">The Assignment of Book Debts Act <Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0"><Text>R.S.N. 1970, c. 15</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Wherever the word “corporation” occurs in section 3, there shall in every case be substituted the expression “corporation or, for greater certainty, partnership of corporations”.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Subsection 5(3) is repealed.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" type="amending"><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Section 14 is repealed and the following substituted therefor:</Text><AmendedText><Section><Label>“14</Label><Text> Subject to the rights of other persons accrued by reason of any omission or misstatement referred to in this section, a judge of the Supreme Court, on being satisfied that any omission or misstatement in any document filed under this Act was accidental or due to inadvertence or impossibility or other sufficient cause, may, in the judge’s discretion, order the omission or misstatement to be rectified on such terms and conditions, if any, as to security, notice by advertisement or otherwise, or as to any other matter or thing as the judge thinks fit to direct, and the order or a copy thereof shall be annexed to the assignment on file or tendered for registration and appropriate entries shall be made in the register.”</Text></Section></AmendedText></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">The Bills of Sale Act<Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0"><Text>R.S.N. 1970, c. 21</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Wherever the word “corporation” occurs in paragraph 2(h), there shall in every case be substituted the expression “corporation or, for greater certainty, partnership of corporations”.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Subsection 7(1) is amended by striking out the words “within thirty days from the date of its execution”.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" type="amending"><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Section 7 is further amended by adding the following subsection:</Text><AmendedText><Section><Label>“(5) </Label><Text>Where a bill of sale that contains an error or omission of a clerical nature made during the preparation of the bill of sale is filed in the registry in accordance with this section, an amended bill of sale, verified by affidavit referring to the former bill of sale and specifying and correcting the error or omission, may be filed.”</Text></Section></AmendedText></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" type="amending"><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Subsection 20(1) is repealed and the following substituted therefor:</Text><AmendedText><Section><Label>“20</Label><Text> (1) A judge of the Supreme Court, on being satisfied that an omission to register a renewal statement within the time prescribed by this Act or that an omission or misstatement in a document registered under this Act was accidental or due to inadvertence or impossibility or other sufficient cause, may, subject to the rights of other persons accrued by reason thereof, extend the time for registration or order the omission or misstatement to be rectified on any terms and conditions the judge directs.”</Text></Section></AmendedText></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">3</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">The Conditional Sales Act<Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0"><Text>R.S.N. 1970, c. 56</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subsection 4(3) is amended by striking out the words “within thirty days from the date of its execution”.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" type="amending"><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Section 4 is further amended by adding the following subsection:</Text><AmendedText><Section><Label>“(5) </Label><Text>Where a conditional sale that contains an error or omission of a clerical nature made during the preparation of the conditional sale has been filed in the registry in accordance with this section, an amended conditional sale, verified by affidavit referring to the former conditional sale and specifying and correcting the error or omission, may be filed.”</Text></Section></AmendedText></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" type="amending"><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Subsection 18(1) is repealed and the following substituted therefor:</Text><AmendedText><Section><Label>“18</Label><Text>(1) A judge of the Supreme Court, on being satisfied that an omission to file a notice required to be filed under section 14 or a renewal statement or amended statement within the time prescribed by this Act or that an omission or misstatement in a document filed under this Act was accidental or due to inadvertence or impossibility or other sufficient cause, may, subject to the rights of other persons accrued by reason thereof, extend the time for filing or order the omission or misstatement to be rectified on any terms and conditions the judge directs.”</Text></Section></AmendedText></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">4</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">The Conveyancing Act<Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0"><Text>R.S.N. 1970, c. 63</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" type="amending"><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subsection 6.1(2) is repealed and the following substituted therefor:</Text><AmendedText><Subsection><Label>“(2) </Label><Text>A notice of sale of amortgaged property by public auction or public tender shall be placed in a newspaper in general circulation in Newfoundland at least once a week for two consecutive weeks before the date on which the sale is to take place.”</Text></Subsection></AmendedText></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Subsection 6.2(2) is repealed.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Section 6.6 is repealed.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Section 6.7 is repealed.</Text></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">5</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">The Registration of Deeds Act<Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0"><Text>R.S.N. 1970, c. 328</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" type="amending"><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Paragraph 6(1)(e) is repealed and the following substituted therefor:</Text><AmendedText><SectionPiece><Paragraph><Label>“(e) </Label><Text>conveyances of personal chattels and the documents referred to in subsection 33(2); and”</Text></Paragraph></SectionPiece></AmendedText></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Where the word “corporation” occurs in paragraph 33(2)(a), there shall be substituted the expression “corporation or, for greater certainty, partnership of corporations”.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Where the word “person” occurs in paragraph 33(2)(c), there shall be substituted the expression “person or partnership.”</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Wherever in paragraph 33(2)(d) the word “corporation” occurs, there shall in every case be substituted the expression “corporation or, for greater certainty, partnership of corporations”.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(5)</Label><Text>Where the expression “the Crown in right of Newfoundland” occurs in subsection 39(4), there shall be substituted the expression “the Crown in right of Canada or the Crown in right of Newfoundland”.</Text></Provision></entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Schedule></Regulation>