<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/88-126</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1988</YYYY><MM>2</MM><DD>4</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2011</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>13</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AERONAUTICS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Cranbrook Airport Zoning Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting Zoning at Cranbrook Airport</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1988-188</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1988</YYYY><MM>2</MM><DD>4</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas, pursuant to section 4.5 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Aeronautics Act</XRefExternal>, a copy of the proposed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Zoning Regulations respecting Cranbrook Airport</XRefExternal>, substantially in the form set out in the schedule hereto, was published in two successive issues of the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>, Part I, on August 22nd and 29th, 1987, and in two successive issues of the Cranbrook Daily Townsman on June 22nd and 23rd, 1987, and a reasonable opportunity was thereby afforded to interested persons to make representations to the Minister of Transport with respect thereto.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Therefore, Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Transport, pursuant to section 4.4 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Aeronautics Act</XRefExternal>, is pleased hereby to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting Zoning at Cranbrook Airport</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Cranbrook Airport Zoning Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>airport</DefinedTermEn> means the Cranbrook Airport at Cranbrook, in the East Kootenay Regional District and in the Kootenay Land District, in the Province of British Columbia; (<DefinedTermFr>aéroport</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>airport reference point</DefinedTermEn> means the point described in Part I of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>point de repère de l’aéroport</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>approach surface</DefinedTermEn> means an imaginary inclined plane that extends upward and outward from each end of a strip, which approach surface is more particularly described in Part II of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>surface d’approche</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Minister</DefinedTermEn> means the Minister of Transport; (<DefinedTermFr>ministre</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>outer surface</DefinedTermEn> means an imaginary surface located above and in the immediate vicinity of the airport, which outer surface is more particularly described in Part III of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>surface extérieure</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>strip</DefinedTermEn> means the rectangular portion of the landing area of the airport, including the runway, prepared for the take-off and landing of aircraft in a particular direction, which strip is more particularly described in Part IV of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>bande</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>transitional surface</DefinedTermEn> means an imaginary inclined plane that extends upward and outward from the lateral limits of a strip and its approach surfaces, which transitional surface is more particularly described in Part V of the schedule. (<DefinedTermFr>surface de transition</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>For the purposes of these Regulations, the elevation of the airport reference point is 924.5 m above sea level.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-169, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>These Regulations apply to all the lands, including public road allowances, adjacent to or in the vicinity of the airport, which lands are more particularly described as follows:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the lands within the outer limits of lands described in Part VI of the schedule; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the lands directly under that portion of the approach surfaces that extend beyond the said outer limits.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-169, s. 2(F).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>No person shall erect or construct on any land to which these Regulations apply, any building, structure or object or any addition to any existing building, structure or object, the highest point of which will exceed in elevation at the location of that point</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the approach surfaces;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the outer surface; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the transitional surfaces.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-169, s. 3(F).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Natural Growth</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>Where an object of natural growth on any land to which these Regulations apply exceeds in elevation any of the surfaces referred to in paragraphs 4(a) to (c), the Minister may require that the owner or occupier of the land on which that object is growing remove the excessive growth.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-169, s. 4.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Disposal of Waste</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>No owner or occupier of any land to which these Regulations apply shall permit that land or any part of it to be used for the disposal of any waste that is edible by or attractive to birds.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-169, s. 5(F).</HistoricalNote></Section></Body><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label><OriginatingRef>(ss. 2 and 3)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><Heading level="1"><Label>PART I</Label><TitleText>Description of the Airport Reference Point</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The airport reference point, shown on Cranbrook Airport Zoning Plan No. B.C. 1640 (Z) dated January 12, 1987, is situated at a point distant 197.83 m measured westerly and perpendicular to the centre line of runway 16-34 from a point on the said centre line distant 1 089.58 m north of the southern end of the strip.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The airport reference point is marked by a brass plate set in a concrete catch basin and is identified as Department of Transport Monument Number 126 + 22.50.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART II</Label><TitleText>Description of the Approach Surfaces</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The approach surfaces, shown on Cranbrook Airport Zoning Plan No. B.C. 1640 (Z) dated January 12, 1987, are surfaces abutting each end of the strip associated with the runway designated 16-34 and are described as follows:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a surface abutting the end of the strip associated with runway approach 16 consisting of an inclined plane having a ratio of 1 m measured vertically to 50 m measured horizontally rising to an imaginary horizontal line drawn at right angles to the projected centre line of the strip and distant 15 000 m measured horizontally from the end of the strip; the outer ends of the imaginary horizontal line being 2 400 m from the projected centre line; said imaginary horizontal line being 300 m above the elevation at the end of the strip;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a surface abutting the end of the strip associated with runway approach 34 consisting of an inclined plane having a ratio of 1.25 m measured vertically to 50 m measured horizontally rising to an imaginary horizontal line drawn at right angles to the projected centre line of the strip and distant 3 000 m measured horizontally from the end of the strip; the outer ends of the imaginary horizontal line being 450 m from the projected centre line; the said imaginary horizontal line being 75 m above the elevation at the end of the strip.</Text></Provision></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART III</Label><TitleText>Description of the Outer Surface</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The outer surface, shown on Cranbrook Airport Zoning Plan No. B.C. 1640 (Z) dated January 12, 1987, is an imaginary surface located at a common plane established at a constant elevation of 45 m above the elevation of the airport reference point, except that, where that common plane is less than 9 m above the surface of the ground, the outer surface is an imaginary surface located at 9 m above the surface of the ground.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART IV</Label><TitleText>Description of the Strip</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The strip associated with runway 16-34, shown on Cranbrook Airport Zoning Plan No. B.C. 1640 (Z) dated January 12, 1987, is described as being 300 m in width, 150 m being on each side of the centre line of the runway, and 1 948.853 m in length.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART V</Label><TitleText>Description of Each Transitional Surface</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Each transitional surface, shown on Cranbrook Airport Zoning Plan No. B.C. 1640 (Z) dated January 12, 1987, is a surface consisting of an inclined plane having a ratio of 1 m measured vertically to 7 m measured horizontally at right angles to the centre line and projected centre line of each strip and extending upward and outward from the lateral limits of each strip and its approach surface to an intersection with the outer surface or another transitional surface of an adjoining strip.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART VI</Label><TitleText>Description of the Outer Limits of Land</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The boundary of the outer limits of lands, shown on Cranbrook Airport Zoning Plan No. B.C. 1640 (Z), dated January 12, 1987, is described as follows:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>All that land in the Kootenay District in the Province of British Columbia contained within the following described boundary:</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Commencing at the northeasterly corner of District Lot 340, Kootenay District;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence, northerly along the westerly limit of Kootenay Indian Reserve Number 1 a distance of 21.4 m, more or less, to a point which lies radially distant 4 000 m on a grid bearing of 353°44′30″ from the Airport Reference Point;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence, easterly, southerly and southwesterly in circular curve to the right of radius 4 000 m a distance of 8 612.73 m to a point of tangency;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence, on a grid bearing of 212°22′00″ a distance of 50 m, more or less, to the point of intersection with the northerly limit of District Lot 2, Kootenay District, being the right bank of Saint Mary River;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence, westerly and southerly following the sinuosities of the northerly limit of said District Lot 2 to the northwesterly corner of said District Lot 2;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence, southerly to the southeasterly corner of District Lot 1, Kootenay District;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence, westerly to the southwesterly corner of assigned Lot B, Sketch Map 20655A;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence, southerly to the southeasterly corner of District Lot 494, Kootenay District;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence, southerly to the southeasterly corner of District Lot 11570, Kootenay District;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence, westerly to the southwesterly corner of said District Lot 11570;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence, westerly to the southwesterly corner of District Lot 11569, Kootenay District;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence, westerly to the northwesterly corner of District Lot 11571, Kootenay District;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence, southerly to the northeasterly corner of Lot 2, Plan 13513;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence, westerly to the northwesterly corner of Lot 1, Plan 13513;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence, northwesterly in a straight line to a point in the easterly limit of District Lot 5267, Kootenay District, distant 300 m northerly from the southeasterly corner of said District Lot 5267;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence, northwesterly in a straight line to a point in the westerly limit of said District Lot 5267 distant 800 m northerly from the southwesterly corner of said District Lot 5267;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence, northwesterly in a straight line to the most southeasterly corner of District Lot 11530, Kootenay District;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence, westerly along the southern limit of said District Lot 11530 to the point of intersection with the southerly production of the westerly limit of District Lot 2045, Kootenay District;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence, northerly along the said southerly production and said westerly limit of District Lot 2045 to the point of intersection with the southerly limit of highway as shown on statutory right-of-way Plan 15445;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence, northerly and westerly along the southerly limit of the said Statutory Right-of-Way plan 15445 to the point of intersection with the easterly limit of District Lot 8748, Kootenay District;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence, northerly to the southeasterly corner of District Lot 6435, Kootenay District;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence, northerly to the southeasterly corner of District Lot 7010, Kootenay District;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence, westerly to the southwesterly corner of District Lot 7010, Kootenay District;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence, northerly to the northwesterly corner of said District Lot 7010;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence, northerly in a straight line to a point in the northerly limit of District Lot 8898, Kootenay District, which point lies 400 m westerly from the most northeasterly corner of said District Lot 8898;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence, northeasterly in a straight line to the northwesterly corner of sub lot 4 (plan x-40) of said District Lot 340;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence, northeasterly in a straight line to the northeasterly corner of sub lot 12 (plan x-40) of said District Lot 340;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence, northeasterly in a straight line to the point of commencement;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Except thereout and therefrom:</Text><Provision format-ref="" first-line-indent="1" subsequent-line-indent="4.5"><Label>Firstly:</Label><Text>Kootenay Indian Reserve Number 1, Plan B.C. 55 (C.L.S.R.);</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="" first-line-indent="1" subsequent-line-indent="5.5"><Label>Secondly:</Label><Text>District Lots 494, 1758 and parts of District Lot 1, Kootenay District, all now part of Saint Mary’s Indian Reserve Number 1A as shown on Plan 58602 (C.L.S.R.), plan B-90 (L.T.O.); and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="" first-line-indent="1" subsequent-line-indent="5"><Label>Thirdly:</Label><Text>Those parts of District Lot 1, Kootenay District, within Saint Mary’s Indian Reserve Number 1A as shown on Plan 59527 (C.L.S.R.), Plan K-854 (L.T.O.).</Text></Provision></Provision></Provision><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-169, ss. 6, 7.</HistoricalNote></Schedule></Regulation>