<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/85-533</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1985</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>7</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2011</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>23</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS MARKETING ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Manitoba Chicken Marketing Levies Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Providing for the Fixing, Imposing and Collecting of Levies From Chicken Producers in Manitoba</LongTitle></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>The Manitoba Chicken Broiler Producers’ Marketing Board, pursuant to section 4 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Manitoba Chicken Order</XRefExternal>, C.R.C., c. 152, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Order providing for the fixing, imposing and collecting of levies from chicken producers in Manitoba</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Winnipeg, Manitoba, May 31, 1985</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Manitoba Chicken Marketing Levies Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In this Order,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Commodity Board</DefinedTermEn> means The Manitoba Chicken Broiler Producers’ Marketing Board established pursuant to <XRefExternal reference-type="act">The Natural Products Marketing Act</XRefExternal> of Manitoba; (<DefinedTermFr>Office de commercialisation</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>chicken</DefinedTermEn> means a chicken of any variety, grade or class that is not more than five months of age and that is raised or kept within the Province of Manitoba for a purpose other than egg production, and includes broiler, fryer and roasting chickens; (<DefinedTermFr>poulet</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>producer</DefinedTermEn> means any person who raises, keeps, prepares for slaughter or slaughters chickens within the Province of Manitoba and includes the employer of any such person, a person who under any lease or agreement is entitled to a share of the chickens raised or kept by such a person and a person who takes possession of any chickens from any such person under any form of security for a debt. (<DefinedTermFr>producteur</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Exception</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>This Order does not apply to the marketing of chickens less than 10 days old.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Levies</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>Every producer shall pay to the Commodity Board levies at the rate of $0.0076 per kilogram live weight on all chicken marketed by the producer in interprovincial or export trade.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/87-48, s. 1; SOR/88-50, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Method of Payment</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (2), every producer shall pay the levies referred to in section 4 to the Commodity Board at its office, 1200 King Edward Street, Winnipeg, Manitoba, not later than seven days after the last day of the week in which the chickens were marketed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The levies referred to in section 4 may be deducted from the amount owed to the producer by the person who purchases the chicken and where a purchaser deducts such levies, the purchaser shall remit the levies so deducted to the Commodity Board at its office, 1200 King Edward Street, Winnipeg, Manitoba, not later than seven days after the last day of the week in which the chickens were purchased.</Text></Subsection></Section></Body></Regulation>