<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en" in-force="yes"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2014-70</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2014</YYYY><MM>3</MM><DD>28</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2014</YYYY><MM>4</MM><DD>9</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">ROYAL CANADIAN MOUNTED POLICE PENSION CONTINUATION ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Royal Canadian Mounted Police (Dependants) Pension Fund Increase in Benefits Order</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2014-308</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>2014</YYYY><MM>3</MM><DD>27</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas it appears from a report made under section 56 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Royal Canadian Mounted Police Pension Continuation Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_81000-2-1893-E_hq_13148">a</FootnoteRef> that the Royal Canadian Mounted Police (Dependants) Pension Fund is substantially in excess of the amount required to make adequate provision for the prospective payments out of it;</Text><Footnote id="fn_81000-2-1893-E_hq_13148" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>R.S.C., 1970, c. R-10</Text></Footnote></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Therefore, His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Public Safety and Emergency Preparedness, pursuant to subsection 57(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Royal Canadian Mounted Police Pension Continuation Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_81000-2-1893-E_hq_13148">a</FootnoteRef>, makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Royal Canadian Mounted Police (Dependants) Pension Fund Increase in Benefits Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>The following pension benefits, as provided in Part IV of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Royal Canadian Mounted Police Pension Continuation Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_81000-2-1893-E_hq_13149">1</FootnoteRef>, are to be increased in the following manner:</Text><Footnote id="fn_81000-2-1893-E_hq_13149" placement="page" status="official"><Label>1</Label><Text>R.S.C., 1970, c. R-10</Text></Footnote><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>pensions for current and prospective widows are to be increased by 1.2% in each of the 2014, 2015 and 2016 plan years, on April 1 of each plan year;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>lump sum benefits payable on the death of a member are to be increased by 1.2% in each of the 2014, 2015 and 2016 plan years, on April 1 of each plan year; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>residual amounts payable on the death of a member’s widow are to be calculated with a deemed increase in the member’s contributions, without crediting the contributions with interest, of</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>1,240% if the widow’s death occurs in the 2015 plan year,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>1,256% if the widow’s death occurs in the 2016 plan year, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>1,272% if the widow’s death occurs in the 2017 plan year.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>This Order comes into effect on April 1, 2014.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>