<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2000-202</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2000</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>31</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2007</YYYY><MM>9</MM><DD>25</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">NUCLEAR SAFETY AND CONTROL ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>General Nuclear Safety and Control Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2000-782</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY> 2000</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>31</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Natural Resources, pursuant to section 44 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Nuclear Safety and Control Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="footnotea_e">a</FootnoteRef>, hereby approves the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">General Nuclear Safety and Control Regulations</XRefExternal> made by the Canadian Nuclear Safety Commission on May 31, 2000.</Text><Footnote id="footnotea_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 1997, c. 9</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation and Application</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>The definitions in this section apply in these Regulations.</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Nuclear Safety and Control Act</XRefExternal>. (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>brachytherapy machine</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2008-119, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>effective dose</DefinedTermEn> has the meaning assigned to that term by subsection 1(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Radiation Protection Regulations</XRefExternal>. (<DefinedTermFr>dose efficace</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>equivalent dose</DefinedTermEn> has the meaning assigned to that term by subsection 1(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Radiation Protection Regulations</XRefExternal>. (<DefinedTermFr>dose équivalente</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>hazardous substance</DefinedTermEn> or <DefinedTermEn>hazardous waste</DefinedTermEn> means a substance or waste, other than a nuclear substance, that is used or produced in the course of carrying on a licensed activity and that may pose a risk to the environment or the health and safety of persons. (<DefinedTermFr>substance dangereuse</DefinedTermFr>ou<DefinedTermFr>déchet dangereux</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>IAEA</DefinedTermEn> means the International Atomic Energy Agency. (<DefinedTermFr>AIEA</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>IAEA Agreement</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Agreement between the Government of Canada and the International Atomic Energy Agency for the Application of Safeguards in Connection with the Treaty on the Non-proliferation of Nuclear Weapons</XRefExternal>, effective on February 21, 1972; INFCIRC/164; UNTS vol. 814, R. No. 11596. (<DefinedTermFr>Accord avec l’AIEA</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>irradiator</DefinedTermEn> means a device that is designed to contain a nuclear substance and to deliver controlled doses of radiation to any target material except persons. (<DefinedTermFr>irradiateur</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>licensed activity</DefinedTermEn> means an activity described in any of paragraphs 26(a) to (f) of the Act that a licence authorizes the licensee to carry on. (<DefinedTermFr>activité autorisée</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>licensee</DefinedTermEn> means a person who is licensed to carry on an activity described in any of paragraphs 26(a) to (f) of the Act. (<DefinedTermFr>titulaire de permis</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>prescribed equipment</DefinedTermEn> means the equipment prescribed by section 20. (<DefinedTermFr>équipement réglementé</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>prescribed information</DefinedTermEn> means the information prescribed by section 21. (<DefinedTermFr>renseignements réglementés</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>radioactive source teletherapy machine</DefinedTermEn> means a teletherapy machine that is designed to deliver doses of radiation produced by a nuclear substance. (<DefinedTermFr>appareil de téléthérapie à source radioactive</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>safeguards</DefinedTermEn> means a verification system that is established in accordance with a safeguards agreement. (<DefinedTermFr>garanties</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>safeguards agreement</DefinedTermEn> means</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">IAEA Agreement</XRefExternal> and any arrangement between Canada and the IAEA made under that agreement; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any agreement to which Canada is a party for the establishment in Canada of a verification system in respect of nuclear substances, prescribed equipment or prescribed information, and any arrangements made under such an agreement. (<DefinedTermFr>accord relatif aux garanties</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>safeguards equipment</DefinedTermEn> means equipment that is used in accordance with a safeguards agreement. (<DefinedTermFr>équipement de garanties</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>teletherapy machine</DefinedTermEn> means a device that is designed to deliver controlled doses of radiation in a collimated beam for therapeutic purposes. (<DefinedTermFr>appareil de téléthérapie</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>transit</DefinedTermEn> means the process of being transported through Canada after being imported into and before being exported from Canada, in a situation where the place of initial loading and the final destination are outside Canada. (<DefinedTermFr>transit</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>worker</DefinedTermEn> means a person who performs work that is referred to in a licence. (<DefinedTermFr>travailleur</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><HistoricalNote>SOR/2008-119, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>These Regulations apply generally for the purposes of the Act.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Licences</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>General Application Requirements</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>An application for a licence shall contain the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the applicant’s name and business address;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the activity to be licensed and its purpose;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the name, maximum quantity and form of any nuclear substance to be encompassed by the licence;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a description of any nuclear facility, prescribed equipment or prescribed information to be encompassed by the licence;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the proposed measures to ensure compliance with the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Radiation Protection Regulations</XRefExternal>, the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Nuclear Security Regulations</XRefExternal> and the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Packaging and Transport of Nuclear Substances Regulations, 2015</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>any proposed action level for the purpose of section 6 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Radiation Protection Regulations</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>the proposed measures to control access to the site of the activity to be licensed and the nuclear substance, prescribed equipment or prescribed information;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>the proposed measures to prevent loss or illegal use, possession or removal of the nuclear substance, prescribed equipment or prescribed information;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>a description and the results of any test, analysis or calculation performed to substantiate the information included in the application;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(j)</Label><Text>the name, quantity, form, origin and volume of any radioactive waste or hazardous waste that may result from the activity to be licensed, including waste that may be stored, managed, processed or disposed of at the site of the activity to be licensed, and the proposed method for managing and disposing of that waste;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(k)</Label><Text>the applicant’s organizational management structure insofar as it may bear on the applicant’s compliance with the Act and the regulations made under the Act, including the internal allocation of functions, responsibilities and authority;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(l)</Label><Text>a description of any proposed financial guarantee relating to the activity to be licensed; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(m)</Label><Text>any other information required by the Act or the regulations made under the Act for the activity to be licensed and the nuclear substance, nuclear facility, prescribed equipment or prescribed information to be encompassed by the licence.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(n)</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2008-119, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(1.1)</Label><Text>The Commission or a designated officer authorized under paragraph 37(2)(c) of the Act, may require any other information that is necessary to enable the Commission or the designated officer to determine whether the applicant</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>is qualified to carry on the activity to be licensed; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>will, in carrying on that activity, make adequate provision for the protection of the environment, the health and safety of persons and the maintenance of national security and measures required to implement international obligations to which Canada has agreed.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Subsection (1) does not apply in respect of an application for a licence to import or export for which the information requirements are prescribed by the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Nuclear Non-Proliferation Import and Export Control Regulations</XRefExternal>, or in respect of an application for a licence to transport while in transit for which the information requirements are prescribed by the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Packaging and Transport of Nuclear Substances Regulations, 2015</XRefExternal>.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2008-119, s. 2; SOR/2015-145, s. 43.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Application for Licence to Abandon</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>An application for a licence to abandon a nuclear substance, a nuclear facility, prescribed equipment or prescribed information shall contain the following information in addition to the information required by section 3:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the name and location of the land, buildings, structures, components and equipment that are to be abandoned;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the proposed time and location of the abandonment;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the proposed method of and procedure for abandonment; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the effects on the environment and the health and safety of persons that may result from the abandonment, and the measures that will be taken to prevent or mitigate those effects.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Application for Renewal of Licence</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>An application for the renewal of a licence shall contain</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the information required to be contained in an application for that licence by the applicable regulations made under the Act; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a statement identifying the changes in the information that was previously submitted.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Application for Amendment, Revocation or Replacement of Licence</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>An application for the amendment, revocation or replacement of a licence shall contain the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a description of the amendment, revocation or replacement and of the measures that will be taken and the methods and procedures that will be used to implement it;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a statement identifying the changes in the information contained in the most recent application for the licence;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a description of the nuclear substances, land, areas, buildings, structures, components, equipment and systems that will be affected by the amendment, revocation or replacement and of the manner in which they will be affected; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the proposed starting date and the expected completion date of any modification encompassed by the application.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Incorporation of Material in Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>7</Label><Text>An application for a licence or for the renewal, suspension in whole or in part, amendment, revocation or replacement of a licence may incorporate by reference any information that is included in a valid, expired or revoked licence.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Renewal, Suspension, Amendment, Revocation or Replacement of Licence on Commission’s Own Motion</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>8</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>For the purpose of section 25 of the Act, the Commission may renew a licence on its own motion if failure to renew the licence could pose an unreasonable risk to the environment, the health and safety of persons or national security.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>For the purpose of section 25 of the Act, the Commission may, on its own motion, suspend in whole or in part, amend, revoke or replace a licence under any of the following conditions:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the licensee is not qualified to carry on the licensed activity;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the licensed activity poses an unreasonable risk to the environment, the health and safety of persons or the maintenance of national security;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the licensee has failed to comply with the Act, the regulations made under the Act or the licence;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the licensee has been convicted of an offence under the Act;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>a record referred to in the licence has been modified in a manner not permitted by the licence;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>the licensee no longer carries on the licensed activity;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>the licensee has not paid the licence fee prescribed by the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Cost Recovery Fees Regulations</XRefExternal>; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>failure to do so could pose an unreasonable risk to the environment, the health and safety of persons or national security.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2007-208, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Exemptions</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Exemptions from Licence Requirement for Inspectors, Designated Officers and Peace Officers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>9</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>An inspector, a designated officer or a peace officer may carry on any of the following activities without a licence to carry on that activity if the activity is carried on by that person to enforce the Act or the regulations made under the Act:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>possess, transfer, transport or store a nuclear substance; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>possess or transfer prescribed equipment or prescribed information.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>An inspector or a designated officer may service prescribed equipment without a licence to carry on that activity if the servicing is carried on by that person to enforce the Act or the regulations made under the Act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>For greater certainty, the exemptions established in subsections (1) and (2) relate only to the activities specified in those subsections and do not derogate from the licence requirement imposed by section 26 of the Act in relation to other activities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Every person who carries on an activity without a licence in accordance with subsection (1) or (2) shall immediately notify the Commission of that fact.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Exemption of Naturally Occurring Nuclear Substances</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>10</Label><Text>Naturally occurring nuclear substances, other than those that are or have been associated with the development, production or use of nuclear energy, are exempt from the application of all provisions of the Act and the regulations made under the Act except the following:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the provisions that govern the transport of nuclear substances;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the case of a nuclear substance listed in the schedule to the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Nuclear Non-proliferation Import and Export Control Regulations</XRefExternal>, the provisions that govern the import and export of nuclear substances.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2003-405, s. 1; SOR/2015-145, s. 44.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Exemption by the Commission</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>11</Label><Text>For the purpose of section 7 of the Act, the Commission may grant an exemption if doing so will not</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>pose an unreasonable risk to the environment or the health and safety of persons;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>pose an unreasonable risk to national security; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>result in a failure to achieve conformity with measures of control and international obligations to which Canada has agreed.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Obligations</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Obligations of Licensees</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>12</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Every licensee shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>ensure the presence of a sufficient number of qualified workers to carry on the licensed activity safely and in accordance with the Act, the regulations made under the Act and the licence;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>train the workers to carry on the licensed activity in accordance with the Act, the regulations made under the Act and the licence;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>take all reasonable precautions to protect the environment and the health and safety of persons and to maintain the security of nuclear facilities and of nuclear substances;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>provide the devices required by the Act, the regulations made under the Act and the licence and maintain them within the manufacturer’s specifications;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>require that every person at the site of the licensed activity use equipment, devices, clothing and procedures in accordance with the Act, the regulations made under the Act and the licence;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>take all reasonable precautions to control the release of radioactive nuclear substances or hazardous substances within the site of the licensed activity and into the environment as a result of the licensed activity;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>implement measures for alerting the licensee to the illegal use or removal of a nuclear substance, prescribed equipment or prescribed information, or the illegal use of a nuclear facility;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>implement measures for alerting the licensee to acts of sabotage or attempted sabotage anywhere at the site of the licensed activity;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>take all necessary measures to facilitate Canada’s compliance with any applicable safeguards agreement;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(j)</Label><Text>instruct the workers on the physical security program at the site of the licensed activity and on their obligations under that program; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(k)</Label><Text>keep a copy of the Act and the regulations made under the Act that apply to the licensed activity readily available for consultation by the workers.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Every licensee who receives a request from the Commission or a person who is authorized by the Commission for the purpose of this subsection, to conduct a test, analysis, inventory or inspection in respect of the licensed activity or to review or to modify a design, to modify equipment, to modify procedures or to install a new system or new equipment shall file, within the time specified in the request, a report with the Commission that contains the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>confirmation that the request will or will not be carried out or will be carried out in part;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any action that the licensee has taken to carry out the request or any part of it;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>any reasons why the request or any part of it will not be carried out;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>any proposed alternative means to achieve the objectives of the request; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>any proposed alternative period within which the licensee proposes to carry out the request.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2007-208, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Transfers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>13</Label><Text>No licensee shall transfer a nuclear substance, prescribed equipment or prescribed information to a person who does not hold the licence, if any, that is required to possess the nuclear substance, prescribed equipment or prescribed information by the Act and the regulations made under the Act.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Notice of Licence</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>14</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Every licensee other than a licensee who is conducting field operations shall post, at the location specified in the licence or, if no location is specified in the licence, in a conspicuous place at the site of the licensed activity,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a copy of the licence, with or without the licence number, and a notice indicating the place where any record referred to in the licence may be consulted; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a notice containing</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the name of the licensee,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>a description of the licensed activity,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>a description of the nuclear substance, nuclear facility or prescribed equipment encompassed by the licence, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>a statement of the location of the licence and any record referred to in it.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Every licensee who is conducting field operations shall keep a copy of the licence at the place where the field operations are being conducted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Subsections (1) and (2) do not apply to a licensee in respect of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a licence to import or export a nuclear substance, prescribed equipment or prescribed information;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a licence to transport a nuclear substance; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a licence to abandon a nuclear substance, a nuclear facility, prescribed equipment or prescribed information.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Representatives of Applicants and Licensees</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>15</Label><Text>Every applicant for a licence and every licensee shall notify the Commission of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the persons who have authority to act for them in their dealings with the Commission;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the names and position titles of the persons who are responsible for the management and control of the licensed activity and the nuclear substance, nuclear facility, prescribed equipment or prescribed information encompassed by the licence; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>any change in the information referred to in paragraphs (a) and (b), within 15 days after the change occurs.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Publication of Health and Safety Information</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>16</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Every licensee shall make available to all workers the health and safety information with respect to their workplace that has been collected by the licensee in accordance with the Act, the regulations made under the Act and the licence.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Subsection (1) does not apply in respect of personal dose records and prescribed information.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Obligations of Workers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>17</Label><Text>Every worker shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>use equipment, devices, facilities and clothing for protecting the environment or the health and safety of persons, or for determining doses of radiation, dose rates or concentrations of radioactive nuclear substances, in a responsible and reasonable manner and in accordance with the Act, the regulations made under the Act and the licence;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>comply with the measures established by the licensee to protect the environment and the health and safety of persons, maintain security, control the levels and doses of radiation, and control releases of radioactive nuclear substances and hazardous substances into the environment;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>promptly inform the licensee or the worker’s supervisor of any situation in which the worker believes there may be</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>a significant increase in the risk to the environment or the health and safety of persons,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>a threat to the maintenance of the security of nuclear facilities and of nuclear substances or an incident with respect to such security,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>a failure to comply with the Act, the regulations made under the Act or the licence,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>an act of sabotage, theft, loss or illegal use or possession of a nuclear substance, prescribed equipment or prescribed information, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(v)</Label><Text>a release into the environment of a quantity of a radioactive nuclear substance or hazardous substance that has not been authorized by the licensee;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>observe and obey all notices and warning signs posted by the licensee in accordance with the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Radiation Protection Regulations</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>take all reasonable precautions to ensure the worker’s own safety, the safety of the other persons at the site of the licensed activity, the protection of the environment, the protection of the public and the maintenance of the security of nuclear facilities and of nuclear substances.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2007-208, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Presentation of Licence to Customs Officer</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>18</Label><Text>On importing or exporting a nuclear substance, prescribed equipment or prescribed information, the licensee shall present the required import or export licence to a customs officer.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Prescribed Nuclear Facilities</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>19</Label><Text>The following facilities are prescribed as nuclear facilities for the purpose of paragraph (i) of the definition <DefinedTermEn>nuclear facility</DefinedTermEn> in section 2 of the Act:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a facility for the management, storage or disposal of waste containing radioactive nuclear substances at which the resident inventory of radioactive nuclear substances contained in the waste is 10<Sup>15</Sup> Bq or more;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a plant for the production of deuterium or deuterium compounds using hydrogen sulphide; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a Class II nuclear facility, as defined in section 1 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Class II Nuclear Facilities and Prescribed Equipment Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2008-119, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Prescribed Equipment</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>20</Label><Text>Each of the following items is prescribed equipment for the purposes of the Act:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a package, special form radioactive material, low dispersible radioactive material, fissile-excepted radioactive material, radioactive material that has a basic radionuclide value that is not listed in the IAEA Regulations and an instrument or article that has an alternative activity limit for an exempt consignment, as those terms are defined in subsection 1(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Packaging and Transport of Nuclear Substances Regulations, 2015</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a radiation device and a sealed source, as defined in section 1 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Nuclear Substances and Radiation Devices Regulations</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>Class II prescribed equipment, as defined in section 1 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Class II Nuclear Facilities and Prescribed Equipment Regulations</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>equipment that is capable of being used in the design, production, operation or maintenance of a nuclear weapon or nuclear explosive device.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2003-405, s. 2; SOR/2015-145, s. 45.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Prescribed Information</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Prescription</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>21</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Information that concerns any of the following, including a record of that information, is prescribed information for the purposes of the Act:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a nuclear substance that is required for the design, production, use, operation or maintenance of a nuclear weapon or nuclear explosive device, including the properties of the nuclear substance;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the design, production, use, operation or maintenance of a nuclear weapon or nuclear explosive device;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the security arrangements, security equipment, security systems and security procedures established by a licensee in accordance with the Act, the regulations made under the Act or the licence, and any incident relating to security; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the route or schedule for the transport of Category I, II or III nuclear material, as defined in section 1 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Nuclear Security Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Information that is made public in accordance with the Act, the regulations made under the Act or a licence is not prescribed information for the purposes of the Act.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2007-208, s. 4(E).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Exemptions from Licence Requirement</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>22</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The following persons may possess, transfer, import, export or use prescribed information without a licence to carry on that activity:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a minister, employee or other person acting on behalf of or under the direction of the Government of Canada, the government of a province or any of their agencies, for the purpose of assisting themselves in exercising a power or performing a duty or function lawfully conferred or imposed on them; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>an official of a foreign government or an international agency, for the purpose of meeting obligations imposed by an arrangement made between the Government of Canada and the foreign government or international agency.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The following persons may possess, transfer or use prescribed information without a licence to carry on that activity:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a worker, for the purpose of enabling the worker to perform duties assigned by the licensee; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a person who is legally required or legally authorized to obtain or receive the information.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>For greater certainty, the exemptions established in subsections (1) and (2) relate only to the activities specified in those subsections and do not derogate from the licence requirement imposed by section 26 of the Act in relation to other activities.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Transfer and Disclosure</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>23</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>No person shall transfer or disclose prescribed information unless the person</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>is legally required to do so; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>transfers or discloses it to</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>a minister, employee or other person acting on behalf or under the direction of the Government of Canada, the government of a province or any of their agencies, for the purpose of assisting themselves in exercising a power or performing a duty or function lawfully conferred or imposed on them,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>an official of a foreign government or an international agency, for the purpose of meeting obligations imposed by an arrangement made between the Government of Canada and the foreign government or international agency,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>a worker, for the purpose of enabling the worker to perform duties assigned by the licensee, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>a person who is legally required or legally authorized to obtain or receive the information.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A person who possesses or has knowledge of prescribed information shall take all necessary precautions to prevent any transfer or disclosure of the prescribed information that is not authorized by the Act and the regulations made under the Act.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Contamination</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Prescribed Limits</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>24</Label><Text>For the purposes of paragraph 45(a) and subsection 46(1) of the Act, the prescribed limit of contamination for a place or vehicle where no licensed activity is being carried on is any quantity of a radioactive nuclear substance that may, based on the circumstances, increase a person’s effective dose by 1 mSv or more per year in excess of the background radiation for the place or vehicle.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Prescribed Public Offices</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>25</Label><Text>For the purpose of subsection 46(2) of the Act, a municipal office, a public library and a public community centre are prescribed public offices.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Prescribed Measures</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>26</Label><Text>For the purpose of subsection 46(3) of the Act, the prescribed measures to reduce the level of contamination are any measures to control access to or clean the place, or to cover or remove the contamination, that are appropriate for the substance and location and that will reduce the level of contamination to below the limit prescribed by section 24.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Records and Reports</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Record of Licence Information</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>27</Label><Text>Every licensee shall keep a record of all information relating to the licence that is submitted by the licensee to the Commission.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Retention and Disposal of Records</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>28</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Every person who is required to keep a record by the Act, the regulations made under the Act or a licence shall retain the record for the period specified in the applicable regulations made under the Act or, if no period is specified in the regulations, for the period ending one year after the expiry of the licence that authorizes the activity in respect of which the records are kept.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>No person shall dispose of a record referred to in the Act, the regulations made under the Act or a licence unless the person</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>is no longer required to keep the record by the Act, the regulations made under the Act or the licence; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>has notified the Commission of the date of disposal and of the nature of the record at least 90 days before the date of disposal.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>A person who notifies the Commission in accordance with subsection (2) shall file the record, or a copy of the record, with the Commission at its request.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>General Reports</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>29</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Every licensee who becomes aware of any of the following situations shall immediately make a preliminary report to the Commission of the location and circumstances of the situation and of any action that the licensee has taken or proposes to take with respect to it:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a situation referred to in paragraph 27(b) of the Act;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the occurrence of an event that is likely to result in the exposure of persons to radiation in excess of the applicable radiation dose limits prescribed by the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Radiation Protection Regulations</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a release, not authorized by the licence, of a quantity of radioactive nuclear substance into the environment;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a situation or event that requires the implementation of a contingency plan in accordance with the licence;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>an attempted or actual breach of security or an attempted or actual act of sabotage at the site of the licensed activity;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>information that reveals the incipient failure, abnormal degradation or weakening of any component or system at the site of the licensed activity, the failure of which could have a serious adverse effect on the environment or constitutes or is likely to constitute or contribute to a serious risk to the health and safety of persons or the maintenance of security;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>an actual, threatened or planned work disruption by workers;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>a serious illness or injury incurred or possibly incurred as a result of the licensed activity;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the death of any person at a nuclear facility; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(j)</Label><Text>the occurrence of any of the following events:</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the making of an assignment by or in respect of the licensee under the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Bankruptcy and Insolvency Act</XRefExternal>,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the making of a proposal by or in respect of the licensee under the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Bankruptcy and Insolvency Act</XRefExternal>,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>the filing of a notice of intention by the licensee under the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Bankruptcy and Insolvency Act</XRefExternal>,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>the filing of a petition for a receiving order against the licensee under the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Bankruptcy and Insolvency Act</XRefExternal>,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(v)</Label><Text>the enforcement by a secured creditor of a security on all or substantially all of the inventory, accounts receivable or other property of the licensee that was acquired for, or used in relation to, a business carried on by the licensee,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(vi)</Label><Text>the filing in court by the licensee of an application to propose a compromise or an arrangement with its unsecured creditors or any class of them under section 4 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Companies’ Creditors Arrangement Act</XRefExternal>,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(vii)</Label><Text>the filing in court by the licensee of an application to propose a compromise or an arrangement with its secured creditors or any class of them under section 5 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Companies’ Creditors Arrangement Act</XRefExternal>,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(viii)</Label><Text>the making of an application for a winding-up order by or in respect of the licensee under the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Winding-up and Restructuring Act</XRefExternal>,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ix)</Label><Text>the making of a liquidation, bankruptcy, insolvency, reorganization or like order in respect of the licensee under provincial or foreign legislation, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(x)</Label><Text>the making of a liquidation, bankruptcy, insolvency, reorganization or like order in respect of a body corporate that controls the licensee under provincial or foreign legislation.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Every licensee who becomes aware of a situation referred to in subsection (1) shall file a full report of the situation with the Commission within 21 days after becoming aware of it, unless some other period is specified in the licence, and the report shall contain the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the date, time and location of becoming aware of the situation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a description of the situation and the circumstances;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the probable cause of the situation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the effects on the environment, the health and safety of persons and the maintenance of security that have resulted or may result from the situation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the effective dose and equivalent dose of radiation received by any person as a result of the situation; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>the actions that the licensee has taken or proposes to take with respect to the situation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Subsections (1) and (2) do not require a licensee to report a situation referred to in paragraphs (1)(a) to (j) if the licence contains a term or condition requiring the licensee to report that situation, or any situation of that nature, to the Commission.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Safeguards Reports</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>30</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Every licensee who becomes aware of any of the following situations shall immediately make a preliminary report to the Commission of the situation and of any action that the licensee has taken or proposes to take with respect to it:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>interference with or an interruption in the operation of safeguards equipment or the alteration, defacement or breakage of a safeguards seal, other than in accordance with the safeguards agreement, the Act, the regulations made under the Act or the licence; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the theft, loss or sabotage of safeguards equipment or samples collected for the purpose of a safeguards inspection, damage to such equipment or samples, or the illegal use, possession, operation or removal of such equipment or samples.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Every licensee who becomes aware of a situation referred to in subsection (1) shall file a full report of the situation with the Commission within 21 days after becoming aware of it, unless some other period is specified in the licence, and the report shall contain the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the date, time and location of becoming aware of the situation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a description of the situation and the circumstances;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the probable cause of the situation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the adverse effects on the environment, the health and safety of persons and the maintenance of national and international security that have resulted or may result from the situation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the effective dose and equivalent dose of radiation received by any person as a result of the situation; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>the actions that the licensee has taken or proposes to take with respect to the situation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Report of Deficiency in Record</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>31</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Every licensee who becomes aware of an inaccuracy or incompleteness in a record that the licensee is required to keep by the Act, the regulations made under the Act or the licence shall file a report of the inaccuracy or incompleteness with the Commission within 21 days after becoming aware of it, and the report shall contain the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the details of the inaccuracy or incompleteness; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any action that the licensee has taken or proposes to take with respect to the inaccuracy or incompleteness.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Subsection (1) does not apply to a licensee if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the licence contains a term or condition that requires the licensee to report inaccuracies or incompleteness in a record to the Commission; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the inaccuracy or incompleteness in the record could not reasonably be expected to lead to a situation in which the environment, the health and safety of persons or national security is adversely affected.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Filing of Reports</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>32</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Every report shall include the name and address of its sender and the date on which it was completed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The date of filing of a report is the date on which it is received by the Commission.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Inspectors and Designated Officers</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Certificate of Inspector</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>33</Label><Text>An inspector’s certificate issued under section 29 of the Act shall be in the form set out in the schedule and shall include, in addition to the information required by subsection 29(2) of the Act,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the name and signature of the inspector;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a photograph showing the face of the inspector;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the name of the employer of the inspector;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a statement of designation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the name, position and signature of the person who issued the certificate; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>the expiry date of the certificate.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Certificate of Designated Officer</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>34</Label><Text>A designated officer’s certificate issued under section 37 of the Act shall include, in addition to the information required by subsection 37(1) of the Act,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the name and position or title of the designated officer;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the name of the employer of the designated officer;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a statement of designation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the name, position and signature of the person who issued the certificate; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the expiry date of the certificate.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Notification and Surrender of Certificate</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>35</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>An inspector and a designated officer shall notify the Commission of any of the following situations:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the loss or theft of their certificate;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any change in their employment that results in their no longer exercising a function that relates to the purpose of the certificate; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the suspension or termination of their employment with the employer named in the certificate.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>An inspector and a designated officer shall surrender their certificate to the Commission</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>if the information contained in the certificate is not accurate;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>when the certificate expires; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>on termination by the Commission of their designation as an inspector or a designated officer, as the case may be.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Repeal</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>36</Label><Text>[Repeal]</Text></Section><Section><Label>37</Label><Text>[Repeal]</Text></Section><Section><Label>38</Label><Text>[Repeal]</Text></Section><Section><Label>39</Label><Text>[Repeal]</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section type="transitional"><Label>40</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on the day on which they are approved by the Governor in Council.</Text></Section></Body><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="yes"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE / <Language xml:lang="fr">ANNEXE</Language></Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 33 / <Language xml:lang="fr">article 33</Language>)</OriginatingRef><TitleText>Certificate of Inspector / Certificat de l’inspecteur</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><ImageGroup bilingual="yes" position="center" width="43pc"><AlternateText>Certificate of Inspector form</AlternateText><Image source="SOR-2000-202img\SOR-2000-202_ef001.jpg" /></ImageGroup></Schedule></Regulation>