<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en" in-force="yes"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2017-9</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2017</YYYY><MM>2</MM><DD>3</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2017</YYYY><MM>2</MM><DD>22</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">PEST CONTROL PRODUCTS ACT</XRefExternal><XRefExternal reference-type="act">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Pest Control Products Fees and Charges Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2017-79</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>2017</YYYY><MM>2</MM><DD>3</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Health and the Treasury Board, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Pest Control Products Fees and Charges Regulations</XRefExternal> pursuant to</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>section 67 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Pest Control Products Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-2017-9_e_hq_19682">a</FootnoteRef>, with respect to sections <XRefInternal>1</XRefInternal> to <XRefInternal>9</XRefInternal> and <XRefInternal>11</XRefInternal>; and</Text><Footnote id="fn_SOR-2017-9_e_hq_19682" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 2002, c. 28</Text></Footnote></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>section 67 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Pest Control Products Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-2017-9_e_hq_19682">a</FootnoteRef> and paragraph 19(1)(a)<FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-2017-9_e_hq_19683">b</FootnoteRef> and section 19.1<FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-2017-9_e_hq_19683">b</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Financial Administration Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-2017-9_e_hq_19684">c</FootnoteRef>, with respect to section <XRefInternal>10</XRefInternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fn_SOR-2017-9_e_hq_19683" placement="page" status="official"><Label>b</Label><Text>S.C. 1991, c. 24, s. 6</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="fn_SOR-2017-9_e_hq_19684" placement="page" status="official"><Label>c</Label><Text>R.S., c. F-11</Text></Footnote></Provision></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 1</Label><TitleText>Fees for the Examination of an Application in Respect of a Pest Control Product</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Non-Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Section 2</MarginalNote><Label>1</Label><Text>Section <XRefInternal>2</XRefInternal> does not apply in respect of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>an application filed by a user of a pest control product or by a user group, to amend the registration of the pest control product by adding a minor use of the product to the label, and that meets the following criteria:</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>some of the information that is required to accompany the application is generated either by the applicant or for the applicant by another person who is not the registrant, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the application is accompanied by a statement by the registrant that they agree to add the new use to the label of the pest control product if the application is approved;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a request for a determination of equivalency made under section 38 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Pest Control Products Regulations</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>an application for an authorization to use a foreign product under subsection 41(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Pest Control Products Regulations</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>except in the case of a type of application set out in Schedule 2 or 3, an application to register, or to amend the registration of, a pest control product whose active ingredient is</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>an organism that is not a microbial agent, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>any of the following substances referred to in the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Food and Drug Regulations</XRefExternal>:</Text><Clause><Label>(A)</Label><Text>a food additive that is set out in a list in accordance with a marketing authorization issued by the Minister under subsection 30.3(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Food and Drugs Act</XRefExternal>,</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(B)</Label><Text>a nutritive substance that is used, recognized or commonly sold as food or as an ingredient of food,</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(C)</Label><Text>a vitamin, mineral nutrient or amino acid,</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(D)</Label><Text>a flavouring preparation, natural extractive, oleoresin, seasoning or spice,</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(E)</Label><Text>a food packaging material or any substance of which such a material is composed, or</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(F)</Label><Text>a drug for veterinary use in animals that may be used as food for human consumption.</Text></Clause></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Fees</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Registration or amendment — Schedule 1</MarginalNote><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The fee for the examination by the Minister of an application to register a pest control product — other than a type of application set out in Schedule 2 or 3 — or to amend such a registration that includes a component set out in column 1 of Schedule 1 is the fee set out in column 2.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>More than one component — Schedule 1</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>If an application referred to in subsection (1) includes more than one component set out in column 1 of Schedule 1, the fee is the sum of the applicable fees set out in column 2 for all of the included components.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Semiochemicals and microbial agents — Schedule 2</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The fee for the examination by the Minister of an application in respect of a pest control product that is a semiochemical or microbial agent for each type of application set out in column 1 of Schedule 2 is the fee set out in column 2.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Applications filed together — Schedule 2</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>If more than one type of application set out in column 1 of Schedule 2 is filed in respect of the same pest control product at the same time, the fee for the examination by the Minister is the highest of the applicable fees set out in column 2 in respect of those applications.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Other applications — Schedule 3</MarginalNote><Label>(5)</Label><Text>The fee for the examination by the Minister of an application in respect of a pest control product for each type of application set out in column 1 of Schedule 3 is the fee set out in column 2.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Applications filed together — Schedule 3</MarginalNote><Label>(6)</Label><Text>If more than one type of application set out in column 1 of Schedule 3 is filed in respect of the same pest control product at the same time, the fee for the examination by the Minister is the highest of the applicable fees set out in column 2 in respect of those applications.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Processing</MarginalNote><Label>3</Label><Text>The fee for the processing by the Minister of any of the following applications, other than an application to renew a registration, is $1,133:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>an application in respect of a pest control product that is described in paragraph <XRefInternal>1</XRefInternal>(d);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>an application that includes a component set out in column 1 of Schedule 1; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>an application in respect of a pest control product that does not include any component set out in Schedule 1, that is not mentioned in Schedule 2 or 3 and for which no information other than what is already available to the Minister is required to conduct an evaluation.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Applications not mentioned in schedules</MarginalNote><Label>4</Label><Text>The fee for the examination by the Minister of an application in respect of a pest control product, other than an application to renew a registration, that does not include any component set out in Schedule 1, that is not mentioned in Schedule 2 or 3 and that does not require an evaluation is $247.</Text></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Renewal</MarginalNote><Label>5</Label><Text>The fee for the examination by the Minister of an application to renew the registration of a pest control product is $80.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Annual Adjustment of Fees</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Fee adjustment</MarginalNote><Label>6</Label><Text>Every fee set out in this Part is to be increased on April 1 of each year by 2%, rounded up to the nearest dollar.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Timing of Payment</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Meaning of <DefinitionRef>preliminary review</DefinitionRef></MarginalNote><Label>7</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>In this section, <DefinedTermEn>preliminary review</DefinedTermEn> means a review by the Minister of the information that is submitted with an application to determine whether the information is sufficient to enable the Minister to conduct an evaluation of the pest control product.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Payment — $2,500 or less</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>If the total fee for an application under this Part is $2,500 or less, it must be paid when the application is filed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Payment — more than $2,500</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>With the exception of fees for applications made in respect of paragraphs 1(a), 1(b), and 3(a) of Schedule 3, which must be paid in full at the time the application is filed, when the total fee for an application under this Part is more than $2,500,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>10% must be paid when the application is filed;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>25% is payable on receipt of a notice from the Minister that the application has been accepted for a preliminary review; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>65% is payable on receipt of a notice from the Minister that the application has been accepted for evaluation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Preliminary review and evaluation</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The preliminary review and the evaluation begin on receipt of the relevant payments.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Fee Reduction</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Definitions</MarginalNote><Label>8</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The following definitions apply in this section.</Text><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>actual gross revenue</DefinedTermEn> means the amount that the person who makes an application to register a pest control product referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>2</XRefInternal>(1) collects during the fee verification period from the sales in Canada of that product. (<DefinedTermFr>recettes brutes réelles</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>anticipated gross revenue</DefinedTermEn> means the amount that the person who makes an application to register a pest control product referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>2</XRefInternal>(1) expects to collect during the fee verification period from the sales in Canada of that product. (<DefinedTermFr>recettes brutes prévues</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>fee verification period</DefinedTermEn>, in respect of a pest control product for which an application for a fee reduction is approved under subsection (3), means the period that begins on the day on which the pest control product is first sold in Canada as a registered pest control product or as an active ingredient in a registered pest control product and that ends three years after that day. (<DefinedTermFr>période de vérification des droits</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>sales in Canada</DefinedTermEn> means</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in the case of an application to register an active ingredient, the sales in Canada of all pest control products that contain that active ingredient and that became registered during the fee verification period;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the case of an application to register a pest control product that is not an active ingredient, the sales in Canada of that product during the fee verification period; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>in the case of more than one application that includes a common component set out in Schedule 1 and that is filed at the same time to register pest control products that contain the same active ingredient, the sales in Canada of those pest control products during the fee verification period. (<DefinedTermFr>ventes au Canada</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Application for fee reduction</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A person who files an application to register a pest control product referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>2</XRefInternal>(1) may apply at the same time to the Minister for a reduction of the fee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Conditions</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The Minister must approve a fee reduction if the following conditions are met:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the person provides to the Minister with their application</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>a statement signed by an individual who is designated by the person for the purpose that indicates the person’s anticipated gross revenue and that certifies that the fee is greater than 10% of that anticipated gross revenue, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>information that establishes that that fee is greater than 10% of the person’s anticipated gross revenue; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the Minister determines, on the basis of the information provided under paragraph (a) and any other information that is available to the Minister, that the fee is likely to be greater than 10% of the person’s actual gross revenue.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Recalculation of fee</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>If the Minister approves a fee reduction, the fee that is payable at the end of the fee verification period is the lesser of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the total fee payable under this Part, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the higher of</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>10% of the fee referred to in paragraph (a), and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>10% of the actual gross revenue, based on the records of the sales in Canada provided to the Minister in accordance with subsection (6).</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Payment when application is filed</MarginalNote><Label>(5)</Label><Text>A person who applies for a fee reduction under subsection (2) must, at the time of filing the application, pay, in accordance with subsection <XRefInternal>7</XRefInternal>(2) or (3), the higher of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>10% of their anticipated gross revenue, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>10% of the total fee payable under this Part.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Records of sales in Canada</MarginalNote><Label>(6)</Label><Text>Within 60 days after the end of the fee verification period, the person must provide the Minister with the records of the sales in Canada, prepared in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles and certified by the individual responsible for the person’s financial affairs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Reconciliation — balance owing</MarginalNote><Label>(7)</Label><Text>If the records of the sales in Canada establish that the amount that the person paid under subsection (5) is less than the amount of the fee calculated in accordance with subsection (4), the person must pay the balance within 60 days after the day on which the fee verification period ends.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Reconciliation — overpayment</MarginalNote><Label>(8)</Label><Text>If the records of the sales in Canada establish that the amount that the person paid under subsection (5) is more than the amount of the fee calculated in accordance with subsection (4), the Minister must repay the amount of the overpayment to the person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Audited records</MarginalNote><Label>(9)</Label><Text>If the Minister determines, on the basis of any information that is available to him or her, that the certified records of the sales in Canada are not adequate to determine the person’s actual gross revenue, the Minister may require that the person provide records of the sales in Canada that have been audited by a qualified independent auditor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>When records inconsistent</MarginalNote><Label>(10)</Label><Text>If there is any inconsistency between the certified records and the audited records, the fee is to be based on whichever records show the higher amount of sales in Canada.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>When records not submitted</MarginalNote><Label>(11)</Label><Text>If the person does not submit the records in accordance with subsections (6) and (9), the fee payable is the total fee calculated under subsections <XRefInternal>2</XRefInternal>(1) and (2) and section <XRefInternal>3</XRefInternal>, minus any portion of the fee that the person paid under subsection (5).</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 2</Label><TitleText>Annual Charge</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Payable annually</MarginalNote><Label>9</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A registrant must pay each year, in respect of every pest control product that is registered in their name on April 1 of the year, an annual charge that is the lesser of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>$3,600, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>4% of the actual gross revenue during the registrant’s preceding fiscal year, but not less than $100.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Timing of payment</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The annual charge is payable</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>on receipt of a notice from the Minister requiring payment; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in four equal quarterly payments, the first of which is payable on receipt of a notice from the Minister requiring payment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Certified records</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>When the annual charge is paid under paragraph (1)(b), the registrant must, when paying it in full or when making the first quarterly instalment, provide the Minister with the records of the sales in Canada for the fiscal year referred to in that paragraph, prepared in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles and certified by the individual responsible for the registrant’s financial affairs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Audited records</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>If the Minister determines, on the basis of any information available to him or her, that the certified records are not adequate to calculate the annual charge, the Minister may require that the registrant provide records of the sales in Canada that have been audited by a qualified independent auditor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>When records inconsistent</MarginalNote><Label>(5)</Label><Text>If there is any inconsistency between the certified records and the audited records, the calculation of the annual charge is to be based on whichever records show the higher amount of sales in Canada.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>When records not submitted</MarginalNote><Label>(6)</Label><Text>If the registrant does not submit the records in accordance with subsections (3) and (4), the annual charge that is payable by the registrant is $3,600.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 3</Label><TitleText>Repeal and Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Repeal</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>10</Label><Text>[Repeal]</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section type="transitional"><MarginalNote>Registration</MarginalNote><Label>11</Label><Subsection type="transitional"><Label>(1)</Label><Text>These Regulations, except section <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>, come into force on the day on which they are registered or on April 1, 2017, whichever is later.</Text></Subsection><Subsection type="transitional"><MarginalNote>Section <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal></MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Section <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal> comes into force on April 1 of the year after the year in which these Regulations are registered.</Text></Subsection></Section></Body><Schedule><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 1</Label><OriginatingRef>(Subsections <XRefInternal>2</XRefInternal>(1) and (2), paragraphs <XRefInternal>3</XRefInternal>(b) and (c), section <XRefInternal>4</XRefInternal> and subsection <XRefInternal>8</XRefInternal>(1))</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><TableGroup pointsize="8" topmarginspacing="10"><table frame="topbot"><title>Fees for Applications to Register, or to Amend the Registration of, a Pest Control Product Other Than a Semiochemical or Microbial Agent</title><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="58.08*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="474.44*" /><colspec colname="3" colwidth="111.08*" /><thead><row topdouble="yes"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top" /><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 1</entry><entry align="right" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 2</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Item</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Component of Application</entry><entry align="right" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Fee ($)</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Product chemistry — active ingredient</entry><entry align="right" colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">4,873</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Product chemistry — end-use product or manufacturing concentrate</entry><entry align="right" colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2,713</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" morerows="2" rowsep="0" valign="top">3</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>Toxicology data accompanying an application to register a pest control product that consists of or that contains a new active ingredient</Text></Provision></entry><entry align="right" colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">75,807</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>Toxicology data accompanying an application to register a pest control product — or to amend the registration of a pest control product — that contains a registered active ingredient</Text></Provision></entry><entry align="right" colsep="0" rowsep="0">15,830</entry></row><row><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>Toxicology data — acute toxicity studies only</Text></Provision></entry><entry align="right" colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2,954</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" morerows="2" rowsep="0" valign="top">4</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>Exposure data accompanying an application to register a pest control product that consists of or that contains a new active ingredient</Text></Provision></entry><entry align="right" colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">17,498</entry></row><row><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>Exposure data accompanying an application to register a pest control product — or to amend the registration of a pest control product — that contains a registered active ingredient, when a new risk assessment is necessary</Text></Provision></entry><entry align="right" colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">5,758</entry></row><row><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>Exposure data — other</Text></Provision></entry><entry align="right" colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">5,214</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">5</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Metabolism data</entry><entry align="right" colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">28,943</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">6</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Residue data</entry><entry align="right" colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">15,838</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" morerows="2" rowsep="0" valign="top">7</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>Environmental fate data accompanying an application to register a pest control product that consists of or that contains a new active ingredient</Text></Provision></entry><entry align="right" colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">42,685</entry></row><row><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>Environmental fate data accompanying an application to register a pest control product — or to amend the registration of a pest control product — that contains a registered active ingredient, when a new risk assessment is necessary</Text></Provision></entry><entry align="right" colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">23,637</entry></row><row><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>Environmental fate data — other</Text></Provision></entry><entry align="right" colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">11,546</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" morerows="2" rowsep="0" valign="top">8</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>Environmental toxicology data accompanying an application to register a pest control product that consists of or that contains a new active ingredient</Text></Provision></entry><entry align="right" colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">37,277</entry></row><row><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>Environmental toxicology data accompanying an application to register a pest control product — or to amend the registration of a pest control product — that contains a registered active ingredient, when a new risk assessment is necessary</Text></Provision></entry><entry align="right" colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">23,690</entry></row><row><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>Environmental toxicology data — other</Text></Provision></entry><entry align="right" colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2,465</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">9</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Value and effectiveness data for a pest control product</entry><entry align="right" colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">906</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">10</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Identification of compensable data</entry><entry align="right" colsep="0" rowsep="0">2,162</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Schedule><Schedule><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 2</Label><OriginatingRef>(Paragraph <XRefInternal>1</XRefInternal>(d), subsections <XRefInternal>2</XRefInternal>(1), (3) and (4), paragraph <XRefInternal>3</XRefInternal>(c) and section <XRefInternal>4</XRefInternal>)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><TableGroup pointsize="8" topmarginspacing="10"><table frame="topbot"><title>Fees for Applications in Respect of a Pest Control Product that is a Semiochemical or Microbial Agent</title><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="0.27*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="2.21*" /><colspec colname="3" colwidth="0.52*" /><thead><row topdouble="yes"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top" /><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 1</entry><entry align="right" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 2</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Item</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Type of Application</entry><entry align="right" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Fee ($)</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry colsep="0" nameend="3" namest="1" rowsep="0"><Emphasis style="bold">Semiochemicals, other than straight-chain lepidopteran pheromones, and microbial agents</Emphasis></entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Registration of a new active ingredient — food use</entry><entry align="right" colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">7,236</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Registration of a new active ingredient — non-food use</entry><entry align="right" colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">4,341</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">3</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Amendment of registration — new risk assessment necessary — environmental fate data, environmental toxicity data or exposure data</entry><entry align="right" colsep="0" rowsep="0">2,894</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">4</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Amendment of registration — data required, label changes</entry><entry align="right" colsep="0" rowsep="0">1,447</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">5</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Amendment of registration — data required, other</entry><entry align="right" colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1,158</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">6</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Amendment of registration — no data required</entry><entry align="right" colsep="0" rowsep="0">290</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" nameend="3" namest="1" rowsep="0"><Emphasis style="bold">Straight-chain lepidopteran pheromones</Emphasis></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">7</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Registration of new active ingredient</entry><entry align="right" colsep="0" rowsep="0">579</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">8</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Amendment of registration</entry><entry align="right" colsep="0" rowsep="0">290</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Schedule><Schedule><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 3</Label><OriginatingRef>(Paragraph <XRefInternal>1</XRefInternal>(d), subsections <XRefInternal>2</XRefInternal>(1), (5) and (6), paragraph <XRefInternal>3</XRefInternal>(c), section <XRefInternal>4</XRefInternal>, and subsection <XRefInternal>7</XRefInternal>(3))</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><TableGroup pointsize="8" topmarginspacing="10"><table frame="topbot"><title>Fees for Other Applications in Respect of a Pest Control Product</title><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="0.28*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="2.20*" /><colspec colname="3" colwidth="0.52*" /><thead><row topdouble="yes"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top" /><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 1</entry><entry align="right" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 2</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Item</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Type of Application</entry><entry align="right" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Fee ($)</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry colsep="0" morerows="3" rowsep="0" valign="top">1</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>Research authorization — major crops, other than research authorizations set out in paragraphs (c) and (d)</Text></Provision></entry><entry align="right" colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">5,080</entry></row><row><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>Research authorization — minor use crops, other than research authorizations set out in paragraphs (c) and (d)</Text></Provision></entry><entry align="right" colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">5,080</entry></row><row><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>Research authorization — microbial agents, semiochemicals and any substance listed in subparagraph <XRefInternal>1</XRefInternal>(d)(ii) of these Regulations</Text></Provision></entry><entry align="right" colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1,217</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(d)</Label><Text>Research authorization — greenhouse crops and non-agricultural uses</Text></Provision></entry><entry align="right" colsep="0" rowsep="0">1,217</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">2</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Research notification</entry><entry align="right" colsep="0" rowsep="0">247</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" morerows="1" rowsep="0">3</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>Registration of active ingredient to be used in pest control product manufactured only for export</Text></Provision></entry><entry align="right" colsep="0" rowsep="0">7,827</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>Amendment to registration of active ingredient used in pest control product manufactured only for export</Text></Provision></entry><entry align="right" colsep="0" rowsep="0">1,133</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" morerows="1" rowsep="0">4</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>Specification of maximum residue limit for a previously unexamined pest control product</Text></Provision></entry><entry align="right" colsep="0" rowsep="0">125,461</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>Specification of maximum residue limit for an unregistered use of a previously examined pest control product</Text></Provision></entry><entry align="right" colsep="0" rowsep="0">15,838</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Schedule></Regulation>