<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/93-384</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1993</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>16</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>25</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">FOREIGN MISSIONS AND INTERNATIONAL ORGANIZATIONS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Administrative and Technical Staff of the Embassy of the United States and Families Privileges and Immunities Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Extending the Privileges and Immunities of Members of the Administrative and Technical Staff of the Embassy of the United States, and Members of their Families, in Canada</LongTitle></Identification><Order><Provision language-align="yes" format-ref="indent-0-0" list-item="no"><Text>The Secretary of State for External Affairs, pursuant to subsection 4(1) of the Foreign Missions and International Organizations Act<FootnoteRef idref="footnote1_e">*</FootnoteRef>, hereby revokes the Administrative and Technical Staff of the Embassy of the United States of America Privileges and Immunities Order<FootnoteRef idref="footnote2_e">**</FootnoteRef>, made on December 15, 1992, and makes the annexed Order extending the privileges and immunities of members of the administrative and technical staff of the Embassy of the United States, and members of their families, in Canada, in substitution therefor.</Text><Footnote id="footnote1_e" placement="section" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>S.C. 1991, c. 41</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="footnote2_e" placement="section" status="official"><Label>**</Label><Text>Not published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal> Part II</Text></Footnote></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>Ottawa, July 14, 1993</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-5-5" list-item="no" language-align="no"><Text>PERRIN BEATTY</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-5-5" topmarginspacing="0" list-item="no" language-align="no"><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Secretary of State for External Affairs</Emphasis></Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Administrative and Technical Staff of the Embassy of the United States and Families Privileges and Immunities Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Privileges and Immunities</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (2), the privileges and immunities accorded to diplomatic agents under section 3 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Foreign Missions and International Organizations Act</XRefExternal>, other than duty and tax relief privileges, shall extend to the members of the administrative and technical staff of the Embassy of the United States, and to the members of their families forming part of their household, in Canada.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The privileges and immunities referred to in subsection (1) shall not extend to the members of the administrative and technical staff, or to the members of their families forming part of their households, who are nationals or permanent residents of Canada.</Text></Subsection></Section></Body></Regulation>