<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en" in-force="yes"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2006-337</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2006</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>12</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2007</YYYY><MM>1</MM><DD>30</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">LIBRARY AND ARCHIVES OF CANADA ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Legal Deposit of Publications Regulations</LongTitle></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>The Minister of Canadian Heritage, pursuant to subsection 10(2) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Library and Archives of Canada Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fna_e">a</FootnoteRef>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Legal Deposit of Publications Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fna_e" placement="page"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 2004, c. 11</Text></Footnote></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Gatineau, Quebec, December 11, 2006</Text></Provision><Provision><SignatureBlock justification="right" width="15pc"><SignatureName justification="left">Beverley J. Oda</SignatureName><SignatureTitle justification="left">Minister of Canadian Heritage</SignatureTitle></SignatureBlock></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>The following definitions apply in these Regulations.</Text><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Library and Archives of Canada Act</XRefExternal>. (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>publisher</DefinedTermEn> means a person who makes a publication available in Canada that the person is authorized to reproduce or over which the person controls the content. It does not include a person who only distributes a publication. (<DefinedTermFr>éditeur</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Deposit — Non-paper Publications</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In order to make a publication and its contents that uses a medium other than paper accessible to the Librarian and Archivist, the publisher shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>before providing a copy of the publication to the Librarian and Archivist,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>decrypt encrypted data contained in the publication, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>remove or disable security systems or devices that are designed to restrict or limit access to the publication; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>when providing a copy of the publication to the Librarian and Archivist,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>provide a copy of software specifically created by the publisher that is necessary to access the publication,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>provide a copy of technical or other information necessary to access the publication, including a copy of manuals that accompany the publication, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>provide any available descriptive data about the publication including its title, creator, language, date of publication, format, subject and copyright information.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Deposit — One Copy</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>The following classes of publications are those in respect of which, except where a publication is also in a class described in section 4, only one copy is required to be provided under section 10 of the Act:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>musical sound recordings;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>multi-media publications consisting of two or more physical parts in different formats;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>publications of which fewer than 100 copies have been produced;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>publications produced on demand from a master copy of which fewer than 100 copies have been produced; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>online publications.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Deposit on Request</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>The following classes of publications are those in respect of which the obligation to provide two copies under subsection 10(1) of the Act applies only on a written request from the Librarian and Archivist:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>publications, other than online publications, of which fewer than four copies have been produced;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>printed publications that are manufactured or distributed in Canada and that are not published under the imprint of a Canadian publisher;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>sound recordings that are manufactured or distributed in Canada and that have no Canadian content or major Canadian contributor such as a composer, artist, narrator, conductor, orchestra, performer, writer, lyricist or producer;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>reissues or portions of publications that are not substantially different from copies already deposited;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>newspapers printed on paper;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>programs of activities and events;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>publications, including <Emphasis style="italic">livres d’artiste</Emphasis> or book objects, produced by the author, the artist or the publisher using a creative process that significantly distinguishes each copy from the others;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>trade catalogues, advertisements, promotional material, prospectuses and price lists;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>timetables of transport services;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(j)</Label><Text>blank books or blank forms without accompanying text;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(k)</Label><Text>calendars and agendas without accompanying text;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(l)</Label><Text>galley copies, works-in-progress, preprints and drafts;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(m)</Label><Text>student reports, theses and other works produced to meet course requirements;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(n)</Label><Text>drawing and colouring books without text and books of cut-outs for children;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(o)</Label><Text>press releases and circulars;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(p)</Label><Text>newsletters of local interest, in particular those that are published by associations, parishes, employee groups, union locals or schools;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(q)</Label><Text>minutes of meetings and by-laws;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(r)</Label><Text>posters and banners;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(s)</Label><Text>patterns, models, plans and blueprints;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(t)</Label><Text>bookmarks;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(u)</Label><Text>postcards;</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(v)</Label><Text>elementary and secondary school yearbooks;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(w)</Label><Text>games;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(x)</Label><Text>deliberations of electronic discussion groups, listservs, bulletin boards and e-mails;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(y)</Label><Text>websites, including portals, personal websites, service sites, intranets and websites consisting primarily of links to other sites; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(z)</Label><Text>dynamic databases and raw data.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Repeal</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>[Repeal]</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section type="transitional"><Label>6</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on January 1, 2007.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>