<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/86-239</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1986</YYYY><MM>2</MM><DD>27</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2011</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>23</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS MARKETING ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Ontario Flue-Cured Tobacco Licence Charges (Interprovincial and Export) Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Provided for the Fixing, Imposing and Collecting of Licence Charges on Persons Engaged in the Marketing in Interprovincial and Export Trade of Flue-Cured Tobacco Produced in Ontario</LongTitle></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>The Ontario Flue-Cured Tobacco Growers’ Marketing Board, pursuant to section 4<FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-86-239_e_hq_10917">*</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Ontario Flue-Cured Tobacco Order</XRefExternal>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Order providing for the fixing, imposing and collecting of licence charges on persons engaged in the marketing in interprovincial and export trade of flue-cured tobacco produced in Ontario</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fn_SOR-86-239_e_hq_10917" placement="page" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>SOR/85-1105, !985 <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal> Part II, p. 4815</Text></Footnote></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Tillsonburg, Ontario, February 26, 1986</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Ontario Flue-Cured Tobacco Licence Charges (Interprovincial and Export) Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In this Order,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Farm Products Marketing Act</XRefExternal> of Ontario; (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Commodity Board</DefinedTermEn> means The Ontario Flue-Cured Tobacco Growers’ Marketing Board established pursuant to the Act and the Plan; (<DefinedTermFr>Office de commercialisation</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>licensed producer</DefinedTermEn> means a producer to whom a licence to produce tobacco has been issued by the Board, but does not include a producer whose licence has been suspended or revoked by the Board; (<DefinedTermFr>producteur agréé</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Plan</DefinedTermEn> means The Ontario Flue-Cured Tobacco Growers’ Marketing Plan established pursuant to the Act and any regulations made thereunder to give effect to the Plan; (<DefinedTermFr>Plan</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>tobacco</DefinedTermEn> means unmanufactured flue-cured tobacco produced in Ontario. (<DefinedTermFr>tabac</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>This Order applies only with respect to the marketing of tobacco in interprovincial and export trade and to persons and property situated in the Province of Ontario.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Licence Charges</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Every licensed producer shall pay licence charges to the Commodity Board at the rate of 2.5¢ for each pound or fraction thereof of tobacco marketed by the producer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The Commodity Board may deduct the licence charges payable by a licensed producer from the moneys paid to the Commodity Board for the tobacco marketed by the producer.</Text></Subsection></Section></Body></Regulation>