<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/82-405</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1982</YYYY><MM>4</MM><DD>13</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2011</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>17</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">SPECIAL AREAS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Special Areas Industrial Renewal Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Designating Special Areas in the Province of Quebec and Ontario and Approving a Plan for the Areas</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1982-1072</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1982</YYYY><MM>4</MM><DD>8</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas the areas in the Province of Quebec and Ontario described in Schedule I to the Order annexed hereto are part of a region that requires, by reason of exceptional inadequacy of opportunities for productive employment of people of that region, special measures to facilitate economic expansion and social adjustment;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>And Whereas the Minister of Regional Economic Expansion has, in accordance with sections 6 and 7 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Department of Regional Economic Expansion Act</XRefExternal>, consulted with the governments of the Province of Quebec and Ontario regarding the designation of those areas as special areas and has, with the participation of persons, voluntary groups, agencies and bodies in those areas formulated a plan for the economic expansion and social adjustment of those areas.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Therefore, His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Industry, Trade and Commerce, the Minister of Regional Economic Expansion and the Treasury Board, pursuant to sections 6 and 7 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Department of Regional Economic Expansion Act</XRefExternal>, is pleased hereby to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Order Designating Special Areas in the Province of Quebec and Ontario and Approving a Plan for the Areas</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Special Areas Industrial Renewal Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Designation of Special Areas</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>The areas described in Schedule I are designated as special areas for the period commencing April 8, 1982 and terminating March 31, 1986.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/84-276, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Approval of Plans for the Areas</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>The plans set out in Schedule II for the economic expansion and social development of the areas designated by this Order are hereby approved.</Text></Section></Body><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE I</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 2)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Special Area of Sherbrooke — Magog</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>In the census division of Sherbrooke, the census subdivisions of Sherbrooke, Lennoxville, Rock Forest, Deauville, Fleurimont and Saint-Elie d’Orford;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>In the census division of Stanstead, the census subdivisions of Magog, Omerville and the northeast portion of the Township of Magog.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Special Area of Drummondville</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>In the census division of Drummond, the census subdivisions of Drummondville, Drummondville-Sud, Grantham-Ouest, Saint-Germain-de-Grantham (village), Saint-Germain-de-Grantham (municipality), Saint-Nicéphore and Wickham.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Special Area of Trois-Rivières — Shawinigan</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>In the census division of Saint-Maurice, the census subdivisions, of Pointe-du-Lac, Trois-Rivières-Ouest, Trois-Rivières, Shawinigan, Baie-de-Shawinigan;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>In the census division of Champlain, the census subdivisions of Cap-de-la-Madeleine, Saint-Louis-de-France, Sainte-Marthe-du-Cap-de-la-Madeleine, Notre-Dame-du-Mont-Carmel, Shawinigan-Sud, Saint-Théophile, Saint-Georges and Grand-Mère.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Special Area of Valleyfield</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>In the census division of Beauharnois, the census subdivisions of Salaberry-de-Valleyfield and Grande-Île;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>In the census division of Soulanges, the census subdivisions of Coteau-du-Lac, Coteau-Landing, La Station-du-Coteau and Saint-Ignace-du-Coteau-du-Lac.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Special Area of Victoriaville — Plessisville</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>In the census division of Arthabaska, the census subdivisions of Sainte-Victoire-d’Arthabaska, Victoriaville, Arthabaska, Princeville (town) and Princeville (municipality).</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>In the census division of Mégantic, the census subdivisions of Plessisville (town) and Plessisville (municipality).</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Special Area of Cornwall</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>In the census division of Stormont, the census subdivision of Cornwall (city) and Cornwall (township municipality).</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Special Area of Hawkesbury</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>In the census division of Prescott, the census subdivisions of Hawkesbury, Vankleek Hill, L’Orignal, West Hawkesbury and Longueuil.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Census Boundaries</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The said census boundaries are as set out on Census Divisions and Subdivisions Maps G81-10 Quebec No. 1 and Ontario No. 1 of Statistics Canada.</Text></Provision></Schedule><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE II</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 3)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The plan provides for the granting of assistance authorized under the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Canadian Industrial Renewal Regulations</XRefExternal> and the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Industrial and Regional Development Regulations</XRefExternal> to the special areas designated by this Order.</Text></Provision><HistoricalNote>SOR/84-276, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Schedule></Regulation>