<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/81-33b</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1980</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>22</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2011</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>13</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">PUBLIC SERVICE EMPLOYMENT ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Public Service Part-time Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting Part-time Work in the Public Service</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1980-3475</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1980</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>18</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas the Public Service Commission has decided that it is not practicable nor in the best interests of the Public Service to apply the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal> to persons who are not ordinarily required to work more than one-third of the normal scheduled daily or weekly hours of work established for persons doing similar work;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas the Public Service Commission has further decided that it is not practicable nor in the best interests of the Public Service to apply the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal> to persons who were employed under the authority of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Part-time Employees Exclusion Approval Order</XRefExternal>, C.R.C., c. 1350 and the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Part-time Employment Regulations</XRefExternal>, C.R.C., c. 1351, and who are ordinarily required to work more than one-third of the normal scheduled daily and weekly hours of work established for persons doing similar work but not more than 15 hours per week;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>And Whereas the Public Service Commission is of the opinion that it is desirable to make the annexed Regulations prescribing how such persons shall be dealt with.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Therefore, His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Public Service Commission, is pleased hereby, effective January 1st, 1981,</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>pursuant to section 39 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal>, to revoke the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Part-time Employees Exclusion Approval Order</XRefExternal>, C.R.C., c. 1350 and to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Order approving the exclusion by the Public Service Commission of persons who are not ordinarily required to work more than one-third of the normal scheduled daily or weekly hours of work established for persons doing similar work and of certain other persons from the operation of the Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal> in substitution therefor; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>pursuant to subsection 35(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal>, to revoke the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Part-time Employment Regulations</XRefExternal>, C.R.C., c. 1351, and to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting Part-time work in the Public Service</XRefExternal> in substitution therefor.</Text></Provision></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Public Service Part-time Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>former part-time worker</DefinedTermEn> means a person employed under the authority of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Part-time Employees Exclusion Approval Order</XRefExternal>, C.R.C., c. 1350 as it read before January 1, 1981 and the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Part-Time Employment Regulations</XRefExternal>, C.R.C., c. 1351 as it read before January 1, 1981, who is ordinarily required to work more than one-third of the normal scheduled daily or weekly hours of work established for persons doing similar work but not more than 15 hours per week; (<DefinedTermFr>ancien travailleur à temps partiel</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Order</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Part-time Work Exclusion Approval Order</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>Décret</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>part-time worker</DefinedTermEn> means a person who is not ordinarily required to work more than one-third of the normal scheduled daily or weekly hours of work established for persons doing similar work. (<DefinedTermFr>travailleur à temps partiel</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>These Regulations apply only in respect of persons to whom the Order applies.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Delegation of Powers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>A deputy head may delegate any of his powers, functions or duties under these Regulations to one or more persons under his jurisdiction.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Part-time Workers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>Subject to section 6, where a department requires the services of a part-time worker, the deputy head</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>shall recruit and select the persons from Canada Employment Centres or from Public Service Commission Staffing Offices; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>upon selecting the person, may appoint him to the position he is to occupy.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Former Part-time Workers and Part-time Workers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>A department in which former part-time workers and part-time workers are employed may:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>maintain a call-back list for such period as the deputy head may establish;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>place on that call-back list the names of former part-time workers and part-time workers who have performed their duties satisfactorily before the termination of their services; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>call back former part-time workers and part-time workers whose names are on the call-back list when positions at a level for which they are qualified become available.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>7</Label><Text>A former part-time worker and a part-time worker shall be granted a least one day’s notice before their services are terminated.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>