<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/60-481</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1960</YYYY><MM>10</MM><DD>20</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>31</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS MARKETING ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Quebec Apple Growers’ Marketing Order</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1960-1430 </OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1960</YYYY><MM>10</MM><DD> 20</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>WHEREAS under the provisions of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Agricultural Products Marketing Act</XRefExternal>, the Governor in Council may by order grant authority in interprovincial and export trade to any board or agency authorized under the law of any province to exercise powers of regulation in relation to the marketing of any agricultural product locally within the province, and for such purposes to exercise all or any powers like the powers exercisable by such board or agency in relation to the marketing of such product locally within the province;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>AND WHEREAS The Quebec Apple Growers’ Marketing Board is authorized under the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Quebec Agricultural Marketing Act</XRefExternal> and regulations thereunder to exercise powers of regulation in relation to the marketing of apples locally within the Province of Quebec, and has applied for, and it is deemed advisable to grant to the Board, authority to regulate the marketing of apples outside the Province of Quebec in interprovincial and export trade;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THEREFORE His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Agriculture, pursuant to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Agricultural Products Marketing Act</XRefExternal>, is pleased hereby to make the annexed Order.</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Order</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Quebec Apple Growers’ Marketing Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In this Order,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Plan</DefinedTermEn> means The Quebec Apple Growers’ Joint Marketing Plan sanctioned and declared in force by the Quebec Agricultural Marketing Board as published, pursuant to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Quebec Agricultural Marketing Act</XRefExternal>, in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Quebec Gazette</XRefExternal> of August 20, 1960 and as amended in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Quebec Gazette</XRefExternal> of September 10, 1960; (<DefinedTermFr>plan</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Growers’ Board</DefinedTermEn> means the Quebec Apple Growers’ Marketing Board constituted under the Plan; (<DefinedTermFr>Office des producteurs</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Apples</DefinedTermEn> means apples grown in the Province of Quebec. (<DefinedTermFr>pommes</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>The Growers’ Board established pursuant to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Quebec Agricultural Marketing Act</XRefExternal> is hereby granted authority to regulate the marketing outside the Province of Quebec in interprovincial and export trade of apples grown in the Province of Quebec, and for such purposes may, with reference to persons and property situated within the Province of Quebec, exercise powers like the powers exercisable by it in relation to the marketing of such apples locally within the Province of Quebec under the chapters “Powers and attributions” and “Powers as negotiating and selling agent”, contained in the Plan, excepting the powers exercisable under paragraphs (f) and (k) in the subsection “Obligations” in the chapter “Powers and attributions” contained in the Plan.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>