<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/87-259</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1987</YYYY><MM>4</MM><DD>30</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2010</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>8</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CANADA POST CORPORATION ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Postal Services Interruption Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting Interruption of Postal Services</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1987-890</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1987</YYYY><MM>4</MM><DD>30</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas a copy of proposed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting interruption of postal services</XRefExternal>, substantially in the form annexed hereto, was published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal> Part I on February 14, 1987, and a reasonable opportunity was thereby afforded to interested persons to make representations to the Minister with respect thereto.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Therefore, Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Consumer and Corporate Affairs, pursuant to subsection 17(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Post Corporation Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="footnote_e">*</FootnoteRef>, is pleased hereby to approve the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting interruption of postal services</XRefExternal>, made by the Canada Post Corporation.</Text><Footnote id="footnote_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>S.C. 1980-81-82-83, c. 54</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Postal Services Interruption Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1.1</Label><Text>In these Regulations, <DefinedTermEn>interruption of postal services</DefinedTermEn> means a state of affairs in which, in Canada or a part of Canada, the Corporation is not capable of maintaining regular postal services by reason of a natural phenomenon, an accident, a labour dispute or any other urgent or critical situation of a temporary nature.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2010-289, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>Where there is an interruption of postal services in Canada or any part of Canada, the Corporation may, to facilitate the efficient operation of its business,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>give notice to the public that, commencing on a day that is not earlier than the day on which the notice is given, an interruption of postal services is in effect in Canada or in a part of Canada described in the notice; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>give notice to the public that, effective on a day that is not earlier than the day on which the notice is given, the interruption of postal services referred to in the notice of interruption of postal services is no longer in effect.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2000-199, s. 27(F).</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>Where the Corporation gives a notice pursuant to section 2, the Corporation shall give the notice by</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>broadcasting it not less than three times by radio or television, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>publishing it in one or more newspapers of general circulation</Text></Paragraph><ContinuedSectionSubsection><Text>in the area affected by the interruption of postal services described in the notice.</Text></ContinuedSectionSubsection></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>Where the Corporation gives a notice of interruption of postal services, the Corporation shall specify in the notice the postal services and classes of mailable matter affected by the interruption of postal services.</Text></Section><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>If notice of an interruption of postal services has been given, mailable matter specified in the notice must not be accepted for transmission from or to an area in which the interruption of postal services is in effect.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2010-289, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section></Body></Regulation>