<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/86-360</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1986</YYYY><MM>3</MM><DD>26</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2010</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>4</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">ACCESS TO INFORMATION ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Access to Information Act Officers or Employees of the Atomic Energy Control Board Designation Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Respecting the Designation of One or More Officers or Employees of the Atomic Energy Control Board to Exercise or Perform Any of the Powers, Duties or Functions of the President of the Atomic Energy Control Board for the Purposes of the Access to Information Act</LongTitle></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>The President of the Atomic Energy Control Board, pursuant to section 73 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Access to Information Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="footnote_e">*</FootnoteRef>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Order respecting the designation of one or more officers or employees of the Atomic Energy Control Board to exercise or perform any of the powers, duties or functions of the President of the Atomic Energy Control Board for the purposes of the Access to Information Act</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="footnote_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>S.C. 1980-81-82-83, c. 111 (Sch. I)</Text></Footnote></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Ottawa, March 26, 1986</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Access to Information Act Officers or Employees of the Atomic Energy Control Board Designation Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Designation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>Where the President of the Atomic Energy Control Board is absent or otherwise unable to exercise or perform his powers, duties or functions as head of that institution for the purposes of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Access to Information Act</XRefExternal>, the person holding the position of Director General, Directorate of Fuel Cycle and Materials Regulation of the Atomic Energy Control Board, or in his absence, the person holding the position of Director, Planning and Administration Branch of the Atomic Energy Control Board, is hereby designated to exercise or perform any of the powers, duties or functions of the President of the Atomic Energy Control Board as head of the Atomic Energy Control Board for the purposes of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Access to Information Act</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>