<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2014-60</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2014</YYYY><MM>3</MM><DD>17</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2014</YYYY><MM>4</MM><DD>9</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">SPECIAL ECONOMIC MEASURES ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Special Economic Measures (Ukraine) Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2014-284</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>2014</YYYY><MM>3</MM><DD>17</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas the Governor in Council is of the opinion that the situation in Ukraine constitutes a grave breach of international peace and security that has resulted or is likely to result in a serious international crisis;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Therefore, His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Foreign Affairs, pursuant to subsections 4(1) to (3) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Special Economic Measures Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_81000-2-1947-revised-E_hq_13243">a</FootnoteRef>, makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Special Economic Measures (Ukraine) Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fn_81000-2-1947-revised-E_hq_13243" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 1992, c. 17</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Definitions</MarginalNote><Label>1</Label><Text>The following definitions apply in these Regulations.</Text><Definition><MarginalNote><DefinedTermEn>Convention</DefinedTermEn></MarginalNote><MarginalNote><DefinedTermFr>Convention</DefinedTermFr></MarginalNote><Text><DefinedTermEn>Convention</DefinedTermEn> means the Vienna Convention on Diplomatic Relations, done at Vienna on April 18, 1961. </Text></Definition><Definition><MarginalNote><DefinedTermEn>Crimea region of Ukraine</DefinedTermEn></MarginalNote><MarginalNote><DefinedTermFr>région de Crimée de l’Ukraine</DefinedTermFr></MarginalNote><Text><DefinedTermEn>Crimea region of Ukraine</DefinedTermEn> means the Autonomous Republic of Crimea and the city of Sevastopol and includes their land areas and territorial sea.</Text></Definition><Definition><MarginalNote><DefinedTermEn>designated person</DefinedTermEn></MarginalNote><MarginalNote><DefinedTermFr>personne désignée</DefinedTermFr></MarginalNote><Text><DefinedTermEn>designated person</DefinedTermEn> means a person who is in Ukraine, or is a national of Ukraine who does not ordinarily reside in Canada, and whose name is listed in the schedule. </Text></Definition><Definition><MarginalNote><DefinedTermEn>Minister</DefinedTermEn></MarginalNote><MarginalNote><DefinedTermFr>ministre</DefinedTermFr></MarginalNote><Text><DefinedTermEn>Minister</DefinedTermEn> means the Minister of Foreign Affairs.</Text></Definition><Definition><MarginalNote><DefinedTermEn>pension</DefinedTermEn></MarginalNote><MarginalNote><DefinedTermFr>pension</DefinedTermFr></MarginalNote><Text><DefinedTermEn>pension</DefinedTermEn> means a benefit paid under the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Old Age Security Act</XRefExternal>, the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Pension Plan</XRefExternal> or an <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Act respecting the Quebec Pension Plan</XRefExternal>, CQLR, c. R-9, any superannuation, pension or benefit paid under or in respect of any retirement savings plan or under any retirement plan, any amount paid under or in respect of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Garnishment, Attachment and Pension Diversion Act</XRefExternal> or the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Pension Benefits Division Act</XRefExternal>, and any other payment made in respect of disability. </Text></Definition><Definition><MarginalNote><DefinedTermEn>Ukraine</DefinedTermEn></MarginalNote><MarginalNote><DefinedTermFr>Ukraine</DefinedTermFr></MarginalNote><Text><DefinedTermEn>Ukraine</DefinedTermEn> includes </Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any political subdivision of Ukraine;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the government, and any department, of Ukraine or of a political subdivision of Ukraine; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>any agency of Ukraine or of a political subdivision of Ukraine.</Text></Paragraph></Definition><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-179, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>List</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Schedule</MarginalNote><Label>2</Label><Text>A person whose name is listed in the schedule is a person in respect of whom the Governor in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister, is satisfied that there are reasonable grounds to believe is</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a person engaged in activities that directly or indirectly facilitate, support, provide funding for or contribute to a violation or attempted violation of the sovereignty or territorial integrity of Ukraine or that obstruct the work of international organizations in Ukraine;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>an associate or family member of a person described in paragraph (a);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>an entity owned or controlled by, or acting on behalf of, a person set out in paragraph (a);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>an entity whose ownership or control was purported to be altered by a person who has violated or attempted to violate the sovereignty or territorial integrity of Ukraine; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>a senior official of an entity engaged in activities described in paragraph (a) or of an entity described in paragraph (c) or (d).</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2014-93, s. 1; SOR/2014-172, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Prohibitions</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Prohibited transactions and activities — designated persons</MarginalNote><Label>3</Label><Text>It is prohibited for any person in Canada and any Canadian outside Canada to</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>deal in any property, wherever situated, held by or on behalf of a designated person;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>enter into or facilitate, directly or indirectly, any transaction related to a dealing referred to in paragraph (a);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>provide any financial or other related service in respect of a dealing referred to in paragraph (a);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>make any goods, wherever situated, available to a designated person; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>provide any financial or related service to or for the benefit of a designated person.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-179, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Non-application</MarginalNote><Label>4</Label><Text>Section 3 does not apply in respect of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any payment made by or on behalf of a designated person that is due under a contract entered into before the person became a designated person, provided that the payment is not made to or for the benefit of a designated person;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>pension payments to any person in Canada or any Canadian outside Canada;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>any transaction in respect of any account at a financial institution held by a diplomatic mission, if the transaction is required in order for the mission to fulfill its diplomatic functions as set out in Article 3 of the Convention or, if the diplomatic mission has been temporarily or permanently recalled, when the transaction is required in order to maintain the mission premises;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>any transaction to international organizations with diplomatic status, a United Nations agency, the International Red Cross and Red Crescent Movement, or Canadian non-governmental organizations that have entered into a grant or contribution agreement with the Department of Foreign Affairs, Trade and Development;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>any transactions necessary for a Canadian to transfer to a non-designated person any accounts, funds or investments of a Canadian held by a designated person on the day on which that person became a designated person;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>financial services required in order for a designated person to obtain legal services in Canada with respect to the application of any of the prohibitions set out in these Regulations; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>loan repayments made to any person in Canada, or any Canadian outside Canada, in respect of loans entered into before the coming into force of these Regulations, enforcement of security in respect of those loans, or payments by guarantors guaranteeing those loans.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Prohibited transactions and activities — Crimea region of Ukraine</MarginalNote><Label>4.1</Label><Text>It is prohibited for any person in Canada and any Canadian outside Canada to</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>make an investment in the Crimea region of Ukraine that involves a dealing in any property located in the Crimea region of Ukraine that is held by or on behalf of the Crimea region of Ukraine or a person in the Crimea region of Ukraine;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>provide or acquire financial or other related services to, from or for the benefit of or on the direction or order of the Crimea region of Ukraine or any person in the Crimea region of Ukraine for the purpose of making an investment referred to in paragraph (a);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>import, purchase, acquire, ship or otherwise deal in goods, wherever situated, that are exported from the Crimea region of Ukraine after the day on which this section comes into force;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>export, sell, supply, ship or otherwise deal in goods, wherever situated, destined for the Crimea region of Ukraine or any person in the Crimea region of Ukraine;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>transfer, provide or communicate technical data or services to, from or for the benefit of or on the direction or order of the Crimea region of Ukraine or any person in the Crimea region of Ukraine;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>provide or acquire financial or other services related to tourism to, from or for the benefit of or on the direction or order of the Crimea Region of Ukraine or any person in the Crimea Region of Ukraine; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>dock a cruise ship in the Crimea region of Ukraine that is registered or licensed, or for which an identification number has been issued, pursuant to any Act of Parliament.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-179, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Non-application</MarginalNote><Label>4.2</Label><Text>Section 4.1 does not apply in respect of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>goods, if a contract for the export, sale, supply, shipment, import, purchase or acquisition of the goods was entered into before the day on which this section comes into force;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>investments, if a contract for making the investment was entered into before the day on which this section comes into force;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>financial or other related services for the purpose of making an investment, if a contract for the provision or acquisition of those financial or other related services was entered into before the day on which this section comes into force;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>technical data or services, if a contract for the transfer, provision or communication of the technical data or services was entered into before the day on which this section comes into force;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>financial or other services related to tourism, if a contract for the provision or acquisition of the services was entered into before the day on which this section comes into force;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>the docking of a cruise ship, if a contract for the docking of the cruise ship was entered into before the day on which this section comes into force; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>the docking of a cruise ship, if the ship enters or calls at a port in the Crimea region of Ukraine to ensure the safety of any ship or the protection of the marine environment in emergency situations or to save life at sea.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-179, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Prohibited act</MarginalNote><Label>5</Label><Text>It is prohibited for any person in Canada and any Canadian outside Canada to do anything that causes, assists or promotes, or is intended to cause, assist or promote, any act or thing prohibited under section 3 or 4.1.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-179, s. 4.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Obligations</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Duty to determine</MarginalNote><Label>6</Label><Text>Each of the following entities must determine on a continuing basis whether it is in possession or control of property owned or controlled by or on behalf of a designated person:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>authorized foreign banks, as defined in section 2 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Bank Act</XRefExternal>, in respect of their business in Canada or banks to which that Act applies;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>cooperative credit societies, savings and credit unions and <Language xml:lang="fr">caisses populaires</Language> regulated by a provincial Act and associations regulated by the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Cooperative Credit Associations Act</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>foreign companies, as defined in subsection 2(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Insurance Companies Act</XRefExternal>, in respect of their insurance business in Canada;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>companies, provincial companies and societies, as those terms are defined in subsection 2(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Insurance Companies Act</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>fraternal benefit societies regulated by a provincial Act in respect of their insurance activities and insurance companies and other entities engaged in the business of insuring risks that are regulated by a provincial Act;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>companies to which the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Trust and Loan Companies Act</XRefExternal> applies;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>trust companies regulated by a provincial Act;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>loan companies regulated by a provincial Act;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>entities that engage in any activity described in paragraph 5(h) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Proceeds of Crime (Money Laundering) and Terrorist Financing Act</XRefExternal>, if the activity involves the opening of an account for a client; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(j)</Label><Text>entities authorized under provincial legislation to engage in the business of dealing in securities, or to provide portfolio management or investment counselling services.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Disclosure</MarginalNote><Label>7</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Every person in Canada and every Canadian outside Canada must disclose without delay to the Commissioner of the Royal Canadian Mounted Police</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the existence of property in their possession or control that they have reason to believe is owned or controlled, directly or indirectly, by a designated person or by an entity owned or controlled by a designated person; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>information about a transaction or proposed transaction in respect of property referred to in paragraph (a).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Immunity</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>No person contravenes subsection (1) by disclosing in good faith under that subsection.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Applications</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Application to no longer be a designated person</MarginalNote><Label>8</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A designated person may apply in writing to the Minister to have their name removed from the schedule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Recommendation</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>On receipt of the application, the Minister must decide whether there are reasonable grounds to recommend to the Governor in Council that the applicant’s name be removed from the schedule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Decision</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The Minister must make a decision on the application within 90 days after the day on which the application is received.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Notice</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The Minister must give notice without delay to the applicant of the decision taken.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>New application</MarginalNote><Label>(5)</Label><Text>If there has been a material change in circumstances since the last application was submitted, a person may submit another application under subsection (1).</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Application for a certificate</MarginalNote><Label>9</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A person claiming not to be a designated person may apply to the Minister for a certificate stating that they are not the person who has been designated under section 2.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Decision</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>If it is established that the person is not a designated person, the Minister must issue a certificate to the applicant within 30 days after the day on which the application is received.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application Prior to Publication</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote><XRefExternal reference-type="act">Statutory Instruments Act</XRefExternal></MarginalNote><Label>10</Label><Text>For the purpose of paragraph 11(2)(a) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Statutory Instruments Act</XRefExternal>, these Regulations apply before they are published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Registration</MarginalNote><Label>11</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on the day on which they are registered.</Text></Section></Body><Schedule><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label><OriginatingRef>(Sections 1, 2 and 8)</OriginatingRef><TitleText>Persons</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 1</Label><TitleText>Individuals</TitleText></Heading><List subsequent-line-indent="2" first-line-indent="0"><Item><Label>1</Label><Text>Serhiy Valeriyovich AKSYONOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>2</Label><Text>Volodymyr Andriyovych KONSTANTYNOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>3</Label><Text>Viktor Volodymyrovich MEDVEDCHUK</Text></Item><Item><Label>4</Label><Text>Rustam Ilmirovich TEMIRGALIEV</Text></Item><Item><Label>5</Label><Text>Deniz Valentinovich BEREZOVSKIY</Text></Item><Item><Label>6</Label><Text>Aleksei Mikhailovich CHALIY</Text></Item><Item><Label>7</Label><Text>Pyotr Anatoliyovych ZIMA</Text></Item><Item><Label>8</Label><Text>Yuriy ZHEREBTSOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>9</Label><Text>Sergey Pavlovych TSEKOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>10</Label><Text>Mikhail MALYSHEV</Text></Item><Item><Label>11</Label><Text>Valery MEDVEDEV</Text></Item><Item><Label>12</Label><Text>Olga Fedorovna KOVATIDI</Text></Item><Item><Label>13</Label><Text>German PROKOPIV</Text></Item><Item><Label>14</Label><Text>Valeriy BOLOTOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>15</Label><Text>Andriy PURGIN</Text></Item><Item><Label>16</Label><Text>Denys PUSHYLIN</Text></Item><Item><Label>17</Label><Text>Sergey Gennadevich TSYPLAKOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>18</Label><Text>Petr Grigorievich JAROSH</Text></Item><Item><Label>19</Label><Text>Oleg Grigorievich KOZYURA</Text></Item><Item><Label>20</Label><Text>Viacheslav PONOMARIOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>21</Label><Text>Igor Mykolaiovych BEZLER</Text></Item><Item><Label>22</Label><Text>Igor KAKIDZYANOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>23</Label><Text>Oleg TSARIOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>24</Label><Text>Roman LYAGIN</Text></Item><Item><Label>25</Label><Text>Aleksandr MALYKHIN</Text></Item><Item><Label>26</Label><Text>Natalia Vladimirovna POKLONSKAYA</Text></Item><Item><Label>27</Label><Text>Igor Sergeievich SHEVCHENKO</Text></Item><Item><Label>28</Label><Text>Viktor Yuriiovych ANOSOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>29</Label><Text>Viacheslav Anatoliiovych APRAKSIMOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>30</Label><Text>Fedir Dmytrovych BEREZIN</Text></Item><Item><Label>31</Label><Text>Ruslan Yunirovish ILKAEV</Text></Item><Item><Label>32</Label><Text>Valery Vladimirovich KAUROV</Text></Item><Item><Label>33</Label><Text>Oleksandr Sergiyovych KHODAKOVSKYI</Text></Item><Item><Label>34</Label><Text>Mykola Ivanovych KOZITSYN</Text></Item><Item><Label>35</Label><Text>Oleksii Borysovych MOZGOVYI</Text></Item><Item><Label>36</Label><Text>Valerii Kostiantynovych MUSIIENKO</Text></Item><Item><Label>37</Label><Text>Viacheslav Mykolaiovych PETROV</Text></Item><Item><Label>38</Label><Text>Ihor Venedyktovych PLOTNYTSKY</Text></Item><Item><Label>39</Label><Text>Yurii Oleksandrovych PROTSENKO</Text></Item><Item><Label>40</Label><Text>Oleh Anatoliiovych VASIN</Text></Item><Item><Label>41</Label><Text>Serhii Anatoliyovych ZDRILIUK</Text></Item><Item><Label>42</Label><Text>Vladimir ANTYUFEYEV</Text></Item><Item><Label>43</Label><Text>Marat BASHIROV</Text></Item><Item><Label>44</Label><Text>Alexsandr Yurivich BORODAI</Text></Item><Item><Label>45</Label><Text>Yuriy IVAKIN</Text></Item><Item><Label>46</Label><Text>Alexandr Alexsandrovich KALYUSSKY</Text></Item><Item><Label>47</Label><Text>Aleksey KARYAKIN</Text></Item><Item><Label>48</Label><Text>Alexandr KHRYAKOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>49</Label><Text>Vasyl NIKITIN</Text></Item><Item><Label>50</Label><Text>Pavel Yurevich GUBAREV</Text></Item><Item><Label>51</Label><Text>Ekaterina Yurevna GUBAREVA</Text></Item><Item><Label>52</Label><Text>Oksana TCHIGRINA</Text></Item><Item><Label>53</Label><Text>Boris LITVINOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>54</Label><Text>Sergey ABISOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>55</Label><Text>Oleh BEREZA</Text></Item><Item><Label>56</Label><Text>Oleksandr KARAMAN</Text></Item><Item><Label>57</Label><Text>Volodimir KONONOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>58</Label><Text>Georgiy L’vovich MURADOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>59</Label><Text>Andriy Yurevich PINCHUK</Text></Item><Item><Label>60</Label><Text>Miroslav Vladimirovich RUDENKO</Text></Item><Item><Label>61</Label><Text>Mikhail Sergeyevich SHEREMET</Text></Item><Item><Label>62</Label><Text>Gennadiy Nikolaiovych TSYPKALOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>63</Label><Text>Oleksandr ZAKHARCHENKO</Text></Item><Item><Label>64</Label><Text>Larisa AIRAPETYAN</Text></Item><Item><Label>65</Label><Text>Eduard BASURIN</Text></Item><Item><Label>66</Label><Text>Olga BESEDINA</Text></Item><Item><Label>67</Label><Text>Oleg BUGROV</Text></Item><Item><Label>68</Label><Text>Vladyslav DEYNEGO</Text></Item><Item><Label>69</Label><Text>Pavel DREMOV also known as “Batya” or “Kazak”</Text></Item><Item><Label>70</Label><Text>Ekaterina FILIPPOVA</Text></Item><Item><Label>71</Label><Text>Sergey IGNATOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>72</Label><Text>Zaur ISMAILOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>73</Label><Text>Ravil KHALIKOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>74</Label><Text>Ihor KOSTENOK</Text></Item><Item><Label>75</Label><Text>Serhiy KOZYAKOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>76</Label><Text>Lesya LAPTEVA</Text></Item><Item><Label>77</Label><Text>Sergey LITVIN</Text></Item><Item><Label>78</Label><Text>Evgeny MANUILOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>79</Label><Text>Yevgeniy MIKHAYLOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>80</Label><Text>Alexey MILCHAKOV also known as “Fritz” or “Serbian”</Text></Item><Item><Label>81</Label><Text>Dmitry NEKLYUDOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>82</Label><Text>Yevgeniy ORLOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>83</Label><Text>Arseny PAVLOV also known as “Motorola”</Text></Item><Item><Label>84</Label><Text>Dmitry SEMYONOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>85</Label><Text>Aleksandr SHUBIN</Text></Item><Item><Label>86</Label><Text>Yuriy SIVOKONENKO</Text></Item><Item><Label>87</Label><Text>Aleksandr TIMOFEEV</Text></Item><Item><Label>88</Label><Text>Mikhail TOLSTYKH also known as “Givi”</Text></Item><Item><Label>89</Label><Text>Viktor YATSENKO</Text></Item><Item><Label>90</Label><Text>Oleg Konstantinovich AKIMOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>91</Label><Text>Aleksandr Igorevich KOFMAN</Text></Item><Item><Label>92</Label><Text>Petr SAVCHENKO</Text></Item><Item><Label>93</Label><Text>Anna Vladimirovna ANYUKHINA</Text></Item><Item><Label>94</Label><Text>Konstantin BAKHAREV</Text></Item><Item><Label>95</Label><Text>Ruslan BALBEK</Text></Item><Item><Label>96</Label><Text>Dmitry BELIK</Text></Item><Item><Label>97</Label><Text>Svetlana Alekseevna BORODULINA</Text></Item><Item><Label>98</Label><Text>Valentin Valentinovich DEMIDOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>99</Label><Text>Irina Valerievna KIVIKO</Text></Item><Item><Label>100</Label><Text>Andrey KOZENKO</Text></Item><Item><Label>101</Label><Text>Mikhail Anatolievich NAZAROV</Text></Item><Item><Label>102</Label><Text>Viktor Nikolayevich PALAGIN</Text></Item><Item><Label>103</Label><Text>Dmitry Anatolievich POLONSKY</Text></Item><Item><Label>104</Label><Text>Svetlana SAVCHENKO</Text></Item><Item><Label>105</Label><Text>Oleg Georgievich SHAPOVALOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>106</Label><Text>Pavel Valentinovich SHPEROV</Text></Item><Item><Label>107</Label><Text>Andrey Gennadievich VASYUTA</Text></Item></List><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 2</Label><TitleText>Entities</TitleText></Heading><List subsequent-line-indent="2" first-line-indent="0"><Item><Label>1</Label><Text>Chernomorneftegaz</Text></Item><Item><Label>2</Label><Text>Feodosia</Text></Item><Item><Label>3</Label><Text>Donetsk People’s Republic</Text></Item><Item><Label>4</Label><Text>Luhansk People’s Republic</Text></Item><Item><Label>5</Label><Text>Federal State of Novorossiya</Text></Item><Item><Label>6</Label><Text>International Union of Public Associations “Great Don Army”</Text></Item><Item><Label>7</Label><Text>Sobol</Text></Item><Item><Label>8</Label><Text>Luhansk Guard</Text></Item><Item><Label>9</Label><Text>Army of the Southeast</Text></Item><Item><Label>10</Label><Text>Donbass People’s Militia</Text></Item><Item><Label>11</Label><Text>Vostok battalion</Text></Item><Item><Label>12</Label><Text>Kerch ferry</Text></Item><Item><Label>13</Label><Text>Sevastopol commercial seaport</Text></Item><Item><Label>14</Label><Text>Kerch commercial seaport</Text></Item><Item><Label>15</Label><Text>Universal-Avia</Text></Item><Item><Label>16</Label><Text>Resort “Nizhnyaya Oreanda”</Text></Item><Item><Label>17</Label><Text>Azov distillery plant</Text></Item><Item><Label>18</Label><Text>National Association of producers “Massandra”</Text></Item><Item><Label>19</Label><Text>Magarach of the national institute of wine</Text></Item><Item><Label>20</Label><Text>Factory of sparkling wine Novy Svet</Text></Item><Item><Label>21</Label><Text>Cossack National Guard</Text></Item><Item><Label>22</Label><Text>Donetsk Republic</Text></Item><Item><Label>23</Label><Text>Free Donbass</Text></Item><Item><Label>24</Label><Text>Kalmius Battalion</Text></Item><Item><Label>25</Label><Text>Luhansk Economic Union</Text></Item><Item><Label>26</Label><Text>Oplot</Text></Item><Item><Label>27</Label><Text>Peace to Luhansk Region</Text></Item><Item><Label>28</Label><Text>People’s Union</Text></Item><Item><Label>29</Label><Text>Prizrak Brigade</Text></Item><Item><Label>30</Label><Text>Profaktor, TOV</Text></Item><Item><Label>31</Label><Text>Smert aka Death Battalion</Text></Item><Item><Label>32</Label><Text>Somali Battalion</Text></Item><Item><Label>33</Label><Text>Sparta Battalion</Text></Item><Item><Label>34</Label><Text>The South-East Movement</Text></Item><Item><Label>35</Label><Text>Zarya Battalion</Text></Item><Item><Label>36</Label><Text>State Enterprise Evpatoria Sea Commercial Port</Text></Item><Item><Label>37</Label><Text>State Enterprise Feodosia Sea Trading Port</Text></Item><Item><Label>38</Label><Text>State Enterprise Yalta Sea Trading Port</Text></Item><Item><Label>39</Label><Text>Yalta Film Studio</Text></Item></List><HistoricalNote>SOR/2014-63, s. 1; SOR/2014-93, ss. 2, 3; SOR/2014-109, s. 1; SOR/2014-172, ss. 2, 3; SOR/2014-180, s. 1; SOR/2014-183, ss. 1, 2; SOR/2014-196, ss. 1, 2; SOR/2014-317, s. 1; SOR/2015-40, ss. 1, 2; SOR/2016-51, ss. 1, 2; SOR/2016-304, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Schedule><Schedule id="RelatedProvs"><ScheduleFormHeading type="amending"><TitleText>RELATED PROVISIONS</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><RegulationPiece><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2014-63, s. 2</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote><XRefExternal reference-type="act">Statutory Instruments Act</XRefExternal></MarginalNote><Label>2</Label><Text>For the purpose of paragraph 11(2)(a) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Statutory Instruments Act</XRefExternal>, these Regulations apply before they are published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2014-93, s. 4</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote><XRefExternal reference-type="act">Statutory Instruments Act</XRefExternal></MarginalNote><Label>4</Label><Text>For the purpose of paragraph 11(2)(a) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Statutory Instruments Act</XRefExternal>, these Regulations apply before they are published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2014-109, s. 2</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote><XRefExternal reference-type="act">Statutory Instruments Act</XRefExternal></MarginalNote><Label>2</Label><Text>For the purpose of paragraph 11(2)(a) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Statutory Instruments Act</XRefExternal>, these Regulations apply before they are published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2014-172, s. 4</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote><XRefExternal reference-type="act">Statutory Instruments Act</XRefExternal></MarginalNote><Label>4</Label><Text>For the purpose of paragraph 11(2)(a) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Statutory Instruments Act</XRefExternal>, these Regulations apply before they are published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2014-180, s. 2</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>For the purpose of paragraph 11(2)(a) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Statutory Instruments Act</XRefExternal>, these Regulations apply before they are published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2014-183, s. 3</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>For the purpose of paragraph 11(2)(a) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Statutory Instruments Act</XRefExternal>, these Regulations apply before they are published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2014-196, s. 3</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>For the purpose of paragraph 11(2)(a) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Statutory Instruments Act</XRefExternal>, these Regulations apply before they are published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2014-317, s. 2</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote><XRefExternal reference-type="act">Statutory Instruments Act</XRefExternal></MarginalNote><Label>2</Label><Text>For the purpose of paragraph 11(2)(a) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Statutory Instruments Act</XRefExternal>, these Regulations apply before they are published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2015-40, s. 3</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>For the purpose of paragraph 11(2)(a) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Statutory Instruments Act</XRefExternal>, these Regulations apply before they are published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2015-179, s. 5</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote><XRefExternal reference-type="act">Statutory Instruments Act</XRefExternal></MarginalNote><Label>5</Label><Text>For the purpose of paragraph 11(2)(a) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Statutory Instruments Act</XRefExternal>, these Regulations apply before they are published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2016-51, s. 3</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>For the purpose of paragraph 11(2)(a) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Statutory Instruments Act</XRefExternal>, these Regulations apply before they are published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2016-304, s. 2</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>For the purpose of paragraph 11(2)(a) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Statutory Instruments Act</XRefExternal>, these Regulations apply before they are published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section></RegulationPiece></Schedule></Regulation>