<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/86-259</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1986</YYYY><MM>2</MM><DD>27</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2010</YYYY><MM>10</MM><DD>12</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CANADA HEALTH ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Extra-billing and User Charges Information Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Prescribing the Types of Information that the Minister of National Health and Welfare may Require under Paragraph 13(a) of the Canada Health Act in Respect of Extra-Billing and User Charges and the Times at which and the Manner in which such Information shall be Provided by the Government of each Province</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1986-499</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1986</YYYY><MM>2</MM><DD>27</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas the Minister of National Health and Welfare has consulted with the Ministers responsible for health care in the provinces respecting proposed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations prescribing the types of information that the Minister may require under paragraph 13(a) of the Canada Health Act in respect of extra-billing and user charges and the times at which and the manner in which such information shall be provided by the government of each province</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Therefore, Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of National Health and Welfare, pursuant to paragraph 22(1)(c) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Health Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="footnote_e">*</FootnoteRef>, is pleased hereby to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations prescribing the types of information that the Minister of National Health and Welfare may require under paragraph 13(a) of the Canada Health Act in respect of extra-billing and user charges and the times at which and the manner in which such information shall be provided by the government of each province</XRefExternal>, effective April 1, 1986.</Text><Footnote id="footnote_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>S.C. 1984, c. 6</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Extra-billing and User Charges Information Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Health Act</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Minister</DefinedTermEn> means the Minister of National Health and Welfare; (<DefinedTermFr>ministre</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>fiscal year</DefinedTermEn> means the period beginning on April 1 in one year and ending on March 31 in the following year. (<DefinedTermFr>exercice</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Types of Information</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>For the purposes of paragraph 13(a) of the Act, the Minister may require the government of a province to provide the Minister with information of the following types with respect to extra-billing in the province in a fiscal year:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>an estimate of the aggregate amount that, at the time the estimate is made, is expected to be charged through extra-billing, including an explanation regarding the method of determination of the estimate; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a financial statement showing the aggregate amount actually charged through extra-billing, including an explanation regarding the method of determination of the aggregate amount.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>For the purposes of paragraph 13(a) of the Act, the Minister may require the government of a province to provide the Minister with information of the following types with respect to user charges in the province in a fiscal year:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>an estimate of the aggregate amount that, at the time the estimate is made, is expected to be charged in respect of user charges to which section 19 of the Act applies, including an explanation regarding the method of determination of the estimate; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a financial statement showing the aggregate amount actually charged in respect of user charges to which section 19 of the Act applies, including an explanation regarding the method of determination of the aggregate amount.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Times and Manner of Filing Information</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The government of a province shall provide the Minister with such information, of the types prescribed by sections 3 and 4, as the Minister may reasonably require, at the following times:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in respect of the estimates referred to in paragraphs 3(a) and 4(a), before April 1 of the fiscal year to which they relate; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in respect of the financial statements referred to in paragraphs 3(b) and 4(b), before the sixteenth day of the twenty-first month following the end of the fiscal year to which they relate.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The government of a province may, at its discretion, provide the Minister with adjustments to the estimates referred to in paragraphs 3(a) and 4(a) before February 16 of the fiscal year to which they relate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The information referred to in subsections (1) and (2) shall be transmitted to the Minister by the most practical means of communication.</Text></Subsection></Section></Body></Regulation>