<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/95-38</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1994</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>30</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2006</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>26</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">EXPORT AND IMPORT PERMITS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>General Import Permit No. 7 — Turkeys and Turkey Products for Personal Use</LongTitle></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas turkeys and turkey products have been included on the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Import Control List</XRefExternal>;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>And Whereas the Secretary of State for External Affairs has determined an import access quantity for turkeys and turkey products pursuant to subsection 6.2(1)<FootnoteRef idref="footnote1_e">*</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Export and Import Permits Act</XRefExternal>;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Therefore, the Secretary of State for External Affairs, pursuant to section 10<FootnoteRef idref="footnote2_e">**</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Export and Import Permits Act</XRefExternal>, hereby cancels the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Import of Turkeys and Turkey Products Permit</XRefExternal>, issued on February 4, 1981<FootnoteRef idref="footnote3_e">***</FootnoteRef>, and, pursuant to subsection 8.3(3)<FootnoteRef idref="footnote4_e">****</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Export and Import Permits Act</XRefExternal>, hereby issues the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">General permit authorizing the importation of turkeys and turkey products for personal use</XRefExternal>, effective on the later of the days on which sections 74, 106, 109 and 111 of <XRefExternal reference-type="act">An Act to implement the Agreement Establishing the World Trade Organization</XRefExternal>, being chapter 47 of the Statutes of Canada, 1994, come into force.</Text><Footnote id="footnote1_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>   *</Label><Text>S.C. 1994, c. 47, s. 106</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="footnote2_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>  **</Label><Text>S.C. 1994, c. 47, s. 111</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="footnote3_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label> ***</Label><Text>SOR/81-122, 1981 <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal> Part II, p. 456</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="footnote4_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>****</Label><Text>S.C. 1994, c. 47, s. 109</Text></Footnote></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Ottawa, Ontario, December 29, 1994</Text></Provision><Provision topmarginspacing="12"><SignatureBlock justification="right" width="20pc"><SignatureName justification="right">ANDRÉ OUELLET</SignatureName><SignatureTitle justification="right"><Emphasis style="italic">Secretary of State for External Affairs</Emphasis></SignatureTitle></SignatureBlock></Provision></Order><Body><Section><Label>1</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/97-43, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In this Permit,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>turkey products</DefinedTermEn> means the goods set out in items 2 to 10 of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>produits de dindons et dindes</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>turkeys</DefinedTermEn> means the goods set out in item 1 of the schedule. (<DefinedTermFr>dindons et dindes</DefinedTermFr>) </Text></Definition><HistoricalNote>SOR/96-53, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>Any resident of Canada may, under the authority of this Permit, import into Canada for the personal use of the importer and the importer’s household</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>one turkey; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>turkey products in a quantity not exceeding 10 kg in net weight for each importation.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>Where any goods imported under the authority of this Permit are required to be reported in the prescribed form under the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Act</XRefExternal>, that form shall contain the statement “Imported under the authority of <Emphasis style="italic">General Import Permit No. 7 — Turkeys and Turkey Products for Personal Use</Emphasis>” or <Language xml:lang="fr">“Importé en vertu de la <Emphasis style="italic">Licence générale d’importation n<Sup>o</Sup> 7 — Dindons et dindes et produits de dindons et dindes pour usage personnel</Emphasis>”</Language>.</Text></Section></Body><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 2)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><RegulationPiece><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>Live turkeys, weighing more than 185 g, that are classified under tariff item No. 0105.99.11 or heading No. 98.04 in the List of Tariff Provisions set out in the schedule to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>Meat and edible offal of turkeys, fresh, chilled or frozen, not cut in pieces, that are classified under tariff item No. 0207.24.11, 0207.24.91, 0207.25.11 or 0207.25.91 in the List of Tariff Provisions set out in the schedule to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>Cuts of meat and edible offal, including livers, of turkeys, fresh, chilled or frozen, that are classified under tariff item No. 0207.26.10, 0207.27.11 or 0207.27.91 in the List of Tariff Provisions set out in the schedule to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>Turkey fat (not rendered or otherwise extracted), fresh, chilled or frozen, salted, in brine, dried or smoked, that is classified under tariff item No. 0209.90.30 in the List of Tariff Provisions set out in the schedule to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>Meat of turkeys, salted, in brine, dried or smoked, that is classified under tariff item No. 0210.99.14 in the List of Tariff Provisions set out in the schedule to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>Sausages and similar products, made from meat, meat offal or blood of turkeys, and food preparation based on those products (other than in cans or glass jars), that are classified under tariff item No. 1601.00.31 in the List of Tariff Provisions set out in the schedule to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Section><Label>7</Label><Text>Prepared or preserved liver paste, made from turkeys (other than in cans or glass jars), that is classified under tariff item No. 1602.20.31 in the List of Tariff Provisions set out in the schedule to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Section><Label>8</Label><Text>Prepared meals, made from turkeys (other than specially defined mixtures), that are classified under tariff item No. 1602.31.12 in the List of Tariff Provisions set out in the schedule to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Section><Label>9</Label><Text>Prepared or preserved meat or meat offal of turkeys (other than prepared meals and specially defined mixtures and other than in cans or glass jars) that is classified under tariff item No. 1602.31.93 in the List of Tariff Provisions set out in the schedule to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Section><Label>10</Label><Text>Goods that are classified under heading No. 98.04 or 98.26 in the List of Tariff Provisions set out in the schedule to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal> and that are otherwise classifiable under a tariff item referred to in any of items 2 to 9 of this schedule.</Text></Section></RegulationPiece><HistoricalNote>SOR/95-399, s. 1; SOR/96-53, ss. 2, 3; SOR/97-43, ss. 3, 4; SOR/98-82, ss. 1, 2; SOR/2002-91, s. 1; SOR/2011-308, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Schedule></Regulation>