<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="I" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/87-379</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1987</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>25</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">TELEGLOBE CANADA REORGANIZATION AND DIVESTITURE ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Teleglobe Canada Pension Protection Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting Pension Protection for Employees of Teleglobe Canada</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1987-1270</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1987</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>25</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of State (Privatization) and the Treasury Board, pursuant to section 25 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Teleglobe Canada Reorganization and Divestiture Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="footnote_e">*</FootnoteRef>, is pleased hereby to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting pension protection for employees of Teleglobe Canada</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="footnote_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>S.C. 1987, c. 12</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Teleglobe Canada Pension Protection Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Teleglobe Canada Reorganization and Divestiture Act</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>new corporation</DefinedTermEn> means the new corporation as defined in the Act. (<DefinedTermFr>nouvelle société</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Applicable Provisions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>All the provisions of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Superannuation Act</XRefExternal>, the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Supplementary Retirement Benefits Act</XRefExternal> and the regulations made under those Acts as amended apply to persons referred to in paragraph 25(1)(d) of the Act except to the extent that those provisions are adapted in accordance with sections 4 and 5.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Adapted Provisions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>For the purposes of section 25 of the Act, subparagraphs 9(7)(b)(i) and (ii) and sections 11 and 12 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Superannuation Act</XRefExternal> are adapted as follows:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in subparagraphs 9(7)(b)(i) and (ii), the year in which a person ceased to be employed in the Public Service shall be considered to be the year in which the person ceased to be employed by the new corporation; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in sections 11 and 12,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>except in subsection 11(4), the number of years of pensionable service and any periods of employment in respect of the person shall be considered to include any such service or employment with the new corporation during the period beginning on the day the person ceases to be employed in the Public Service and ending on the day immediately preceding the day on which the person ceases to be employed by the new corporation, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>except for the purposes of subparagraph (i) the day on which a person ceases to be employed in the Public Service shall be considered to be the day on which the person ceases to be employed by the new corporation.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>For the purposes of section 25 of the Act, subsection 4(3) and subparagraphs 6(2)(b)(i) and (ii) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Supplementary Retirement Benefits Act</XRefExternal> are adapted as follows:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in subsection 4(3), the retirement year or retirement month of a person shall be considered to be 1987 or April 1987, as the case may be; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in subparagraphs 6(2)(b)(i) and (ii), the year in which a person ceased to contribute in respect of current service to the Supplementary Retirement Benefits Account shall be considered to be the year in which the person ceased to be employed by the new corporation.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>These Regulations apply on and after April 4, 1987.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>