<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/94-142</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1994</YYYY><MM>1</MM><DD>31</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><LastAmendedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>4</DD></Date></LastAmendedDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CANADA DEPOSIT INSURANCE CORPORATION ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Canada Deposit Insurance Corporation Prescribed Practices Premium Surcharge By-law</ShortTitle><LongTitle> By-Law Prescribing the Practices of Member Institutions Warranting a Premium Surcharge</LongTitle></Identification><Order><Provision language-align="yes" format-ref="indent-0-0" list-item="no"><Text>The Board of Directors of the Canada Deposit Insurance Corporation, pursuant to paragraph 11(2)(g)<FootnoteRef idref="footnotea_e">*</FootnoteRef> and subsection 25.1(1)<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteb_e">**</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Deposit Insurance Corporation Act</XRefExternal>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">By-law prescribing the practices of member institutions warranting a premium surcharge</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="footnotea_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label> *</Label><Text>R.S., c. 18 (3rd Supp.), s. 51</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="footnoteb_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>**</Label><Text>R.S., c. 18 (3rd Supp.), s. 59</Text></Footnote></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>January 31, 1994</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This By-law may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Canada Deposit Insurance Corporation Prescribed Practices Premium Surcharge By-law</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Practices</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A practice that warrants a premium surcharge is any act or omission of a member institution that results in the member institution</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>failing to comply with subsection 8(2) of the policy of deposit insurance, as prescribed by section 1 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Canada Deposit Insurance Corporation Deposit Insurance Policy By-law</XRefExternal> and as set out in the schedule to that By-law, that requires the member institution to have the practices and controls referred to in that subsection;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>failing to comply with one or more provisions of the policy of deposit insurance, as prescribed by section 1 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Canada Deposit Insurance Corporation Deposit Insurance Policy By-law</XRefExternal> and as set out in the schedule to that By-law, that require the member institution to provide the Corporation with the information specified in that policy;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>failing to comply with section 24 of the policy of deposit insurance, as prescribed by section 1 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Canada Deposit Insurance Corporation Deposit Insurance Policy By-law</XRefExternal> and as set out in the schedule to that By-law, that requires the member institution to prepare and maintain the records specified in that section and to retain those records for the period of time specified in that section;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>failing to comply with one or more provisions of a relevant statute described in subsection (2) that relate to the objects of the Corporation set out in section 7 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Deposit Insurance Corporation Act</XRefExternal> and that impose a duty on the member institution in respect of any of the following matters, namely,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>corporate governance,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>preparation and filing of financial statements,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>business and powers,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>investments,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(v)</Label><Text>capital and liquidity, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(vi)</Label><Text>self-dealing;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>failing to fulfil the terms of any undertaking given by the member institution to the Corporation; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>failing to comply with one or more provisions of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Canada Deposit Insurance Corporation Data and System Requirements By-law</XRefExternal>.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>For the purposes of paragraph (1)(d), <DefinedTermEn>relevant statute</DefinedTermEn> means</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in the case of a federal member institution that is a bank, the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Bank Act</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the case of a federal member institution that is a trust or loan company, the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Trust and Loan Companies Act</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b.1)</Label><Text>in the case of a federal member institution that is an association, the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Cooperative Credit Associations Act</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>in the case of a provincial member institution, the provincial Act that authorizes the member institution to accept deposits within the meaning of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Deposit Insurance Corporation Act</XRefExternal>.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2001-299, s. 39; SOR/2005-117, s. 1; SOR/2008-294, s. 1; SOR/2010-293, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section></Body></Regulation>