<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en" in-force="yes"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2010-65</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2010</YYYY><MM>3</MM><DD>17</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2010</YYYY><MM>3</MM><DD>31</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">TELECOMMUNICATIONS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Telecommunications Fees Regulations, 2010</LongTitle></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas, pursuant to subsection 69(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Telecommunications Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_3928_hq_2623">a</FootnoteRef>, a copy of the proposed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Telecommunications Fees Regulations, 2010</XRefExternal>, substantially in the annexed form, was published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>, Part I, on November 7, 2009 and a reasonable opportunity was thereby afforded to interested persons to make representations to the Canadian Radio-television and Telecommunications Commission with respect to the proposed Regulations;</Text><Footnote id="fn_3928_hq_2623" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 1993, c. 38</Text></Footnote></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Therefore, the Canadian Radio-television and Telecommunications Commission, with the approval of the Treasury Board, pursuant to subsection 68(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Telecommunications Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_3928_hq_2623">a</FootnoteRef>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Telecommunications Fees Regulations, 2010</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Gatineau, Quebec, March 16, 2010</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" topmarginspacing="12"><SignatureBlock justification="right" width="15pc"><SignatureName justification="right">ROBERT A. MORIN</SignatureName><SignatureTitle justification="right"><Emphasis style="italic">Secretary General</Emphasis></SignatureTitle><SignatureTitle justification="right"><Emphasis style="italic">Canadian Radio-television and Telecommunications Commission</Emphasis></SignatureTitle></SignatureBlock></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>The following definitions apply in these Regulations.</Text><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Canadian telecommunications services revenues</DefinedTermEn> has the same meaning as in Part B of the <XRefExternal reference-type="standard">Telecom Circular CRTC 2007-15, The Canadian revenue-based contribution regime</XRefExternal>, published on June 8, 2007.(<DefinedTermFr>revenus des services de télécommunication canadiens</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>contribution-eligible revenues</DefinedTermEn> means revenues calculated in accordance with the formula set out in Part A of the <XRefExternal reference-type="standard">Telecom Circular CRTC 2007-15, The Canadian revenue-based contribution regime</XRefExternal>, published on June 8, 2007. (<DefinedTermFr>revenus admissibles à la contribution</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>related</DefinedTermEn> in relation to telecommunications service providers, means two or more telecommunications service providers that are related parties within the meaning of Section 3840 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="standard">Canadian Institute of Chartered Accountants Handbook</XRefExternal> as amended from time to time. (<DefinedTermFr>apparentés</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>telecommunications service</DefinedTermEn> has the same meaning as in section 23 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Telecommunications Act</XRefExternal>. (<DefinedTermFr>service de télécommunication</DefinedTermFr> )</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Fees and Adjustments</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>A telecommunications service provider shall, in every calendar year and within 30 days after the date of the invoice sent by the Commission, pay to the Commission the annual fee calculated in accordance with subsection 3(1), the supplementary fee calculated in accordance with subsection 3(2) and the annual adjustment calculated in accordance with subsection 3(5) if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the telecommunications service provider was in operation on April 1 of the year; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the telecommunications service provider had at least $10 million in Canadian telecommunications services revenues for its fiscal year ending in the preceding calendar year or is one of a group of related telecommunications service providers which in the aggregate had at least $10 million in Canadian telecommunications services revenues for its fiscal year ending in the preceding calendar year.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The annual fee shall be the amount determined by the formula</Text><FormulaGroup><Formula><FormulaText>A/B × C</FormulaText></Formula><FormulaConnector>where</FormulaConnector><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>A</FormulaTerm><Text>is the telecommunications service provider’s contribution-eligible revenues for its fiscal year ending in the preceding calendar year;</Text></FormulaDefinition><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>B</FormulaTerm><Text>is the aggregate of the contribution-eligible revenues for the fiscal year ending in the preceding calendar year of the telecommunications service providers that are required to pay under section 2; and</Text></FormulaDefinition><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>C</FormulaTerm><Text>is the estimated total regulatory costs of the Commission for the fiscal year as set out in the Commission’s Expenditure Plan published in Part III of the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Estimates</XRefExternal> of the Government of Canada.</Text></FormulaDefinition></FormulaGroup></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The supplementary fee shall be the amount determined by the formula</Text><FormulaGroup><Formula><FormulaText>A/B × D</FormulaText></Formula><FormulaConnector>where</FormulaConnector><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>A</FormulaTerm><Text>is the telecommunications service provider’s contribution-eligible revenues for its fiscal year ending in the preceding calendar year;</Text></FormulaDefinition><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>B</FormulaTerm><Text>is the aggregate of the contribution-eligible revenues for the fiscal year ending in the preceding calendar year of the telecommunications service providers that are required to pay under section 2; and</Text></FormulaDefinition><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>D</FormulaTerm><Text>is the supplementary estimated regulatory costs of the Commission for the fiscal year as set out in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Supplementary Estimates</XRefExternal> of the Government of Canada.</Text></FormulaDefinition></FormulaGroup></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The regulatory costs of the Commission for the fiscal year is the sum of the following amounts:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the costs of the Commission’s Telecommunications Activity; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the share</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>of the costs of the Commission’s administrative activities that is attributable to its Telecommunications Activity, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>of the other costs that are taken into account to arrive at the net cost of the Commission’s program that is attributable to its Telecommunications Activity.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The Commission shall publish, each year, the estimated total regulatory costs referred to in subsection (1) and the supplementary estimated regulatory costs referred to in subsection (2) in a public notice in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>, Part I.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>The annual adjustment shall be determined by the following formula:</Text><FormulaGroup><Formula><FormulaText>A/B × E</FormulaText></Formula><FormulaConnector>where</FormulaConnector><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>A</FormulaTerm><Text>is the telecommunications service provider’s contribution-eligible revenues;</Text></FormulaDefinition><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>B</FormulaTerm><Text>is the aggregate of contribution-eligible revenues of the telecommunications service providers that are required to pay under section 2; and</Text></FormulaDefinition><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>E</FormulaTerm><Text>is the difference between the sum of the estimated regulatory costs referred to in subsections (1) and (2) and the actual total regulatory costs for the fiscal year.</Text></FormulaDefinition></FormulaGroup></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(6)</Label><Text>The annual adjustment amount shall be charged or credited to the telecommunications service provider in the following year’s invoice and shall not result in a disbursement of monies on the part of the Commission.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Transitional</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>A telecommunications service provider who is required to pay an annual adjustment under the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Telecommunications Fees Regulations, 1995</XRefExternal> for the fiscal year ending on March 31, 2010 shall pay that adjustment within 30 days after the date of the invoice sent by the Commission.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Repeal</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>[Repeal]</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section type="transitional"><Label>6</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on April 1, 2010.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>