<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/89-512</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1989</YYYY><MM>10</MM><DD>24</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>1</MM><DD>16</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">FARM PRODUCTS AGENCIES ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Canadian Broiler Hatching Egg (Interprovincial) Pricing Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting the Pricing of Broiler Hatching Eggs Marketed in Interprovincial Trade</LongTitle></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Whereas the Governor in Council has, by the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Canadian Broiler Hatching Egg Marketing Agency Proclamation</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-89-512_e_hq_3640">*</FootnoteRef>, established the Canadian Broiler Hatching Egg Marketing Agency pursuant to subsection 16(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Farm Products Marketing Agencies Act</XRefExternal>;</Text><Footnote id="fn_SOR-89-512_e_hq_3640" placement="page" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>SOR/87-40, 1987 <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal> Part II, p. 317</Text></Footnote></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" list-item="no" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas the Canadian Broiler Hatching Egg Marketing Agency has been empowered to implement a marketing plan pursuant to the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Canadian Broiler Hatching Egg Marketing Agency Proclamation</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-89-512_e_hq_3640">*</FootnoteRef>;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" list-item="no" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas, the proposed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting the pricing of broiler hatching eggs marketed in Interprovincial Trade</XRefExternal> set out in the schedule hereto are of a class to which paragraph 7(1)(d) of the said Act applies by reason of section 2 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Agencies’ Orders and Regulations Approval Order</XRefExternal>, C.R.C., c. 648, and have been submitted to the National Farm Products Marketing Council pursuant to paragraph 22(1)(f) of the said Act;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" list-item="no" language-align="yes"><Text>And Whereas, pursuant to paragraph 7(1)(d) of the said Act, the National Farm Products Marketing Council is satisfied that the proposed Regulations are necessary for the implementation of the marketing plan that the Canadian Broiler Hatching Egg Marketing Agency is authorized to implement and has approved the proposed Regulations on October 3, 1989.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" list-item="no" language-align="yes"><Text>Therefore, the Canadian Broiler Hatching Egg Marketing Agency, pursuant to paragraph 22(1)(f) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Farm Products Marketing Agencies Act </XRefExternal>and section 9 of the schedule to the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Canadian Broiler Hatching Egg Marketing Agency Proclamation</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-89-512_e_hq_3640">*</FootnoteRef>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting the pricing of broiler hatching eggs marketed in interprovincial trade</XRefExternal>, effective December 1, 1989.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" list-item="no" language-align="yes"><Text>Ottawa, Ontario, October 20, 1989</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Canadian Broiler Hatching Egg (Interprovincial) Pricing Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>broiler hatching egg</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2013-256, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Commodity Board</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2013-256, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>hatchability</DefinedTermEn> means the percentage of saleable chicks obtained from the incubation of broiler hatching eggs as established for each province by the Department of Agriculture and Agri-Food and published by that Department in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Hatchery Review</XRefExternal>. (<DefinedTermFr>coefficient d’éclosion</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>non-signatory provinces</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2013-256, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>signatory provinces</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2013-256, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2016-290, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2008-10, s. 1; SOR/2013-256, s. 1; SOR/2016-290, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Minimum Price</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>No person shall sell into a signatory province broiler hatching eggs produced in another signatory province at a price per dozen broiler hatching eggs that is less than the aggregate of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>where the Commodity Board of the province of production has established a minimum price for the marketing of broiler hatching eggs in intraprovincial trade on the basis of</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>a dozen broiler hatching eggs, the minimum price established for a dozen broiler hatching eggs in effect in the province of production at the time of the sale, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>a saleable chick, the minimum price established for a saleable chick that is in effect in the province of production at the time of the sale, multiplied by 12 times the hatchability, during the year preceding the year of the sale, for the province of production; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the actual cost of transporting the broiler hatching eggs from the vendor’s premises in the province of production to the purchaser’s premises in the other signatory province.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>Subject to section 5, no person shall sell into a signatory province broiler hatching eggs produced in a non-signatory province at a price per dozen broiler hatching eggs that is less than the aggregate of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>where the person sells broiler hatching eggs in intraprovincial trade on the basis of</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>a dozen broiler hatching eggs, the average price for a dozen broiler hatching eggs charged by the person in the province of production during the four week period immediately preceding the week of the sale, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>a saleable chick, the average price for a saleable chick charged by the person in the province of production during the four week period immediately preceding the week of the sale, multiplied by 12 times the hatchability, during the year preceding the year of the sale, for the province of production; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the actual cost of transporting the broiler hatching eggs from the vendor’s premises in the province of production to the purchaser’s premises in the signatory province.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>Where a person has not sold broiler hatching eggs produced in a non-signatory province in intraprovincial trade during the four week period referred to in section 4, the person shall not sell into a signatory province broiler hatching eggs produced in the non-signatory province at a price per dozen broiler hatching eggs that is less than the aggregate of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>where the person intends to sell broiler hatching eggs into the signatory province on the basis of</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>a dozen broiler hatching eggs, the market price for a dozen broiler hatching eggs payable at the time of the sale in the ordinary course of trade in the province of production, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>a saleable chick, the market price for a saleable chick payable at the time of the sale in the ordinary course of trade in the province of production, multiplied by 12 times the hatchability, during the year preceding the year of the sale, for the province of production; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the actual cost of transporting the broiler hatching eggs from the vendor’s premises in the province of production to the purchaser’s premises in the signatory province.</Text></Paragraph></Section></Body></Regulation>