<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/86-873</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1986</YYYY><MM>8</MM><DD>14</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><LastAmendedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>14</DD></Date></LastAmendedDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2006</YYYY><MM>3</MM><DD>20</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CUSTOMS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Reporting of Imported Goods Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting the Reporting of Imported Goods</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1986-1842</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1986</YYYY><MM>8</MM><DD>13</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas, pursuant to subsection 164(3) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Act</XRefExternal>, a copy of proposed Regulations, substantially in the form annexed hereto, was published in Part I of the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal> on March 29, 1986 and a reasonable opportunity was thereby afforded to interested persons to make representations with respect thereto to the Minister of National Revenue.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Therefore, Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of National Revenue, pursuant to section 12, subsections 14(2) and 18(2) and paragraph 164(1)(i) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_1e">*</FootnoteRef>, is pleased hereby to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting the reporting of imported goods</XRefExternal>, effective on the coming into force of section 12, subsections 14(2) and 18(2) and paragraph 164(1)(i) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Act</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fn_1e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>S.C. 1986, c. 1</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Reporting of Imported Goods Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Act</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>ACI Marine Client Document</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2006-148, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>airport of arrival</DefinedTermEn> means the customs office in Canada at which a carrier that operates an aircraft expects a report to be made under section 12 of the Act with respect to goods imported on board that aircraft; (<DefinedTermFr>aéroport d’arrivée</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>break-bulk goods</DefinedTermEn> means specified goods other than</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>goods within cargo containers,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>bulk goods, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>empty cargo containers; (<DefinedTermFr>marchandises diverses</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>bulk goods</DefinedTermEn> means, in respect of goods transported by a vessel, goods that are loose or in mass, such that they are confined only by the permanent structures of the vessel, without intermediate containment or intermediate packaging; (<DefinedTermFr>marchandises en vrac</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>cargo container</DefinedTermEn> means a container that</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>is fully or partially enclosed to constitute a receptacle intended for containing goods,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>is of a permanent character and is suitable for repeated use,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>is designed to carry goods, by one or more modes of transport, without intermediate reloading, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>has an internal volume of one or more cubic metres,</Text></Paragraph><ContinuedDefinition><Text>and includes the ancillary equipment of the container — provided that the ancillary equipment is carried with the container — and demountable bodies; (<DefinedTermFr>conteneur</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></ContinuedDefinition></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>CBSA</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2006-155, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>chief officer of customs</DefinedTermEn>, with respect to an area or place, means the manager of the customs office or customs offices that serve that area or place; (<DefinedTermFr>agent en chef des douanes</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>commercial driver</DefinedTermEn> has the same meaning as in section 1 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Presentation of Persons (2003) Regulations</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>routier</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>commercial goods</DefinedTermEn> means goods that are or will be imported for sale or for any commercial, industrial, occupational, institutional or other similar use; (<DefinedTermFr>marchandises commerciales</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>commercial passenger conveyance</DefinedTermEn> has the same meaning as in section 1 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Presentation of Persons (2003) Regulations</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>moyen de transport commercial de passagers</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>corporate aircraft</DefinedTermEn> has the same meaning as in section 1 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Presentation of Persons (2003) Regulations</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>aéronef d’affaires</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>courier</DefinedTermEn> has the same meaning as in section 2 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Persons Authorized to Account for Casual Goods Regulations</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>messager</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>CSA carrier</DefinedTermEn> has the same meaning as in section 2 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Accounting for Imported Goods and Payment of Duties Regulations</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>transporteur PAD</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>CSA importer</DefinedTermEn> has the same meaning as in section 2 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Accounting for Imported Goods and Payment of Duties Regulations</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>importateur PAD</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>designated customs office</DefinedTermEn> means a place designated under section 5 of the Act as a customs office where goods may be reported under section 12 of the Act; (<DefinedTermFr>bureau de douane établi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>designated holding area</DefinedTermEn> means a room or other area designated by the President for the use of persons arriving in Canada who are in transit to another place in Canada or to a place outside Canada; (<DefinedTermFr>zone d’attente désignée</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn><XRefExternal reference-type="other">Electronic Commerce Client Requirements Document</XRefExternal></DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Electronic Commerce Client Requirements Document</XRefExternal> established by the Agency, as amended from time to time; (<DefinedTermFr><XRefExternal reference-type="other">Document sur les exigences à l’égard des clients du commerce électronique</XRefExternal></DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>eligible goods</DefinedTermEn> has the same meaning as in section 2 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Accounting for Imported Goods and Payment of Duties Regulations</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>marchandises admissibles</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>emergency conveyance</DefinedTermEn> means a conveyance that is clearly marked for use for emergency purposes, such as a vehicle that is clearly marked as a fire-fighting or police vehicle or as an ambulance; (<DefinedTermFr>moyen de transport de secours</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>fishing vessel</DefinedTermEn> has the same meaning as in section 2 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Fisheries Act</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>bateau de pêche</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>freight forwarder</DefinedTermEn> means a person who, on behalf of one or more owners, importers, shippers or consignees of goods, causes specified goods to be transported by one or more carriers; (<DefinedTermFr>agent d’expédition</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>international commercial transportation</DefinedTermEn> means</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any transportation resulting in, or intended to result in, the carriage of persons or goods for hire or reward, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any transportation of persons or goods by or on behalf of an enterprise engaged in an activity of financial return,</Text></Paragraph><ContinuedDefinition><Text>where the persons or goods are conveyed</Text></ContinuedDefinition><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>from a place outside Canada to a place inside Canada,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>from a place inside Canada to a place outside Canada, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>from a place outside Canada in transit through Canada to a place outside Canada; (<DefinedTermFr>transport commercial international</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>List of Tariff Provisions</DefinedTermEn> means the List of Tariff Provisions set out in the schedule to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>liste des dispositions tarifaires</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>marine pleasure craft</DefinedTermEn> has the same meaning as in section 1 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Presentation of Persons (2003) Regulations</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>embarcation de plaisance</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>NAV CANADA</DefinedTermEn> means the corporation that was incorporated as NAV CANADA on May 26, 1995 under Part II of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Corporations Act</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>NAV CANADA</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>participants’ requirements document</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2006-155, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>port of arrival</DefinedTermEn> means the customs office in Canada at which a carrier that operates a vessel expects a report to be made under section 12 of the Act with respect to goods imported on board that vessel; (<DefinedTermFr>port d’arrivée</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>private aircraft</DefinedTermEn> has the same meaning as in section 1 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Presentation of Persons (2003) Regulations</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>aéronef privé</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>specified goods</DefinedTermEn> means commercial goods, goods that are or will be imported to Canada for a fee or empty cargo containers that are not for sale but does not include</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>goods that will be released after they have been accounted for and all duties with respect to them have been paid under subsection 32(1) of the Act if</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the goods are or will be in the actual possession of a person arriving in Canada, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the goods form or will form part of a person’s baggage and the person and the baggage arrive or will arrive in Canada on board the same conveyance,</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>mail,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>commercial goods that are used in a repair that is made outside Canada to a conveyance that was built in Canada or in respect of which duties have been paid, if the repair is made as a result of an unforeseen contingency that occurs outside Canada and is necessary to enable the conveyance to return safely to Canada,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a military conveyance as defined in subsection 18(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canadian Transportation Accident Investigation and Safety Board Act</XRefExternal> or goods that are transported on board that conveyance,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>an emergency conveyance or goods that are transported on board that conveyance, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>a conveyance that returns to Canada immediately after being denied entry to the United States or goods that are transported on board that conveyance; (<DefinedTermFr>marchandises spécifiées</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>time of departure</DefinedTermEn>, in respect of an aircraft, means the eastern standard time or, if it is in effect, the eastern daylight savings time at which the aircraft leaves the gate or dock of the airport of departure and, if the aircraft is not departing from a gate or dock, the time at which the blocks are removed from the wheels of the aircraft before its departure. (<DefinedTermFr>heure du départ</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>vessel</DefinedTermEn> means</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any ship, vessel, dredge, scow, yacht, boat or other water-borne craft, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any floating submersible or semi-submersible structure such as a dock, caisson, pontoon, coffer-dam, production platform, drilling ship, drilling barge, drilling rig, jack-up drilling ship, jack-up drilling platform or other drilling platform. (<DefinedTermFr>bateau</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2008-25, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Paragraph></Definition><HistoricalNote>SOR/88-77, s. 1; SOR/96-156, s. 1; SOR/98-53, s. 2; SOR/2005-175, s. 1; SOR/2005-303, s. 1; SOR/2005-387, s. 1; SOR/2006-148, s. 1; SOR/2006-155, ss. 1, 6; SOR/2008-25, s. 1; SOR/2015-90, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>2.1</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a shipment for which a carrier is responsible consists of</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>a specified good or collection of specified goods that is listed in a single bill of lading, waybill or similar document that is issued by the carrier and that relates to the carriage of those goods by the carrier, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>a specified good that is an empty cargo container that is not for sale and that is transported by the carrier but is not listed in a bill of lading, waybill or similar document; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a shipment for which a freight forwarder is responsible consists of a specified good or collection of specified goods that is listed in a single bill of lading, waybill or similar document that is issued by the freight forwarder and that relates to the carriage of those goods.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2005-175, s. 2; SOR/2015-90, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Time for Reporting Goods</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>Except as otherwise provided in these Regulations, all goods that are imported shall be reported under section 12 of the Act without delay after arrival in Canada.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/96-156, s. 2(F); SOR/2015-90, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>3.1</Label><Text>Subject to sections 8 and 9, specified goods that are imported by water shall be reported under section 12 of the Act without delay after the vessel that is transporting them lands at a customs office following arrival in Canada.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>3.2</Label><Text>Specified goods that are imported by air shall be reported under section 12 of the Act without delay after the aircraft that is transporting them is cleared by NAV CANADA to land at an airport following arrival in Canada.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Manner of Reporting Goods</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>Unless a person is required to report goods in writing under section 5 or is permitted to report them orally under that section or in writing under section 12, they shall report the goods to the Agency by electronic means in accordance with the technical requirements, specifications and procedures that are set out in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Electronic Commerce Client Requirements Document</XRefExternal>.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/96-156, s. 4; SOR/2006-155, s. 2; SOR/2015-90, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>5</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsections (2) to (4), the following goods may be reported orally unless an officer requires the importer of the goods to report the goods in writing:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>goods in the actual possession of a person arriving in Canada, or that form part of his baggage where the person and his baggage are being carried on board the same conveyance;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>fishing vessels;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b.1)</Label><Text>eligible goods that meet the requirements for release under paragraph 32(2)(b) of the Act if they are reported by a CSA carrier or if they are transported into Canada by a commercial highway conveyance as defined in section 1 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Presentation of Persons (2003) Regulations</XRefExternal> and are reported by the driver of the conveyance who holds an authorization under those Regulations;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>foreign based cargo containers engaged in international commercial transportation that are imported</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>under the control of a person who maintains an inventory of the containers that are used in international commercial transportation where the person</Text><Clause><Label>(A)</Label><Text>keeps records of all containers imported into Canada that would enable a customs officer to verify that the containers were not used in Canadian domestic service or that, if they were used in Canadian domestic service, all applicable duties thereon were paid, and</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(B)</Label><Text>permits the customs officer access to the records of the containers referred to in clause (A), or</Text></Clause></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>by a person who leases containers for use in international commercial transportation where the person</Text><Clause><Label>(A)</Label><Text>keeps records of all containers imported into Canada that would enable a customs officer to verify that the containers were not used in Canadian domestic service or that, if they were used in Canadian domestic service, all applicable duties thereon were paid, and</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(B)</Label><Text>permits the customs officer access to the records of the containers referred to in clause (A);</Text></Clause></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>Canadian-based highway vehicles, aircraft and cargo containers that are built in Canada, or in respect of which duties have been paid, and that qualify for entry into Canada at a free rate of customs duty as Canadian goods returned that are classified under tariff item No. 9813.00.00 or 9814.00.00 in the List of Tariff Provisions; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>goods in respect of which information has been given to the Agency under subsection 12.1(1) of the Act in the circumstances set out in subsection <XRefInternal>22</XRefInternal>(1) or <XRefInternal>23</XRefInternal>(1).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-90, s. 3]</Repealed></Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2005-387, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Goods that are imported by a person arriving in Canada on board a commercial passenger conveyance other than a bus shall be reported in writing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Goods in the actual possession of, or that form part of the baggage of, a crew member arriving in Canada aboard a freight train shall be reported in writing.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/88-77, s. 2; SOR/95-409, s. 2; SOR/96-156, s. 5; SOR/98-53, s. 3; SOR/2005-175, s. 3; SOR/2005-387, s. 2; SOR/2006-148, s. 2; SOR/2006-155, s. 3; SOR/2015-90, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Exceptions to Reporting at the Nearest Customs Office</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-90, s. 4]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>7</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Goods in the actual possession of a person arriving in Canada aboard a commercial passenger conveyance who has as his destination a place outside Canada, and any goods being carried on board the same conveyance and forming part of his baggage, do not have to be reported, on condition that</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the person does not disembark from the conveyance in Canada and the goods are not removed from the conveyance in Canada other than to be transferred under customs control directly to another commercial passenger conveyance for departure to a place outside Canada or directly to a designated holding area; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>where the person and goods are transferred under customs control directly to a designated holding area, the person does not leave and the goods are not removed from that designated holding area other than to board or to be loaded on board a commercial passenger conveyance for departure to a place outside Canada.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Goods in the actual possession of a person arriving in Canada aboard a commercial passenger conveyance who has as his destination another place in Canada at which there is a designated customs office, and any goods being carried on board the same conveyance and forming part of his baggage, may be reported at that designated customs office on condition that</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the person does not disembark from the conveyance at the place of arrival in Canada and the goods are not removed from the conveyance at the place of arrival in Canada other than to be transferred under customs control directly to another commercial passenger conveyance for departure to that other place in Canada or directly to a designated holding area; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>where the person and goods are transferred under customs control directly to a designated holding area, the person does not leave and the goods are not removed from that designated holding area other than to board or to be loaded on board a commercial passenger conveyance for departure to that other place in Canada.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2006-155, s. 4(F).</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>7.1</Label><Text>Goods in the actual possession of, or that form part of the baggage of, a crew member arriving in Canada aboard a freight train shall be reported forthwith at a place specified by an officer.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/96-156, s. 6.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>7.2</Label><Text>If goods are reported under section 12 of the Act by electronic means, the report is not required to be made at the nearest customs office designated for that purpose.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 5.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Periodic Reporting</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>8</Label><Text>Canadian-built commercial fishing vessels and duty-paid fishing vessels that are registered under the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Shipping Act, 2001</XRefExternal> and that are imported during a fishing season may be reported at the close of that fishing season if the vessels do not, after last having been reported under section 9 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Reporting of Exported Goods Regulations</XRefExternal>,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>take on ships stores other than diesel fuel;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>land in a country other than Canada; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>pick up goods that are not the product of Canada and that have not been reported under section 12 of the Act.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 6.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>9</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A vessel that is used on a day solely or principally to transport highway conveyances or passengers across international waters may be reported on that day after the vessel’s last trip.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Subsection (1) does not apply if the vessel transports specified goods to Canada that are required to be reported by the person in charge of the vessel.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/88-77, s. 3; SOR/2015-90, s. 7.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>10</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-90, s. 7]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>11</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Goods imported by means of a pipeline used by one importer only during any period commencing on the 20th day of one month and ending on the 19th day of the month next following may be reported on or before the last day of that month.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Goods that are part of a shipment of goods imported by means of a pipeline used by more than one importer may be reported forthwith on arrival of the whole shipment.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/87-579, s. 1(F).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Report of Goods Unloaded Prior to Report</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>12</Label><Text>If a conveyance is unloaded in the circumstances set out in subsection 14(1) of the Act, the conveyance and the goods described in subsection 14(2) of the Act shall be reported under that subsection by telephone or other expedient means. The conveyance and goods shall then be reported under section 12 of the Act in writing or by electronic means without delay.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 8.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>12.1</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-90, s. 8]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>12.2</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-90, s. 8]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>12.3</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-90, s. 8]</Repealed></Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Information Required — Transport of Specified Goods</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Marine Mode</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Carrier</TitleText><HistoricalNote>[SOR/2015-90, s. 29]</HistoricalNote></Heading><Section><Label>13</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>If specified goods will be transported to Canada by vessel, the carrier that operates the vessel is required under subsection 12.1(1) of the Act to give the Agency</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the information set out in Part 1 of Schedule 1;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each shipment for which the carrier is responsible, the information set out in Part 1 of Schedule 2 in connection with the vessel and the goods in the shipment; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the information set out in Schedule 3 if there is a cargo container on board the vessel.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Despite subsection (1), the carrier is not required to give the information if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the vessel will arrive in Canada directly from the United States or Mexico;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>every importer of the specified goods is a CSA importer;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the carrier is a CSA carrier;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>every importer of the specified goods has given written instructions to the carrier to submit a request to the Agency for the release of those goods under paragraph 32(2)(b) of the Act; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>no federal or provincial Act or regulation requires that a permit, licence or similar document be provided to the Agency before any of the specified goods are released.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/88-77, s. 3(E); SOR/2006-148, s. 5; SOR/2015-90, ss. 8, 30.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>13.1</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-90, s. 8]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>13.2</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-90, s. 8]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>13.3</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-90, s. 8]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>13.4</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-90, s. 8]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>13.5</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-90, s. 8]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>13.6</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-90, s. 8]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>13.7</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-90, s. 8]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>13.71</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-90, s. 8]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>13.8</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-90, s. 8]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>13.81</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-90, s. 8]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>13.82</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-90, s. 8]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>13.83</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-90, s. 8]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>13.84</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-90, s. 8]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>13.85</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-90, s. 8]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>13.86</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-90, s. 8]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>13.87</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-90, s. 8]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>13.88</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-90, s. 8]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>13.89</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-90, s. 8]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>13.9</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-90, s. 8]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>13.91</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-90, s. 8]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>14</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The carrier shall give the Agency the information set out in Part 1 of Schedule 1</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>at least 96 hours before the vessel is scheduled to arrive at its port of arrival if there is a cargo container on board the vessel; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>at least 24 hours before the vessel is scheduled to arrive at its port of arrival in any other case.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Despite subsection (1), if the vessel will arrive in Canada directly from the United States or Puerto Rico and all of the shipments for which the carrier is responsible were loaded onto it in the United States or Puerto Rico, the carrier shall give the information</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>at least four hours before the vessel is scheduled to arrive at its port of arrival if all of those shipments consist of empty cargo containers that are not for sale; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>at least 24 hours before the vessel is scheduled to arrive at its port of arrival in any other case.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Despite subsections (1) and (2), the carrier shall give the information before or at the time the vessel leaves the last foreign port before its arrival in Canada if the duration of the voyage from that foreign port to the vessel’s port of arrival is less than the period within which the information would otherwise be given.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 8.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>15</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The carrier shall give the Agency the information set out in Part 1 of Schedule 2</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>at least 24 hours before the shipment is loaded onto the vessel if all or part of the shipment is in a cargo container or if the shipment consists of one or more empty cargo containers that are for sale;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>at least 24 hours before the vessel is scheduled to arrive at its port of arrival if the shipment consists of either bulk goods or break-bulk goods; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>at least 96 hours before the vessel is scheduled to arrive at its port of arrival if the shipment consists of an empty cargo container that is not for sale.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Despite subsection (1), if the vessel will arrive in Canada directly from the United States or Puerto Rico and the shipment was loaded onto it in the United States or Puerto Rico, the carrier shall give the information</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>at least four hours before the vessel is scheduled to arrive at its port of arrival if the shipment consists of an empty cargo container that is not for sale; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>at least 24 hours before the vessel is scheduled to arrive at its port of arrival in any other case.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Despite paragraphs (1)(b) and (c) and subsection (2), the carrier shall give the information before or at the time the vessel leaves the last foreign port before its arrival in Canada if the duration of the voyage from that foreign port to the vessel’s port of arrival is less than the period within which the information would otherwise be given.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 8.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>15.1</Label><Text>The carrier shall give the Agency the information set out in Schedule 3 within 48 hours after the vessel leaves the last foreign port before its arrival in Canada.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 31.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Freight Forwarder</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>15.2</Label><Text>If one or more shipments for which a freight forwarder is responsible will be transported to Canada by vessel, the freight forwarder is required under subsection 12.1(1) of the Act to give the Agency, for each shipment,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the information set out in Part 1.1 of Schedule 2 if the vessel will travel from a place outside Canada through Canada to another place outside Canada and the shipment will remain on board the vessel while the vessel is in Canada; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the information set out in Part 4 of Schedule 2 if the shipment will be unloaded from the vessel either to remain in Canada or to be transported on board another conveyance to a place outside Canada.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 31.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>15.3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The freight forwarder shall give the Agency the information</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>at least 24 hours before the shipment is loaded onto the vessel if all or part of the shipment is in a cargo container; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>at least 24 hours before the vessel is scheduled to arrive at its port of arrival in any other case.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Despite paragraph (1)(a), if the vessel will arrive in Canada directly from the United States or Puerto Rico and the shipment was loaded onto it in the United States or Puerto Rico, the freight forwarder shall give the information at least 24 hours before the vessel is scheduled to arrive at its port of arrival.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Despite paragraph (1)(b) and subsection (2), the freight forwarder shall give the information before or at the time the vessel leaves the last foreign port before its arrival in Canada if the duration of the voyage from that foreign port to the vessel’s port of arrival is less than 24 hours.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 31.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Air Mode</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Carrier</TitleText><HistoricalNote>[SOR/2015-90, s. 32]</HistoricalNote></Heading><Section><Label>16</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>If specified goods will be transported to Canada by aircraft, the carrier that operates the aircraft is required under subsection 12.1(1) of the Act to give the Agency</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the information set out in Part 2 of Schedule 1; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each shipment for which the carrier is responsible, the information set out in Part 2 of Schedule 2 in connection with the aircraft and the goods in the shipment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Despite subsection (1), the carrier is not required to give the information if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the aircraft will arrive in Canada directly from the United States or Mexico;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>every importer of the specified goods is a CSA importer;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the carrier is a CSA carrier;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>every importer of the specified goods has given written instructions to the carrier to submit a request to the Agency for the release of those goods under paragraph 32(2)(b) of the Act; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>no federal or provincial Act or regulation requires that a permit, licence or similar document be provided to the Agency before any of the specified goods are released.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Despite subsection (1), the carrier is not required to give the information set out in Part 2 of Schedule 2 for a shipment if it consists of goods that the carrier will transport as or on behalf of a courier and those goods will be released under subsection 32(4) of the Act before the accounting required under subsection 32(1) of the Act and the payment of duties.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 8.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>17</Label><Text>The carrier shall give the Agency the information no later than four hours before the aircraft is scheduled to arrive at its airport of arrival or, if the duration of the flight to Canada is less than four hours, no later than the aircraft’s time of departure.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 8.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Freight Forwarder</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>17.1</Label><Text>If one or more shipments for which a freight forwarder is responsible will be transported to Canada by aircraft, the freight forwarder is required under subsection 12.1(1) of the Act to give the Agency, for each shipment,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the information set out in Part 2.1 of Schedule 2 if the aircraft will travel from a place outside Canada through Canada to another place outside Canada and the shipment will remain on board the aircraft while the aircraft is in Canada; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the information set out in Part 4 of Schedule 2 if the shipment will be unloaded from the aircraft either to remain in Canada or to be transported on board another conveyance to a place outside Canada.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 33.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>17.2</Label><Text>The freight forwarder shall give the Agency the information no later than four hours before the aircraft is scheduled to arrive at its airport of arrival or, if the duration of the flight to Canada is less than four hours, no later than the aircraft’s time of departure.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 33.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Highway Mode</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Carrier</TitleText><HistoricalNote>[SOR/2015-90, s. 34]</HistoricalNote></Heading><Section><Label>18</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>If specified goods will be transported to Canada by a highway conveyance, the carrier that operates the conveyance is required under subsection 12.1(1) of the Act to give the Agency</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the information set out in Part 3 of Schedule 1; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each shipment for which the carrier is responsible, the information set out in Part 3 of Schedule 2.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Despite subsection (1), the carrier is not required to give the information if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the conveyance will arrive in Canada directly from the United States or Mexico;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>every importer of the specified goods is a CSA importer;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the carrier is a CSA carrier and the person in charge of the conveyance is a commercial driver who holds an authorization under section 6.2 or 6.21 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Presentation of Persons (2003) Regulations</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>every importer of the specified goods has given written instructions to the carrier to submit a request to the Agency for the release of those goods under paragraph 32(2)(b) of the Act; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>no federal or provincial Act or regulation requires that a permit, licence or similar document be provided to the Agency before any of the specified goods are released.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Despite subsection (1), the carrier is not required to give the information set out in Part 3 of Schedule 2 for a shipment if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>it consists of goods that the carrier will transport as or on behalf of a courier and those goods will be released under subsection 32(4) of the Act before the accounting required under subsection 32(1) of the Act and the payment of duties;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>it consists of an empty cargo container that is not for sale;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>it is listed in an air bill of lading, air waybill or similar document that is issued by a carrier and that relates to the carriage of the shipment to Canada by air but it will arrive in Canada on board the highway conveyance;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the highway conveyance that transports the shipment will travel from a place in the United States through Canada to another place in the United States and no specified good will be unloaded from the conveyance in Canada; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the highway conveyance that transports the shipment will travel from a place in Canada through the United States to another place in Canada and no specified good will be unloaded from the conveyance in the United States.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 8.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>19</Label><Text>The carrier shall give the Agency the information at least one hour before the highway conveyance arrives in Canada.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 8.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Freight Forwarder</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>19.1</Label><Text>If one or more shipments for which a freight forwarder is responsible will be transported to Canada by a highway conveyance, the freight forwarder is required under subsection 12.1(1) of the Act to give the Agency, for each shipment, the information set out in Part 4 of Schedule 2.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 35.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>19.2</Label><Text>The freight forwarder shall give the Agency the information at least one hour before the highway conveyance arrives in Canada.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 35.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Rail Mode</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Carrier</TitleText><HistoricalNote>[SOR/2015-90, s. 36]</HistoricalNote></Heading><Section><Label>20</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>If specified goods will be transported to Canada by a rail conveyance, the carrier that operates the conveyance is required under subsection 12.1(1) of the Act to give the Agency</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the information set out in Part 4 of Schedule 1; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each shipment for which the carrier is responsible, the information set out in Part 3 of Schedule 2.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Despite subsection (1), the carrier is not required to give the information if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the conveyance will arrive in Canada directly from the United States or Mexico;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>every importer of the specified goods is a CSA importer;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the carrier is a CSA carrier;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>every importer of the specified goods has given written instructions to the carrier to submit a request to the Agency for the release of those goods under paragraph 32(2)(b) of the Act; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>no federal or provincial Act or regulation requires that a permit, licence or similar document be provided to the Agency before any of the specified goods are released.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Despite subsection (1), the carrier is not required to give the information set out in Part 3 of Schedule 2 for a shipment if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>it consists of goods that the carrier will transport as or on behalf of a courier and those goods will be released under subsection 32(4) of the Act before the accounting required under subsection 32(1) of the Act and the payment of duties;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>it consists of an empty cargo container that is not for sale;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the rail car that carries the shipment will travel from a place in the United States through Canada to another place in the United States and no specified good will be unloaded from it in Canada; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the rail car that carries the shipment will travel from a place in Canada through the United States to another place in Canada and no specified good will be unloaded from it in the United States.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 8.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>21</Label><Text>The carrier shall give the Agency the information at least two hours before the rail conveyance arrives in Canada.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 8.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Freight Forwarder</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>21.1</Label><Text>If one or more shipments for which a freight forwarder is responsible will be transported to Canada by a rail conveyance, the freight forwarder is required under subsection 12.1(1) of the Act to give the Agency, for each shipment, the information set out in Part 4 of Schedule 2.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 37.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>21.2</Label><Text>The freight forwarder shall give the Agency the information at least two hours before the rail conveyance arrives in Canada.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 37.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Information Required — Other Circumstances</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>22</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>If a marine pleasure craft will arrive in Canada with no specified goods on board and the person in charge of the marine pleasure craft is authorized to present themselves in the alternative manner described in paragraph 11(e) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Presentation of Persons (2003) Regulations</XRefExternal>, that person is required under subsection 12.1(1) of the Act to give the Agency the time and place at which the marine pleasure craft is scheduled to land following arrival in Canada and a description of all of the goods carried on board, including their value and quantity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The person in charge of the marine pleasure craft shall give the information by telephone to an officer at a designated customs office at least 30 minutes but no more than four hours before the marine pleasure craft arrives in Canada.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The person in charge of the marine pleasure craft shall, before it arrives in Canada, notify an officer at a designated customs office by telephone of any change to the information given unless there are emergency circumstances, in which case they shall notify an officer at a designated customs office of the change, and explain the circumstances, by telephone when the marine pleasure craft arrives in Canada.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 8.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>23</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>If a corporate aircraft or private aircraft will arrive in Canada with no specified goods on board and the person in charge of the aircraft is authorized to present themselves in an alternative manner described in paragraph 11(b) or (c) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Presentation of Persons (2003) Regulations</XRefExternal>, that person is required under subsection 12.1(1) of the Act to give the Agency the time and place at which the aircraft is scheduled to land following arrival in Canada and a description of all of the goods carried on board, including their value and quantity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The person in charge of the aircraft shall give the information by telephone to an officer at a designated customs office at least two but no more than 48 hours before the aircraft arrives in Canada.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The person in charge of the aircraft shall, before it arrives in Canada, notify an officer at a designated customs office by telephone of any change to the information given unless there are emergency circumstances, in which case they shall notify an officer at a designated customs office of the change, and explain the circumstances, by telephone when the aircraft arrives in Canada.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 8.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>24</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>If a highway conveyance that is ordinarily used to transport specified goods to or from Canada will arrive in Canada with no specified goods on board, the carrier that operates the conveyance is required under subsection 12.1(1) of the Act to give the Agency the information set out in Part 3 of Schedule 1.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Despite subsection (1), the carrier is not required to give the information if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the conveyance is a tractor that is not towing a trailer; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the carrier is a CSA carrier and the person in charge of the conveyance is a commercial driver who holds an authorization under section 6.2 or 6.21 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Presentation of Persons (2003) Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The carrier shall give the information at least one hour before the highway conveyance arrives in Canada.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 8.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>25</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>If a rail conveyance that is ordinarily used to transport specified goods to or from Canada will arrive in Canada with no specified goods on board and either with no rail car or with all of its rail cars empty, the carrier that operates the conveyance is required under subsection 12.1(1) of the Act to give the Agency the information set out in Part 4 of Schedule 1.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The carrier shall give the information at least two hours before the rail conveyance arrives in Canada.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 8.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>26</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>If a rail conveyance that is ordinarily used to transport specified goods to or from Canada will arrive in Canada, a crew member on board the conveyance who will have goods in their actual possession or that form part of their baggage on arrival in Canada is required under subsection 12.1(1) of the Act to give the Agency the time and place at which the conveyance is scheduled to arrive in Canada.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The crew member shall give the information by radio or telephone to the chief officer of customs at the place at which the rail conveyance is scheduled to arrive in Canada at least two hours before it arrives.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 8.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>27</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>If a vessel, aircraft or rail conveyance is or will be used to transport 30 or more persons to Canada other than on a regular schedule or predetermined charter schedule, the carrier that operates the conveyance is required under subsection 12.1(1) of the Act to give the Agency the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in the case of a vessel, the time and place at which it is scheduled to land following arrival in Canada;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the case of an aircraft, the time and place at which it is scheduled to land following arrival in Canada; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>in the case of a rail conveyance, the time and place at which it is scheduled to arrive in Canada.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Despite paragraphs (1)(a) and (b), the carrier is not required to give the information when the person in charge of the conveyance is required to give it in the circumstances set out in subsection <XRefInternal>22</XRefInternal>(1) or <XRefInternal>23</XRefInternal>(1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The carrier shall give the information in writing to the chief officer of customs at the place referred to in paragraph (1)(a), (b) or (c), as the case may be, at least 72 hours before the conveyance arrives in Canada.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 8.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>General Provision Regarding Time for Giving Information Before Arrival</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>28</Label><Text>For greater certainty, nothing in any of sections <XRefInternal>13</XRefInternal> to <XRefInternal>27</XRefInternal> permits a person to give information to the Agency under subsection 12.1(1) of the Act on or after the arrival of the conveyance in Canada.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 8.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Manner of Giving Information Before Arrival</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>29</Label><Text>A person that is required to give information to the Agency under subsection 12.1(1) of the Act in the circumstances set out in section <XRefInternal>13</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>15.2</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>16</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>17.1</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>19.1</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>20</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>21.1</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>24</XRefInternal> or <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal> shall give the Agency the information by electronic means in accordance with the technical requirements, specifications and procedures that are set out in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Electronic Commerce Client Requirements Document</XRefExternal>.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, ss. 8, 38.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Corrections</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>30</Label><Text>A person that gives information to the Agency under subsection 12.1(1) of the Act in the circumstances set out in section <XRefInternal>13</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>15.2</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>16</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>17.1</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>19.1</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>20</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>21.1</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>24</XRefInternal> or <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal> shall, if they become aware that the information is inaccurate or incomplete, notify the Agency without delay by electronic means of a change to that information.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, ss. 8, 39.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Carrier Code</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>31</Label><Text>The requirements and conditions that are to be met before the Minister may issue a carrier code are the following:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>if the application is for a carrier code that would be held by the applicant as a carrier in connection with a mode of conveyance,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the applicant does not already hold a carrier code as a carrier in connection with that mode of conveyance,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>if a carrier code previously held by the applicant as a carrier in connection with that mode of conveyance was cancelled, the matter that gave rise to the cancellation has been corrected, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>the applicant expects to operate at least one conveyance of that mode that would ordinarily be used to transport specified goods to or from Canada; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>if the application is for a carrier code that would be held by the applicant as a freight forwarder,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the applicant does not already hold a carrier code as a freight forwarder,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>if a carrier code previously held by the applicant as a freight forwarder was cancelled, the matter that gave rise to the cancellation has been corrected, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>the applicant expects to cause specified goods to be transported to Canada.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 8.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>32</Label><Text>A person that holds a carrier code shall notify the Agency without delay of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a change to the information that is given in the application for the carrier code;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a merger or amalgamation with another person that holds a carrier code; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the cessation of a business activity to which the carrier code relates.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 8.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>33</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The circumstances in which the Minister may suspend a carrier code held by a person are the following:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the person contravenes</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>a provision of a federal Act or regulation if the provision relates to the importation or exportation of goods,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Immigration and Refugee Protection Act</XRefExternal> or a regulation made under it, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Proceeds of Crime (Money Laundering) and Terrorist Financing Act</XRefExternal> or a regulation made under it;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the person fails to pay an amount that is payable under the Act; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the person provided false or misleading information in the application for the carrier code.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The Minister shall notify the person that holds the carrier code without delay and in writing of the suspension of the carrier code, the period during which the suspension applies and the reasons for the suspension.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The person may make representations to the Minister within the period of suspension as to why the carrier code should be reinstated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The Minister may reinstate a carrier code that is suspended under subsection 12.1(5) of the Act only if the matter that gave rise to the suspension has been corrected during the period of suspension.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 8.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>34</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The circumstances in which the Minister may cancel a carrier code held by a person are the following:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the matter that gave rise to a suspension has not been corrected within the period of suspension;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the person has ceased all business activities to which the carrier code relates;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the person holds more than one carrier code as a carrier in connection with a particular mode of conveyance;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the person holds more than one carrier code as a freight forwarder;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the carrier code was issued before the coming into force of subsection 12.1(4) of the Act and the person holds it in a capacity other than that of a carrier or a freight forwarder, such as an agent or a person in charge of a conveyance; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>the person requests the cancellation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Before cancelling a carrier code, the Minister shall send written notice of the proposed cancellation and the reasons for it to the last known address of the person that holds the carrier code and, unless the carrier code is being cancelled in the circumstances set out in paragraph (1)(e) or (f), shall give the person the opportunity to make representations in writing as to why the carrier code should not be cancelled.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The cancellation of a carrier code is not effective until the earlier of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>30 days after the day on which the person that holds the carrier code receives the notice, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>45 days after the day on which the notice is sent.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 8.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>35</Label><Text>The following persons are exempted from holding a valid carrier code:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a person in charge of a marine pleasure craft in the circumstances set out either in subsection <XRefInternal>22</XRefInternal>(1) or in subsection 17(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Presentation of Persons (2003) Regulations</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a person in charge of a corporate aircraft or private aircraft in the circumstances set out either in subsection <XRefInternal>23</XRefInternal>(1) or in subsection 15(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Presentation of Persons (2003) Regulations</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a crew member of a rail conveyance that is ordinarily used to transport specified goods to or from Canada in the circumstances set out in subsection <XRefInternal>26</XRefInternal>(1);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a carrier that operates a vessel, aircraft or rail conveyance in the circumstances set out in subsection <XRefInternal>27</XRefInternal>(1); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>a person in charge of a non-commercial passenger conveyance in the circumstances set out in subsection 4(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Presentation of Persons (2003) Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 8.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Liability for Duties on Goods Reported</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>36</Label><Text>For the purposes of subsection 18(2) of the Act, proof that duties have been paid or of any of the events described in paragraphs (a) to (f) thereof shall be given in writing to an officer within 70 days after the date on which the duties are claimed to have been paid or the events are claimed to have happened.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 9.</HistoricalNote></Section></Body><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 1</Label><OriginatingRef>(Paragraph <XRefInternal>13</XRefInternal>(1)(a), subsection <XRefInternal>14</XRefInternal>(1), paragraphs <XRefInternal>16</XRefInternal>(1)(a), <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(1)(a) and <XRefInternal>20</XRefInternal>(1)(a) and subsections <XRefInternal>24</XRefInternal>(1) and <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1))</OriginatingRef><TitleText>Conveyance Data</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 1</Label><TitleText>Marine Mode</TitleText></Heading><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>1</Label><Text>Numeric code that identifies the movement of the vessel (also known as the “customs procedure, coded” or the “application type” for marine conveyance)<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch1Pt1_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>2</Label><Text>Conveyance type code assigned by the American National Standards Institute</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>3</Label><Text>Conveyance report number (also known as the conveyance reference number)<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch1Pt1_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>4</Label><Text>Vessel code number assigned by the International Maritime Organization or the Lloyd’s Register</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>5</Label><Text>Voyage number<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch1Pt1_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>6</Label><Text>Vessel name</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>7</Label><Text>Vessel registration number assigned by the International Maritime Organization or the Lloyd’s Register and place and date of registration</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>8</Label><Text>Carrier code</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>9</Label><Text>Number of crew members</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>10</Label><Text>Number of passengers</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>11</Label><Text>Name and address of the persons who cause the goods to be transported on board the vessel</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>12</Label><Text>Number of cargo containers on board the vessel</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>13</Label><Text>Weight of containerized cargo and unit of measurement</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>14</Label><Text>Weight of non-containerized cargo and unit of measurement</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>15</Label><Text>Type and size of cargo containers (also known as equipment) using the classification of the International Organization for Standardization</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>16</Label><Text>Whether each cargo container is empty or full (also known as empty or loaded)<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch1Pt1_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>17</Label><Text>All ports of call (also known as the itinerary route)</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>18</Label><Text>Last foreign port of departure</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>19</Label><Text>Date and time of departure</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>20</Label><Text>Port of arrival in Canada</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>21</Label><Text>Arrival terminal in Canada</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>22</Label><Text>Estimated date and time of arrival in Canada</Text></Provision><Footnote id="footnoteSch1Pt1_e" placement="section" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>to be determined in accordance with the specifications that are set out in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Electronic Commerce Client Requirements Document</XRefExternal></Text></Footnote><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 2</Label><TitleText>Air Mode</TitleText></Heading><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>1</Label><Text>Numeric code that identifies the movement of the aircraft (also known as the “customs procedure, coded” for air conveyance)<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch1Pt2_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>2</Label><Text>Conveyance reference number<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch1Pt2_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>3</Label><Text>Aircraft registration number assigned by the appropriate national aviation transportation administration agency</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>4</Label><Text>Aircraft type code assigned by the International Air Transport Association or the International Civil Aviation Organization</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>5</Label><Text>Carrier code</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>6</Label><Text>Flight number</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>7</Label><Text>Date and time of departure</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>8</Label><Text>Airport of departure (also known as place of departure)</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>9</Label><Text>Estimated date and time of arrival in Canada</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>10</Label><Text>Flight routing (also known as the itinerary route)</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>11</Label><Text>Arrival terminal in Canada</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>12</Label><Text>Airport of arrival in Canada<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch1Pt2_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Footnote id="footnoteSch1Pt2_e" placement="section" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>to be determined in accordance with the specifications set out in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Electronic Commerce Client Requirements Document</XRefExternal></Text></Footnote><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 3</Label><TitleText>Highway Mode</TitleText></Heading><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>1</Label><Text>Conveyance reference number — Number assigned by the carrier, beginning with its carrier code, to identify the trip to Canada by the highway conveyance</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>2</Label><Text>Code provided by the Agency to identify the customs office in Canada at which the carrier expects a report to be made under section 12 of the Act with respect to goods transported on board the conveyance<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch1Pt3_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>3</Label><Text>Estimated date and time of arrival of the conveyance in Canada</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>4</Label><Text>Code provided by the Agency to identify the mode of conveyance<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch1Pt3_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>5</Label><Text>Code provided by the Agency to indicate whether the conveyance is empty or loaded<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch1Pt3_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>6</Label><Text>Licence plate number of the conveyance and the country and province or state of issue</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>7</Label><Text>Licence plate number of each trailer and the country and province or state of issue</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>8</Label><Text>Seal numbers, if any, for each cargo container on board the conveyance</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>9</Label><Text>Manifest summary list — List of all of the primary cargo control numbers (the number assigned by the carrier, beginning with its carrier code, to a bill of lading, waybill or similar document that is issued by the carrier and that relates to the carriage of specified goods on board the conveyance)</Text></Provision><Footnote id="footnoteSch1Pt3_e" placement="section" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>to be determined in accordance with the specifications that are set out in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Electronic Commerce Client Requirements Document</XRefExternal></Text></Footnote><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 4</Label><TitleText>Rail Mode</TitleText></Heading><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>1</Label><Text>Conveyance reference number — Number assigned by the carrier, beginning with its carrier code, to identify the trip to Canada by the rail conveyance</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>2</Label><Text>Code provided by the Agency to identify the customs office in Canada at which the carrier expects a report to be made under section 12 of the Act with respect to goods transported on board the conveyance<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch1Pt4_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>3</Label><Text>Estimated date and time of arrival of the conveyance in Canada</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>4</Label><Text>Code provided by the Agency to identify the mode of conveyance<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch1Pt4_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>5</Label><Text>Codes provided by the Agency to indicate whether the conveyance and each rail car that is part of the conveyance are empty or loaded<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch1Pt4_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>6</Label><Text>Number assigned by the carrier that identifies each locomotive</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>7</Label><Text>Number assigned by the carrier that identifies each rail car</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>8</Label><Text>Number that identifies each cargo container on board the conveyance</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>9</Label><Text>Manifest summary list — List of all of the primary cargo control numbers (the number assigned by the carrier, beginning with its carrier code, to a bill of lading, waybill or similar document that is issued by the carrier and that relates to the carriage of specified goods on board the conveyance)</Text></Provision><Footnote id="footnoteSch1Pt4_e" placement="section" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>to be determined in accordance with the specifications that are set out in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Electronic Commerce Client Requirements Document</XRefExternal></Text></Footnote><HistoricalNote>SOR/2005-175, s. 5; SOR/2005-303, s. 11; SOR/2006-148, ss. 12 to 14; SOR/2015-90, ss. 10, 11(F), 12 to 14.</HistoricalNote></Schedule><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 2</Label><OriginatingRef>(Paragraph <XRefInternal>13</XRefInternal>(1)(b), subsection <XRefInternal>15</XRefInternal>(1), section <XRefInternal>15.2</XRefInternal>, paragraph <XRefInternal>16</XRefInternal>(1)(b), subsection <XRefInternal>16</XRefInternal>(3), section <XRefInternal>17.1</XRefInternal>, paragraph <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(1)(b), subsection <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(3), section <XRefInternal>19.1</XRefInternal>, paragraph <XRefInternal>20</XRefInternal>(1)(b), subsection <XRefInternal>20</XRefInternal>(3) and section <XRefInternal>21.1</XRefInternal>)</OriginatingRef><TitleText>Data Relating to Cargo</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 1</Label><TitleText>Marine Mode — Carrier</TitleText></Heading><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>1</Label><Text>Numeric code that identifies the movement of the goods (also known as the “customs procedure, coded” or the “application type” for marine cargo)<FootnoteRef idref="footnotestar_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>2</Label><Text>Report number<FootnoteRef idref="footnotestar_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>3</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-90, s. 42]</Repealed></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>4</Label><Text>Bill of lading number (also known as the associated transport document number)<FootnoteRef idref="footnotestar_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>5</Label><Text>Conveyance report number (also known as the conveyance reference number)<FootnoteRef idref="footnotestar_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>6</Label><Text>Cargo control number<FootnoteRef idref="footnotestar_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>7</Label><Text>Voyage number<FootnoteRef idref="footnotestar_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>8</Label><Text>Number, type and size of each cargo container (also known as equipment)<FootnoteRef idref="footnotestar_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>9</Label><Text>Seal number of each cargo container<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteplus_e">+</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>10</Label><Text>Whether each cargo container is empty or full (also known as empty or loaded)<FootnoteRef idref="footnotestar_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>11</Label><Text>Vessel name</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>12</Label><Text>Carrier code</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>13</Label><Text>Name and address of the persons who cause the goods to be transported on board the vessel<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteplus_e">+</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>14</Label><Text>Name and address of ultimate consignee<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteplus_e">+</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>15</Label><Text>Place (country, city and port) where the carrier takes possession of the goods in a foreign country, known as the place of acceptance or place of receipt</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>16</Label><Text>Port of loading</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>16.1</Label><Text>Estimated date and time of loading</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>17</Label><Text>Port of arrival in Canada</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>18</Label><Text>Arrival terminal in Canada</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>19</Label><Text>Customs office of manifest origin in Canada (also known as the customs office of declaration or port of report)</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>20</Label><Text>Customs office of manifest destination in Canada (also known as the customs office port of discharge)</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>21</Label><Text>Place of destination (also known as the place of delivery) listing the country, city and port</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>22</Label><Text>Delivery address<FootnoteRef idref="footnotestar_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>23</Label><Text>Description of the goods<FootnoteRef idref="footnotestar_e">*</FootnoteRef><FootnoteRef idref="footnoteplus_e">+</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>24</Label><Text>Quantity of the goods<FootnoteRef idref="footnotestar_e">*</FootnoteRef><FootnoteRef idref="footnoteplus_e">+</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>25</Label><Text>Weight of the goods and unit of measurement<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteplus_e">+</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>26</Label><Text>Supplementary data required indicator, which indicates if a supplementary report will be sent<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteplus_e">+</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Footnote id="footnotestar_e" placement="section" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>to be determined in accordance with the specifications set out in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Electronic Commerce Client Requirements Document</XRefExternal></Text></Footnote><Footnote id="footnoteplus_e" placement="section" status="official"><Label>+</Label><Text>item of information not required in relation to empty cargo containers</Text></Footnote><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 1.1</Label><TitleText>Marine Mode — Freight Forwarder</TitleText></Heading><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>1</Label><Text>Code provided by the Agency to identify the movement of the shipment<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch2Pt1.1_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>2</Label><Text>Primary cargo control number — Number assigned by the carrier that operates the vessel, beginning with its carrier code, to the bill of lading, waybill or similar document that is issued by the carrier and that relates to the carriage of the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>3</Label><Text>Number assigned by the freight forwarder to the bill of lading, waybill or similar document that is issued by the freight forwarder and that relates to the carriage of the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>4</Label><Text>Secondary cargo control number — Number assigned by the freight forwarder, beginning with its carrier code, to identify the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>5</Label><Text>Manifest quantity and qualifier — Number and nature of pieces indicated on the bill of lading, waybill or similar document that is issued by the freight forwarder and that relates to the carriage of the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>6</Label><Text>Code provided by the Agency to identify the mode of conveyance<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch2Pt1.1_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>7</Label><Text>If a cargo container contains all or part of the shipment</Text><Provision first-line-indent="2.5" subsequent-line-indent="2.5"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the number that identifies the cargo container, and</Text></Provision><Provision first-line-indent="2.5" subsequent-line-indent="2.5"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the number assigned by the carrier that describes its size and type</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>8</Label><Text>Description of the goods in the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>9</Label><Text>The <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal> item number that applies to each good in the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>10</Label><Text>Each UN number listed in column 1 of Schedule 1 to the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Transportation of Dangerous Goods Regulations</XRefExternal> that applies to a good in the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>11</Label><Text>Volume of the shipment and unit of measurement</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>12</Label><Text>Weight of the shipment and unit of measurement</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>13</Label><Text>Name and address of the shipper of the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>14</Label><Text>Name and address of the consignee of the shipment, every delivery address and name of every person to be notified, as indicated on the bill of lading, waybill or similar document that is issued by the freight forwarder and that relates to the carriage of the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>15</Label><Text>Description of all markings on the outer packaging of the shipment, if any</Text></Provision><Footnote id="footnoteSch2Pt1.1_e" placement="section" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>to be determined in accordance with the specifications that are set out in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Electronic Commerce Client Requirements Document</XRefExternal></Text></Footnote><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 2</Label><TitleText>Air Mode — Carrier</TitleText></Heading><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>1</Label><Text>Numeric code that identifies the movement of the goods (also known as the “customs procedure, coded” for air cargo)<FootnoteRef idref="footnote3star_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>2</Label><Text>Conveyance reference number<FootnoteRef idref="footnote3star_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>3</Label><Text>Cargo control number (also known as the master air waybill number)<FootnoteRef idref="footnote3star_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>4</Label><Text>Itinerary routing of the cargo using the airport codes (also known as the routing and destination — location) and the airline codes (also known as the routing and destination — carrier) of the International Air Transport Association or the International Civil Aviation Organization</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>5</Label><Text>Carrier code</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>6</Label><Text>Name and address of the persons who cause the goods to be transported on board the aircraft</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>7</Label><Text>Name and address of the ultimate consignee</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>8</Label><Text>Part arrival reference number in the case of a split shipment<FootnoteRef idref="footnote3star_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>9</Label><Text>Place (country, city and terminal) where the carrier takes possession of the goods in a foreign country (also known as the place of receipt or place of acceptance)</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>10</Label><Text>Port of loading</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>11</Label><Text>Customs office of declaration in Canada (also known as the port of report)</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>12</Label><Text>Place of discharge in Canada</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>13</Label><Text>Place of destination (country, city and terminal of destination)<FootnoteRef idref="footnote3star_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>14</Label><Text>Delivery destination name and address<FootnoteRef idref="footnote3star_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>15</Label><Text>Description of the goods<FootnoteRef idref="footnote3star_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>16</Label><Text>Equipment identification number<FootnoteRef idref="footnote3star_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>17</Label><Text>Flight number</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>18</Label><Text>Manifest quantity and qualifier<FootnoteRef idref="footnote3star_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>19</Label><Text>Quantity and qualifier of the cargo to be loaded on the aircraft<FootnoteRef idref="footnote3star_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>20</Label><Text>In the case of a split shipment, the quantity and qualifier of the cargo loaded on the aircraft<FootnoteRef idref="footnote3star_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>21</Label><Text>Volume of goods and unit of measurement</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>22</Label><Text>Weight of the goods and unit of measurement</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>23</Label><Text>Split shipment indicator, which indicates whether a split shipment report will be sent or whether the report is a split shipment report<FootnoteRef idref="footnote3star_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>24</Label><Text>Supplementary data required indicator, which indicates if a supplementary report will be sent</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>25</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-90, s. 45]</Repealed></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>26</Label><Text>Ramp transfer indicator<FootnoteRef idref="footnote3star_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>27</Label><Text>Dangerous goods code<FootnoteRef idref="footnote3star_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Footnote id="footnote3star_e" placement="section" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>to be determined in accordance with the specifications set out in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Electronic Commerce Client Requirements Document</XRefExternal></Text></Footnote><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 2.1</Label><TitleText>Air Mode — Freight Forwarder</TitleText></Heading><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>1</Label><Text>Code provided by the Agency to identify the movement of the shipment<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch2Pt2.1_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>2</Label><Text>Primary cargo control number — Number assigned by the carrier that operates the aircraft, beginning with its carrier code, to the bill of lading, waybill or similar document that is issued by the carrier and that relates to the carriage of the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>3</Label><Text>Secondary cargo control number — Number assigned by the freight forwarder, beginning with its carrier code, to identify the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>4</Label><Text>Manifest quantity and qualifier — Number and nature of pieces indicated on the bill of lading, waybill or similar document that is issued by the freight forwarder and that relates to the carriage of the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>5</Label><Text>Code provided by the Agency to identify the mode of conveyance<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch2Pt2.1_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>6</Label><Text>Description of the goods in the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>7</Label><Text>The <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal> item number that applies to each good in the shipment </Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>8</Label><Text>Each UN number listed in column 1 of Schedule 1 to the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Transportation of Dangerous Goods Regulations</XRefExternal> that applies to a good in the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>9</Label><Text>Volume of the shipment and unit of measurement</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>10</Label><Text>Weight of the shipment and unit of measurement</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>11</Label><Text>Name and address of the shipper of the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>12</Label><Text>Name and address of the consignee of the shipment, every delivery address and name of every person to be notified, as indicated on the bill of lading, waybill or similar document that is issued by the freight forwarder and that relates to the carriage of the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>13</Label><Text>Description of all markings on the outer packaging of the shipment, if any</Text></Provision><Footnote id="footnoteSch2Pt2.1_e" placement="section" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>to be determined in accordance with the specifications that are set out in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Electronic Commerce Client Requirements Document</XRefExternal></Text></Footnote><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 3</Label><TitleText>Highway and Rail Modes — Carrier</TitleText></Heading><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>1</Label><Text>Code provided by the Agency to identify the movement of the shipment<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch2Pt3_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>2</Label><Text>Cargo control number — Number assigned by the carrier, beginning with its carrier code, to identify the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>3</Label><Text>Code provided by the Agency to indicate every condition that applies to the carriage of the shipment and that is listed in the bill of lading, waybill or similar document that is issued by the carrier and that relates to the carriage of the shipment<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch2Pt3_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>4</Label><Text>Manifest quantity and qualifier — Number and nature of pieces indicated on the bill of lading, waybill or similar document that is issued by the carrier and that relates to the carriage of the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>5</Label><Text>Code provided by the Agency to identify the mode of conveyance<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch2Pt3_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>6</Label><Text>In the case of a shipment that was transported by vessel from a location outside Canada or the United States to a port in the United States and that will then be transported by a highway conveyance or a rail conveyance from the United States to Canada without passing through any other country, the ocean bill of lading number (the number assigned by the carrier that operated the vessel to the bill of lading, waybill or similar document that was issued by that carrier and that relates to the carriage of the shipment on board the vessel)</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>7</Label><Text>Estimated date of arrival of the conveyance in Canada</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>8</Label><Text>Foreign address where the shipment is transferred to the carrier that will transport it to Canada, if that address is different from the shipper’s address</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>9</Label><Text>Foreign address where the shipment is loaded onto the conveyance that will transport it to Canada</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>10</Label><Text>If a cargo container contains all or part of the shipment or is an empty cargo container that is for sale,</Text><Provision first-line-indent="2.5" subsequent-line-indent="2.5"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the number that identifies the cargo container,</Text></Provision><Provision first-line-indent="2.5" subsequent-line-indent="2.5"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the number assigned by the carrier that describes its size and type, and</Text></Provision><Provision first-line-indent="2.5" subsequent-line-indent="2.5"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the seal numbers for it, if any</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>11</Label><Text>Consolidation indicator that indicates whether the shipment consists of more than one shipment for which a freight forwarder is responsible<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch2Pt3_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>12</Label><Text>Description of the goods in the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>13</Label><Text>The <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal> item number that applies to each good in the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>14</Label><Text>Each UN number listed in column 1 of Schedule 1 to the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Transportation of Dangerous Goods Regulations</XRefExternal> that applies to a good in the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>15</Label><Text>Weight of the shipment and unit of measurement</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>16</Label><Text>Name and address of the shipper of the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>17</Label><Text>Name and address of the consignee of the shipment, every delivery address and name of every person to be notified, as indicated on the bill of lading, waybill or similar document that is issued by the carrier and that relates to the carriage of the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>18</Label><Text>Customs Self-Assessment (CSA) indicator that indicates whether the importer of the shipment has given written instructions to the carrier to submit a request to the Agency under paragraph 32(2)(b) of the Act for its release and, if so, the importer’s business number<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch2Pt3_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>19</Label><Text>Code provided by the Agency to identify the customs office in Canada at which the carrier expects a report to be made under section 12 of the Act with respect to goods transported on board the conveyance<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch2Pt3_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>20</Label><Text>Code provided by the Agency to identify the location where the shipment will be unloaded from the conveyance in Canada<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch2Pt3_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>21</Label><Text>Location where the release of the shipment will be sought</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>22</Label><Text>Description of all markings on the outer packaging of the shipment, if any</Text></Provision><Footnote id="footnoteSch2Pt3_e" placement="section" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>to be determined in accordance with the specifications that are set out in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Electronic Commerce Client Requirements Document</XRefExternal></Text></Footnote><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 4</Label><TitleText>All Modes — Freight Forwarder</TitleText></Heading><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>1</Label><Text>Code provided by the Agency to identify the movement of the shipment<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch2Pt4_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>2</Label><Text>Primary cargo control number — Number assigned by the carrier that operates the conveyance, beginning with its carrier code, to the bill of lading, waybill or similar document that is issued by the carrier and that relates to the carriage of the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>3</Label><Text>Secondary cargo control number — Number assigned by the freight forwarder, beginning with its carrier code, to identify the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>4</Label><Text>List of all secondary cargo control numbers for shipments for which the freight forwarder is responsible that are to be transported to Canada on board the conveyance</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>5</Label><Text>Code provided by the Agency to indicate every condition that applies to the carriage of the shipment and that is listed in the bill of lading, waybill or similar document that is issued by the freight forwarder and that relates to the carriage of the shipment<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch2Pt4_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>6</Label><Text>Manifest quantity and qualifier — Number and nature of pieces indicated on the bill of lading, waybill or similar document that is issued by the freight forwarder and that relates to the carriage of the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>7</Label><Text>Code provided by the Agency to identify the mode of conveyance<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch2Pt4_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>8</Label><Text>If a cargo container contains all or part of the shipment</Text><Provision first-line-indent="2.5" subsequent-line-indent="2.5"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the number that identifies the cargo container,</Text></Provision><Provision first-line-indent="2.5" subsequent-line-indent="2.5"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the number assigned by the carrier that describes its size and type,</Text></Provision><Provision first-line-indent="2.5" subsequent-line-indent="2.5"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the seal numbers for it, if any, and</Text></Provision><Provision first-line-indent="2.5" subsequent-line-indent="2.5"><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the name and address of the person who placed the shipment in it</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>9</Label><Text>Consolidation indicator that indicates whether, under a bill of lading, waybill or similar document that is issued by the carrier, the shipment is consolidated with other shipments for which another freight forwarder is responsible<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch2Pt4_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>10</Label><Text>Description of the goods in the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>11</Label><Text>The <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal> item number that applies to each good in the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>12</Label><Text>Each UN number listed in column 1 of Schedule 1 to the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Transportation of Dangerous Goods Regulations</XRefExternal> that applies to a good in the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>13</Label><Text>Weight of the shipment and unit of measurement</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>14</Label><Text>Name and address of the shipper of the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>15</Label><Text>Name and address of the consignee of the shipment, every delivery address and name of every person to be notified, as indicated on the bill of lading, waybill or similar document that is issued by the freight forwarder and that relates to the carriage of the shipment</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>16</Label><Text>Code provided by the Agency to identify the location where the shipment will be unloaded from the conveyance in Canada<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch2Pt4_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>17</Label><Text>Location where the release of the shipment will be sought</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>18</Label><Text>Description of all markings on the outer packaging of the shipment, if any</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>19</Label><Text>Carrier code of the carrier</Text></Provision><Footnote id="footnoteSch2Pt4_e" placement="section" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>to be determined in accordance with the specifications that are set out in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Electronic Commerce Client Requirements Document</XRefExternal></Text></Footnote><HistoricalNote>SOR/2005-175, s. 5; SOR/2005-303, s. 11; SOR/2006-148, ss. 15 to 20; SOR/2011-48, s. 6; SOR/2015-90, ss. 15, 16(E), 17 to 19, 40 to 48.</HistoricalNote></Schedule><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 3</Label><OriginatingRef>(Paragraph 13(1)(c) and section 15.1)</OriginatingRef><TitleText>Cargo and Stowage Plan — Marine Mode</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>1</Label><Text>Conveyance reference number — Number assigned by the carrier, beginning with its carrier code, to identify the trip to Canada by the vessel</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>2</Label><Text>Reference number assigned by the carrier to a voyage, which includes the voyage to Canada</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>3</Label><Text>Vessel name and the International Maritime Organization ship identification number of the vessel</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>4</Label><Text>Each foreign address where a cargo container or a fully or partially non-containerized shipment for which the carrier is responsible is loaded onto the vessel for transport to Canada</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>5</Label><Text>Last foreign port of departure and time of departure</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>6</Label><Text>Estimated date and time of arrival of the vessel at the port of arrival in Canada</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>7</Label><Text>Port of arrival in Canada and, if different, each location where a cargo container or a fully or partially non-containerized shipment for which the carrier is responsible will be unloaded from the vessel</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>8</Label><Text>Code provided by the Agency for each cargo container to indicate whether it is empty or loaded<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch3_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>9</Label><Text>Description of each shipment for which the carrier is responsible</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>10</Label><Text>Number that identifies each cargo container</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>11</Label><Text>Number assigned by the carrier that describes the size and type of each cargo container</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>12</Label><Text>Weight of each cargo container and its contents, if any, and unit of measurement</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>13</Label><Text>Dimensions of each non-standard cargo container and unit of measurement</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>14</Label><Text>Number that identifies each piece of equipment attached to a cargo container</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>15</Label><Text>Code provided by the Agency to identify the size and type of each piece of equipment attached to a cargo container<FootnoteRef idref="footnoteSch3_e">*</FootnoteRef></Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>16</Label><Text>Location on board the vessel of each cargo container (by bay, row and tier)</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>17</Label><Text>For each shipment for which the carrier is responsible that is fully non-containerized,</Text><Provision first-line-indent="2.5" subsequent-line-indent="2.5"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>its weight and unit of measurement,</Text></Provision><Provision first-line-indent="2.5" subsequent-line-indent="2.5"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>its dimensions and unit of measurement; and</Text></Provision><Provision first-line-indent="2.5" subsequent-line-indent="2.5"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>if all or part of the shipment is packaged, the form of packaging and number of packages</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>18</Label><Text>Each UN number listed in column 1 of Schedule 1 to the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Transportation of Dangerous Goods Regulations</XRefExternal> that applies to a specified good</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes" first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2.5" list-item="yes"><Label>19</Label><Text>Temperature, other than the ambient temperature, at which a specified good must be kept, if applicable, and unit of measurement</Text></Provision><Footnote id="footnoteSch3_e" placement="section" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>to be determined in accordance with the specifications that are set out in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Electronic Commerce Client Requirements Document</XRefExternal></Text></Footnote><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-90, s. 49.</HistoricalNote></Schedule></Regulation>