<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/78-148</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1978</YYYY><MM>2</MM><DD>14</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>8</MM><DD>19</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CANADA ELECTIONS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Special Voting Rules</LongTitle></Identification><Order><Provision language-align="yes" format-ref="indent-0-0" list-item="no"><Text>The Chief Electoral Officer, pursuant to subsection 27(16) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Special Voting Rules</XRefExternal> contained in Schedule II to the<XRefExternal reference-type="act"> Canada Elections Act</XRefExternal>, hereby makes the annexed Regulations in accordance with the schedule hereto.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>Dated at Ottawa, this 14th day of February, 1978</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-5-5" list-item="no" language-align="no"><Text>JOHN P. DEWIS</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-5-5" list-item="no" language-align="no"><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Assistant Chief Electoral Officer </Emphasis></Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-5-5" list-item="no" language-align="no"><Text>for <Emphasis style="italic">Chief Electoral Officer of Canada</Emphasis></Text></Provision></Order><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label></ScheduleFormHeading><RegulationPiece><Body><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>Section 27 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Special Voting Rules</XRefExternal> contained in Schedule II to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Elections Act</XRefExternal> is, for the purpose of making it applicable to Canadian Forces electors described in subsection 21(3) of the Rules, modified to read as follows:</Text><QuotedText><Section><Label>“27</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Every person other than a person referred to in subsection (2) shall, forthwith on becoming a Canadian Forces elector pursuant to subsection 21(3), complete in triplicate, before a commissioned officer, a statement of ordinary residence in the prescribed form indicating</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the city, town, village or other place in Canada, with street address, if any, and province, in which the place of his ordinary residence was situated immediately prior to becoming such an elector; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>as the place of his ordinary residence the city, town, village or other place in Canada, with street address, if any, and province, in which is situated the residence of a person who is the spouse, dependant, relative or next of kin of such an elector.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Subsection (1) does not apply to a Canadian Forces elector described in subsection 21(3) who is not a Canadian citizen, but, on becoming a Canadian citizen, such elector shall forthwith complete a statement of ordinary residence in accordance with subsection (1) indicating a place of ordinary residence described in subsection (1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The original and duplicate copy of a statement of ordinary residence completed pursuant to this section shall be forwarded to National Defence Headquarters and the triplicate copy shall be retained in the unit responsible for the administrative support of the Canadian Forces school in which the Canadian Forces elector is employed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The original and duplicate copy of a statement of ordinary residence received by National Defence Headquarters pursuant to subsection (3) shall be forwarded to the Chief Electoral Officer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>On receipt pursuant to subsection (4) of the original and duplicate copy of a statement of ordinary residence, the Chief Electoral Officer shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>cause the original and duplicate copy to be stamped with the name of the electoral district in which is situated the place of ordinary residence shown in the statement; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>send the original and duplicate copy of the statement to National Defence Headquarters.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(6)</Label><Text>Upon receipt of the original and duplicate copy of a statement of ordinary residence stamped pursuant to subsection (5), National Defence Headquarters shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>retain the original of the statement; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>send the duplicate copy to the commanding officer of the unit referred to in subsection (3).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(7)</Label><Text>Upon receipt in the unit referred to in subsection (3) of a stamped duplicate copy of a statement referred to in subsection (6), the commanding officer of the unit shall destroy the triplicate copy of the statement and retain the stamped duplicate copy.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(8)</Label><Text>The original and all copies of a statement of ordinary residence of a person who ceases to be a Canadian Forces elector shall be retained for a period of one year after he ceases to be a Canadian Forces elector and may thereafter be destroyed.”</Text></Subsection></Section></QuotedText><HistoricalNote> SOR/78-165, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section></Body></RegulationPiece></Schedule></Regulation>