<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2004-53</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2004</YYYY><MM>3</MM><DD>23</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><LastAmendedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>14</DD></Date></LastAmendedDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2006</YYYY><MM>3</MM><DD>1</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CANADA ELECTIONS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Federal Elections Fees Tariff</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2004-272</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>2004</YYYY><MM>3</MM><DD>23</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of State styled Leader of the Government in the House of Commons and Minister responsible for Democratic Reform and of the Chief Electoral Officer, pursuant to sections 542 to 545 and 553 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Elections Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="footnotea_e">a</FootnoteRef>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Federal Elections Fees Tariff</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="footnotea_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 2000, c. 9</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>The following definitions apply in this Tariff.</Text><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Elections Act</XRefExternal>. (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>travel time</DefinedTermEn> means time spent travelling to and returning from the place where a task is to be accomplished if that place is located more than 16 km from the traveller’s home or work place, whichever is closer, using the most direct route, but does not include stops during the journey. (<DefinedTermFr>temps de déplacement</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Returning officers and other persons employed at or in relation to elections shall be paid the fees, costs, allowances and expenses as set out in the schedule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>With respect to a monthly fee set out in the schedule, if a person only works for part of the month for which he or she is entitled to the fee, he or she is to be paid as follows:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>if he or she has worked less than half the number of working days during that month, an amount equal to half the monthly fee; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>if he or she has worked at least half the number of working days during that month, the entire monthly fee.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Allowances for travel expenses are to be paid only for travelling to and returning from the place where a task is to be accomplished if that place is located more than 16 km from the traveller’s home or workplace, whichever is closer, using the most direct route.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-162, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>The allowances for travel and living expenses referred to in paragraph 50(a) and subparagraph 50(c)(ii) of the schedule are based on the rates and allowances set out in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Travel Directive</XRefExternal> of the National Joint Council and the Treasury Board of Canada Secretariat, including Appendices B and C, that are in effect</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>on the day on which the writ for the election is issued for an electoral district, in the case where the services to which the travel or living expenses relate are performed in respect of an election in an electoral district during the period that begins on that day and ends on</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the day on which the return of the writ is completed for that electoral district, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the day, if any, on which the writ is withdrawn for that electoral district under subsection 59(1) of the Act or deemed to be withdrawn for that electoral district under section 551 of the Act; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>on the day on which the services are performed, in all other cases.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2007-170, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Annual Inflation Adjustment</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-162, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>5</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-162, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>6</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsections (1.1), (3) and (4), the amounts set out in the schedule shall be adjusted, annually on January 31, by multiplying each of them by the annual inflation adjustment factor set out in subsection (2), and the resulting amounts, rounded to the nearest cent, apply during the calendar year beginning on that date and ending on January 30 of the following year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(1.1)</Label><Text>Subsection (1) does not apply to the amounts set out in paragraph 23(e), item 27, paragraph 29(e) and item 43 of the schedule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The annual inflation adjustment factor is a fraction with</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a numerator that is the annual average Consumer Price Index, as published by Statistics Canada under the authority of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Statistics Act</XRefExternal>, for the calendar year preceding the January 31 adjustment date, calculated on the basis of 2002 being equal to 100; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a denominator that is 125.2, which is the annual average Consumer Price Index, as published by Statistics Canada under the authority of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Statistics Act</XRefExternal>, for 2014, calculated on the basis of 2002 being equal to 100.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>In any given calendar year, the maximum adjustment that may be effected by the application of the annual inflation adjustment factor is three percent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>If, in any given calendar year, the annual inflation adjustment factor is below zero, no adjustment will be effected in that year.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2007-170, s. 3; SOR/2015-162, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>7</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>If the hourly rate provided for in this Tariff is lower than the highest minimum hourly rate that applies in a province, other than a territory, on the January 31 immediately before the work is performed, the highest provincial hourly rate applies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>For the purposes of subsection (1), only provincial minimum hourly rates that are generally applicable regardless of occupation, status or work experience are to be considered.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-162, s. 4.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>8</Label><Text>The Chief Electoral Officer may make accountable advances to returning officers and to additional assistant returning officers to defray office and other incidental expenses in an amount that does not exceed $2,000.00 per advance and per officer.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-162, s. 4.</HistoricalNote></Section></Body><Schedule><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label><OriginatingRef>(Sections 2, 3 and 6)</OriginatingRef><TitleText>Fees, Costs, Allowances and Expenses Payable</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><RegulationPiece><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Returning Officers and Staff</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Before the Issue of a Writ for an Election</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>A returning officer shall be paid, for services performed and expenses incurred during the period beginning on the day that is three months after the end of an election period and ending on the day before the date of the issue of the writ, including keeping current with communications, conducting a reconciliation of all time and financial account statements, appointing and training an assistant returning officer and storing election materials at his or her residence, per month <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $395.52</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>During an Election Period</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A returning officer shall be paid, for services performed during an election period,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>if a poll is held, a base fee of <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $23,879.52</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>when a poll is not held because of a return by acclamation or if the writ is withdrawn on or before the close of nominations, a fee of <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> 33% of the amount payable under paragraph (a)</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>when a poll is not held because of the withdrawal of the writ after the close of nominations, in addition to the amount under paragraph (b), for each day after the close of nominations, a fee of <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> 3% per day of the amount payable under paragraph (a)</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A returning officer shall be paid, for attending a recount, for each hour worked as certified by the judge who conducts the recount <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $49.44</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2.1)</Label><Text>A returning officer shall be paid, for each hour of travel time to attend a recount <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $49.44</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>A returning officer shall be paid, for necessary travel expenses incurred in connection with the conduct of an election <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Support Staff</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Office Coordinator</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as an office coordinator shall be paid, for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $15.00</Text></Subsection><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Office Clerk</TitleText></Heading><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as an office clerk shall be paid, for each hour worked, <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $13.15</Text></Subsection><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Receptionist</TitleText></Heading><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a receptionist shall be paid, for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $13.15</Text></Subsection><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Electoral Material Coordinator</TitleText></Heading><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as an electoral material coordinator shall be paid, for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $15.00</Text></Subsection><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Community Relations Officer</TitleText></Heading><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a community relations officer shall be paid,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $16.50</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each hour of travel time <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $16.50</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>for travel expenses <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Recruitment Officer</TitleText></Heading><Subsection><Label>(6)</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a recruitment officer shall be paid,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $24.12</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each hour of travel time <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $24.12</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>for travel expenses <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Assistant Recruitment Officer</TitleText></Heading><Subsection><Label>(7)</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as an assistant recruitment officer shall be paid,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $17.00</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each hour of travel time <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $17.00</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>for travel expenses <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Financial Officer</TitleText></Heading><Subsection><Label>(8)</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a financial officer at the office of a returning officer shall be paid, for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $23.26</Text></Subsection><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Office Messenger</TitleText></Heading><Subsection><Label>(9)</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as an office messenger shall be paid,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $13.15</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each hour of travel time <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $13.15</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>for travel expenses <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Safety Officer</TitleText></Heading><Subsection><Label>(10)</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a safety officer to maintain order in the office of a returning officer shall be paid, for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $15.00</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>After an Election Period</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>A returning officer shall be paid, for services performed at the Chief Electoral Officer’s request, other than services performed under any other item of this schedule, during the three months after the end of an election period, including making the campaign election returns available for inspection <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $1,977.60</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Assignments</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>A returning officer who, at the Chief Electoral Officer’s request, in addition to the duties set out in items 1, 2 and 4, carries out an assignment or participates in a working group studying a particular aspect of the federal electoral process, shall be paid,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for services performed in connection with that assignment or that participation, for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $49.44</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each hour of travel time <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $49.44</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>for travel and living expenses <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Sessions on Electoral and Related Matters</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>A returning officer who attends a session on electoral and related matters shall be paid,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for each hour of attendance at the session <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $49.44</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each hour of travel time <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $49.44</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>for travel and living expenses <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Assistant Returning Officers and Staff</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>During an Election Period</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>7</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>An assistant returning officer shall be paid, for services performed by the officer during an election period,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>if a poll is held, a base fee of <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $17,576.37</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>if a poll is not held because of a return by acclamation or if the writ is withdrawn on or before the close of nominations, a fee of <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> 33% of the amount payable under paragraph (a)</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>if a poll is not held because of the withdrawal of the writ after the close of nominations, in addition to the amount referred to in paragraph (b), for each day after the close of nominations, a fee of <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> 3% per day of the amount payable under paragraph (a)</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>An assistant returning officer shall be paid, for necessary travel expenses incurred in connection with the conduct of an election <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Assignments</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>8</Label><Text>An assistant returning officer who, at the Chief Electoral Officer’s request, in addition to the duties set out in item 7, carries out an assignment or participates in a working group studying a particular aspect of the federal electoral process, shall be paid,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for services performed in connection with that assignment or that participation, for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $36.39</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each hour of travel time <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $36.39</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>for travel and living expenses <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Sessions on Electoral and Related Matters</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>9</Label><Text>An assistant returning officer who attends a session on electoral and related matters shall be paid,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for each hour of attendance at the session <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $36.39</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each hour of travel time <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $36.39</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>for travel and living expenses <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Automation of Lists of Electors</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Automation Coordinators</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>10</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as an automation coordinator to support computerized systems in the office of a returning officer shall be paid, for services performed during an election period,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>if a poll is held <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $8,220.52</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>if a poll is not held because of a return by acclamation or if the writ is withdrawn on or before the close of nominations <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> 33% of the amount payable under paragraph (a)</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>if a poll is not held because of the withdrawal of the writ after the close of nominations, in addition to the amount referred to in paragraph (b), for each day after the close of nominations <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> 3% per day of the amount payable under paragraph (a)</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as an automation coordinator to support computerized systems in the office of a returning officer shall be paid, for necessary travel expenses, incurred in connection with the conduct of an election <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as an automation coordinator to support computerized systems in the office of a returning officer and who attends a session on electoral and related matters, shall be paid,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for each hour of attendance at the session <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $26.69</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each hour of travel time <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $26.69</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>for travel and living expenses <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Assistant Automation Coordinators</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>11</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as an assistant automation coordinator to support computerized systems in the office of a returning officer shall be paid, for services performed during an election period,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>if a poll is held <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $2,391.60</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>if a poll is not held because of a return by acclamation or if the writ is withdrawn on or before the close of nominations <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> 33% of the amount payable under paragraph (a)</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>if a poll is not held because of the withdrawal of the writ after the close of nominations, in addition to the amount referred to in paragraph (b), for each day after the close of nominations <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> 3% per day of the amount payable under paragraph (a)</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as an assistant automation coordinator to support computerized systems in the office of a returning officer and who attends a session on electoral and related matters shall be paid,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for each hour of attendance at the session <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $19.93</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each hour of travel time <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $19.93</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>for travel and living expenses <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Revision Centre Clerks</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>12</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a revision centre clerk with respect to entries made or to be made into a computerized list of electors shall be paid, for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $13.15</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Registration Officers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>13</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a registration officer shall be paid, for services performed to register electors at a central polling place, for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $15.00</Text></Section><Section><Label>14</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a standby registration officer shall be paid, for being on standby on polling day <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $45.00</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Revision Supervisors</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>15</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a revision supervisor shall be paid, for services performed, for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $26.69</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Revising Agents</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>16</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a revising agent shall be paid,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for services performed during the revision period, for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $15.00</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each hour of travel time <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $15.00</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>for travel expenses <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>17. to 22</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-162, s. 9]</Repealed></Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Polling</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Special Ballot Coordinators</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>23</Label><Text>A person appointed as a special ballot coordinator shall be paid</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $18.17</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for any sundry expenses in relation to their duties <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> the actual and reasonable amount paid, as supported by vouchers</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>for each hour of travel time <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $18.17</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>for travel expenses <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>if authorized in writing by the returning officer to use his or her personal telephone for electoral purposes, per day <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $10.00</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Hospital Liaison Officer</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>23.1</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-162, s. 11]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>24</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a hospital liaison officer shall be paid,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $13.63</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each hour of travel time <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $13.63</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>for travel expenses <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Advance and Ordinary Polls</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Deputy Returning Officers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>25</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a deputy returning officer for an advance poll shall be paid, for services performed, including the counting of the votes on polling day <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $680.00</Text></Section><Section><Label>26</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a deputy returning officer at a polling station on polling day shall be paid, for services performed <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $238.00</Text></Section><Section><Label>27</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as deputy returning officer who is authorized in writing by the returning officer to use his or her personal telephone for electoral purposes shall be paid, per day <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $10.00</Text></Section><Section><Label>28</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a deputy returning officer and who is tasked with verifying and counting the special ballots received in the returning officer’s office shall be paid, for services performed, for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $17.00</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Central Poll Supervisors</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>29</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a central poll supervisor shall be paid,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for services performed, including the return of ballot boxes to the returning officer when instructed to do so, for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $21.00</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for the return to the returning officer’s office of all large envelopes referred to in subsection 288(3) of the Act, accompanied by a signed statement indicating they contain the ballots, the poll book and the list of electors, of the envelopes containing the registration certificates and of the envelopes containing all completed oath forms referred to in section 288.01 of the Act <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $50.00</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>for each hour of travel time <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $21.00</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>for travel expenses <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>if authorized in writing by the returning officer to use his or her personal telephone for electoral purposes, per day <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $10.00</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>30</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a standby central poll supervisor shall be paid, for each hour of being on standby <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $21.00</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Deputy Returning Officers — Return of Ballot Boxes and Standby</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>31</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a deputy returning officer and who is tasked with returning ballot boxes to the returning officer shall be paid, for returning the ballot boxes, in addition to their fee under items 25 or 26,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $17.00</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each hour of travel time <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $17.00</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>for travel expenses <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>32</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a standby deputy returning officer shall be paid, for being on standby on polling day <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $51.00</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Poll Clerks</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>33</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a poll clerk for an advance poll shall be paid, for services performed, including the counting of the votes on polling day <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $600.00</Text></Section><Section><Label>34</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a poll clerk at a polling station on polling day shall be paid, for services performed <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $210.00</Text></Section><Section><Label>35</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a poll clerk and who is tasked with verifying and counting the special ballots received in the returning officer’s office shall be paid, for services performed, for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $15.00</Text></Section><Section><Label>36</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a poll clerk and who is tasked to return ballot boxes to the returning officer shall be paid, for returning the ballot boxes, in addition to their fee under item 33 or 34,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $15.00</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each hour of travel time <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $15.00</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>for travel expenses <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>37. and 38</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-162, s. 11]</Repealed></Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Special Messengers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>39</Label><Text>A person appointed as a special messenger for the delivery or pick-up of ballot boxes shall be paid</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $13.15</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for travel and living expenses at a place other than their place of residence <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Interpreters</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>40</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a language interpreter shall be paid,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $13.27</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each hour of travel time <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $13.27</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>for travel and living expenses <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Information Officers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>41</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as an information officer and who is employed at a central polling place shall be paid, for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $13.15</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Witnesses</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>42</Label><Text>An elector called on by a returning officer to be a witness at the validation of the results where no candidate is present or represented shall be paid, for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $11.25</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Additional Assistant Returning Officers and Staff</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Before the Issuance of a Writ for an Election</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>43</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as an additional assistant returning officer shall be paid, for the storing of election materials at the officer’s own residence before the issue of a writ for an election and for expenses in connection with that storage, per month <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $40.00</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>During an Election Period</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>44</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as an additional assistant returning officer on a full-time basis shall be paid, for services performed during the election period,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>if a poll is held <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $17,576.37</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>if a poll is not held because of a return by acclamation or if the writ is withdrawn on or before the close of nominations <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> 33% of the amount payable under paragraph (a)</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>if a poll is not held because of the withdrawal of the writ after the close of nominations, in addition to the amount referred to in paragraph (b), for each day after the close of nominations <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> 3% per day of the amount payable under paragraph (a)</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as an additional assistant returning officer on a part-time basis shall be paid, for services performed during the election period, for each hour worked, as authorized by the Chief Electoral Officer <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $36.39</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as an additional assistant returning officer shall be paid, for necessary travel expenses incurred in connection with the conduct of an election <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Sessions on Electoral and Related Matters</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>45</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as an additional assistant returning officer and who attends a session on electoral and related matters shall be paid,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for each hour of attendance at the session <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $36.39</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each hour of travel time <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $36.39</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>for travel and living expenses <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Support Staff</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>46</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as support staff at the office of an additional assistant returning officer shall be paid, for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $13.15</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Field Liaison Officers</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Before an Election Period</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>47</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a field liaison officer shall be paid, for services performed during the period beginning on the day that is three months after the end of an election period and ending on the day before the date of the issue of the writ, per month <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $568.60</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>During the Election Period of a General Election</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>48</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a field liaison officer shall be paid, for services performed during the election period of a general election, if a poll is held <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $27,461.45</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a field liaison officer shall be paid, for attending a recount, for each hour worked as certified by the judge who conducts the recount <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $56.86</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a field liaison officer shall be paid, for necessary travel expenses incurred in connection with the conduct of an election <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>During the Election Period of a By-election</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>49</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a field liaison officer shall be paid, for each hour worked during the election period of a by-election <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $56.86</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>After an Election Period</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>49.1</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a field liaison officer shall be paid, for services performed at the Chief Electoral Officer’s request, other than services performed under any other item of this schedule, during the three months after the end of an election period, including making the campaign election returns available for inspection <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $2,274.40</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Assignments</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>49.2</Label><Text>A field liaison officer who, at the Chief Electoral Officer’s request, in addition to the duties set out in items 47 to 49.1, carries out an assignment or participates in a working group studying a particular aspect of the federal electoral process, shall be paid,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for services performed in connection with that assignment or that participation, for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $56.86</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each hour of travel time <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $56.86</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>for travel and living expenses <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Sessions on Electoral and Related Matters</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>49.3</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a field liaison officer who attends a session on electoral and related matters shall be paid,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for each hour of attendance at the session <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $56.86</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each hour of travel time <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $56.86</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>for travel and living expenses <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Training</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Training Officers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>49.4</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a training officer shall be paid,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for services related to providing training sessions, for each hour worked as certified by the returning officer <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $24.12</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each hour of attendance at a session on electoral and related matters <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $24.12</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>for each hour of travel time <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $24.12</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>for travel and living expenses <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Training Sessions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>49.5</Label><Text>Any person appointed by the returning officer shall be paid, for attending a training session on electoral and related matters arranged by the returning officer <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $50.00</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Travel and Living Expenses</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>50</Label><Text>Each person who, pursuant to this schedule, is authorized to be paid for expenses incurred in connection with the services that the person is required to perform shall be paid for travel and living expenses as follows:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for travel by means of a private motor vehicle <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the allowances established by the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Travel Directive</XRefExternal></Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for travel by means other than a private motor vehicle <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> the actual and reasonable amount paid, as supported by vouchers</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>for living expenses</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>lodging <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the actual and reasonable expenses paid, as supported by vouchers</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>meals and incidental expenses <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the allowances established by the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Travel Directive</XRefExternal></Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Support Staff at a Recount</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>51</Label><Text>A person whose services are retained under subsection 304(6) of the Act to assist with a recount shall be paid for their attendance and services, as certified by the judge who conducts the recount, for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $13.27</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Judicial Recount Teams</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>52</Label><Text>A handler appointed in accordance with section 3 of schedule 4 to the Act shall be paid for their attendance and services during a recount, for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $20.80</Text></Section><Section><Label>52.1</Label><Text>A recorder appointed in accordance with section 3 of schedule 4 to the Act shall be paid for their attendance and services during a recount, for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $20.80</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Persons Appointed Under Part 11 of the Act</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>53</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A person appointed by the Chief Electoral Officer to be a special ballot officer under Part 11 of the Act shall be paid</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for services performed, for each hour worked <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $15.00</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for travel and living expenses that are incurred in the performance of their duties with the authorization of the Chief Electoral Officer <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>for other sundry expenses incurred in the performance of their duties, as approved by the Chief Electoral Officer <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> the actual and reasonable amount paid, as supported by vouchers</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a deputy returning officer for the taking of the vote within a correctional institution shall be paid,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for the first four hours or less during which services are performed <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $68.00</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each additional hour during which services are performed <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> $17.00</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>A person who is appointed as a poll clerk for the taking of the vote within a correctional institution shall be paid,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for the first four hours or less during which services are performed <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> $60.00</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each additional hour during which services are performed <Leader leader="dot" length="3pc" /> $15.00</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>For the services of liaison officers and necessary support staff who perform duties required under the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Special Voting Rules</XRefExternal>, there shall be paid, to the correctional institution by which those persons are employed, the value of any overtime paid to those persons for the performance of those services and any related sundry expenses incurred <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> the actual and reasonable amount paid, as supported by vouchers</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Other Travel and Living Expenses</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>54</Label><Text>Each person, other than a person referred to in any of items 1 to 53, who is employed in connection with the conduct of an election before or after the date of the issue of the writ shall, when requested by the Chief Electoral Officer to travel, be paid for travel and living expenses <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /> the allowances and expenses referred to in item 50</Text></Section><Section><Label>55</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2015-162, s. 16]</Repealed></Text></Section></RegulationPiece><HistoricalNote>SOR/2005-382, s. 1; SOR/2007-170, s. 4; SOR/2015-162, ss. 5 to 16.</HistoricalNote></Schedule></Regulation>