<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/97-62</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1996</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>30</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>10</MM><DD>28</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CUSTOMS TARIFF</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Regulations Defining Certain Expressions for the Purposes of the Customs Tariff</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1996-2074 </OrderNumber><Date><YYYY> 1996</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>30</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Finance, pursuant to section 58.4<FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-97-62_e_hq_5665">a</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-97-62_e_hq_5666">b</FootnoteRef>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations Defining Certain Expressions for the Purposes of the Customs Tariff</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fn_SOR-97-62_e_hq_5665" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 1996, c. 33, s. 45</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="fn_SOR-97-62_e_hq_5666" placement="page" status="official"><Label>b</Label><Text>R.S., c. 41 (3rd Supp.)</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Expressions Defined</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>For the purposes of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal>, the following expressions are defined.</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>imported from Israel or another CIFTA beneficiary</DefinedTermEn> means, in respect of goods,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>goods that are shipped to Canada from Israel or another CIFTA beneficiary without shipment through another country;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>goods that are shipped to Canada from Israel or another CIFTA beneficiary through another country, other than the United States, if</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the goods do not undergo further production or any other operation in the territory of that other country, other than unloading, splitting up of loads, reloading or any other operation necessary to preserve them in good condition or to ship them to Canada, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the goods remain under customs control in that other country;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>goods that are shipped to Canada from Israel or another CIFTA beneficiary through the United States, except for goods listed in any of Chapters 50 through 63 of the List of Tariff Provisions, if</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the goods do not undergo further production in the territory of the United States other than minor processing, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>any processing that occurs in the territory of the United States does not increase the transaction value of the goods by greater than 10%; or</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>goods listed in any of Chapters 50 through 63 of the List of Tariff Provisions that are shipped to Canada from Israel or another CIFTA beneficiary through the United States, if</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the goods do not undergo further production or any other operation in the territory of the United States, other than unloading, splitting up of loads, reloading or any other operation necessary to preserve them in good condition or to ship them to Canada, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the goods remain under customs control while in the United States. (<DefinedTermFr>importé d’Israël ou d’un autre bénéficiaire de l’ALÉCI</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Israel or another CIFTA beneficiary</DefinedTermEn> means the territory where the customs laws of Israel are applied and includes the territory where those laws are applied in accordance with Article III of the Protocol on Economic Relations set out in Annex V of the Israeli-Palestinian Interim Agreement on the West Bank and the Gaza Strip, dated September 28, 1995, as that Protocol is amended from time to time. (<DefinedTermFr>Israël ou autre bénéficiaire de l’ALÉCI</DefinedTermFr>) </Text></Definition><HistoricalNote>SOR/2002-250, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>1.1</Label><Text>For the purpose of section 1, <DefinedTermEn>territory</DefinedTermEn>, with respect to the United States, has the same meaning as in subsection 2(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">NAFTA Rules of Origin Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2002-250, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label><FootnoteRef idref="fn_Ind5BD7_hq_16389">*</FootnoteRef>2</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on the day on which section 45 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada-Israel Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act</XRefExternal>, chapter 33 of the Statutes of Canada, 1996, comes into force.</Text><Footnote id="fn_Ind5BD7_hq_16389" placement="section" status="editorial"><Label>*</Label><Text>[Note: Regulations in force January 1, 1997, <Emphasis style="italic">see</Emphasis> SI/97-9.]</Text></Footnote></Section></Body></Regulation>