<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2017-73</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2017</YYYY><MM>4</MM><DD>24</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2017</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>3</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">VISITING FORCES ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Proclamation Designating the Republic of Montenegro as a Designated State for the Purposes of the Act</LongTitle></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>David Johnston</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>[L.S.]</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Canada</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Elizabeth the Second, by the Grace of God of the United Kingdom, Canada and Her other Realms and Territories QUEEN, Head of the Commonwealth, Defender of the Faith.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><SignatureBlock justification="left" width="15pc"><SignatureName justification="left">William Pentney</SignatureName><SignatureTitle justification="left">Deputy Attorney General</SignatureTitle></SignatureBlock></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>TO ALL TO WHOM these presents shall come or whom the same may in any way concern,</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>GREETING:</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Heading level="1"><TitleText>A Proclamation</TitleText></Heading></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas section 4 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Visiting Forces Act</XRefExternal>, chapter V-2 of the Revised Statutes of Canada, 1985, provides that the Governor in Council may, by proclamation, designate any country as a designated state for the purposes of that Act, declare the extent to which that Act is applicable in respect of any designated state and designate civilian personnel as a civilian component of a visiting force;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Now Know You that We, by and with the advice of Our Privy Council for Canada, pursuant to Order in Council P.C. 2017-260 of March 24, 2017, do by this Our Proclamation</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>designate the Republic of Montenegro as a designated state for the purposes of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Visiting Forces Act</XRefExternal>;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>declare that the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Visiting Forces Act</XRefExternal>, with the exception of Part VI, is applicable in respect of the Republic of Montenegro; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>designate, as a civilian component of a visiting force from the Republic of Montenegro, the civilian personnel in the employ of that force in Canada who are not stateless persons, nationals of any state that is not a designated state or citizens or residents of Canada.</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Of all which Our Loving Subjects and all others whom these presents may concern are required to take notice and to govern themselves accordingly.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>IN TESTIMONY WHEREOF, We have caused this Our Proclamation to be published and the Great Seal of Canada to be affixed to it.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>WITNESS:</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="yes"><Text>Our Right Trusty and Well-beloved David Johnston, Chancellor and Principal Companion of Our Order of Canada, Chancellor and Commander of Our Order of Military Merit, Chancellor and Commander of Our Order of Merit of the Police Forces, Governor General and Commander-in-Chief of Canada.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>AT OUR GOVERNMENT HOUSE, in Our City of Ottawa, this eleventh day of April in the year of Our Lord two thousand and seventeen and in the sixty-sixth year of Our Reign.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>By Command,</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><SignatureBlock justification="left" width="15pc"><SignatureName justification="left">John Knubley</SignatureName><SignatureTitle justification="left">Deputy Registrar General of Canada</SignatureTitle></SignatureBlock></Provision></Order></Regulation>