<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en" in-force="yes"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2015-26</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2015</YYYY><MM>2</MM><DD>6</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2015</YYYY><MM>2</MM><DD>25</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">RAILWAY SAFETY ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Railway Safety Management System Regulations, 2015</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2015-91</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>2015</YYYY><MM>2</MM><DD>5</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Transport, pursuant to sections 37<FootnoteRef idref="fn_2-173e_hq_11993">a</FootnoteRef>, 47 and 47.1<FootnoteRef idref="fn_2-173e_hq_11994">b</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Railway Safety Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_2-173e_hq_11992">c</FootnoteRef>, makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Railway Safety Management System Regulations, 2015</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fn_2-173e_hq_11993" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 2012, c. 7, s. 30</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="fn_2-173e_hq_11994" placement="page" status="official"><Label>b</Label><Text>S.C. 2012, c. 7, s. 37</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="fn_2-173e_hq_11992" placement="page" status="official"><Label>c</Label><Text>R.S., c. 32 (4th Supp.)</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Definitions</MarginalNote><Label>1</Label><Text>The following definitions apply in these Regulations.</Text><Definition><MarginalNote><DefinedTermEn>accountable executive</DefinedTermEn></MarginalNote><MarginalNote><DefinedTermFr>gestionnaire supérieur responsable</DefinedTermFr></MarginalNote><Text><DefinedTermEn>accountable executive</DefinedTermEn> means the executive referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>8</XRefInternal>(1) or <XRefInternal>43</XRefInternal>(1), as the case may be.</Text></Definition><Definition><MarginalNote><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn></MarginalNote><MarginalNote><DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr></MarginalNote><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Railway Safety Act</XRefExternal>.</Text></Definition><Definition><MarginalNote><DefinedTermEn>dangerous goods</DefinedTermEn></MarginalNote><MarginalNote><DefinedTermFr>marchandises dangereuses</DefinedTermFr></MarginalNote><Text><DefinedTermEn>dangerous goods</DefinedTermEn> has the meaning assigned in section 2 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Transportation of Dangerous Goods Act, 1992</XRefExternal>.</Text></Definition><Definition><MarginalNote><DefinedTermEn>main track</DefinedTermEn></MarginalNote><MarginalNote><DefinedTermFr>voie ferrée principale</DefinedTermFr></MarginalNote><Text><DefinedTermEn>main track</DefinedTermEn> means a line of railway on which the movement of railway equipment is authorized by a railway company.</Text></Definition><Definition><MarginalNote><DefinedTermEn>non-main track</DefinedTermEn></MarginalNote><MarginalNote><DefinedTermFr>voie ferrée non principale</DefinedTermFr></MarginalNote><Text><DefinedTermEn>non-main track</DefinedTermEn> means a line of railway other than a main track.</Text></Definition><Definition><MarginalNote><DefinedTermEn>railway occurrence</DefinedTermEn></MarginalNote><MarginalNote><DefinedTermFr>accident ferroviaire</DefinedTermFr></MarginalNote><Text><DefinedTermEn>railway occurrence</DefinedTermEn> means a railway occurrence that is reportable under section 5 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Transportation Safety Board Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Overview</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Purpose</MarginalNote><Label>2</Label><Text>These Regulations establish the minimum requirements with respect to the safety management system that a company must develop and implement for the purpose of achieving the highest level of safety in its railway operations.</Text></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Organization — Parts</MarginalNote><Label>3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>These Regulations are divided into three Parts:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>Part 1 sets out the requirements applicable to a railway company with respect to its safety management system and with respect to record-keeping, notification and filing of information;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>Part 2 sets out</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>in Division 1, the requirements applicable to a local railway company that operates railway equipment on main track with respect to its safety management system and with respect to record-keeping, notification and filing of information, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>in Division 2, the requirements applicable to a local railway company that operates railway equipment exclusively on non-main track with respect to its safety management system and with respect to record-keeping, notification and filing of information; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>Part 3 makes consequential amendments to the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Railway Operating Certificate Regulations</XRefExternal>, repeals the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Railway Safety Management System Regulations</XRefExternal> and sets out the date on which these Regulations come into force.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Organization — processes</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The safety management system requirements set out in Parts 1 and 2 are organized into key processes that group together related requirements, including, in most instances, the requirement that a company develop and implement</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>procedures that establish a step-by-step sequence of activities for dealing with certain matters;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>methods that are not necessarily a step-by-step sequence of activities, but that establish the manner in which certain evaluation, verification or supervisory activities are to be carried out; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>plans that establish the proposed time for carrying out certain activities with respect to the consultation and knowledge management requirements, and the proposed manner in which those activities are to be carried out.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 1</Label><TitleText>Railway Companies</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Railway company</MarginalNote><Label>4</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>This Part applies to a railway company.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Delayed application</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>In the case of a railway company that begins railway operations after the day on which these Regulations come into force, sections <XRefInternal>21</XRefInternal> to <XRefInternal>23</XRefInternal> do not apply until the day that is six months after the day on which the railway company begins railway operations.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Safety Management System</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Processes, Procedures, Plans and Methods</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Processes</MarginalNote><Label>5</Label><Text>A railway company must develop and implement a safety management system that includes</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a process for accountability;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a process with respect to a safety policy;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a process for ensuring compliance with regulations, rules and other instruments;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a process for managing railway occurrences;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>a process for identifying safety concerns;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>a risk assessment process;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>a process for implementing and evaluating remedial action;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>a process for establishing targets and developing initiatives;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>a process for reporting contraventions and safety hazards;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(j)</Label><Text>a process for managing knowledge;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(k)</Label><Text>a process with respect to scheduling; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(l)</Label><Text>a process for continual improvement of the safety management system.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Index</MarginalNote><Label>6</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A railway company must keep an up-to-date index of all the processes referred to in section <XRefInternal>5</XRefInternal> that it has implemented.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Content of index</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The index must indicate the date of the last revision of the railway company’s safety policy and must indicate, for each process,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the management position occupied by a person designated under subsection <XRefInternal>8</XRefInternal>(4), if applicable;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the procedures, plans and methods required by this Part that are associated with the process, and the date of their last revision; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the position in the railway company that has responsibility for the development and implementation of the procedures, plans and methods.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Procedures, plans and methods</MarginalNote><Label>7</Label><Text>Every procedure, plan and method required by this Part must be in writing and must indicate the date of its last revision.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Process for Accountability — Accountable Executive</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Designation of executive</MarginalNote><Label>8</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A railway company must designate an executive who is responsible for the operations and activities of the railway company to be accountable for the extent to which the requirements of the safety management system are met, including its effectiveness in achieving the highest level of safety in its railway operations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Notice to Minister</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The railway company must provide the Minister with the name of the accountable executive as soon as possible after he or she has been designated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Declaration to the Minister</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The railway company must ensure that, within 30 days after the day on which it designates an accountable executive, the accountable executive provides the Minister with a signed declaration accepting accountability for the extent to which the requirements of the safety management system have been met.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Designation of managers</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The railway company may, in its safety management system, permit the accountable executive to designate one or more persons to develop and implement one or more of the processes required by this Part. A designated person must occupy a management position within the railway company that includes responsibilities relevant to the process or processes and the authority to make decisions with respect to that process or those processes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Annual update</MarginalNote><Label>(5)</Label><Text>If the accountable executive designates a person under subsection (4), the accountable executive must ensure that the person reports to him or her, on an annual basis, with respect to</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any problems following the procedures or implementing the plans and methods, and the manner in which those problems have been or are being resolved or, if applicable, the reasons why they have not been or are not being resolved; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the effectiveness of the procedures, plans and methods in contributing to the improvement of the safety of the railway company’s operations.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Process with Respect to a Safety Policy</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Safety policy</MarginalNote><Label>9</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A railway company must include, in its safety management system, a written safety policy that reflects the railway company’s commitment to promoting railway safety. The policy must be approved and signed by the accountable executive.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Annual review</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The railway company must ensure that its safety policy is reviewed annually.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Communication</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The railway company must communicate its safety policy, and any changes to the policy, to its employees.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Process for Ensuring Compliance with Regulations, Rules and Other Instruments</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>List of instruments</MarginalNote><Label>10</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A railway company must include, in its safety management system, a list of the following instruments relating to railway safety:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any regulations made under the Act that apply to the railway company and that are in force;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any engineering standards approved by the Minister under section 7 of the Act or established by the Minister under subsection 19(7) of the Act that apply to the railway company and that are in effect;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>any rules approved or established by the Minister under section 19 of the Act that apply to the railway company and that are in force;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>any exemptions granted under section 22 or 22.1 of the Act that apply to the railway company and that are in effect;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>any notices sent to the railway company under section 31 of the Act that contain an order and that are in effect; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>any documents in effect by which the Minister has ordered the railway company to do or to not do something, including a ministerial order issued under section 32 of the Act and an emergency directive sent under section 33 of the Act.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Date and subject matter</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The list of instruments must include</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in the case of an engineering standard or a rule, the date on which it was approved or established; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the case of an exemption, a notice, or a document referred to in paragraph (1)(f), the date and subject matter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Update</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The railway company must keep the list of instruments up to date and must indicate the date of its last revision.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Procedure</MarginalNote><Label>11</Label><Text>A railway company must include, in its safety management system, a procedure for</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>reviewing and updating the list of instruments referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>10</XRefInternal>(1); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>verifying compliance with</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the requirements of the regulations, engineering standards, rules, and notices and documents containing an order, that are referred to in the list of instruments, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the terms of the exemptions referred to in the list of instruments.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Process for Managing Railway Occurrences</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Procedure</MarginalNote><Label>12</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A railway company must include, in its safety management system, a procedure for</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>reporting a railway occurrence to the railway company’s management; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>reviewing a railway occurrence.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Communication</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The railway company must communicate to its employees the procedure for reporting railway occurrences.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Process for Identifying Safety Concerns</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Analyses</MarginalNote><Label>13</Label><Text>A railway company must, on a continual basis, conduct analyses of its railway operations to identify safety concerns, including any trends, any emerging trends or any repetitive situations. The analyses must, at a minimum, be based on</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any reports of railway occurrences;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any internal documentation relating to railway occurrences;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>any reports of injuries;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the results of any inspections conducted by the railway company or by a railway safety inspector;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>any reports of contraventions or safety hazards that are received by the railway company from its employees;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>any complaints relating to safety that are received by the railway company;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>any data from safety monitoring technologies;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>the conclusions of the annual report referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>29</XRefInternal>(3); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the findings of any audit reports.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Procedure</MarginalNote><Label>14</Label><Text>A railway company must include, in its safety management system, a procedure for conducting the analyses referred to in section <XRefInternal>13</XRefInternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Risk Assessment Process</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Risk assessment</MarginalNote><Label>15</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A railway company must conduct a risk assessment in the following circumstances:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>when it identifies a safety concern in its railway operations as a result of the analyses conducted under section <XRefInternal>13</XRefInternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>when it proposes to begin transporting dangerous goods, or to begin transporting dangerous goods different from those it already transports; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>when a proposed change to its railway operations, including a change set out below, may affect the safety of the public or personnel or the protection of property or the environment:</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the introduction or elimination of a technology, or a change to a technology,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the addition or elimination of a railway work, or a change to a railway work,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>an increase in the volume of dangerous goods it transports,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>a change to the route on which dangerous goods are transported, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(v)</Label><Text>a change affecting personnel, including an increase or decrease in the number of employees or a change in their responsibilities or duties.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Components</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The risk assessment must</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>describe the circumstances that triggered the requirement to conduct the risk assessment;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>identify and describe the risks associated with those circumstances;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>identify the factors taken into account in the risk assessment, including the persons who may be affected and whether property or the environment is affected;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>indicate, for each risk, the likelihood that the risk will occur and the severity of its consequences;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>identify the risks that require remedial action; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>identify the remedial action for each of those risks.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Consultation</MarginalNote><Label>16</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>When identifying the risks that require remedial action and the remedial action to be implemented, a railway company must consult with the bargaining agents representing the employees of the railway company who are affected by any of those risks or, if there is no bargaining agent, with</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the employees of the railway company who are affected by any of those risks; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a representative selected by the employees of the railway company.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Communication</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The railway company must communicate the risks identified as requiring remedial action, and the remedial action to be implemented, to the employees of the railway company who are affected by any of the circumstances referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>15</XRefInternal>(1).</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Procedure, plan and method</MarginalNote><Label>17</Label><Text>A railway company must include, in its safety management system,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a procedure for identifying the risks that require remedial action, taking into account, for each risk, the likelihood that the risk will occur and the severity of its consequences;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a plan for the consultation referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>16</XRefInternal>(1); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a method for evaluating the level of risk, taking into account the likelihood that a risk will occur and the severity of its consequences.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Process for Implementing and Evaluating Remedial Action</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Remedial action — implementation</MarginalNote><Label>18</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A railway company must implement remedial action with respect to the risks that it has identified in its risk assessment as requiring remedial action.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Remedial action — evaluation</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The railway company must evaluate the effectiveness of the remedial action in reducing or eliminating the risks.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Consultation</MarginalNote><Label>19</Label><Text>When evaluating the effectiveness of remedial action with respect to a risk, a railway company must consult with the bargaining agents representing the employees of the railway company who are affected by the risk or, if there is no bargaining agent, with</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the employees of the railway company who are affected by the risk; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a representative selected by the employees of the railway company.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Procedures and plan</MarginalNote><Label>20</Label><Text>A railway company must include, in its safety management system,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a procedure for selecting the remedial action to be implemented;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a procedure for implementing the remedial action and evaluating its effectiveness; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a plan for the consultation referred to in section <XRefInternal>19</XRefInternal>.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Process for Establishing Targets and Developing Initiatives</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Targets and initiatives</MarginalNote><Label>21</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A railway company must, for each calendar year,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>establish targets designed to improve the safety of its railway operations; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>develop initiatives to achieve each target.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Basis for establishing targets</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The targets must be based on the analyses conducted under section <XRefInternal>13</XRefInternal> and must take into account the results of any previous analyses.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Details of initiatives</MarginalNote><Label>22</Label><Text>A railway company must include, in its safety management system, a written description of each initiative to be implemented in order to achieve each target and a written explanation of how the initiative will contribute to achieving that target.</Text></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Communication</MarginalNote><Label>23</Label><Text>A railway company must communicate to its employees the targets established and the initiatives to be implemented.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Process for Reporting Contraventions and Safety Hazards</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Internal reporting</MarginalNote><Label>24</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A railway company must include, in its safety management system, a procedure for enabling its employees to report to the railway company, without fear of reprisal, a contravention of the Act or of any regulations, rules, certificates, orders or emergency directives made under the Act in relation to safety, or a safety hazard.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Policy</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The railway company must include, in its safety management system, a policy, in writing, for protecting its employees from reprisals for reporting a contravention or safety hazard.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Collaboration</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The railway company must develop the procedure and the policy in collaboration with the bargaining agents or, if there is no bargaining agent, with its employees or a representative selected by its employees.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Communication</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The railway company must communicate the procedure and the policy to its employees.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Process for Managing Knowledge</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>List</MarginalNote><Label>25</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A railway company must establish a list setting out</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the duties that are essential to safe railway operations;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the positions in the railway company that have responsibility for the performance of each of those duties; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the skills and qualifications required to perform each of those duties safely.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Employees — skills and qualifications</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The railway company must ensure that an employee who performs any of the duties referred to in paragraph (1)(a) has the skills and qualifications referred to in paragraph (1)(c).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Employees — knowledge</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The railway company must ensure that an employee who performs any of the duties referred to in paragraph (1)(a) has knowledge of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the requirements of the instruments referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>10</XRefInternal>(1) that the employee needs to know to carry out his or her duties safely;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any federal legislation that may affect railway safety and that the employee needs to know to carry out his or her duties safely; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>any of the railway company’s procedures — including any procedure referred to in this Part — standards, instructions, bulletins or other internal documents that may affect railway safety and that the employee needs to know to carry out his or her duties safely.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Other persons</MarginalNote><Label>26</Label><Text>A railway company must ensure that any person, other than an employee, who is authorized by the railway company to access the railway and whose activities may affect the safety of railway operations has knowledge of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the requirements of the instruments referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>10</XRefInternal>(1) that the person needs to know to carry out his or her activities safely;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any federal legislation that may affect railway safety and that the person needs to know to carry out his or her activities safely; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>any of the railway company’s procedures — including any procedure referred to in this Part — standards, instructions, bulletins or other internal documents that may affect railway safety and that the person needs to know to carry out his or her activities safely.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Plan and methods</MarginalNote><Label>27</Label><Text>A railway company must include, in its safety management system,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a plan for ensuring that an employee who performs any of the duties referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1)(a) has the skills and qualifications referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1)(c) and the knowledge referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(3);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a method for verifying that an employee who performs any of the duties referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1)(a) has the skills and qualifications referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1)(c) and the knowledge referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(3);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a method for supervising an employee who performs any of the duties referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1)(a); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a method for verifying that a person referred to in section <XRefInternal>26</XRefInternal> has the knowledge referred to in that section.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Process with Respect to Scheduling</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Principles of fatigue science</MarginalNote><Label>28</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A railway company must apply the principles of fatigue science when scheduling the work of the employees referred to in subsection (2), including the principles</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>that human fatigue is governed by physiology;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>that human alertness is affected by circadian rhythms;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>that human performance degrades in relation to hours of wakefulness and accumulated sleep debt; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>that humans have baseline minimum physiological sleep needs.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Method</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The railway company must include, in its safety management system, a method for applying the principles of fatigue science when scheduling the work of an employee who is required to work according to a schedule that</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>is not communicated to the employee at least 72 hours in advance;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>requires the employee to work beyond his or her normal work schedule; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>requires the employee to work between midnight and 6:00 a.m.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Communication</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The railway company must communicate, to any employees who are required by the railway company to work according to a schedule referred to in subsection (2), how the principles of fatigue science have been taken into account when requiring them to work according to that schedule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Exception</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>This section does not apply when scheduling the work of employees during an emergency related to the safety of railway operations.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Process for Continual Improvement of the Safety Management System</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Internal Monitoring</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Monitoring</MarginalNote><Label>29</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A railway company must, on a continual basis, monitor the implementation of its safety management system to verify</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>whether the bargaining agents, the employees or a representative selected by the employees are being involved in the processes as required by this Part;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>whether the targets established by the railway company under section <XRefInternal>21</XRefInternal> are being achieved; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>whether the procedures required by this Part are being followed, and whether the policy referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>24</XRefInternal>(2) and the methods and plans required by this Part are being implemented.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Deficiencies in implementation</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Monitoring must include, if applicable, inquiring into</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the cause of any deficiencies in the implementation of the railway company’s safety management system and any actions being taken to remedy those deficiencies; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the reasons why the targets are not being achieved.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Annual report</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The railway company must prepare an annual report setting out the conclusions of its monitoring activities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Accountable executive</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The railway company must ensure that the conclusions of the annual report are brought to the attention of the accountable executive.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Internal Audit</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Scope and frequency</MarginalNote><Label>30</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A railway company must conduct an audit of its safety management system every three years to evaluate</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the extent to which the requirements related to each process have been implemented; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the extent to which the policy referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>24</XRefInternal>(2) and the procedures, plans and methods developed by the railway company are effective in improving the level of safety of its railway operations.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Audit plan</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The railway company must include, in its safety management system, an audit plan that</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>defines the scope of each audit;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>indicates the evaluation criteria to be applied;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>specifies the method to be used in conducting each evaluation; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>sets out the schedule for evaluating each process.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Audit report</MarginalNote><Label>31</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A railway company must prepare an audit report that includes the findings of the audit.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Accountable executive</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The accountable executive must sign the audit report to attest to his or her acceptance of the report.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Action plan</MarginalNote><Label>32</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A railway company must prepare an action plan setting out the action to be taken to address each finding in the audit report that it identifies as a deficiency in its safety management system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Approval of action plan</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The accountable executive must sign the action plan to acknowledge that he or she approves it.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Records</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Review, analysis and evaluation</MarginalNote><Label>33</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A railway company must keep a record of the factors taken into account in, and the results of,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the annual review of its safety policy;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>each analysis conducted under section <XRefInternal>13</XRefInternal>; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>each evaluation conducted under subsection <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(2).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Date</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The record referred to in subsection (1) must include the date on which the review, analysis or evaluation was undertaken.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Consultation, communication or collaboration</MarginalNote><Label>34</Label><Text>For each instance in which a railway company, in accordance with this Part, consults, communicates or collaborates with bargaining agents, employees or a representative selected by employees, the railway company must keep a record of the date and subject matter of the consultation, communication or collaboration and the manner in which it was carried out.</Text></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Specified documents</MarginalNote><Label>35</Label><Text>A railway company must keep the following records:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the documentation relating to each risk assessment conducted under section <XRefInternal>15</XRefInternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the written description and written explanation referred to in section <XRefInternal>22</XRefInternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the annual report referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>29</XRefInternal>(3);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the audit plan referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>30</XRefInternal>(2);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the signed audit report referred to in section <XRefInternal>31</XRefInternal>; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>the approved action plan referred to in section <XRefInternal>32</XRefInternal>.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Duration</MarginalNote><Label>36</Label><Text>A railway company must keep the records referred to in sections <XRefInternal>33</XRefInternal> to <XRefInternal>35</XRefInternal> for six years after the day on which they are created.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Filing and Notification</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Filing with the Minister</MarginalNote><Label>37</Label><Text>A railway company must, at the request of the Minister, file with the Minister</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>an up-to-date copy of the index referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(1);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the targets and initiatives referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>21</XRefInternal>(1) for the current calendar year;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the written description and written explanation referred to in section <XRefInternal>22</XRefInternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the latest annual report referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>29</XRefInternal>(3); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the latest signed audit report referred to in section <XRefInternal>31</XRefInternal>.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Notification and filing</MarginalNote><Label>38</Label><Text>A railway company that proposes to make a change referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>15</XRefInternal>(1)(b) or (c) must, before making the change, notify the Minister of the change and must, at the request of the Minister, file with the Minister the documentation relating to the risk assessment that it conducted with respect to the change.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 2</Label><TitleText>Local Railway Companies</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><Label>DIVISION 1</Label><TitleText>Main Track Operations</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Local railway company — main track</MarginalNote><Label>39</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>This Division applies to a local railway company that operates railway equipment on main track.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Delayed application</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>In the case of a local railway company that begins operating railway equipment on a railway after the day on which these Regulations come into force, sections <XRefInternal>54</XRefInternal> to <XRefInternal>56</XRefInternal> do not apply until the day that is six months after the day on which the local railway company begins operating railway equipment on a railway.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Safety Management System</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Processes, Procedures and Methods</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Processes</MarginalNote><Label>40</Label><Text>A local railway company must develop and implement a safety management system that includes</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a process for accountability;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a process with respect to a safety policy;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a process for ensuring compliance with regulations, rules and other instruments;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a process for identifying safety concerns;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>a risk assessment process;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>a process for implementing and evaluating remedial action;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>a process for establishing targets and developing initiatives; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>a process for continual improvement of the safety management system.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Index</MarginalNote><Label>41</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A local railway company must keep an up-to-date index of all the processes referred to in section <XRefInternal>40</XRefInternal> that it has implemented.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Content of index</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The index must indicate the date of the last revision of the local railway company’s safety policy and must indicate, for each process,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the management position occupied by a person designated under subsection <XRefInternal>43</XRefInternal>(4), if applicable;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the procedures and methods required by this Division that are associated with the process, and the date of their last revision; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the position in the local railway company that has responsibility for the development and implementation of the procedures and methods.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Procedures and methods</MarginalNote><Label>42</Label><Text>Every procedure and method required by this Division must be in writing and must indicate the date of its last revision.</Text></Section><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Process for Accountability — Accountable Executive</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Designation of executive</MarginalNote><Label>43</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A local railway company must designate an executive who is responsible for the operations and activities of the local railway company to be accountable for the extent to which the requirements of the safety management system are met, including its effectiveness in achieving the highest level of safety in its railway operations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Notice to Minister</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The local railway company must provide the Minister with the name of the accountable executive as soon as possible after he or she has been designated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Declaration to the Minister</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The local railway company must ensure that, within 30 days after the day on which it designates an accountable executive, the accountable executive provides the Minister with a signed declaration accepting accountability for the extent to which the requirements of the safety management system have been met.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Designation of managers</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The local railway company may, in its safety management system, permit the accountable executive to designate one or more persons to develop and implement one or more of the processes required by this Division. A designated person must occupy a management position within the local railway company that includes responsibilities relevant to the process or processes and the authority to make decisions with respect to that process or those processes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Annual update</MarginalNote><Label>(5)</Label><Text>If the accountable executive designates a person under subsection (4), the accountable executive must ensure that the person reports to him or her, on an annual basis, with respect to</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any problems following the procedures or implementing the methods, and the manner in which those problems have been or are being resolved or, if applicable, the reasons why they have not been or are not being resolved; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the effectiveness of the procedures and methods in contributing to the improvement of the safety of the local railway company’s operations.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Process with Respect to a Safety Policy</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Safety policy</MarginalNote><Label>44</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A local railway company must include, in its safety management system, a written safety policy that reflects the local railway company’s commitment to promoting railway safety. The policy must be approved and signed by the accountable executive.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Annual review</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The local railway company must ensure that its safety policy is reviewed annually.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Communication</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The local railway company must communicate its safety policy, and any changes to the policy, to its employees.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Process for Ensuring Compliance with Regulations, Rules and Other Instruments</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>List of instruments</MarginalNote><Label>45</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A local railway company must include, in its safety management system, a list of the following instruments relating to railway safety:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any regulations made under the Act that apply to the local railway company and that are in force;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any rules approved or established by the Minister under section 19 of the Act that apply to the local railway company and that are in force;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>any exemptions granted under section 22 or 22.1 of the Act that apply to the local railway company and that are in effect;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>any notices sent to the local railway company under section 31 of the Act that contain an order and that are in effect; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>any documents in effect by which the Minister has ordered the local railway company to do or to not do something, including a ministerial order issued under section 32 of the Act and an emergency directive sent under section 33 of the Act.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Date and subject matter</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The list of instruments must include</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in the case of a rule, the date on which it was approved or established; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the case of an exemption, a notice, or a document referred to in paragraph (1)(e), the date and subject matter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Update</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The local railway company must keep the list of instruments up to date and must indicate the date of its last revision.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Procedures</MarginalNote><Label>46</Label><Text>A local railway company must include, in its safety management system, a procedure for</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>reviewing and updating the list of instruments referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>45</XRefInternal>(1); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>verifying compliance with</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the requirements of the regulations, rules, and notices and documents containing an order, that are referred to in the list of instruments, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the terms of the exemptions referred to in the list of instruments.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Process for Identifying Safety Concerns</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Analyses</MarginalNote><Label>47</Label><Text>A local railway company must, on a continual basis, conduct analyses of its railway operations to identify safety concerns, including any trends, any emerging trends or any repetitive situations. The analyses must, at a minimum, be based on</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any reports of accidents;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any internal documentation relating to accidents;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>any reports of injuries;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the results of any inspections conducted by the local railway company or by a railway safety inspector;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>any reports of contraventions or safety hazards that are received by the local railway company from its employees;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>any complaints relating to safety that are received by the local railway company;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>any data that is accessible to the local railway company from safety monitoring technologies;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>the conclusions of the annual report referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>57</XRefInternal>(3); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the findings of any audit reports.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Procedure</MarginalNote><Label>48</Label><Text>A local railway company must include, in its safety management system, a procedure for conducting the analyses referred to in section <XRefInternal>47</XRefInternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Risk Assessment Process</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Risk assessment</MarginalNote><Label>49</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A local railway company must conduct a risk assessment in the following circumstances:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>when it identifies a safety concern in its railway operations as a result of the analyses conducted under section <XRefInternal>47</XRefInternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>when it proposes to begin transporting dangerous goods, or to begin transporting dangerous goods different from those it already transports; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>when a proposed change to its railway operations, including a change set out below, may affect the safety of the public or personnel or the protection of property or the environment:</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the introduction or elimination of a technology, or a change to a technology,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>an increase in the volume of dangerous goods it transports,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>a change to the route on which dangerous goods are transported, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>a change affecting personnel, including an increase or decrease in the number of employees or a change in their responsibilities or duties.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Components</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The risk assessment must</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>describe the circumstances that triggered the requirement to conduct the risk assessment;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>identify and describe the risks associated with those circumstances;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>identify the factors taken into account in the risk assessment, including the persons who may be affected and whether property or the environment is affected;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>indicate, for each risk, the likelihood that the risk will occur and the severity of its consequences;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>identify the risks that require remedial action; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>identify the remedial action for each of those risks.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Communication</MarginalNote><Label>50</Label><Text>A local railway company must communicate the risks identified as requiring remedial action, and the remedial action to be implemented, to the employees of the local railway company who are affected by any of the circumstances referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>49</XRefInternal>(1).</Text></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Procedure and method</MarginalNote><Label>51</Label><Text>A local railway company must include, in its safety management system,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a procedure for identifying the risks that require remedial action, taking into account, for each risk, the likelihood that the risk will occur and the severity of its consequences; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a method for evaluating the level of risk, taking into account the likelihood that a risk will occur and the severity of its consequences.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Process for Implementing and Evaluating Remedial Action</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Remedial action — implementation</MarginalNote><Label>52</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A local railway company must implement remedial action with respect to the risks that it has identified in its risk assessment as requiring remedial action.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Remedial action — evaluation</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The local railway company must evaluate the effectiveness of the remedial action in reducing or eliminating the risks.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Procedures</MarginalNote><Label>53</Label><Text>A local railway company must include, in its safety management system,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a procedure for selecting the remedial action to be implemented; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a procedure for implementing the remedial action and evaluating its effectiveness.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Process for Establishing Targets and Developing Initiatives</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Targets and initiatives</MarginalNote><Label>54</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A local railway company must, for each calendar year,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>establish targets designed to improve the safety of its railway operations; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>develop initiatives to achieve each target.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Basis for establishing targets</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The targets must be based on the analyses conducted under section <XRefInternal>47</XRefInternal> and must take into account the results of any previous analyses.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Details of initiative</MarginalNote><Label>55</Label><Text>A local railway company must include, in its safety management system, a written description of each initiative to be implemented in order to achieve each target and a written explanation of how the initiative will contribute to achieving that target.</Text></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Communication</MarginalNote><Label>56</Label><Text>A local railway company must communicate to its employees the targets established and the initiatives to be implemented.</Text></Section><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Process for Continual Improvement of the Safety Management System</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="5"><TitleText>Internal Monitoring</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Monitoring</MarginalNote><Label>57</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A local railway company must, on a continual basis, monitor the implementation of its safety management system to verify</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>whether the targets established by the local railway company under section <XRefInternal>54</XRefInternal> are being achieved; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>whether the procedures required by this Division are being followed, and whether the methods required by this Division are being implemented.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Deficiencies in implementation</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Monitoring must include, if applicable, inquiring into</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the cause of any deficiencies in the implementation of the local railway company’s safety management system and any actions being taken to remedy those deficiencies; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the reasons why the targets are not being achieved.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Annual report</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The local railway company must prepare an annual report setting out the conclusions of its monitoring activities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Accountable executive</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The local railway company must ensure that the conclusions of the annual report are brought to the attention of the accountable executive.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="5"><TitleText>Internal Audit</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Scope and frequency</MarginalNote><Label>58</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A local railway company must conduct an audit of its safety management system every three years to evaluate</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the extent to which the requirements related to each process have been implemented; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the extent to which the procedures and methods developed by the local railway company are effective in improving the level of safety of its railway operations.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Audit plan</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The local railway company must include, in its safety management system, an audit plan that</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>defines the scope of each audit;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>indicates the evaluation criteria to be applied;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>specifies the method to be used in conducting each evaluation; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>sets out the schedule for evaluating each process.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Audit report</MarginalNote><Label>59</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A local railway company must prepare an audit report that includes the findings of the audit.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Accountable executive</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The accountable executive must sign the audit report to attest to his or her acceptance of the report.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Action plan</MarginalNote><Label>60</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A local railway company must prepare an action plan setting out the action to be taken to address each finding in the audit report that it identifies as a deficiency in its safety management system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Approval of action plan</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The accountable executive must sign the action plan to acknowledge that he or she approves it.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Records</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Review, analysis and evaluation</MarginalNote><Label>61</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A local railway company must keep a record of the factors taken into account in, and the results of,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the annual review of its safety policy;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>each analysis conducted under section <XRefInternal>47</XRefInternal>; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>each evaluation conducted under subsection <XRefInternal>52</XRefInternal>(2).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Date</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The record referred to in subsection (1) must include the date on which the review, analysis or evaluation was undertaken.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Communication</MarginalNote><Label>62</Label><Text>For each instance in which a local railway company communicates with its employees in accordance with this Division, the local railway company must keep a record of the date and subject matter of the communication and the manner in which it was carried out.</Text></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Specified documents</MarginalNote><Label>63</Label><Text>A local railway company must keep the following records:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the documentation relating to each risk assessment conducted under section <XRefInternal>49</XRefInternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the written description and written explanation referred to in section <XRefInternal>55</XRefInternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the annual report referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>57</XRefInternal>(3);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the audit plan referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>58</XRefInternal>(2);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the signed audit report referred to in section <XRefInternal>59</XRefInternal>; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>the approved action plan referred to in section <XRefInternal>60</XRefInternal>.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Duration</MarginalNote><Label>64</Label><Text>A local railway company must keep the records referred to in sections <XRefInternal>61</XRefInternal> to <XRefInternal>63</XRefInternal> for six years after the day on which they are created.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Filing and Notification</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Filing with the Minister</MarginalNote><Label>65</Label><Text>A local railway company must, at the request of the Minister, file with the Minister</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>an up-to-date copy of the index referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>41</XRefInternal>(1);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the targets and initiatives referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>54</XRefInternal>(1) for the current calendar year;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the written description and written explanation referred to in section <XRefInternal>55</XRefInternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the latest annual report referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>57</XRefInternal>(3); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the latest signed audit report referred to in section <XRefInternal>59</XRefInternal>.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Notification and filing</MarginalNote><Label>66</Label><Text>A local railway company that proposes to make a change referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>49</XRefInternal>(1)(b) or (c) must, before making the change, notify the Minister of the change and must, at the request of the Minister, file with the Minister the documentation relating to the risk assessment that it conducted with respect to the change.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><Label>DIVISION 2</Label><TitleText>Non-Main Track Operations</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Local railway company — non-main track</MarginalNote><Label>67</Label><Text>This Division applies to a local railway company that operates railway equipment exclusively on non-main track.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Safety Management System</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Processes, Procedures and Methods</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Processes</MarginalNote><Label>68</Label><Text>A local railway company must develop and implement a safety management system that includes</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a process with respect to a safety policy;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a process for ensuring compliance with regulations, rules and other instruments;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a process for identifying safety concerns;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a risk assessment process; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>a process for implementing and evaluating remedial action.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Index</MarginalNote><Label>69</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A local railway company must keep an up-to-date index of all the processes referred to in section <XRefInternal>68</XRefInternal> that it has implemented.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Content of index</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The index must indicate the date of the last revision of the local railway company’s safety policy and must indicate, for each process,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the procedures and methods required by this Division that are associated with the process, and the date of their last revision; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the position in the local railway company that has responsibility for the development and implementation of the process, procedures and methods.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Procedures and methods</MarginalNote><Label>70</Label><Text>Every procedure and method required by this Division must be in writing and must indicate the date of its last revision.</Text></Section><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Process with Respect to a Safety Policy</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Safety policy</MarginalNote><Label>71</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A local railway company must include, in its safety management system, a written safety policy that reflects the local railway company’s commitment to promoting railway safety. The policy must be approved and signed by an executive who is responsible for the operations and activities of the local railway company.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Annual review</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The local railway company must ensure that its safety policy is reviewed annually.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Communication</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The local railway company must communicate its safety policy, and any changes to the policy, to its employees.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Process for Ensuring Compliance with Regulations, Rules and Other Instruments</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>List of instruments</MarginalNote><Label>72</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A local railway company must include, in its safety management system, a list of the following instruments relating to railway safety:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any regulations made under the Act that apply to the local railway company and that are in force;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any rules approved or established by the Minister under section 19 of the Act that apply to the local railway company and that are in force;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>any exemptions granted under section 22 or 22.1 of the Act that apply to the local railway company and that are in effect;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>any notices sent to the local railway company under section 31 of the Act that contain an order and that are in effect; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>any documents in effect by which the Minister has ordered the local railway company to do or to not do something, including a ministerial order issued under section 32 of the Act and an emergency directive sent under section 33 of the Act.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Date and subject matter</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The list of instruments must include</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in the case of a rule, the date on which it was approved or established; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the case of an exemption, a notice, or a document referred to in paragraph (1)(e), the date and subject matter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Update</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The local railway company must keep the list of instruments up to date and must indicate the date of its last revision.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Procedures</MarginalNote><Label>73</Label><Text>A local railway company must include, in its safety management system, a procedure for</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>reviewing and updating the list of instruments referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>72</XRefInternal>(1); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>verifying compliance with</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the requirements of the regulations, rules, and notices and documents containing an order, that are referred to in the list of instruments, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the terms of the exemptions referred to in the list of instruments.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Process for Identifying Safety Concerns</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Analyses</MarginalNote><Label>74</Label><Text>A local railway company must, on a continual basis, conduct analyses of its railway operations to identify safety concerns, including any trends, any emerging trends or any repetitive situations. The analyses must, at a minimum, be based on</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any reports of accidents;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any internal documentation relating to accidents;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>any reports of injuries;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the results of any inspections conducted by the local railway company or by a railway safety inspector;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>any reports of contraventions or safety hazards that are received by the local railway company from its employees;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>any complaints relating to safety that are received by the local railway company;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>any data that is accessible to the local railway company from safety monitoring technologies; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>the findings of any audit reports.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Procedure</MarginalNote><Label>75</Label><Text>A local railway company must include, in its safety management system, a procedure for conducting the analyses referred to in section <XRefInternal>74</XRefInternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Risk Assessment Process</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Risk assessment</MarginalNote><Label>76</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A local railway company must conduct a risk assessment in the following circumstances:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>when it identifies a safety concern in its railway operations as a result of the analyses conducted under section <XRefInternal>74</XRefInternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>when it proposes to begin transporting dangerous goods, or to begin transporting dangerous goods different from those it already transports; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>when a proposed change to its railway operations, including a change set out below, may affect the safety of the public or personnel or the protection of property or the environment:</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the introduction or elimination of a technology, or a change to a technology,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>an increase in the volume of dangerous goods it transports,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>a change to the route on which dangerous goods are transported, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>a change affecting personnel, including an increase or decrease in the number of employees or a change in their responsibilities or duties.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Components</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The risk assessment must</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>describe the circumstances that triggered the requirement to conduct the risk assessment;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>identify and describe the risks associated with those circumstances;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>identify the factors taken into account in the risk assessment, including the persons who may be affected and whether property or the environment is affected;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>indicate, for each risk, the likelihood that the risk will occur and the severity of its consequences;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>identify the risks that require remedial action; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>identify the remedial action for each of those risks.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Communication</MarginalNote><Label>77</Label><Text>A local railway company must communicate the risks identified as requiring remedial action, and the remedial action to be implemented, to the employees of the local railway company who are affected by any of the circumstances referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>76</XRefInternal>(1).</Text></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Procedure and method</MarginalNote><Label>78</Label><Text>A local railway company must include, in its safety management system,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a procedure for identifying the risks that require remedial action, taking into account, for each risk, the likelihood that the risk will occur and the severity of its consequences; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a method for evaluating the level of risk, taking into account the likelihood that a risk will occur and the severity of its consequences.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Process for Implementing and Evaluating Remedial Action</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Remedial action — implementation</MarginalNote><Label>79</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A local railway company must implement remedial action with respect to the risks that it has identified in its risk assessment as requiring remedial action.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Remedial action — evaluation</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The local railway company must evaluate the effectiveness of the remedial action in reducing or eliminating the risks.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Procedures</MarginalNote><Label>80</Label><Text>A local railway company must include, in its safety management system,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a procedure for selecting the remedial action to be implemented; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a procedure for implementing the remedial action and evaluating its effectiveness.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Records</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Review, analysis and evaluation</MarginalNote><Label>81</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A local railway company must keep a record of the factors taken into account in, and the results of,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the annual review of its safety policy;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>each analysis conducted under section <XRefInternal>74</XRefInternal>; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>each evaluation conducted under subsection <XRefInternal>79</XRefInternal>(2).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Date</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The record referred to in subsection (1) must include the date on which the review, analysis or evaluation was undertaken.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Communication</MarginalNote><Label>82</Label><Text>For each instance in which a local railway company communicates with its employees in accordance with this Division, the local railway company must keep a record of the date and subject matter of the communication and the manner in which it was carried out.</Text></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Risk assessment</MarginalNote><Label>83</Label><Text>A local railway company must keep the documentation relating to each risk assessment conducted under section <XRefInternal>76</XRefInternal>.</Text></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Duration</MarginalNote><Label>84</Label><Text>A local railway company must keep the records referred to in sections <XRefInternal>81</XRefInternal> to <XRefInternal>83</XRefInternal> for three years after the day on which they are created.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Filing and Notification</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Filing with the Minister</MarginalNote><Label>85</Label><Text>A local railway company must, at the request of the Minister, file with the Minister an up-to-date copy of the index referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>69</XRefInternal>(1).</Text></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Notification and filing</MarginalNote><Label>86</Label><Text>A local railway company that proposes to make a change referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>76</XRefInternal>(1)(b) or (c) must, before making the change, notify the Minister of the change and must, at the request of the Minister, file with the Minister the documentation relating to the risk assessment that it conducted with respect to the change.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 3</Label><TitleText>Consequential Amendments, Repeal and Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Consequential Amendments to the Railway Operating Certificate Regulations</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>87</Label><Text>[Amendment]</Text></Section><Section><Label>88</Label><Text>[Amendment]</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Repeal</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>89</Label><Text>[Repeal]</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section type="transitional"><MarginalNote>April 1, 2015</MarginalNote><Label>90</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on April 1, 2015.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>