<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 238</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>13</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS MARKETING ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>P.E.I. Vegetable Licensing (Interprovincial and Export) Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting the Licensing in Interprovincial and Export Trade of Persons Engaged in the Marketing of Vegetable Produced in Prince Edward Island</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">P.E.I. Vegetable Licensing (Interprovincial and Export) Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Agency</DefinedTermEn> means the Prince Edward Island Vegetable Growers Cooperative Association and includes any sub-agents thereof; (<DefinedTermFr>Agence</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Commodity Board</DefinedTermEn> means the Prince Edward Island Vegetable Commodity Marketing Board; (<DefinedTermFr>Office de commercialisation</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>grower</DefinedTermEn> means any person who produces vegetable and includes a producer as defined in the Plan; (<DefinedTermFr>producteur</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>person</DefinedTermEn> means any individual, firm, partnership, association or corporation that grows or markets vegetable and includes any servants or agents thereof; (<DefinedTermFr>personne</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Plan</DefinedTermEn> means the Prince Edward Island Vegetable Commodity Marketing Plan established pursuant to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Prince Edward Island Natural Products Marketing Act</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>Plan</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>vegetable</DefinedTermEn> means any turnip produced in Prince Edward Island; (<DefinedTermFr>légumes</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>wholesaler</DefinedTermEn> means any person other than the Agency, who sells or offers for sale vegetable to any person other than directly to the consumer, but does not include a jobber or broker or a person who has no facilities that are customarily employed in his business to store or transport vegetable. (<DefinedTermFr>grossiste</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>These Regulations are limited in their application to regulating the marketing of vegetable in interprovincial and export trade and to persons and property situated in the Province of Prince Edward Island.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Prohibition</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>No person shall act as a wholesaler of vegetable in interprovincial or export trade unless he holds a subsisting wholesaler’s interprovincial and export licence issued by the Commodity Board.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Licences</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>Subject to section 6, the Commodity Board may issue a wholesaler’s interprovincial and export licence to any person who submits to the Commodity Board an application on the form prescribed by the Commodity Board together with a fee of $1.</Text></Section><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>No wholesaler’s interprovincial and export licence may be issued to a person who holds a licence as a grower under any regulation or order of the Commodity Board.</Text></Section><Section><Label>7</Label><Text>Every licence issued pursuant to section 5 shall expire on June 30th of the year for which it was issued.</Text></Section><Section><Label>8</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Any licence issued pursuant to section 5 may be suspended by the Commodity Board if the wholesaler fails to take reasonable steps to maintain the quality of any vegetable in his control or to comply with any regulation or order of the Commodity Board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Upon the application of any wholesaler whose licence has been suspended pursuant to subsection (1), the Commodity Board may reinstate the licence if such wholesaler satisfies the Commodity Board that he will comply with all regulations or orders of the Commodity Board in the future.</Text></Subsection></Section></Body></Regulation>