<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 1385</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>28</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">RAILWAY RELOCATION AND CROSSING ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Urban Development and Transportation Plans Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulation Respecting the Payment of Costs in Respect of the Preparation of Transportation Plans or Urban Development Plans</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Urban Development and Transportation Plans Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations, <DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Railway Relocation and Crossing Act</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Costs</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The part of the costs that may be included in calculating the amount of any payment authorized pursuant to subsection 3(3) of the Act are those costs that are in addition to the normal operating costs of the recipient of the payment and</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>that, in the case of a transportation plan, were, in the opinion of the Minister of Transport, incurred in the preparation of the plan; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>that, in the case of an urban development plan, were, in the opinion of the Minister of State for Urban Affairs, incurred in the preparation of the plan.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Any interest on funds borrowed in respect of the preparation of a plan shall not be included in calculating the additional costs referred to in subsection (1).</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/80-839, s. 1; SOR/82-502, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Payments</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A payment may be authorized pursuant to subsection 3(3) of the Act if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>prior to the commencement of the preparation of a plan, the Minister of Transport, in the case of a transportation plan, or the Minister of State for Urban Affairs, in the case of an urban development plan, has approved the proposed preparation and the terms of reference of the plan;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the recipient of the payment, who incurred, in whole or in part, the cost of preparing</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>a transportation plan,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>an urban development plan, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>a transportation plan and an urban development plan in respect of the same transportation study area,</Text></Subparagraph><ContinuedParagraph><Text>has granted any request made at any time by the Minister of Transport or the Minister of State for Urban Affairs to inspect and audit any receipts, records or other documents relating to the costs incurred in the preparation of the plan; and</Text></ContinuedParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>approval of the Treasury Board has been received where the payment in respect of the preparation of</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>a transportation plan,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>an urban development plan, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>a transportation plan and an urban development plan in respect of the same transportation study area,</Text></Subparagraph><ContinuedParagraph><Text>is in excess of $250,000.</Text></ContinuedParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Where a transportation plan and an urban development plan are prepared in respect of the same transportation study area and payment has been authorized pursuant to subsection 3(3) of the Act and these Regulations, the Minister of Transport and the Minister of State for Urban Affairs shall jointly establish the portion of the payment to be applied to each plan.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The Minister of Transport, in the case of the preparation of a transportation plan, or the Minister of State for Urban Affairs, in the case of an urban development plan, or both Ministers in the case of the preparation of a transportation plan and an urban development plan in respect of the same transportation study area, may authorize payments from time to time under subsection 3(3) of the Act and these Regulations in respect of a portion of the preparation of the plan prior to the completion of the plan.</Text></Subsection></Section></Body></Regulation>