<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 1126</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>15</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CANADA NATIONAL PARKS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>National Parks Highway Traffic Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Governing Highway Traffic in the National Parks of Canada</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">National Parks Highway Traffic Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>all terrain vehicle</DefinedTermEn> means a tracked, wheeled or air-cushioned motor vehicle designed for travel over trails, marshlands, muskeg, sand, snow or trackless terrain; (<DefinedTermFr>véhicule tout terrain</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>annual park motor licence</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/96-169, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>chartered bus</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/96-169, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>commercial vehicle</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/90-79, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Department</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/90-79, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Director</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/90-79, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>fiscal year</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/96-169, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>four-day park motor licence</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/96-169, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>gross vehicle weight</DefinedTermEn> means the combined weight of a motor vehicle and its load, if any; (<DefinedTermFr>masse brute</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>highway</DefinedTermEn> includes a road, street, avenue, parkway, driveway, lane, square, bridge, viaduct, trestle or other place within a park intended for use by the public for the passage or parking of vehicles; (<DefinedTermFr>route</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>local park motor licence</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/96-169, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>motor vehicle</DefinedTermEn> means any vehicle that is designed to be driven by any means other than by muscular power but does not include any vehicle designed to run upon rails, or to be drawn by another motor vehicle or an over-snow vehicle; (<DefinedTermFr>véhicule automobile</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>night time</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/96-169, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>non-profit charitable organization</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/96-169, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>one-day park motor licence</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/96-169, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>over-snow vehicle</DefinedTermEn> means a vehicle that is designed to</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>be driven by any means other than muscular power,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>run on tracks or skis or both, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>operate on snow or ice; (<DefinedTermFr>véhicule circulant sur la neige</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>park</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/96-169, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>park</DefinedTermEn>, in relation to a motor vehicle, means the stationing of the motor vehicle other than when it is being loaded or unloaded; (<DefinedTermFr>stationnement</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>park motor licence</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/96-169, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>park motor licence for a bus</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/96-169, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>passenger vehicle</DefinedTermEn> means an automobile, a motorcycle or a motor home and includes a bus converted to provide camping accommodation or a truck that has a gross vehicle weight not exceeding 4 550 kg; (<DefinedTermFr>véhicule de tourisme</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>public lane</DefinedTermEn> means a lane in a park appurtenant to business or residential premises generally used by the occupier of the premises and his servants and agents for the loading and unloading of chattels, including garbage, necessarily incidental to the business or residential use of the premises; (<DefinedTermFr>ruelle publique</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>scheduled bus</DefinedTermEn> means a bus operated on a fixed schedule, but does not include a chartered bus; (<DefinedTermFr>autobus à service régulier</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>seasonal park motor licence</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/96-169, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>senior citizen</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/95-150, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>sidewalk</DefinedTermEn> means a sidewalk in a park and includes any walk or path bordering a highway and constructed for pedestrian use; (<DefinedTermFr>trottoir</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Superintendent</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/90-79, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>trailer</DefinedTermEn> means a vehicle that is designed to be drawn along a highway by a motor vehicle but does not include</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>an implement of farm husbandry,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a side car attached to a motorcycle,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a disabled motor vehicle that is towed by a tow car, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a trailer unit that is borne and rides directly on the wheels of a truck tractor towing unit. (<DefinedTermFr>remorque</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, s. 1; SOR/91-375, s. 3(E); SOR/92-253, s. 1; SOR/92-546, s. 1(F); SOR/95-150, s. 1; SOR/96-169, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2.1</Label><Text>The following provisions do not apply in any Park in the Province of Alberta, namely, sections 11 to 14, subsections 16(3) and (4), sections 20 and 21, paragraph 26(a), sections 27 to 29, sections 32 and 33, sections 43 to 46, subsection 47(1) and sections 48 and 49.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/80-63, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>2.2</Label><Text>The following provisions do not apply in the Town of Banff or in the Town of Jasper, namely, section 15, subsections 16(1) and (2), sections 23 to 25, paragraph 26(b), sections 30, 31 and 34 to 39, paragraph 40(1)(d), sections 41 and 42 and subsection 47(2).</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-235; SOR/2010-23, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>2.3</Label><Text>The following provisions do not apply in any park in Newfoundland, namely, sections 11 to 14, subsections 16(3) and (4), sections 17, 18, 21, 22, 27 to 29 and 32 to 34, subsection 47(1) and sections 48 and 49.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/91-479, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Licences</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (2), no person shall operate a motor vehicle within a park except on a highway.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The superintendent may issue a permit for a specified period authorizing a person to operate the motor vehicle described in the permit on a specified trail or in a specified place or area in a park.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, s. 25(F); SOR/91-375, s. 3(E).</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/96-169, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>5 to 6.1</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/95-150, s. 3]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>7 to 9.2</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/96-169, s. 3]</Repealed></Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Special Permits</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>10</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (2), no person shall operate a truck that has a gross vehicle weight in excess of 4 550 kg or a scheduled bus on the Icefields Parkway in Banff and Jasper National Parks.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The superintendent shall, without charge, issue a special permit for the operation of a truck or a bus referred to in subsection (1) on the Icefields Parkway in Banff and Jasper National Parks where the operation of that truck or bus is required for park purposes or for the conduct of businesses on that Parkway.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/96-169, s. 4]</Repealed></Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, s. 6; SOR/92-546, s. 4; SOR/96-169, s. 4.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Provincial Laws</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>11</Label><Text>No person shall operate a motor vehicle on a highway unless</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the person holds all licences, permits and certificates required to operate the motor vehicle by the laws of the province in which the highway is situated;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the motor vehicle is registered and equipped in accordance with the laws of the province in which the highway is situated; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the person wears the equipment required to operate the motor vehicle by the laws of the province in which the highway is situated.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, s. 6; SOR/92-546, s. 5(F).</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>12</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>No person shall operate a motor vehicle on a highway otherwise than in accordance with the laws of the province in which the highway is situated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Notwithstanding subsection (1), in the event of any inconsistency between these Regulations and the laws of a province in which a highway is situated, these Regulations prevail to the extent of the inconsistency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>No passenger of a motor vehicle shall ride in or on a motor vehicle on a highway otherwise than in accordance with the laws of the province in which the highway is situated.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, s. 7.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Dimensions of Motor Vehicles</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>13</Label><Text>Subject to sections 14 and 16, no person shall operate a bus, truck tractor trailer combination, truck, or a passenger vehicle and house-trailer combination on any highway within a park unless the unit conforms with the dimensions and gross weights approved for the unit by the province in which the highway is situated.</Text></Section><Section><Label>14</Label><Text>The superintendent may issue a single trip permit for the operation of a motor vehicle having any dimensions or carrying any load, and a person in possession of that permit may operate that motor vehicle for the single trip authorized by the permit along such portion of the highway and under such conditions as the permit specifies.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, s. 25(F); SOR/91-375, s. 3(E).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Disposal of Waste</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>15</Label><Text>No person shall discharge or dispose of liquid or solid waste matter from a trailer or motor vehicle on a highway.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, s. 8.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Traffic Signs and Devices</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>16</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The superintendent may mark and erect on or along a highway a traffic sign or device that</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>prescribes rates of speed;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>regulates or prohibits the tethering of horses or the stopping or parking of motor vehicles or any class thereof;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>prescribes load limits and dimensions for motor vehicles or any class thereof or prohibits the use of the highway by a motor vehicle carrying loads in excess of prescribed load limits;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>designates the highway as a one-way highway;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>requires motor vehicles to stop;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>closes the highway to all motor vehicles or any class thereof;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>limits the hours during which the highway may be used;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>regulates pedestrian traffic;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>limits the use of the highway by horses or by a specific class or specific classes of motor vehicles;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(j)</Label><Text>designates a taxi or cab stand; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(k)</Label><Text>regulates, directs or controls in any other manner the use of the highway by horses, motor vehicles or pedestrians.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>No person other than the superintendent shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>mark or erect any traffic sign or device on or along a highway; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>remove or deface any traffic sign or device on or along a highway.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Every person using a highway shall obey the instructions on every traffic sign or device.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Subsection (3) does not apply to</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a person driving or operating a motor vehicle for the park fire protection service when proceeding to a fire; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a person driving or operating a police motor vehicle, ambulance or motor vehicle that belongs to the Department when proceeding to the scene of an accident, or when using the motor vehicle for any emergency purpose.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, ss. 9, 25(F); SOR/91-375, s. 3(E).</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>17</Label><Text>Where any traffic sign or device erected pursuant to section 16 bears a regulatory symbol, the symbol has the meaning prescribed for that symbol by the laws of the province in which the highway is situated.</Text></Section><Section><Label>18</Label><Text>Any traffic sign or device in a national park bearing the words “Government of Canada”, “Gouvernement du Canada”, “National Parks of Canada”, “Parcs nationaux du Canada” or any abbreviation thereof or purporting to have been erected by or under the authority of the superintendent shall be deemed to have been erected pursuant to these Regulations.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, s. 25(F); SOR/91-375, s. 3(E).</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>19</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/90-79, s. 10]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>20</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The superintendent may by order prohibit a person from</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>parking a motor vehicle on a highway; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>loading or unloading a motor vehicle on a highway.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A person who receives a copy of an order made by the superintendent under subsection (1) shall comply with the order.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, s. 25(F); SOR/91-375, s. 3(E).</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>21</Label><Text>The driver of a motor vehicle on a highway shall, notwithstanding any traffic sign or device, comply with any traffic directions given to him by a police constable or any person appointed by the superintendent to direct the movement of motor vehicles.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, s. 25(F); SOR/91-375, s. 3(E).</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>22</Label><Text>Every person operating a motor vehicle within a park shall, on the request of a park warden, police constable or peace officer,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>stop the motor vehicle and give to the park warden, police constable or peace officer information respecting the motor vehicle; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>produce for inspection by the park warden, police constable or peace officer any licence, permit, pass or certificate that is required by these Regulations or by the laws of the province in which the park is situated to operate the motor vehicle in the park.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, s. 11; SOR/92-546, s. 6(F).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Parking</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>23</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The superintendent may erect a sign that designates an area as</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>an area where parking is reserved for persons holding parking permits;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>an area where parking is permitted for a period of time; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>an area where parking is not permitted.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>No person shall park a motor vehicle in an area designated pursuant to paragraph (1)(a) unless he</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>holds a parking permit authorizing him to park in the area;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>attaches to and exposes on the motor vehicle the label furnished with the parking permit; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>parks in accordance with the terms of his parking permit.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>No person shall park a motor vehicle in an area designated pursuant to paragraph (1)(b) for any greater period of time than that designated by the sign.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>No person shall park a motor vehicle in an area designated pursuant to paragraph (1)(c).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>No person shall park a motor vehicle or a trailer on a highway for purposes of overnight accommodation except in areas or at locations designated for that purpose by the superintendent.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, ss. 12, 25(F); SOR/91-375, s. 3(E).</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>24</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The superintendent may issue parking permits and furnish labels for the purposes of these Regulations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A parking permit issued pursuant to subsection (1) is valid for the period stated thereon or until revoked by the superintendent and a label furnished with the permit is valid for the same period.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, s. 25(F); SOR/91-375, s. 3(E).</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>25</Label><Text>Where an area in a park is designated by a sign as an area where parking is reserved for a category of persons, no person shall park in the area unless he is included in that category.</Text></Section><Section><Label>26</Label><Text>No person shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>abandon a motor vehicle in a park; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>park a motor vehicle in an area that is not designated by a sign pursuant to subsection 23(1) and that is not an area in which parking is prohibited, for a greater period of time than 48 hours, unless he</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>has obtained the prior permission of the superintendent to park in such area for a greater period than 48 hours,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>is the owner, lessee or licensee of the property, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>is authorized by the owner, lessee or licensee of the property to park the motor vehicle for a greater period than 48 hours.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, s. 25(F); SOR/91-375, s. 3(E).</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>27</Label><Text>No person shall park a motor vehicle within 6 m of any highway intersection or within 3 m of a water hydrant or fire plug within a park.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, s. 13.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>28</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>No person shall park a motor vehicle on any highway so as to</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>obstruct a driveway leading to a private residence or business premises; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>interfere with a motor vehicle that is being loaded or unloaded.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>No person shall park a motor vehicle on a sidewalk unless he is permitted to do so by the superintendent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>No person shall, without permission from the superintendent, stop or park a motor vehicle on a highway otherwise than in the direction of the vehicular traffic on the side of the highway on which he proposes to stop or park, and parallel with, and no further distant than 1 foot from, the curb or edge of the highway.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Where the superintendent has permitted the stopping or parking of a motor vehicle on a highway in a manner other than the manner described in subsection (3), every person stopping or parking a motor vehicle on that highway, shall comply with any order of the superintendent regarding the manner of stopping or parking the motor vehicle.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>Where the superintendent has designated parking spaces on a highway, no person shall park a motor vehicle on that highway except</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in one of those parking spaces; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>if the motor vehicle exceeds the length of one parking space, in not more than two of those parking spaces.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(6)</Label><Text>No person shall park a motor vehicle on a sloping highway without having set the vehicle’s parking brakes and, by turning the wheels of the motor vehicle or by other suitable means, ensure that in case of brake failure the motor vehicle will not run down the slope.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, s. 25(F); SOR/91-375, s. 3(E).</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>29</Label><Text>No person shall stop or park a motor vehicle in any public lane except while engaged in loading or unloading chattels to or from the motor vehicle.</Text></Section><Section><Label>30</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>No person shall park a trailer within a park in a location other than a location designated by a sign erected by the superintendent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>No person shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>abandon a trailer in a park; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>park a trailer in a location designated by a sign erected by the superintendent for a greater period than is specified on the sign.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, s. 14.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>31</Label><Text>A park warden, police constable or peace officer may, at the expense of the owner of a motor vehicle or trailer that is parked or left in contravention of these Regulations, cause the motor vehicle or trailer to be moved or taken to and stored in a suitable place.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, s. 14.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Speed</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>32</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>No person shall drive a motor vehicle on a highway at a rate of speed in excess of the speed limit prescribed by a traffic sign for the highway.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2009-322, s. 10]</Repealed></Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/96-169, s. 5; SOR/2009-322, s. 10.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Careless Driving Prohibited</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>33</Label><Text>No person shall drive or ride any motor vehicle, bicycle, horse or other animal upon any highway without due care and attention or without reasonable consideration for other persons using the highway.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Bicycles</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>34</Label><Text>Every person riding a bicycle on a highway shall ride as close as possible to the right-hand edge or curb of the highway and, when riding with other persons, shall not ride more than two abreast.</Text></Section><Section><Label>35</Label><Text>No person shall ride a bicycle on a sidewalk in a park.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, s. 15.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>36</Label><Text>No person shall ride a bicycle in a park unless the bicycle is equipped in accordance with the laws of the province in which the park is situated.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, s. 15.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Sidewalks and Boulevards</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>37</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Where an access driveway to a lot within a townsite or subdivision within a park is not provided or conveniently located, and a person desires to ride or drive a horse or motor vehicle from the highway to the lot, he shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>construct across the drain, gutter or water course skirting the place where he intends to enter the lot a good and sufficient bridge of planks or other material satisfactory to the superintendent; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>construct over the sidewalk or boulevard to be crossed and of the full width thereof a temporary crossing of planks or other material satisfactory to the superintendent sufficient to prevent injury to the sidewalk or boulevard.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The temporary crossing described in subsection (1) shall be removed forthwith after it has served its purpose.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, s. 25(F); SOR/91-375, s. 3(E).</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>38</Label><Text>Except as authorized by these Regulations, no person shall ride, drive, lead or back any horse or motor vehicle across or along any sidewalk or boulevard within a park.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Taxi or Cab Stands</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>39</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>No chauffeur shall park a motor vehicle for hire at any place within a park other than a place designated by the superintendent as a taxi or cab stand.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A person who operates a motor vehicle for hire shall not solicit passengers on any highway or sidewalk other than a highway or sidewalk at or adjacent to a taxi or cab stand or his place of business.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, s. 25(F); SOR/91-375, s. 3(E).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Snow Tires and Chains</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>40</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>No person shall drive a motor vehicle</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>on any highway in Mount Revelstoke National Park, Glacier National Park or Yoho National Park,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>on the Icefield Parkway in Banff National Park and Jasper National Park,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>on the Banff-Windermere Highway in Banff National Park and Kootenay National Park, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>on any other highway in Banff National Park, Jasper National Park or Kootenay National Park that has been designated by the superintendent by means of a notice prominently posted or displayed on any such highway</Text></Paragraph><ContinuedSectionSubsection><Text>during the period between November 1 to March 31 or any other period during which the highway is covered with snow or ice unless adequate snow tires or tire chains have been installed on the motor vehicle.</Text></ContinuedSectionSubsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, ss. 16, 25(F); SOR/91-375, s. 3(E).</HistoricalNote></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Over-snow Vehicles and All-terrain Vehicles</TitleText><HistoricalNote>[SOR/90-79, s. 17]</HistoricalNote></Heading><Section><Label>41</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>No person shall operate an over-snow vehicle in a park unless</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>he has the written permission of the superintendent;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the over-snow vehicle is licensed, registered and equipped as required by the laws of the province in which the park is situated;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>he operates it in accordance with such conditions and in such areas as the superintendent may specify; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>that person and any passenger on the over-snow vehicle are wearing the equipment required to operate the over-snow vehicle by the laws of the province in which the park is situated.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>No person shall operate an all-terrain vehicle in a park except for purposes of administration of the park and with the permission of the superintendent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/90-79, s. 18]</Repealed></Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, ss. 18, 25(F); SOR/91-375, s. 3(E).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Miscellaneous</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>42</Label><Text>No person shall leave any horse unattended on a highway.</Text></Section><Section><Label>43</Label><Text>No person shall, within a park, coast or slide upon any toboggan or sled along or across a highway or public place that has not been set aside by the superintendent for coasting or sliding.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, s. 25(F); SOR/91-375, s. 3(E).</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>44</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (2), no person shall, without the permission of the superintendent, haul any dead animal, offal, nightsoil or other offensive matter or thing on a highway in a park during the hours of daylight.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The owner of any animal that dies or has been killed on any highway shall forthwith cause the carcass to be removed therefrom and suitably disposed of.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, s. 25(F); SOR/91-375, s. 3(E).</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>45</Label><Text>When the load of a passenger vehicle, truck or trailer consists of loose material or of material that is likely to slip, swing out, sway, shift, spill, leak, blow off, fall off or otherwise escape in any direction while being conveyed, the load shall be placed inside a container or shall be secured and bound so as to prevent such escape.</Text></Section><Section><Label>46</Label><Text>No person shall place on or over any highway or sidewalk any material or commodity of any description that might cause personal or property damage or in any way interfere with traffic on the highway or sidewalk.</Text></Section><Section><Label>47</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>No person shall draw or tow by motor vehicle on a highway a sled, toboggan, ski, bicycle or any other conveyance on which a person is riding.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>No person shall skate, roller skate, roller blade, roller ski or ride a skateboard on any highway or sidewalk in a town, visitor centre or resort subdivision.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Every person who roller blades or roller skis on a highway outside a town, visitor centre or resort subdivision shall travel as close as possible to the left-hand edge or curb of the highway and, when roller blading or roller skiing with other persons, shall travel in single file.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, s. 19.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>48</Label><Text>In every prosecution of an owner of a motor vehicle in respect of the use or operation of the vehicle in violation of any provision of these Regulations, the onus of proving that the motor vehicle was not in his possession or control at the time of the violation is on the accused.</Text></Section><Section><Label>49</Label><Text>In any violation of these Regulations where the owner of a motor vehicle is identified through provincial motor vehicle registration records, the court may accept as evidence of ownership of the motor vehicle a written statement of ownership of that motor vehicle that is duly completed in accordance with the laws of the province in which the park is situated.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-79, s. 20.</HistoricalNote></Section></Body><Schedule bilingual="no" spanlanguages="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULES I AND II</Label></ScheduleFormHeading><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/96-169, s. 6]</Repealed></Schedule></Regulation>