<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 1270</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>28</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">PILOTAGE ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Pacific Pilotage Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting the Operation, Maintenance and Administration of Pilotage Services Including Compulsory Pilotage and the Qualifications for Holders of Licences and Pilotage Certificates Within the Pacific Pilotage Authority Region</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Pacific Pilotage Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Pilotage Act</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>apprentice pilot</DefinedTermEn> means a person who is training to become a licensed pilot; (<DefinedTermFr>apprenti pilote</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>arrangement of ships</DefinedTermEn> means a number of ships travelling together that are joined by lines or other means; (<DefinedTermFr>ensemble de navires</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Authority</DefinedTermEn> means the Pacific Pilotage Authority; (<DefinedTermFr>Administration</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>certificate of competency</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2009-329, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>coastal trade</DefinedTermEn> means the regular employment and operation of ships in the waters of the region, the waters of Puget Sound, the Strait of Juan de Fuca and the coastal waters of the State of Alaska not west of Cook Inlet; (<DefinedTermFr>cabotage</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>committee of examiners</DefinedTermEn> means a committee of examiners appointed under section 21 to conduct examinations for any class of licence or a pilotage certificate or for the apprenticeship system; (<DefinedTermFr>commission d’examen</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>compulsory pilotage area</DefinedTermEn> means an area of water in which ships are subject to compulsory pilotage; (<DefinedTermFr>zone de pilotage obligatoire</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>dangerous goods</DefinedTermEn> has the meaning assigned by section 2 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Transportation of Dangerous Goods Act, 1992</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>marchandises dangereuses</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>day of service</DefinedTermEn> means a period of watchkeeping duty performed over a period of 12 hours that are not necessarily consecutive; (<DefinedTermFr>jour de service</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>deck watch officer</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2003-224, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>familiarization trip</DefinedTermEn> means a voyage in a compulsory pilotage area on board a ship during which an applicant for a licence or pilotage certificate observes the licensed pilot assigned to the ship; (<DefinedTermFr>voyage d’entraînement</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>ferry</DefinedTermEn> means a ship or an arrangement of ships that carries passengers or goods according to a fixed schedule between terminals; (<DefinedTermFr>traversier</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>gross tons</DefinedTermEn> means gross tonnage as defined in section 2 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Shipping Act, 2001</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>tonneaux de jauge brute</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>marine occurrence</DefinedTermEn> has the meaning assigned by section 2 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canadian Transportation Accident Investigation and Safety Board Act</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>accident maritime</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>movage</DefinedTermEn> means the moving of a ship wholly within a harbour or port from one anchored or moored position to another or back to the same position, but does not include the warping of a ship from one berth to another solely by means of mooring lines unless a pilot is employed, and includes anchoring of a ship while en route between one harbour, port or pilot boarding station and another due to stress of weather, tidal conditions, safety of the ship or crew, waiting berth availability or waiting due to minor engine or equipment repairs performed by ship’s personnel that are considered reasonable engine or equipment maintenance; (<DefinedTermFr>déplacement</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>person in charge of the deck watch</DefinedTermEn> means a person who has immediate charge of the navigation, manoeuvring, operation or safety of a ship, but does not include a pilot; (<DefinedTermFr>personne responsable du quart à la passerelle</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>pilot boarding station</DefinedTermEn> means a place used for the purpose of embarking or disembarking pilots; (<DefinedTermFr>station d’embarquement de pilotes</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>pleasure craft</DefinedTermEn> has the meaning assigned by section 2 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Shipping Act, 2001</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>embarcation de plaisance</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>region</DefinedTermEn> means all Canadian waters in and around the Province of British Columbia; (<DefinedTermFr>région</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>regularly employed</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2003-224, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Second Narrows Movement Restriction Area</DefinedTermEn> means that part of Area 2 that is enclosed within a line drawn 000° from the fixed light on the northeastern end of Terminal Dock to the North Vancouver shoreline at Neptune Terminals and a line drawn 000° from Berry Point Light (approximately 2.4 km east of the CN bridge on the South Shore of the Port of Vancouver) to the North Shore on the opposite side of the channel; (<DefinedTermFr>périmètre de déplacement restreint de Second Narrows</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>senior watch keeping deck officer</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2003-224, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>tug</DefinedTermEn> means a ship used for towing or pushing purposes; (<DefinedTermFr>remorqueur</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>voyage</DefinedTermEn> includes a passage or trip of a ship and any movement of a ship from one place to another but does not include a movage. (<DefinedTermFr>voyage</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>warping</DefinedTermEn> means the moving of a ship from one berth to another solely by means of mooring lines; (<DefinedTermFr>halage</DefinedTermFr>) </Text></Definition><HistoricalNote>SOR/2003-224, s. 1; SOR/2009-329, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Establishment of Compulsory Pilotage Areas</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>The following compulsory pilotage areas are hereby established in the region:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>Area 1, being all waters of the Fraser River and other rivers flowing into it including all of the North Arm of the Fraser River and the waters extending to seawards from Point Grey in position Latitude 49°15′57″ N., Longitude 123°15′48″ W., THENCE, to position Latitude 49°15′57″ N., Longitude 123°26′00″ W., THENCE, to position Latitude 49°02′15″ N., Longitude 123°26′00″ W., THENCE, to position Latitude 49°02′15″ N., Longitude 123°05′45″ W., and including all waters of Boundary Bay, North of Latitude 49°00′07″ N.;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>Area 2, being</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>all waters enclosed within a line commencing from a position in Latitude 49°00′07″ N., Longitude 123°05′24″ W. and following the International Boundary between the Province of British Columbia and the State of Washington to a position in Latitude 48°15′48″ N., Longitude 123°21′12″ W., and THENCE, to a position Latitude 48°22′27″ N., Longitude 123°23′12″ W., and THENCE, to a position Latitude 48°22′27″ N., Longitude 123°25′48″ W., and THENCE, to a position Latitude 48°16′03″ N., Longitude 123°29′36″ W., and THENCE, to a position Latitude 48°15′54″ N., Longitude 123°31′48″ W., and THENCE, to Christopher Point in position Latitude 48°18′36″ N., Longitude 123°33′45″ W., and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>all waters enclosed within a line extending from Cape Caution Light in position Latitude 51°09′50″ N., Longitude 127°47′06″ W., to a position in Latitude 50°58′00″ N., Longitude 127°44′33″ W., and THENCE, to Cape James on Hope Island in position Latitude 50°56′00″ N., Longitude 127°50′12″ W., and THENCE, from Nahwitti Point Light on Hope Island in position Latitude 50°54′18″ N., Longitude 127°59′02″ W., to Cape Sutil on Vancouver Island in position Latitude 50°52′30″ N., Longitude 128°02′54″ W., except those waters eastward of a line from Point Grey in position Latitude 49°15′57″ N., Longitude 123°15′48″ W., THENCE, to position Latitude 49°15′57″ N., Longitude 123°16′39″ W., THENCE, to position Latitude 49°05′15″ N., Longitude 123°18′54″ W., THENCE, to position Latitude 49°02′15″ N., Longitude 123°15′18″ W., THENCE, to position Latitude 49°02′15″ N., Longitude 123°05′45″ W.;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>Area 3, being all waters enclosed within a line extending from Christopher Point in position Latitude 48°18′36″ N., Longitude 123°33′45″ W., to a position Latitude 48°15′54″ N., Longitude 123°31′48″ W., and THENCE, to a position Latitude 48°20′48″ N., Longitude 123°56′00″ W., and THENCE, to a position Latitude 48°30′12″ N., Longitude 124°28′30″ W., and THENCE, to a position Latitude 48°33′45″ N., Longitude 124°43′48″ W., and THENCE, to a position Latitude 48°41′33″ N., Longitude 125°07′00″ W., and THENCE, to a position Latitude 48°50′36″ N., Longitude 125°30′00″ W., and THENCE, to a position Latitude 49°21′24″ N., Longitude 126°34′24″ W., and THENCE, to a position Latitude 50°05′06″ N., Longitude 127°58′18″ W., and THENCE, to a position Latitude 50°38′39″ N., Longitude 128°24′36″ W., and THENCE, to a position Latitude 50°46′51″ N., Longitude 128°28′42″ W., and THENCE, to a position Latitude 50°48′36″ N., Longitude 128°27′36″ W., and THENCE, to a position Latitude 50°58′27″ N., Longitude 127°56′06″ W., and THENCE, to a position Latitude 50°58′00″ N., Longitude 127°44′33″ W., and THENCE, to Cape James on Hope Island in position Latitude 50°56′00″ N., Longitude 127°50′12″ W., and THENCE, from Nahwitti Point Light on Hope Island in position Latitude 50°54′18″ N., Longitude 127°59′02″ W., to Cape Sutil on Vancouver Island in position Latitude 50°52′30″ N., Longitude 128°02′54″ W.;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>Area 4, being all waters enclosed within a line extending from Cape Caution Light in position Latitude 51°09′50″ N., Longitude 127°47′06″ W., and THENCE, to a position Latitude 50°58′00″ N., Longitude 127°44′33″ W., THENCE, to a position Latitude 51°15′00″ N., Longitude 128°16′00″ W., THENCE, to a position Latitude 52°15′12″ N., Longitude 128°46′30″ W., THENCE, to a position Latitude 52°23′00″ N., Longitude 129°24′45″ W., THENCE, to a position Latitude 53°23′15″ N., Longitude 130°38′12″ W., THENCE, to a position Latitude 53°29′30″ N., Longitude 130°41′30″ W., THENCE, to a position Latitude 54°02′06″ N., Longitude 130°57′15″ W., THENCE, to a position Latitude 54°15′24″ N., Longitude 131°02′30″ W., THENCE, to a position Latitude 54°18′21″ N., Longitude 130°57′51″ W., THENCE, to a position Latitude 54°35′15″ N., Longitude 131°16′45″ W., THENCE, to a position Latitude 54°41′57″ N., Longitude 131°07′21″ W., THENCE, a line following the International Boundary between the Province of British Columbia and the State of Alaska, terminating in a position Latitude 55°54′42″ N., Longitude 130°00′48″ W.; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>Area 5, being all waters enclosed within a line extending from a position Latitude 54°17′24″ N., Longitude 131°28′00″ W., and THENCE, to a position Latitude 53°46′36″ N., Longitude 131°18′30″ W., THENCE, to a position Latitude 52°52′12″ N., Longitude 131°25′18″ W., THENCE, to a position Latitude 52°13′18″ N., Longitude 130°54′24″ W., THENCE, to a position Latitude 52°05′42″ N., Longitude 130°52′42″ W., THENCE, to a position Latitude 51°46′36″ N., Longitude 130°52′12″ W., THENCE, to a position Latitude 52°11′50″ N., Longitude 131°28′12″ W., THENCE, to a position Latitude 52°32′12″ N., Longitude 131°53′24″ W., THENCE, to a position Latitude 52°47′00″ N., Longitude 132°17′00″ W., THENCE, to a position Latitude 52°55′48″ N., Longitude 132°28′24″ W., THENCE, to a position Latitude 53°25′12″ N., Longitude 132°59′00″ W., THENCE, to a position Latitude 53°31′24″ N., Longitude 133°04′36″ W., THENCE, to a position Latitude 53°45′18″ N., Longitude 133°13′24″ W., THENCE, to a position Latitude 53°56′21″ N., Longitude 133°15′24″ W., THENCE, to a position Latitude 54°10′12″ N., Longitude 133°10′54″ W., THENCE, to a position Latitude 54°16′36″ N., Longitude 133°07′21″ W., THENCE, to a position Latitude 54°18′24″ N., Longitude 133°00′00″ W., THENCE, to a position Latitude 54°09′06″ N., Longitude 132°18′48″ W., THENCE, to a position Latitude 54°17′24″ N., Longitude 131°28′00″ W.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2014-240, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Experience at Sea Qualifications</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>An applicant for a licence or pilotage certificate shall hold a certificate of competency not lower than Master 500 Gross Tonnage, Near Coastal and</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>have served not less than 700 days of service in the region as master of a ship of 25 gross tons or more in the region, and have completed 10 familiarization trips as an observer in the Familiarization Program prior to the date of application;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>have served not less than 365 days of service in the region as master of a ship of 25 gross tons or more, and have completed not less than 547 additional days in the region as a deck officer on a ship of 25 gross tons or more while holding a Watchkeeping Mate certificate of competency, and have completed 15 familiarization trips as an observer in the Familiarization Program prior to the date of application;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>have served not less than 1000 days of service in the region as a deck officer on a ship of 25 gross tons or more while holding a Watchkeeping Mate certificate of competency, and have completed not less than 20 familiarization trips as an observer in the Familiarization Program prior to the date of application; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>have served not less than 635 days of service in the region as master or as a deck officer while holding a Watchkeeping Mate certificate of competency and</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>have served not less than 365 days of service outside the region as master or as a deck officer while holding a Watchkeeping Mate certificate of competency on a ship of 100 gross tons or more, and have completed 30 familiarization trips as an observer in the Familiarization Program prior to the date of application, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>have served not less than 365 days of service in the region while holding a Fishing Master, Third Class certificate of competency on a ship of 25 gross tons or more, and have completed 30 familiarization trips as an observer in the Familiarization Program prior to the date of application.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A minimum of 100 of the days of service required by subsection (1) must have been served within the 24 months before the date of application.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>An applicant for a licence or pilotage certificate for Area 1 must have served a minimum of 250 of the days of service required by subsection (1) in Area 1.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>An applicant for a licence for Areas 2 to 5 must have served the days of service required by subsection (1) in at least two of those Areas.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>An applicant for a pilotage certificate for Area 2, 3, 4 or 5 must have served at least 250 of the days of service required by subsection (1) in the Area being applied for.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/78-839, s. 1; SOR/83-401, s. 1; SOR/84-415, s. 1; SOR/89-415, s. 1; SOR/2003-224, s. 2; SOR/2009-329, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Familiarization Program</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4.1</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A person may apply to the Authority for entry into the Familiarization Program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The Authority shall approve familiarization trips if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in the case of 10 familiarization trips or less, the applicant has served at least 50% of the days of service required by any of paragraphs (4)(1)(a) to (d); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the case of more than 10 familiarization trips, the applicant has served at least 75% of the days of service required by any of paragraphs 4(1)(b) to (d).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2009-329, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Certificates</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>In addition to the certificates required by subsection 10(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">General Pilotage Regulations</XRefExternal>, an applicant for or a holder of a licence or a pilotage certificate shall hold a training certificate indicating that they have successfully completed a course approved in accordance with section 114 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Marine Personnel Regulations</XRefExternal></Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in simulated electronic navigation, level 2; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in automatic radar plotting aids.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2003-224, s. 2; SOR/2009-329, s. 3; SOR/2014-240, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Apprenticeship</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>The holder of a licence shall have successfully completed the apprenticeship system approved by the Authority.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Requirements</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>7</Label><Text>The holder of a licence or pilotage certificate shall have provided the Authority with evidence that the holder maintained a record of safe ship handling and navigation before applying for their licence or pilotage certificate.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2003-224, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>8</Label><Text>The holder of a licence or pilotage certificate shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>have passed the required examinations of their qualifications conducted by the committee of examiners;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>speak, write and understand English to the extent necessary to carry out their pilotage duties; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>have passed a medical examination that tests the holder’s physical and mental fitness for pilotage duties.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2003-224, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Ships Subject to Compulsory Pilotage</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>9</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Every ship over 350 gross tons that is not a pleasure craft and every pleasure craft over 500 gross tons is subject to compulsory pilotage.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>For the purposes of subsection (1), if a ship is part of an arrangement of ships, then the combined tonnage of all the ships in the arrangement of ships is taken into consideration in determining whether the ship is subject to compulsory pilotage.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Subsection (1) does not apply in respect of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a government vessel as defined in section 2 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Shipping Act, 2001</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a ferry; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a United States government ship under 10 000 gross tons.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/83-23, s. 1; SOR/85-256, s. 1(F); SOR/2003-224, s. 3; SOR/2009-329, s. 4.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Waiver of Compulsory Pilotage</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>10</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The Authority may waive compulsory pilotage in respect of a ship if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the ship is in distress;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a person on board the ship requires medical evacuation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the ship is engaged in rescue or salvage operations;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the ship is seeking refuge;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>a licensed pilot is not available to perform the functions of a pilot and the following conditions have been met:</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the owner, master or agent of the ship has complied with sections 12 and 13, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>all persons in charge of the deck watch are familiar with the route and the marine traffic control system in the compulsory pilotage area that the ship is entering; or</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>the ship is warping and is not utilizing its engines or a tug except as a line boat for the handling of the ship’s lines.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>If a pilot boarding station is within a compulsory pilotage area, the Authority may waive compulsory pilotage in order to allow a ship to</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>enter the compulsory pilotage area to embark a licensed pilot at the pilot boarding station; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>leave the compulsory pilotage area after a licensed pilot has been disembarked at the pilot boarding station.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Subject to subsections (4) to (6), the Authority may waive compulsory pilotage in respect of a ship under 10 000 gross tons if all persons in charge of the deck watch</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>hold certificates of competency of the proper class and category of voyage for the ship that are required by Part 2 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Marine Personnel Regulations</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>have served either 150 days of service in the preceding 18 months or 365 days of service in the preceding 60 months, of which 60 days must have been served in the preceding 24 months, at sea as a person in charge of the deck watch on one or more ships on voyages in the region or engaged in the coastal trade; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>have served as persons in charge of the deck watch in the compulsory pilotage area for which the waiver is sought on one or more occasions during the preceding 24 months.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The Authority may waive compulsory pilotage in respect of a ship under 10 000 gross tons travelling in the portion of Area 1 below the New Westminster railway bridge if all persons in charge of the deck watch meet the conditions set out in subsection (3) and have completed five return voyages through that portion of Area 1 within the 24 months before the application</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>with a licensed pilot; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>with a person in charge of the deck watch who has completed five return voyages through that portion of Area 1 with a licensed pilot, if the Authority is given prior notice of each voyage.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>The Authority may waive compulsory pilotage in respect of a ship under 10 000 gross tons travelling in the portion of Area 1 above the New Westminster railway bridge if all persons in charge of the deck watch meet the conditions set out in subsection (3) and have completed 10 return voyages through that portion of Area 1 within the 24 months before the application</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>with a licensed pilot; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>with a person in charge of the deck watch who has completed 10 return voyages through that portion of Area 1 with a licensed pilot, if the Authority is given prior notice of each voyage.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(6)</Label><Text>The Authority may waive compulsory pilotage in respect of a ship under 10 000 gross tons carrying dangerous goods and travelling in the Second Narrows Movement Restriction Area if all persons in charge of the deck watch meet the conditions set out in subsection (3) and have completed six return voyages through that Area, one of which was completed within the 24 months before the application</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>with a licensed pilot; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>with a person in charge of the deck watch who has completed six return voyages through that Area with a licensed pilot, if the Authority is given prior notice of each voyage.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(7)</Label><Text>For the purposes of subsections (3) to (6), if a ship is part of an arrangement of ships, then the combined tonnage of all the ships in the arrangement of ships is taken into consideration in determining whether the ship qualifies for a waiver of compulsory pilotage.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(8)</Label><Text>Despite subsections (3) to (6), a ship is subject to compulsory pilotage if there is a risk to navigational safety because of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>ship safety orders resulting from an environmental risk;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>exceptional circumstances on board the ship; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>extreme conditions related to weather, tides or currents or freshet conditions.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(9)</Label><Text>An application for a waiver of compulsory pilotage other than an application made under a circumstance described in subsection (1) or (2) shall be made in writing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(10)</Label><Text>At the request of the Authority, the persons in charge of the deck watch referred to in subsections (1) to (6) shall produce evidence that the conditions set out in this section continue to be met.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/83-23, s. 1; SOR/83-255, s. 1; SOR/2003-224, s. 3; SOR/2009-329, s. 5.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Pilot Boarding Stations</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>11</Label><Text>There shall be a pilot boarding station</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>at Fairway Buoy, off Brotchie Ledge near Victoria;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>off Cape Beale, at the entrance to Trevor Channel in Barkley Sound;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>off Triple Island, near Prince Rupert;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>off Pine Island, near Port Hardy;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>off Sand Heads, at the mouth of the Fraser River, for Area 1 pilot transfers; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>at any point or place in the region that the Authority considers necessary to ensure a safe and efficient pilotage service.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2003-224, s. 3; SOR/2009-329, s. 6.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Notice to Obtain Pilots</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>12</Label><Text>The master, owner or agent of a ship that is subject to compulsory pilotage and requires the services of a licensed pilot shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>with respect to the pilot boarding station referred to in paragraph 11(a),</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>provide notice to the Authority of the estimated time of the ship’s arrival, Coordinated Universal Time, at least 12 hours before arrival, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>confirm or correct the estimated time of the ship’s arrival four hours prior to arrival; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>with respect to any of the pilot boarding stations referred to in paragraphs 11(b) to (f),</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>provide notice to the Authority of the estimated time of the ship’s arrival, Coordinated Universal Time, at least 48 hours before arrival, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>confirm or correct the estimated time of the ship’s arrival at least 12 hours prior to arrival.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2003-224, s. 3; SOR/2009-329, s. 7(F).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Required Information in Notice</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>13</Label><Text>The notice referred to in section 12 shall include</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the pilotage service to be performed;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the name, nationality, length, breadth, deepest draft and gross tons of the ship; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>any other information about the ship that affects its speed, manoeuvrability or the safety of navigation.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2003-224, s. 3; SOR/2009-329, s. 8.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>14</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2014-240, s. 3]</Repealed></Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Notification of Pilotage Certificate Holders or Waivers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>15</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>If a person in charge of the deck watch of a ship is a holder of a pilotage certificate, the master, owner or agent of that ship shall, 48 hours before entering a compulsory pilotage area, notify the Authority of the intended voyage of the ship and the name of the holder and the number of their certificate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>If a waiver of compulsory pilotage has been granted in respect of a ship, the master, owner or agent of that ship shall, 48 hours before entering a compulsory pilotage area, notify the Authority of the intended voyage of the ship and the names of all persons in charge of the deck watch.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2003-224, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Minimum Number of Licensed Pilots or Holders of Pilotage Certificates on Board</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>16</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (2), the minimum number of licenced pilots or holders of pilotage certificates that shall be on board a ship at any time is one, except that two pilots shall be on board</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for any voyage during which the ship would require the services of a pilot on bridge watch for a period exceeding eight consecutive hours;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for any voyage during which the ship would require the services of a pilot on bridge watch for a distance exceeding 105 consecutive nautical miles;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>where the ship cannot be safely navigated by only one pilot on bridge watch; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>where the ship has requested two pilots.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A licensed pilot or holder of a pilotage certificate who has conduct of a towed ship may be on board the tug by which it is towed.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/83-23, s. 2; SOR/85-256, s. 2; SOR/90-292, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Licences</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>17</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The classes of licences that may be issued by the Authority are Class I and Class II licences.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A licence issued by the Authority shall have an endorsement on it that states what class of licence it is as well as the compulsory pilotage areas in which the holder may pilot.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The holder of a Class II licence is entitled to receive a Class I licence after having served satisfactorily as the holder of a Class II licence for a period of one year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>An apprentice pilot who meets the qualifications for a licence, shall be issued a Class II licence.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2009-329, s. 9.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Pilotage Certificates</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>18</Label><Text>A pilotage certificate issued by the Authority shall have an endorsement thereon stating</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the size and type of ship that the holder of the certificate may pilot, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the compulsory pilotage areas in which or the specific routes within a compulsory pilotage area on which the holder may pilot,</Text></Paragraph><ContinuedSectionSubsection><Text>and may have an endorsement thereon setting out any requirements or restrictions applicable to the holder.</Text></ContinuedSectionSubsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Applications for Licences and Pilotage Certificates</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>19</Label><Text>An applicant for a licence or pilotage certificate shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>provide the Authority with such evidence, information and references as will satisfy the Authority that he meets all the qualifications prescribed by the Act, the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">General Pilotage Regulations</XRefExternal> and these Regulations of an applicant for and the holder of the licence or pilotage certificate for which he is applying; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>pay a fee of $50 to the Authority for the issue of the licence or pilotage certificate.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Further Training</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>20</Label><Text>The holder of a licence or pilotage certificate shall be required to take further training to enable him to meet the qualifications of holders of licences and pilotage certificates prescribed by these Regulations since his licence or certificate was issued when he is unable to meet those qualifications.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Examinations</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>21</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>To determine whether an applicant for or the holder of a licence or pilotage certificate or an applicant who wishes to become an apprentice pilot meets the qualifications prescribed for applicants and holders by the Act, the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">General Pilotage Regulations</XRefExternal> and these Regulations, the Authority may refer the qualifications of the applicant or holder to a committee of examiners.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>There shall be two committees of examiners consisting of five members each.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>One of the committees of examiners shall examine the qualifications of applicants and holders with respect to Area 1 compulsory pilotage area and the other committee shall examine the qualifications of applicants and holders with respect to Areas 2, 3, 4 and 5 compulsory pilotage areas.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Each committee of examiners shall consist of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>two persons appointed by the Authority, one of whom shall be chairman of the committee;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a licensed pilot appointed by the representative body of licensed pilots;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a licensed pilot appointed by the Authority; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a master mariner appointed by the Authority.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>A committee of examiners shall be appointed for a term of one year commencing July 1st in each year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(6)</Label><Text>Any retiring member of a committee of examiners shall be eligible for re-appointment to that committee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(7)</Label><Text>A quorum of a committee of examiners shall be four members.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>22</Label><Text>A committee of examiners shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>prepare a list of applicants who are eligible to become apprentice pilots or holders of licences or pilotage certificates and submit the list to the Authority for approval;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>conduct examinations under the direction of the Authority;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>submit to the Authority statements of the results of all examinations conducted by it;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>prepare the curriculum of training for the apprenticeship system and any pilotage certificate training program that is established by the Authority; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>hold regular meetings as directed by the Authority to review the progress of persons in the apprenticeship system and any pilotage certificate training program that is established by the Authority.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>23</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Examinations held by a committee of examiners shall be in such form as the Authority may determine and shall consist of, but not be limited to, questions on the following subjects:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>local knowledge of every area to which the application, licence or pilotage certificate relates including</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>tides and currents,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>dredged channel widths and depths,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>depth of water,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>important and essential cable areas and prohibited anchorage areas,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(v)</Label><Text>anchorage areas and depths,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(vi)</Label><Text>aides to navigation, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(vii)</Label><Text>bridge signals and clearances;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>knowledge of</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Collision Regulations</XRefExternal>,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>regulations under the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Shipping Act</XRefExternal> respecting harbours and ports,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Pilotage Act</XRefExternal> and regulations thereunder, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Quarantine Regulations</XRefExternal>;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>seamanship and ship handling;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>docking problems and the use of tug boats and anchors;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>general chart work, including the correction of courses and compass errors;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>communications;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>International Code of Signals, including the use of one and two flag signals;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>duties of a pilot;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>use of navigational and bridge instruments;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(j)</Label><Text>practical knowledge of the interpretation and operation of radar; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(k)</Label><Text>such other subjects as the committee of examiners may consider necessary.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A candidate has a maximum of six attempts at the examination referred to in subsection (1).</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2009-329, s. 10.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Place of and Fees for Examinations</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>24</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Examinations conducted by the committee of examiners shall be held at such place as the Authority may from time to time prescribe in a notice given by the Authority to the persons who will take the examinations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The fees payable for the examination are the following:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>$150 for the written portion; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>$100 for the oral portion.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2003-224, s. 4; SOR/2009-329, s. 11.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Eligibility for Apprenticeship System</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>25</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The name of an applicant who wishes to become an apprentice pilot and meets the qualifications for an applicant for or a holder of a licence set out in the Act, the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">General Pilotage Regulations</XRefExternal> and these Regulations shall be placed by a committee of examiners on an eligibility list prepared by them under paragraph 22(a).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(1.1)</Label><Text>The name of an applicant who meets the qualifications referred to in subsection (1) shall be placed on the eligibility list after the last name on the list.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(1.2)</Label><Text>If several applicants meet the qualifications referred to in subsection (1) at the same time, their names shall be placed on the eligibility list after the last name on the list in an order that ranks them, from highest to lowest, in accordance with their results in the examinations referred to in section 23.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The name of an applicant referred to in subsection (1) shall remain on the eligibility list for a period of two years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Upon the expiration of the two-year period referred to in subsection (2), the name of the applicant shall be removed from the eligibility list unless he establishes to the satisfaction of the committee of examiners that he</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>has, during the two-year period, maintained sea service in each area in respect of which he intends to become an apprentice pilot; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>meets the qualifications referred to in subsection (1).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2003-224, s. 5.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Appointment of Apprentice Pilots</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>26</Label><Text>If the Authority requires an apprentice pilot to meet the needs of the pilotage service, the Authority may appoint as an apprentice pilot a person whose name is at the top of the eligibility list referred to in section 25.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2003-224, s. 6.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Duration of Apprenticeship</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>27</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>An apprentice pilot shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>to qualify for a licence for Area 1, serve as an apprentice for a period of not less than three months in that Area and complete during that period not less than 50 assignments in the Area with a licensed pilot; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>to qualify for a licence for Areas 2 to 5,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>serve as an apprentice for a period of not less than six months and not more than 24 months in those Areas, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>during the period served as required by subparagraph (i), complete not less than 90 assignments with a licensed pilot.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A person shall cease to be an apprentice pilot when he</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>is granted a licence;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>withdraws from the apprenticeship system; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>is discharged from the apprenticeship system by the Authority.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/78-839, s. 2; SOR/2009-329, s. 12.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Apprenticeship System Training</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>28</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>An apprentice pilot shall,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>when directed to do so by the Authority, take examinations both written and oral before the committee of examiners;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>make such voyages at the direction of the Authority as will give him the most extensive experience in the waters and ports of the compulsory pilotage area in respect of which he wishes to obtain a licence; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>keep a log of all voyages made by him pursuant to paragraph (b) in a form approved by the Authority.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>An apprentice pilot shall be under the direction and command of the licensed pilot of the ship to which he is assigned.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The Authority may assign one apprentice pilot to a ship and may assign a second apprentice pilot to a ship after consultation with the master, owner or agent thereof.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Marine Occurrence Report</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>29</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>If a ship that is subject to compulsory pilotage or a ship in respect of which a waiver of compulsory pilotage has been granted is involved in a marine occurrence in a compulsory pilotage area, the person who has the conduct of the ship at the time of the marine occurrence shall submit a full report on the marine occurrence to the Authority on a form provided by the Authority for that use.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>If the person who has the conduct of the ship at the time of the marine occurrence is not the master, the master shall also submit a full report on the marine occurrence to the Authority on a form provided by the Authority for that use.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>A person who is required to submit a full report on the marine occurrence shall do so</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>within 72 hours after the marine occurrence; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>within an additional period of time granted to the person by the Authority under subsection (4).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The Authority shall grant an additional period of time if the Authority is notified within 72 hours after the marine occurrence that the person is unable to submit the report within those 72 hours because the person was injured in the marine occurrence or because the person is in a remote location that does not have a scheduled transportation service or a communication system that can be used to submit the report.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2003-224, s. 7; SOR/2014-240, s. 4.</HistoricalNote></Section></Body></Regulation>