<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 1537</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>28</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">TERRITORIAL LANDS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Withdrawal of Certain Lands (Lockhart River N.W.T.) from Disposal Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Withdrawing from Disposal, Setting Apart and Appropriating Certain Lands in the Northwest Territories for the Purpose of the Development of Hydro Electric Power</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Withdrawal of Certain Lands (Lockhart River N.W.T.) from Disposal Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Withdrawal from Disposal</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>It is hereby ordered, for the purpose of future development of hydro electric power by the Northern Canada Power Commission, to withdraw from disposal under the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Territorial Lands Act</XRefExternal> the lands described in the schedule, including the minerals underlying such lands, without prejudice to the rights of holders of recorded mineral claims in good standing.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Setting Apart and Appropriation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>The lands described in the schedule are set apart and appropriated for the purpose of future development of hydro electric power by the Northern Canada Power Commission.</Text></Section></Body><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label><OriginatingRef>(Sections 2 and 3)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>All and singular that certain parcel or tract of land and land covered by water situate, lying and being on the Lockhart River, in the Northwest Territories, and being more particularly described as follows, all topographic features hereinafter referred to being according to the Parry Falls map sheet number 75 K/15 produced in 1961, at a scale of 1:50,000 by the Department of Energy, Mines and Resources, at Ottawa, Ontario:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>COMMENCING at a peak having an elevation of about 750 feet, said peak lying northerly of the Lockhart River at approximate latitude 62°49′15″ and longitude 108°52′00″;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE, northeasterly in a straight line to a peak having an elevation of about 1,250 feet, at approximate latitude 62°51′30″ and longitude 108°47′20″;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE, southeasterly in a straight line to the most northerly point on the bank of an unnamed lake, at approximate latitude 62°50′40″ and longitude 108°46′20″;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE, in a general southwesterly direction along the last aforesaid bank to its most westerly point;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE, southwesterly in a straight line to the most northerly point on the bank of an unnamed lake, at approximate latitude 62°49′40″ and longitude 108°47′15″;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE, southwesterly in a straight line to the most northerly point on the bank of an unnamed lake, at approximate latitude 62°48′45″ and longitude 108°50′30″;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE, northwesterly in a straight line to the point of commencement; all coordinates described above being Geodetic, referred to the 1927 North American datum; the said parcel containing 3.9 square miles, more or less.</Text></Provision></Provision></Schedule></Regulation>