<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 967</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2006</YYYY><MM>2</MM><DD>14</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">DEPARTMENT OF INDUSTRY ACT</XRefExternal><XRefExternal reference-type="act">APPROPRIATION ACTS</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Consolidated Computer Inc. Adjustment Assistance Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting Adjustment Assistance to Consolidated Computer Inc.</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Consolidated Computer Inc. Adjustment Assistance Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations, all words and expressions have the same meaning as in the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">General Adjustment Assistance Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Special Loans</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Notwithstanding subsection 14(8) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">General Adjustment Assistance Regulations</XRefExternal>, the Board may, under subsection 14(4) of those Regulations, provide insurance in an amount not exceeding 99 per cent of the amount of loans, not exceeding $30 million in the aggregate, made by private lenders for the purpose of facilitating the leasing of computer products manufactured by Consolidated Computer Inc., a corporation incorporated under the laws of the Province of Ontario and having its head office in the City of Toronto in that Province.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Notwithstanding section 17 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">General Adjustment Assistance Regulations</XRefExternal>, where a private lender had demanded repayment of a loan described in subsection (1) in respect of which insurance has been provided under subsection 14(8) of the said Regulations, prior to the maturity of that loan, the amount payable by Her Majesty to the private lender shall not exceed the lesser of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the amount of insurance in effect on the date of such demand: and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>99 per cent of the loss incurred by the private lender.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section></Body></Regulation>