<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 1367</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>27</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">PUBLICATION OF STATUTES ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Publication of Statutes Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting the Publication of Statutes</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Publication of Statutes Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>Subject to these Regulations, the annual Statutes of Canada shall be printed, so far as practicable, in the same size of type and in the same form as the printed Bills of Parliament.</Text></Section><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>The annual Statutes of Canada shall be printed on Number 1 Opaque Litho Book according to Canadian Government Specifications Board Standard 9-GP-29, Grade 2, Type 1, (except moisture content) or equivalent in white colour, English finish, and the basic weight shall be 100 pounds per 1,000 sheets 25 inches by 38 inches.</Text></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>The table of contents, table of public statutes, index and list of proclamations shall be printed on Number 1, Litho Book according to Canadian Government Specifications Board Standard 9-GP-29, Grade 1, Type 1 (except moisture content), or equivalent English finish, basic weight 120 pounds per 1,000 sheets 25 inches by 38 inches, in apricot colour for English text and light blue for French text.</Text></Section><Section><Label>5</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The trim size of the printed page shall not exceed 8 1/8 inches in width by 9 3/4 inches in length.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The size of the printed page shall be 41 picas and four points in width by 52 picas in length including the headline at the top of the page and the general page number centred at the bottom of the page.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>6</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>In this section and section 7, "volume" means a volume of the annual Statutes of Canada.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A volume shall not exceed 1,300 pages including the table of contents, table of public statutes, index and list of proclamations.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>7</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The covers of every volume shall be</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>composed of solid binders board of 0.120 inch thickness; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>bound in fawn coloured buckram of Vellum finish equivalent to PX101, colour ST-729 Fawn and finish Vellum "M" manufactured by Canadian Industries Limited.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The buckram binding of every volume shall wrap around the inside covers thereof by a minimum of 5/8 inch.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The overhang on the inside of the covers at the head, side and foot of every volume shall be 1/8 inch larger than the size of the trimmed page.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>A loosely woven cloth strip shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>be glued on the spine of every volume;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>extend one inch over the front and back covers of every volume; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>be covered by a paper strip on that portion of the spine of every volume containing the signature backs.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>The signature backs referred to in subsection (4) shall have two 5/8 inch tapes sewn across the back of the spine and extending one inch onto the front and back covers of the volume.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(6)</Label><Text>The lettering on the cover of every volume shall be black.</Text></Subsection></Section></Body></Regulation>