<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 659</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>6</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">FARM PRODUCTS AGENCIES ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Canadian Turkey Anti-dumping Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting the Pricing of Turkeys Iin Interprovincial Trade</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Canadian Turkey Anti-dumping Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>marketing</DefinedTermEn>, in relation to turkeys, means selling and offering for sale and buying, pricing, assembling, packing, processing, transporting, storing, and reselling, whether in whole or in processed form, and includes marketing by or on behalf of a producer; (<DefinedTermFr>commercialisation</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>regulated area</DefinedTermEn> means the Provinces of Nova Scotia, New Brunswick, Quebec, Ontario, Manitoba, Saskatchewan, Alberta and British Columbia; (<DefinedTermFr>région réglementée</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>turkey</DefinedTermEn> means any turkey, male or female, live or slaughtered, of any size and includes any part of any turkey; (<DefinedTermFr>dindon</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>unregulated area</DefinedTermEn> means any part of Canada not within the regulated area. (<DefinedTermFr>région non réglementée</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interprovincial Price</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>Within the regulated area and with respect to turkeys shipped from the unregulated area into the regulated area in interprovincial trade and not for export, no person shall market turkeys in a province other than the province in which the turkeys are produced at a price that is less than the aggregate of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the price charged at or about the same time for turkeys of an equivalent variety, class or grade in the province or other geographical area in which the turkeys are produced; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any reasonable transportation charges therefor to the place where such turkeys are marketed and that are incurred by the person marketing the turkeys.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>With respect to turkeys from the regulated area shipped into the unregulated area in interprovincial trade, no person shall market turkeys in a province other than the province in which the turkeys are produced at a price that is less than the aggregate of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the price charged at or about the same time for turkeys of an equivalent variety, class or grade in the province or other geographical area in which the turkeys are produced; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any reasonable transportation charges therefor to the place where such turkeys are marketed and that are incurred by the person marketing the turkeys.</Text></Paragraph></Section></Body></Regulation>