<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 886</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>13</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">GOVERNMENT PROPERTY TRAFFIC ACT</XRefExternal><XRefExternal reference-type="act">DEPARTMENT OF TRANSPORT ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Airport Traffic Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting the Control of Motor Vehicles, Pedestrians, Aircraft and Equipment at Airports</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Airport Traffic Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>aerodrome</DefinedTermEn> means an area of land, water (including the frozen surface thereof) or other supporting surface used, designed, prepared, equipped or set apart for use either in whole or in part for the arrival, departure, movement or servicing of aircraft and includes any buildings, installations and equipment used in connection therewith; (<DefinedTermFr>aérodrome</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>aircraft</DefinedTermEn> means any machine used or designed for navigation in the air but does not include a machine designed to derive support in the atmosphere from reactions against the earth’s surface of air expelled from the machine; (<DefinedTermFr>aéronef</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>airport</DefinedTermEn> means an aerodrome in respect of which a Canadian aviation document issued pursuant to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Aeronautics Act</XRefExternal> is in force; (<DefinedTermFr>aéroport</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>airport manager</DefinedTermEn> means the person in charge of an airport or the authorized representative of that person; (<DefinedTermFr>directeur d’aéroport</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>animal</DefinedTermEn> means any domestic animal and includes poultry; (<DefinedTermFr>animal</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>apron</DefinedTermEn> means that part of an airport, other than the manoeuvring area, intended to accommodate the loading and unloading of passengers and cargo, the refuelling, servicing, maintenance and parking of aircraft and the movement of aircraft, vehicles and pedestrians to allow execution of those functions; (<DefinedTermFr>aire de trafic</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>apron traffic</DefinedTermEn> means all aircraft, vehicles, pedestrians and equipment utilizing the apron area of the airport; (<DefinedTermFr>trafic de l’aire de trafic</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>commercial passenger vehicle</DefinedTermEn> means any taxi, bus or other vehicle used or intended for use in the transportation of persons for compensation; (<DefinedTermFr>véhicule commercial pour passager</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>constable</DefinedTermEn> means</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a member of the Royal Canadian Mounted Police,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a member of a provincial or municipal police force, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>any person or a member of a class of persons authorized by the Minister to enforce these Regulations; (<DefinedTermFr>agent</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>cross-walk</DefinedTermEn> means</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any portion of a road, apron or other area designated by a sign or surface marking as a pedestrian crossing, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>that part of a road at an intersection that is included within the connections of the lateral lines of the sidewalks on opposite sides of the road or, in the absence of curbs, from the edges of the road; (<DefinedTermFr>passage pour piétons</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Department</DefinedTermEn> means the Department of Transport; (<DefinedTermFr>ministère</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>driver</DefinedTermEn> means a person who is driving or is in actual physical control of a motor vehicle or bicycle; (<DefinedTermFr>conducteur</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>intersection</DefinedTermEn> means the area embraced within the prolongation or connection of the lateral curb lines or, in the absence of curb lines, of the lateral boundary lines of two or more roads that join one another at an angle whether or not one road crosses the other; (<DefinedTermFr>carrefour</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>land side</DefinedTermEn> means land side as defined in section 1 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Traffic on the Land Side of Airports Regulations</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>côté ville</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>loading area</DefinedTermEn> means any portion of an airport designated by a sign and made available to the public for loading or unloading; (<DefinedTermFr>aire d’embarquement</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>manoeuvring area</DefinedTermEn> means that part of an airport ordinarily used for the take-off and landing of aircraft and for the movement of aircraft associated with the take-off and landing, but does not include the apron; (<DefinedTermFr>aire de manoeuvre</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Minister</DefinedTermEn> means the Minister of Transport; (<DefinedTermFr>ministre</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>motor vehicle</DefinedTermEn> means an automobile, over-snow vehicle, truck, bus or any self-propelled vehicle or device in, upon or by which a person or property is or may be transported, carried or conveyed upon land and includes a machine designed to derive support in the atmosphere from reactions against the earth’s surface of air expelled from the machine; (<DefinedTermFr>véhicule à moteur</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>over-snow vehicle</DefinedTermEn> means a vehicle that is capable of being propelled or driven otherwise than by muscular power, that runs on tracks or skis or on tracks and skis and that is designed for operation on snow or ice; (<DefinedTermFr>autoneige</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>owner</DefinedTermEn>, with respect to a motor vehicle, means a person who holds legal title to it or a person in whose name it is or is required to be registered by the laws of a province and includes a conditional purchaser, lessee or mortgagor who is entitled to or is in possession of the motor vehicle; (<DefinedTermFr>propriétaire</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>park</DefinedTermEn> means the standing of a motor vehicle whether occupied or not, except for the purpose of and while actually engaged in loading or unloading passengers or goods; (<DefinedTermFr>laisser en stationnement</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>parking area</DefinedTermEn> means a part of an airport property that is designated by a sign or by surface markings as an area for parking motor vehicles; (<DefinedTermFr>parc de stationnement</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>parking meter</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/92-120, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>parking permit</DefinedTermEn> means a permit issued by the airport manager that authorizes the permit holder to park a motor vehicle in a specific parking area in accordance with the terms of the permit; (<DefinedTermFr>permis de stationnement</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>parking space</DefinedTermEn> means a space for parking motor vehicles that is located in a parking area and that, in most cases, is delineated by surface markings; (<DefinedTermFr>place de stationnement</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>pay-in-advance parking control system</DefinedTermEn> means a system of parking control whereby the person who parks a motor vehicle in a parking space is required, immediately before or after parking the motor vehicle, to pay a fee in respect of the period of time during which the person anticipates that the motor vehicle will remain in that parking space; (<DefinedTermFr>péage anticipé</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>pedestrian</DefinedTermEn> means a person on foot and includes an invalid or child in a wheelchair or carriage; (<DefinedTermFr>piéton</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>restricted area</DefinedTermEn> means an area at an aerodrome that is designated by a sign as an area to which access is restricted to persons authorized by the airport manager; (<DefinedTermFr>zone réglementée</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>road</DefinedTermEn> includes any highway, street or place designed and intended for or used for the passage of motor vehicles; (<DefinedTermFr>route</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>sidewalk</DefinedTermEn> means that part of a road or apron that is constructed for the use of pedestrians; (<DefinedTermFr>trottoir</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>special parking permit</DefinedTermEn> means a permit issued by the airport manager that authorizes the permit holder to park a motor vehicle in such place and in accordance with such terms as are specified by the airport manager. (<DefinedTermFr>permis spécial de stationnement</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>valid identification</DefinedTermEn> means a document issued or approved by the airport manager authorizing the holder to have access to a restricted area of the airport. (<DefinedTermFr>pièce d’identité valable</DefinedTermFr>) </Text></Definition><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-120, s. 1; SOR/2006-102, s. 26.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>These Regulations apply in respect of an area other than the land side of an airport set out in Schedule I or II.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-120, s. 2; SOR/2006-102, s. 27.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Enforcement</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>The Minister may authorize any person or class of persons to act as a constable to enforce these Regulations.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART I</Label><TitleText>Operation of Motor Vehicles</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Prohibition</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>No person shall operate a motor vehicle on an airport unless</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>he holds all licences and permits that he is, by the laws of the province and the municipality in which the airport is situated, required to hold in order to operate the motor vehicle in that province and municipality; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the motor vehicle is registered and equipped as required by the laws of the province and the municipality in which the airport is situated.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>For the purpose of these Regulations, a provincial certificate of motor vehicle registration shall be <Language xml:lang="la">prima facie</Language> proof of ownership of the motor vehicle.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Compliance with Provincial and Municipal Laws</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>No person shall operate a motor vehicle on an airport otherwise than in accordance with the laws of the province and the municipality in which the airport is situated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>In this Part, the expression “laws of the province and the municipality” does not include laws that are inconsistent with or repugnant to any of the provisions of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Government Property Traffic Act</XRefExternal> or these Regulations.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Traffic Signs and Devices</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>7</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The Minister may mark or erect or cause to be marked or erected on any airport traffic signs or devices</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>prescribing the rate of speed;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>regulating or prohibiting parking and designating parking, loading or restricted areas;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>prescribing load limits for any motor vehicle or class of motor vehicles;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>prohibiting or regulating the use of any road or place by any motor vehicle or class of motor vehicles, or by persons or animals;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>designating any road as a one-way road;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>stopping motor vehicles;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>regulating pedestrian traffic; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>directing or controlling in any other manner traffic on the airport.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Except as authorized by subsection (1), no person shall mark or erect any traffic sign or device on any airport.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-120, s. 3(F).</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>8</Label><Text>Any traffic sign or device on any airport bearing the words “Department of Transport”, “Ministère des Transports”, or an abbreviation thereof, or purporting to have been erected by or under the authority of the Minister, shall be deemed <Language xml:lang="la">prima facie</Language> to have been erected pursuant to this Part.</Text></Section><Section><Label>9</Label><Text>The driver of a motor vehicle on an airport shall obey the instruction of any traffic sign or device applicable to that driver or motor vehicle.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Traffic Direction and Control</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>10</Label><Text>No person shall, on an airport, drive</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a motor vehicle other than an over-snow vehicle, except on a road; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>an over-snow vehicle except with the permission of the airport manager.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>11</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The driver of a motor vehicle on an airport shall comply with any traffic directions given to him by a constable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A constable may, for the purpose of ensuring the orderly movement of all traffic on an airport, direct or control such traffic.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>12</Label><Text>Every person on an airport shall produce to a constable upon demand</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any permit issued to him under this Part;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any licence or permit he holds authorizing him to drive a motor vehicle; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>any certificate of registration referred to in subsection 5(2).</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>13</Label><Text>Every driver of a motor vehicle who is directly or indirectly involved in an accident on an airport shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>report the accident forthwith as required by the laws of the province in which the accident occurred; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>if any property of Her Majesty is damaged by the accident, report the accident forthwith to a member of the Royal Canadian Mounted Police or the airport manager.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>14</Label><Text>No person shall operate or park a motor vehicle</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>on an apron unless he has the permission of the airport manager; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in any area designated by a sign as a restricted area unless he is in possession of valid identification.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>15</Label><Text>Where an apron traffic control unit, as defined in Part IV, has been established at an airport, the operator of a motor vehicle on the apron shall acknowledge and obey any instruction received from the unit.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Parking</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>16</Label><Text>No person shall park a motor vehicle in any area designated by a sign as an area in which parking is prohibited.</Text></Section><Section><Label>17</Label><Text>No person shall, without the permission of the Minister, park a motor vehicle on any portion of an airport that is grassed or that is not intended for the use of motor vehicles.</Text></Section><Section><Label>18</Label><Text>No person shall park a motor vehicle in a place designated by a sign as a loading area.</Text></Section><Section><Label>19</Label><Text>No driver of a commercial passenger vehicle shall load or unload passengers at an airport except in an area designated by a sign as an area in which passenger loading or unloading is permitted.</Text></Section><Section><Label>20</Label><Text>Where an area is designated by a sign as an area in which parking is reserved for persons who hold a parking permit or special parking permit, as the case may be, no person shall park a motor vehicle in that area unless the person</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>holds a parking permit or special parking permit that authorizes the person to park in that area;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>where an identifying label or ticket has been issued with the parking permit or special parking permit, affixes the label to the lower corner of the driver’s side of the windshield of the motor vehicle, or displays the ticket on the driver’s side of the dashboard of the motor vehicle in such a manner that it is clearly visible; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>parks the motor vehicle in accordance with the terms of the parking permit or special parking permit.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-120, s. 4.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>21</Label><Text>Where an area is designated by a sign as an area in which parking is permitted for a period of time, no person shall park a motor vehicle in that area for any greater period of time than that indicated on the sign.</Text></Section><Section><Label>22</Label><Text>Where an area is designated by a sign as an area in which parking is prohibited during certain hours, no person shall park a motor vehicle in that area during the hours when parking is prohibited.</Text></Section><Section><Label>23</Label><Text>Where a parking area is designated by a sign or surface markings as an area in which parking is permitted only in parking spaces, no person shall park a motor vehicle in a parking space in the parking area unless the person pays for the use of the parking space in accordance with the system of parking control in effect in that part of the parking area in which the motor vehicle is to be parked.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-120, s. 5.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>24</Label><Text>No person who has parked a motor vehicle in a parking space that is governed by a pay-in-advance parking control system shall allow the motor vehicle to remain parked in that parking space for a period of time greater than the period of time for which a fee has been paid in respect of that parking space.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-120, s. 5.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>25</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Where an area is designated by a sign as an area in which parking is reserved for handicapped persons, no person shall park a motor vehicle in that area unless the motor vehicle is identified by a sign as a motor vehicle used for the transport of a handicapped person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Where an area is designated by a sign as an area in which parking is reserved for certain persons or a particular class of persons, other than handicapped persons, no person shall park a motor vehicle in that area unless the person is one of those persons.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-120, s. 5.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>26</Label><Text>No person shall park a motor vehicle at an airport in such a manner as to obstruct traffic.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-120, s. 5.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>27</Label><Text>Subject to section 28, where a parking area is designated by a sign or surface markings as an area in which parking is permitted only in delineated parking spaces, no person shall park a motor vehicle in that area unless the motor vehicle is parked wholly within a delineated parking space.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-120, s. 5.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>28</Label><Text>Where a person parks a motor vehicle that is longer or wider than one delineated parking space so that it wholly or partially occupies more than one delineated parking space, the person shall pay the fee that is required in respect of each parking space wholly or partially occupied by the motor vehicle.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-120, s. 5.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>29</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Where a parking area contains delineated parking spaces for normal sized vehicles and an area designated by a sign for the parking of oversized vehicles, any person who parks a motor vehicle that is longer or wider than a delineated parking space shall park it in the designated area.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Any person who contravenes subsection (1) shall be considered to have parked a motor vehicle in such a manner as to obstruct traffic.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-120, s. 5; SOR/95-536, s. 6(F); SOR/2002-356, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>30</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/95-536, s. 6]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>31</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The Minister may issue or authorize the issue of permits and labels for the purposes of this Part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The Minister or a person authorized by him may at any time revoke a permit issued under this Part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Unless sooner revoked, a permit issued under this Part is valid only for the period stated thereon and a label furnished with the permit is valid only during the period that the permit is valid.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>32</Label><Text>A constable who finds a motor vehicle parked in contravention of this Part may, at the expense of the owner, remove the vehicle and, if he deems it necessary to protect the vehicle or the interests of the owner, store it in a suitable place.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Speed</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>33</Label><Text>No person shall drive a motor vehicle on a road at a rate of speed in excess of the speed limit indicated for that road by a sign.</Text></Section><Section><Label>34</Label><Text>Unless otherwise authorized by the airport manager, no person shall drive a motor vehicle on an apron at a rate of speed in excess of 15 mph (25 km/h).</Text></Section><Section><Label>35</Label><Text>No person shall drive a motor vehicle on an apron or manoeuvring area in a manner that is dangerous to persons, aircraft, vehicles or equipment, having regard to all the circumstances including the amount of traffic thereon or reasonably expected to be thereon.</Text></Section><Section><Label>36</Label><Text>The provisions of this Part relating to motor vehicles apply with such modifications as the circumstances require to a bicycle or any cycle regardless of the number of wheels it may have.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Animals</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>37</Label><Text>No person shall allow an animal owned by him or under his control to be at large on an airport.</Text></Section><Section><Label>38</Label><Text>A constable or person in charge of an airport may, at the expense of the owner of the animal, cause any animal found at large on the airport to be confined or driven off the airport or impounded in accordance with the laws of the province and municipality in which the airport is situated.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Penalties</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>39</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsections (2) and (3) and subsection 40(4), every person who contravenes a provision of this Part is liable on summary conviction to</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a fine not exceeding an amount equal to the lesser of</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the maximum fine, if any, prescribed under the highway traffic laws of the province in which the offence was committed, as amended from time to time, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>in any other case, $500;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a term of imprisonment not exceeding six months; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>both.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Every person who contravenes any provision of these Regulations governing the parking of motor vehicles shall be liable on summary conviction to a fine not exceeding $50.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Where a person is convicted of driving a motor vehicle in contravention of this Part, the convicting court or judge may, in addition to any other penalty imposed, make an order prohibiting that person from driving any motor vehicle on any lands belonging to or occupied by Her Majesty in right of Canada for any period not exceeding one year from the date of the conviction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Every person who drives a motor vehicle contrary to an order made pursuant to subsection (3) is liable on summary conviction to a fine not exceeding $500 or to imprisonment for a term not exceeding six months or to both.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/96-476, s. 1; SOR/2002-356, s. 2; SOR/2006-102, s. 28.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>40</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Any person who is alleged to have contravened any provision of this Part governing the parking of a motor vehicle may, at any time within 72 hours after the expiration of the day on which the contravention is alleged to have occurred, excluding holidays, register a plea of guilty to the alleged offence and pay into court, either personally or by mail,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>where the alleged offence relates to parking in an area in which parking is prohibited, in contravention of section 16,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>$25, where the alleged offence occurred at an airport set out in Schedule I,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>$15, where the alleged offence occurred at an airport set out in Schedule II that is denoted by an asterisk, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>$10, where the alleged offence occurred at an airport set out in Schedule II that is not denoted by an asterisk;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>where the alleged offence relates to parking in a loading area, in contravention of section 18,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>$30, where the alleged offence occurred at an airport set out in Schedule I,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>$20, where the alleged offence occurred at an airport set out in Schedule II that is denoted by an asterisk, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>$15, where the alleged offence occurred at an airport set out in Schedule II that is not denoted by an asterisk;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>where the alleged offence relates to parking in an area that is reserved for persons who hold a parking permit or special parking permit, in contravention of section 20,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>$25, where the alleged offence occurred at an airport set out in Schedule I,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>$15, where the alleged offence occurred at an airport set out in Schedule II that is denoted by an asterisk, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>$10, where the alleged offence occurred at an airport set out in Schedule II that is not denoted by an asterisk;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>where the alleged offence relates to overtime parking, in contravention of section 21 or 24,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>$15, where the alleged offence occurred at an airport set out in Schedule I,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>$10, where the alleged offence occurred at an airport set out in Schedule II that is denoted by an asterisk, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>$5, where the alleged offence occurred at an airport set out in Schedule II that is not denoted by an asterisk;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>where the alleged offence relates to parking a motor vehicle in such a manner as to obstruct traffic, in contravention of section 26 or subsection 29(2),</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>$30, where the alleged offence occurred at an airport set out in Schedule I,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>$20, where the alleged offence occurred at an airport set out in Schedule II that is denoted by an asterisk, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>$15, where the alleged offence occurred at an airport set out in Schedule II that is not denoted by an asterisk;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>where the alleged offence relates to parking in an area</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>that is reserved for handicapped persons, in contravention of subsection 25(1), $50, where the alleged offence occurred at an airport set out in Schedule I or II,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>that is reserved for certain persons or a particular class of persons, other than handicapped persons, in contravention of subsection 25(2), $25, where the alleged offence occurred at an airport set out in Schedule I or II;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>where the alleged offence relates to a contravention of section 17, 19, 22, 23, 27 or 28 or subsection 29(1),</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>$25, where the alleged offence occurred at an airport set out in Schedule I,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>$15, where the alleged offence occurred at an airport set out in Schedule II that is denoted by an asterisk, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>$10, where the alleged offence occurred at an airport set out in Schedule II that is not denoted by an asterisk.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Any amount paid pursuant to subsection (1) shall be paid into the court designated by the Minister for such payment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Where a payment referred to in subsection (1) is sent to the court by mail, the payment into court shall be deemed to have been made on the day on which the payment was mailed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Where a person who is alleged to have contravened a provision of this Part governing the parking of a motor vehicle has, in accordance with subsection (1), paid money into court with respect to that contravention, no further penalty shall be imposed on him for that contravention.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/81-663, s. 1; SOR/92-120, s. 6; SOR/93-27, s. 1; SOR/95-536, s. 6; SOR/2006-102, s. 29(F).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART II</Label><TitleText>Pedestrians</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Prohibition</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>41</Label><Text>No person who is not in possession of valid identification shall enter upon or remain in any area that is designated by a sign or device as a restricted area unless authorized to do so by the airport manager.</Text></Section><Section><Label>41.1</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>No person, being the holder of valid identification designed to be worn on outer clothing, shall enter on or remain in a restricted area unless that identification is at all times visibly displayed on his person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Every holder of valid identification who fails to comply with the terms of issue of that identification shall surrender the identification to the airport manager.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/81-663, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>42</Label><Text>Every person found on or in a restricted area in contravention of section 41 or subsection 41.1(1) may be removed therefrom by a constable but such removal shall be without prejudice toward any other proceeding that may be taken.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/81-663, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>43</Label><Text>Where a portion of a road or apron has been designated as a cross-walk, no pedestrian shall proceed to cross the road or apron except within the designated cross-walk.</Text></Section><Section><Label>44</Label><Text>Where a sidewalk or path is located beside a road or apron, a pedestrian shall, at all times when reasonable and practicable to do so, use the sidewalk or path and shall not walk or remain on the road or apron.</Text></Section><Section><Label>45</Label><Text>Where there is no sidewalk or path located beside a road, a pedestrian walking along or upon the road shall, at all times when practicable to do so, walk on the left side or shoulder of the road facing on-coming traffic.</Text></Section><Section><Label>46</Label><Text>No pedestrian on an apron shall impede, interfere with or obstruct in any way the free movement of other apron traffic except in the course of his or her employment relating to the control of such traffic.</Text></Section><Section><Label>47</Label><Text>Where no cross-walk has been designated, every pedestrian crossing a road shall yield the right-of-way to motor vehicles using the road.</Text></Section><Section><Label>48</Label><Text>A pedestrian shall obey the instruction of any traffic sign or device and comply with any traffic directions given by a constable to him.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Smoking and Littering</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>49</Label><Text>No person shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>smoke, carry or deposit lighted cigars, cigarettes, pipes or matches or carry a naked flame</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>on an apron or any open deck gallery or balcony contiguous to and overlooking an apron,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>in any area where smoking is specifically prohibited by a sign, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>in any other place at an airport under such circumstances as may or might be likely to endanger persons or property;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>throw, deposit or knowingly leave on a road, apron or manoeuvring area any glass, nails, tacks, scraps of metal, chemical substance or other material that may damage an aircraft or motor vehicle; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>throw, deposit or knowingly leave on any airport any form of trash or garbage except in containers provided for that purpose.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Penalties</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>50</Label><Text>Every person who contravenes section 41, subsection 41.1(1) or (2) or section 49 is liable on summary conviction to a fine not exceeding $400.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/81-663, s. 4; SOR/2006-102, s. 30.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>51</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Any person who is alleged to have contravened any provision of this Part other than section 41 may, at any time within 72 hours from the expiration of the day on which the contravention is alleged to have occurred, excluding holidays, register a plea of guilty to the alleged offence by paying into court, either personally or by mail,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>$2, where the alleged offence relates to crossing a road or apron otherwise than at a designated cross-walk;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>$2, where the alleged offence relates to walking on a road or apron in contravention of section 44;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>$2, where the alleged offence relates to walking on a road in contravention of section 45;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>$5, where the alleged offence relates to impeding, interfering or obstructing the free movement of an aircraft on the apron or manoeuvring area in contravention of section 46;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>$5, where the alleged offence relates to failing to yield the right-of-way to motor vehicles in contravention of section 47;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>$5, where the alleged offence relates to disobeying instructions of any traffic sign or device or instruction given by a constable;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>$75, where the alleged offence relates to smoking or littering in contravention of section 49;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>$20, where the alleged offence relates to entering or remaining in a restricted area without visible identification in contravention of subsection 41.1(1); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>$20, where the alleged offence relates to failure to comply with subsection 41.1(2).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Any amount paid pursuant to subsection (1) shall be paid into the court designated by the Minister for such payment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Where a payment referred to in subsection (1) is sent to the court by mail, the payment into court shall be deemed to have been made on the day on which the payment was mailed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Where a person who is alleged to have contravened any provision of this Part other than section 41 has, in accordance with subsection (1), paid money into court with respect to that contravention, no further punishment shall be imposed on him for that contravention.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/81-663, s. 5; SOR/2006-102, s. 31.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART III</Label><TitleText>Registration of Mobile Equipment</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>52</Label><Text>In this Part,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>equipment</DefinedTermEn> means</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any motor vehicle or mobile device used in the direct fuelling or defuelling of aircraft, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any other motor vehicle or mobile device of a specialized nature for use in the maintenance, repair and servicing of an aircraft on the ground, including testing equipment and cargo and passenger handling equipment; (<DefinedTermFr>matérial</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>gross weight</DefinedTermEn>, with respect to any equipment, means the total weight of the equipment as specified by its manufacturer; (<DefinedTermFr>poids brut</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>registration year</DefinedTermEn> means the period commencing on January 1st in any year and ending on December 31st in that year. (<DefinedTermFr>année d’immatriculation</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Registration</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>53</Label><Text>Subject to this Part, the owner of equipment used at airports shall register that equipment each year in accordance with this Part.</Text></Section><Section><Label>54</Label><Text>No person shall operate any equipment at an airport unless that equipment has been registered in accordance with this Part.</Text></Section><Section><Label>55</Label><Text>Sections 53 and 54 do not apply to equipment operated exclusively on airport areas leased from the Department by the owner of the equipment.</Text></Section><Section><Label>56</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Applications for the registration of equipment shall be made in the form prescribed by the Minister and delivered together with the fees prescribed by this Part to the airport manager at the airport at which the equipment is to be used.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>On receipt of the application and fees described in subsection (1), the airport manager may, if he is of the opinion that the equipment for which registration is applied for can be safely operated at the airport, issue a registration certificate for that equipment.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Fees</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>57</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (2), the annual registration fee payable in respect of any motor vehicle or mobile device used in the direct fuelling or defuelling of aircraft shall be $15 or the amount obtained by multiplying the gross weight of the equipment, calculated in kilograms, by $0.033, whichever is the greater amount.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Where any equipment is registered after June 30th in any registration year, the fee shall be one-half of the fee prescribed by subsection (1).</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>58</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Where equipment registered at any airport is replaced by other equipment of a similar kind, there shall be paid to the airport manager of that airport</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>if the other equipment is of an equivalent or lower gross weight than the equipment replaced, a registration fee of $5; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>if the other equipment is of a greater gross weight than the equipment being replaced, a registration fee equal to the amount obtained by multiplying the difference between the gross weight of the equipment being replaced and the other equipment, calculated in kilograms, by $0.033.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The registration certificate for any equipment that is being replaced at an airport shall be surrendered to the airport manager of that airport.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>59</Label><Text>Where equipment registered under this Part is sold or transferred, the new owner of the equipment shall, before operating the equipment at an airport, notify the airport manager of that airport, and the airport manager may,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>on payment of a fee of $5 by the new owner,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>on surrender of the registration certificate previously issued for that equipment to the previous owner, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>upon being satisfied that the equipment may be safely operated at the airport,</Text></Paragraph><ContinuedSectionSubsection><Text>issue a new registration certificate for the equipment.</Text></ContinuedSectionSubsection></Section><Section><Label>60</Label><Text>Where a certificate of registration for any equipment is lost, a duplicate certificate may be issued by the airport manager on payment of a fee of $5.</Text></Section><Section><Label>61</Label><Text>The Minister or airport manager may exempt any equipment or class of equipment from the provisions of this Part.</Text></Section><Section><Label>62</Label><Text>Certificates of registration for any equipment shall be carried on the equipment at all times and shall be produced for examination on request by a constable or by an authorized representative of the airport manager.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-120, s. 7.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>63</Label><Text>Any person who contravenes any provision of this Part is guilty of an offence and is liable on summary conviction to a fine not exceeding $100.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART IV</Label><TitleText>Control of Aircraft on Aprons</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>64</Label><Text>In this Part,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>apron traffic control clearance</DefinedTermEn> means authorization by an apron traffic control unit for an aircraft to proceed on a controlled apron; (<DefinedTermFr>autorisation du contrôle de la circulation sur l’aire de trafic</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>apron traffic control instruction</DefinedTermEn> means a directive issued by an apron traffic control unit for airport apron traffic and gate control purposes; (<DefinedTermFr>instruction du contrôle de la circulation sur l’aire de trafic</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>apron traffic control unit</DefinedTermEn> means staff at an airport that provides apron traffic control service at the airport and includes the staff of a mobile control vehicle; (<DefinedTermFr>organe du contrôle de la circulation sur l’aire de trafic</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>controlled apron</DefinedTermEn> means an apron at an airport where apron traffic control service is provided; (<DefinedTermFr>aire de trafic contrôlée</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>operator</DefinedTermEn>, in respect of an aircraft, means the person in possession of the aircraft, whether as owner, lessee, hirer or otherwise, and in section 68 includes the person in whose name the aircraft is registered; (<DefinedTermFr>exploitant</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>owner</DefinedTermEn> has the same meaning as in the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Air Regulations</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>propriétaire</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>park</DefinedTermEn> means the standing of an aircraft, whether occupied or not; (<DefinedTermFr>laisser en stationnement</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>pilot-in-command</DefinedTermEn> means the pilot responsible for the operation and safety of an aircraft. (<DefinedTermFr>pilote commandant de bord</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>65</Label><Text>The operator or pilot-in-command of an aircraft shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>maintain</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>a continuous watch on the radio frequencies designated for apron communications, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>where a continuous radio watch is not possible, a watch for such instructions as may be issued by visual means from an apron traffic control unit;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>observe other apron traffic for the purpose of avoiding collision; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>where an apron traffic control unit is in operation, obtain, either by radio or by visual signal, authorization for his movements from that unit.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>66</Label><Text>No person shall operate or park an aircraft on an apron negligently, recklessly or in any other manner that endangers or is likely to endanger life or property.</Text></Section><Section><Label>67</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>No person shall move or park an aircraft on a controlled apron except in compliance with an apron traffic control clearance or an apron traffic control instruction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The operator or pilot-in-command of an aircraft shall immediately, upon receipt of an apron traffic control clearance or an apron traffic control instruction, acknowledge that he has received that clearance or instruction.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>68</Label><Text>No person shall park an aircraft on a controlled apron beyond the time limit set in the last apron traffic control instruction that was received by the operator or pilot-in-command before the aircraft was parked, or that is later issued by the apron traffic control unit and delivered to the owner or operator of the aircraft or the person in whose name the aircraft is registered.</Text></Section><Section><Label>69</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>An airport manager may order that an aircraft parked at an airport be moved.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The operator or pilot-in-command of an aircraft shall comply with any instructions or orders given to him by the airport manager pursuant to subsection (1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Where an aircraft is parked at an airport</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>beyond the time limit set by an apron traffic control unit,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in an unauthorized place, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>in a manner that obstructs traffic</Text></Paragraph><ContinuedSectionSubsection><Text>the airport manager may, at the expense of the operator of the aircraft, cause the aircraft to be moved and if he deems it necessary for the protection of the aircraft, store it in a suitable place.</Text></ContinuedSectionSubsection></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>70</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (2), any person who contravenes any provision of this Part is liable on summary conviction to a fine not exceeding $400.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Where a contravention of this Part relates to the parking of an aircraft, the fine shall not exceed $50.</Text></Subsection></Section></Body><Schedule bilingual="no" spanlanguages="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE I</Label><OriginatingRef>(Sections 3 and 40)</OriginatingRef><TitleText>International Airports</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><List><Item><Label>1</Label><Text>Calgary</Text></Item><Item><Label>2</Label><Text>Edmonton</Text></Item><Item><Label>3</Label><Text>Halifax (Robert L. Stanfield)</Text></Item><Item><Label>4</Label><Text>Montréal (Pierre Elliott Trudeau)</Text></Item><Item><Label>5</Label><Text>Montreal (Mirabel)</Text></Item><Item><Label>6</Label><Text>Ottawa</Text></Item><Item><Label>7</Label><Text>Toronto</Text></Item><Item><Label>8</Label><Text>Vancouver</Text></Item><Item><Label>9</Label><Text>Winnipeg (James Armstrong Richardson)</Text></Item></List><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-120, s. 8; SOR/2004-29, s. 11; SOR/2009-167, s. 6.</HistoricalNote></Schedule><Schedule><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE II</Label><OriginatingRef>(Sections 3 and 40)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><Heading style="listcaption" level="1"><Label>PART I</Label><TitleText>Atlantic Region Airports</TitleText></Heading><List><Item><Label>1</Label><Text>Charlottetown</Text></Item><Item><Label>2</Label><Text>Fredericton</Text></Item><Item><Label>3</Label><Text>Gander*</Text></Item><Item><Label>4</Label><Text>Moncton*</Text></Item><Item><Label>5</Label><Text>Saint John</Text></Item><Item><Label>6</Label><Text>St. Anthony</Text></Item><Item><Label>7</Label><Text>St. John’s*</Text></Item><Item><Label>8</Label><Text>Wabush</Text></Item></List><Heading style="listcaption" level="1"><Label>PART II</Label><TitleText>Quebec Region Airports</TitleText></Heading><List><Item><Label>1</Label><Text>Chevery</Text></Item><Item><Label>2</Label><Text>Îles-de-la-Madeleine</Text></Item><Item><Label>3</Label><Text>Lourdes-de-Blanc-Sablon</Text></Item><Item><Label>4</Label><Text>Natashquan</Text></Item><Item><Label>5</Label><Text>Québec*</Text></Item><Item><Label>6</Label><Text>Schefferville</Text></Item><Item><Label>7</Label><Text>Sept-Îles</Text></Item><Item><Label>8</Label><Text>Kuujjuaq</Text></Item></List><Heading style="listcaption" level="1"><Label>PART III</Label><TitleText>Ontario Region Airports</TitleText></Heading><List><Item><Label>1</Label><Text>London*</Text></Item></List><Heading style="listcaption" level="1"><Label>PART IV</Label><TitleText>Central Region Airports</TitleText></Heading><List><Item><Label>1</Label><Text>Churchill</Text></Item><Item><Label>2</Label><Text>Regina*</Text></Item><Item><Label>3</Label><Text>Saskatoon*</Text></Item><Item><Label>4</Label><Text>Thunder Bay</Text></Item></List><Heading style="listcaption" level="1"><Label>PART V</Label><TitleText>Western Region Airports</TitleText></Heading><List><Item><Label>1</Label><Text>Springbank</Text></Item></List><Heading style="listcaption" level="1"><Label>PART VI</Label><TitleText>Pacific Region Airports</TitleText></Heading><List><Item><Label>1</Label><Text>Kelowna</Text></Item><Item><Label>2</Label><Text>Penticton</Text></Item><Item><Label>3</Label><Text>Port Hardy</Text></Item><Item><Label>4</Label><Text>Prince George</Text></Item><Item><Label>5</Label><Text>Sandspit</Text></Item><Item><Label>6</Label><Text>Victoria*</Text></Item></List><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-120, s. 8; SOR/93-27, ss. 2 to 7; SOR/2006-102, s. 32.</HistoricalNote></Schedule></Regulation>