<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 1526</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>8</MM><DD>9</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">TERRITORIAL LANDS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Territorial Lands Act Exclusion Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Respecting the Acquisition of Interests in Territorial Lands by Officers or Employees of or under the Government of Canada</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Territorial Lands Act Exclusion Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Authority</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (2), an officer or employee of or under the Government of Canada may be a shareholder in a corporation that purchases, acquires or holds territorial land or any interest therein where</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the shares held by the officer or employee are of a class of shares of the capital stock of the corporation that are listed on a stock exchange in Canada that is prescribed for the purposes of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Income Tax Act</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the sole interest of the officer or employee in the corporation is as holder of shares of a class described in paragraph (a).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Nothing in subsection (1) shall be construed as authorizing an officer or employee of or under the Government of Canada to hold an interest as a shareholder in a corporation where that interest</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>would enable him to derive any direct or indirect benefit or interest from any government contracts over which he can influence decisions; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>would create a conflict with his public duties.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>This Order applies to shares described in subsection 2(1) acquired by an officer or employee of or under the Government of Canada either before or after August 13, 1975.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>