<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 1171</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>14</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">RAILWAY SAFETY ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Railway Safety Appliance Standards Regulations</ShortTitle><Note status="official" xml:space="default">CANADIAN TRANSPORT COMMISSION</Note><Note status="official" xml:space="default">GENERAL ORDER NO. 0-10</Note><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting Railway Safety Appliance Standards</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Railway Safety Appliance Standards Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>These Regulations apply to all rolling stock constructed or reconstructed and used on railways owned and operated by railway companies subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission.</Text></Section><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>Notwithstanding section 2,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>sections 1 to 112 of Schedule I apply in respect of box and other house cars built or rebuilt prior to October 1, 1966; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>sections 112.1 to 112.44 of Schedule I shall apply in respect of box and other house cars built or rebuilt on and after October 1, 1966, or under construction prior thereto.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>Sections 112.1 to 112.44 of Schedule I apply to all box and other house cars in service after December 31, 1982.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/80-751, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>Notwithstanding section 1 and sections 316 to 349 of Schedule I, sections 349.1 to 349.20 of Schedule I apply to</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>all caboose cars with platforms built new or rebuilt after January 1, 1967; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>all caboose cars with platforms in service after December 31, 1982.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/80-751, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>6</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Every railway company shall submit to the secretary of the Railway Transport Committee</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>before September 1, 1974,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>information respecting the total number and types of cars and caboose cars with platforms that will require modification by virtue of section 4 and paragraph 5(b), and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the time schedule fixed by the company for the making of any such modification; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>progress reports on the railway company’s compliance with the time schedule referred to in subparagraph (a)(ii), including information respecting the total number and type of the cars and caboose cars with platforms that remains to be modified</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>before August 1, 1980, for the period commencing on July 1, 1979 and ending on June 30, 1980,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>before February 1, 1981, for the period commencing on July 1, 1980 and ending on December 31, 1980,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>before August 1, 1981, for the period commencing on January 1, 1981 and ending on June 30, 1981,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>before February 1, 1982 for the period commencing on July 1, 1981 and ending on December 31, 1981, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(v)</Label><Text>before August 1, 1982 for the period commencing on January 1, 1982 and ending on June 30, 1982.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Every railway company shall, not later than February 1, 1983, submit to the Secretary of the Railway Transport Committee a final report containing information respecting</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the total number of cars and caboose cars with platforms that have been modified as required by virtue of section 4 and paragraph 5(b); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the action that has been taken in respect of any cars or caboose cars with platforms that have not been modified for the reason that they are not in service.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>No railway company shall put in service any car or caboose car with platform that has not been modified as required by virtue of section 4 or paragraph 5(b).</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/80-751, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section></Body><Schedule bilingual="no" spanlanguages="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE I</Label><OriginatingRef>(ss. 3, 4 and 5)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><RegulationPiece><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Box and other House Cars</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Hand Brakes</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Each box or other house car shall be equipped with an efficient hand brake which shall operate in harmony with the power brake thereon.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The hand brake may be of any efficient design, but shall provide the same degree of safety as the design shown on Plate A of Schedule II.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The brake shaft shall be not less than 1 1/4 inches in diameter, of wrought iron or steel without weld.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The brake wheel may be flat or dished, not less than 15, preferably 16, inches in diameter, of malleable iron, wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The hand brake shall be so located that it can be safely operated while the car is in motion.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The brake shaft shall be located on the end of the car to the left of and not less than 17 nor more than 22 inches from the centre.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>There shall be not less than four inches clearance around rim of brake wheel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Outside edge of brake wheel shall be not less than four inches from a vertical plane parallel with end of car and passing through the inside face of knuckle when closed with coupler horn against the buffer block or end sill.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Top brake shaft support shall be fastened with not less than 1/2-inch bolts or rivets (See Plate A of Schedule II).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>A brakeshaft step</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>shall support the lower end of the brake shaft;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>which will permit the brake chain to drop under the brake shaft shall not be used; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>in a u-shaped form is preferred (See Plate A of Schedule II).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>Brake shaft shall be arranged with a square fit at its upper end to secure the hand brake wheel; said square fit shall be not less than 7/8 inch square. Square-fit taper; nominally 2 in 12 inches (See Plate A of Schedule II).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(6)</Label><Text>Brake chain shall be of not less than 3/8, preferably 7/16 inch wrought iron or steel, with a link on the brake rod end of not less than 7/16, preferably 1/2 inch wrought iron or steel, and shall be secured to brake shaft drum by not less than 1/2 inch hexagon or square-headed bolt. Nut on said bolt shall be secured by riveting end of bolt over nut (See Plate A of Schedule II).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(7)</Label><Text>Lower end of brake shaft shall be provided with a trunnion of not less than 3/4, preferably one inch in diameter extending through brake shaft step and held in operating position by a suitable cotter or ring (See Plate A of Schedule II).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(8)</Label><Text>Brake shaft drum shall be not less than 1 1/2 inches in diameter (See Plate A of Schedule II).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(9)</Label><Text>Brake ratchet wheel shall be secured to brake shaft by a key or square fit; said square fit shall be of not less than 1 5/16 inches square.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(10)</Label><Text>When ratchet wheel with square fit is used provision shall be made to prevent ratchet wheel from rising on shaft to disengage brake pawl (See Plate A of Schedule II).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(11)</Label><Text>Brake ratchet wheel shall be not less than 5 1/4, preferably 5 1/2 inches in diameter and shall have not less than 14, preferably 16 teeth (See Plate A of Schedule II).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(12)</Label><Text>If brake ratchet wheel is more than 36 inches from brake wheel, a brake shaft support shall be provided to support this extended upper portion of brake shaft; said brake shaft support shall be fastened  with not less than 1/2-inch bolts or rivets.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(13)</Label><Text>The brake pawl shall be pivoted</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>upon a bolt or rivet not less than 5/8 inch in diameter; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>upon a trunnion secured by not less than 1/2-inch bolt or rivet.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(14)</Label><Text>Where the brake pawl is pivoted as provided under paragraph (a) or (b), there shall be a rigid metal connection between brake shaft and pivot of pawl.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(15)</Label><Text>Brake wheel shall be held in position on brake shaft by a nut on a threaded extended end of brake-shaft; said threaded portion shall be not less than 3/4 inch in diameter; said nut shall be secured by riveting over or by the use of a lock nut or suitable cotter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(16)</Label><Text>Brake wheel shall be arranged with a square fit for brake shaft in hub of said wheel; taper of said fit, nominally 2 in 12 inches (See Plate A of Schedule II).</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Brake Step</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>If brake step is used, it shall be not less than 28 inches in length.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Outside edge shall be not less than eight inches from face of car and not less than four inches from a vertical plane parallel with end of car and passing through the inside face of knuckle when closed with coupler horn against the bufferblock or end sill.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>Brake step shall be supported by not less than two metal braces having a minimum cross-sectional area 3/8 by 1 1/2 inches or equivalent, which shall be securely fastened to body of car with not less than 1/2-inch bolts or rivets.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Running Boards</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>7</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>One longitudinal running board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>On outside-metal roof cars, two latitudinal extensions.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>8</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Longitudinal running board shall be not less than 18, preferably 20, inches in width.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Latitudinal extensions shall be not less than 24 inches in width.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>9</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Full length of car, centre of roof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>On outside-metal roof cars there shall be two latitudinal extensions from longitudinal running board to ladder locations, except on refrigerator cars where such latitudinal extensions cannot be applied on account of ice hatches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>10</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Running boards shall be continuous from end to end and not cut or hinged at any point; the length and width of runningboards may, however, be made up of a number of pieces securely fastened to saddle blocks with screws or bolts.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The ends of longitudinal running boards shall be not less than six nor more than 10 inches from a vertical plane parallel with end of car and passing through the inside face of knuckle when closed with coupler horn against the buffer block or end sill; and if more than four inches from edge of roof of car, shall be securely supported their full width by substantial metal braces.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Running boards shall be made of wood and securely fastened to car.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Notwithstanding subsection (3) but subject to the following conditions, running boards may be of a material other than wood if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the material and design is of a type accepted by the A.A.R. and approved by the Commission; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the construction and installation is in accordance with A.A.R. requirements and acceptable to the Commission.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Sill Steps</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>11</Label><Text>Six.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>12</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum cross-sectional area 1/2 inch by 1 1/2 inches, or equivalent, of wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum length of tread, 10, preferably 12, inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Minimum clear depth, eight inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>13</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>One near each end on each side of car, so that there shall be not more than 18 inches from end of car to centre of tread of sill step.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>One at each end of car, centre of sill step to be as nearly central with the ladder as possible.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Outside edge of tread of step shall be not more than four inches inside of face of side of car, preferably flush with side of car.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Tread shall be not more than 24, preferably not more than 22, inches above the top of rail.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>14</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Sill steps exceeding 21 inches in depth shall have an additional tread.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Sill steps shall be securely fastened with not less than 1/2-inch bolts with nuts outside (when possible) and riveted over, or with not less than 1/2-inch rivets.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Ladders</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>15</Label><Text>Four.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>16</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum clear length of tread:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>side ladders, 16 inches; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>end ladders, 14 inches.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Maximum spacing between ladder treads, 19 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Top ladder tread shall be located not less than 12 nor more than 18 inches from roof at eaves.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Spacing of side ladder treads shall be uniform within a limit of two inches from top ladder tread to bottom tread of ladder.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>Maximum distance from bottom tread of side ladder to top tread of sill step, 21 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(6)</Label><Text>End ladder treads</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>shall, where construction of car permits, be spaced to coincide with treads of side ladders, a variation of two inches being allowed; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>where construction of car will not permit the application of a tread of end ladder to coincide with bottom tread of side ladder, the bottom tread of end ladder shall coincide with second tread from bottom of side ladder.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(7)</Label><Text>Hard wood treads, minimum dimensions 1 1/2 by two inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(8)</Label><Text>Iron or steel treads, minimum diameter 5/8 inch.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(9)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance of treads, two, preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>17</Label><Text>Ladders shall be located</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>one on each side, not more than eight inches from right end of car, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>one on each end, not more than eight inches from left side of car,</Text></Paragraph><ContinuedSectionSubsection><Text>measured from inside edge of ladder-stile or clearance of ladder treads to corner of car.</Text></ContinuedSectionSubsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>18</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Metal ladders without stiles near corners of cars shall have foot guards or upward projections not less than two inches in height near inside end of bottom treads.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Stiles of ladders, projecting two or more inches from face of car, will serve as foot guards.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Ladders shall be securely fastened with not less 1/2-inch bolts with nuts outside (when possible) and riveted over, or with not less than 1/2-inch rivets; 3/8-inch bolts may be used for wooden treads that are gained into stiles.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Ladder Clearance</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>19</Label><Text>No part of car above end sills within 30 inches from side of car, except buffer block, brake shaft, brake wheel, brake step, running board or uncoupling lever shall extend to within 12 inches of a vertical plane parallel with end of car and passing through the inside face of knuckle when closed with coupler horn against the buffer block, or end sill, and no other part of end of car or fixtures on same above end sills, other than exceptions herein noted, shall extend beyond the outer face of buffer block.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Roof Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>20</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>One over each ladder.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>One right-angle handhold may take the place of two adjacent specified roof handholds, if the dimensions and locations coincide, and an extra leg is securely fastened to car at point of angle.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>21</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter, 5/8 inch, wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clear length, 16 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance, two, preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>22</Label><Text>On roof of car: one parallel to treads of each ladder, not less than eight nor more than 15 inches from edge of roof, except that on refrigerator cars, where ice hatches prevent, the location may be nearer edge of roof.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>23</Label><Text>Roof handholds shall be securely fastened with not less than 1/2-inch bolts with nuts outside (when possible) and riveted over, or with not less than 1/2-inch rivets.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Side Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>24</Label><Text>Four. (Tread of side ladder is a side handhold)</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>25</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter, 5/8 inch, wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clear length, 16 inches, preferably 24 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance, two, preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>26</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Horizontal: one near each end on each side of car.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Side handholds shall be not less than 24 nor more than 30 inches above centre line of coupler, except as provided above, where tread of ladder is a handhold.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Clearance of outer end of handhold shall be not more than eight inches from end of car.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>27</Label><Text>Side handholds shall be securely fastened with not less than 1/2-inch bolts with nuts outside (when possible) and riveted over or with not less than 1/2-inch rivets.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Horizontal End Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>28</Label><Text>Eight or more. (Four on each end of car.) (Tread of end ladder is an end handhold.)</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>29</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter, 5/8 inch, wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clear length, 16 inches, preferably 24 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Notwithstanding subsection (2), a handhold 14 inches in length may be used where it is impossible to use one 16 inches in length.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance, two, preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>30</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>One near each side on each end of car, not less than 24 nor more than 30 inches above centre line of coupler, except as provided above, when tread of end ladder is an end handhold.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Clearance of outer end of handhold shall be not more than eight inches from side of car.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>One near each side of each end of car on face of end sill or sheathing over end sill, projecting outward or downward.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Clearance of outer end of handhold shall be not more than 16 inches from side of car.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>On each end of cars with platform end sills six or more inches in width, measured from end post or siding, and extending entirely across end of car, there shall be one additional end handhold not less than 24 inches in length, located near centre of car, not less than 30 nor more than 60 inches above platform end sill.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>31</Label><Text>Horizontal end handholds shall be securely fastened with not less than 1/2-inch bolts with nuts outside (when possible) and riveted over, or with not less than 1/2-inch rivets.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Vertical End Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>32</Label><Text>Two on full-width platform end sill cars, as heretofore described.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>33</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter, 5/8 inch, wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clear length, 18, preferably 24, inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance, two preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>34</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>One on each end of car opposite ladder, not more than eight inches from side of car.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Clearance of bottom end of handhold shall be not less than 24 nor more than 30 inches above centre line of coupler.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>35</Label><Text>Vertical end handholds shall be securely fastened with not less than 1/2-inch bolts with nuts outside (when possible) and riveted over, or with not less than 1/2-inch rivets.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Uncoupling Levers</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>36</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Two.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Uncoupling levers may be either single or double, and of any efficient design.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>37</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Handles of uncoupling levers, except those shown on Plate B of Schedule II, or of similar designs, shall be not more than six inches from sides of car.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Uncoupling levers of design shown on Plate B of Schedule II and of similar designs, shall conform to the following prescribed limits:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>handles shall be not more than 12, preferably nine, inches from sides of cars;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>centre lift-arms shall be not less than seven inches long;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>centre of eye at end of centre lift-arm shall be not more than 3 1/2 inches beyond centre of eye of uncoupling pin of coupler when horn of coupler is against the buffer block or end sill (See Plate B of Schedule II);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>ends of handles shall extend not less than four inches below bottom of end sill or shall be so constructed as to give a minimum clearance of two inches around handle (See Plate B of Schedule II);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>minimum drop of handles shall be 12 inches; maximum, 15 inches over all (See Plate B of Schedule II);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>handles of uncoupling levers of the rocking or push-down type shall be not less than 18 inches from top of rail when lock block has released knuckle, and a suitable stop shall be provided to prevent inside arm from flying up in case of breakage.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>38</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>One on each end of car; when single lever is used it shall be placed on left side of end of car.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Cars built after June 1, 1919 must be equipped with coupler operating lever connected directly with coupler lock of lock lift without the use of links, clevises or chains.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Box or other House Cars Having Centre Sill or Underframe Cushioning Devices with More than Twelve Inches Longitudinal Impact Absorbing Travel</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Hand Brakes</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>39</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>40</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>41</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>42</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Brake Step</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>43</Label><Text>If brake step is used, it shall not be less than 28 inches in length and the outside edge shall not be less than eight inches from face of car and not less than four inches from a vertical plane parallel with end of car and passing through the inside face of knuckle when closed with coupler horn against buffer block or end sill and the cushioning device at full buff.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>44</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Running Boards</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>45</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>46</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>47</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>48</Label><Text>Running boards shall be continuous from end to end and not cut or hinged at any point; the length and width of running boards may, however, be made up of a number of pieces securely fastened to saddle blocks with screws, bolts, or rivets. The ends of longitudinal running boards shall not be less than six nor more than 10 inches from a vertical plane parallel with end of car and passing through the inside face of knuckle when closed with coupler horn against buffer block or end sill, and the cushioning device at full buff; and if more than four inches from edge of roof of car, shall be securely supported their full width by substantial metal braces. Running boards shall be securely fastened to car and be made of a material which provides the same as or a greater degree of safety than wood of 1 1/8 inch thickness. When made of material other than wood, the tread surface shall be of anti-skid design and constructed with sufficient open space to prevent the accumulation of snow and ice on the tread surface.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Sill Steps</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>49</Label><Text>Four.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimension</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>50</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum cross-sectional area 1/2 inch by 1 1/2 inches, or equivalent, of wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum length of tread, 10, preferably 12, inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Minimum clear depth, eight inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>51</Label><Text>One near each end on each side of car, so that there shall not be more than 18 inches from end of car to centre of tread of sill step. Outside edge of tread of step shall be not more than four inches inside of face of side of car, preferably flush with side of car. Tread shall be not more than 24, preferably not more than 22, inches above the top of rail.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>52</Label><Text>Sill steps exceeding 21 inches in depth shall have an additional tread. Sill steps shall be securely fastened with not less than 1/2-inch bolts with nuts outside (when possible) and riveted over or with not less than 1/2-inch rivets.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Ladders</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>53</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>54</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum clear length of tread</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>side ladders 16 inches;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>end ladders 14 inches.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Maximum spacing between ladder treads, 19 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Top ladder tread shall be located not less than 12 nor more than 18 inches from roof at eaves.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Spacing of side ladder treads shall be uniform within a limit of two inches from top ladder tread to bottom tread of ladder.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>Maximum distance from bottom tread of side ladder to top tread of sill step, 21 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(6)</Label><Text>End ladder treads shall, where construction of car permits, be spaced to coincide with treads of side ladders, a variation of two inches being allowed; where construction of car will not permit the application of a tread of end ladder to coincide with bottom tread of side ladder, the bottom tread of end ladder shall coincide with second tread from bottom of side ladder.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(7)</Label><Text>One tread of end ladders shall be located below the bottom of the end sill.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(8)</Label><Text>Iron or steel treads, minimum diameter 5/8 inch.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(9)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance of treads, two, preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>55</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>56</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Ladder Clearance</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>57</Label><Text>No part of car above end sills within 30 inches from side of car, except buffer block, brake shaft, brake wheel, brake step, running board, end platform, or uncoupling lever shall extend to within 12 inches of vertical plane parallel with end of car and passing through the inside face of knuckle, when closed with the coupler horn against the buffer block or end sill, and the cushioning device at full buff, and no other part of end of car or fixtures on same above end sill, other than exceptions herein noted, shall extend beyond the outer face of buffer block.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Roof Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>58</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>59</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>60</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>61</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Side Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>62</Label><Text>Sixteen. (Treads of side ladders are side handholds.)</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>63</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>64</Label><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Horizontal</Emphasis></Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Four near right end on each side of car.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Four near left end on each side of car, all side handholds shall be spaced not more than 19 inches apart and with the bottom handhold located not more than 21 inches from top tread of sill step. Such handholds shall meet ladder specifications and clearance of outer ends of handholds shall be not more than eight inches from end of car.</Text></Provision></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>65</Label><Text>Bottom side handholds shall have footguards or upward projections not less than two inches in height near inside ends. Side handholds shall be securely fastened with not less than 1/2-inch bolts with nuts outside (when possible) and riveted over, or with not less than 1/2-inch rivets.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Horizontal End Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>66</Label><Text>Eighteen or more (Nine on each end of car.)</Text><ContinuedSectionSubsection><Text>(Treads of end ladders are end handholds.)</Text></ContinuedSectionSubsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>67</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>68</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>One near each side of each end of car on face of end sill or sheathing over end sill, projecting outward or downward.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Three near each side of each end of car directly over the end sill handhold spaced not more than 19 inches apart to coincide with side handholds, with a variation of not more than two inches being allowed; except as provided above when tread of end ladder is an end handhold. Clearance of outer end of handholds shall be not more than eight inches from side of car.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>One not less than 36 inches in length located on each end near centre of car not less than 30 nor more than 60 inches above end platform.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>69</Label><Text>The end sill handholds near the right side of car shall have footguards or upward projections not less than two inches in height near inside end. End handholds shall be securely fastened with not less than 1/2-inch bolts with nuts outside and riveted over or with not less than 1/2-inch rivets.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Platforms</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>70</Label><Text>Two.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>71</Label><Text>Not less than eight inches wide and of such length as to substantially fill the space between the end ladders and the end handholds, but not less than 60 inches.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>72</Label><Text>One near the centre on each end of car not more than eight inches above centre sill.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>73</Label><Text>End platforms shall be supported by not less than three metal braces having a minimum cross-sectional area 3/8 inch by 1 1/2 inches or equivalent which shall be securely fastened to body of car with not less than 1/2-inch bolts or rivets. The outer edges of end platforms shall not extend to a point less than six inches from a vertical plane parallel with end of car and passing through the inside face of knuckle when closed with coupler horn against the buffer block or end sill and the cushioning device at full buff. End platforms shall be made of suitable running board material.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Uncoupling Levers</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>74</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>75</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>76</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Uncoupling Device and Brake Pipe Appurtenances</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>77</Label><Text>When a part of the uncoupling device and/or brake pipe is located parallel to the exposed ends of the centre sill, such part shall be installed in a manner providing at least two inches of clearance near the coupler of sufficient length to permit use as a handhold.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Exposed Top Sections of Centre Sills</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>78</Label><Text>The top of the exposed end of centre sill shall be coated with anti-skid paint.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Box or other House Cars Having Centre Sill or Underframe Cushioning Devices with Twelve Inches or Less Longitudinal Impact Absorbing Travel</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Hand Brakes</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>79</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>80</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>81</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>82</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Brake Step</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>83</Label><Text>If brake step is used, it shall not be less than 28 inches in length. Outside edge shall be not less than eight inches from face of car and not less four inches from a vertical plane parallel with end of car and passing through the inside face of knuckle when closed with coupler horn against buffer block or end sill and the cushioning device at full buff.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>84</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Running Boards</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>85</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>86</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>87</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>88</Label><Text>Running boards shall be continuous from end to end and not cut or hinged at any point; the length and width of running boards may, however, be made up of a number of pieces securely fastened to saddle blocks with screws, bolts, or rivets. The ends of longitudinal running board shall not be less than six nor more than 10 inches from a vertical plane parallel with end of car and passing through the inside face of knuckle when closed with coupler horn against buffer block or end sill, and the cushioning device at full buff; and if more than four inches from edge of roof of car, shall be securely supported their full width by substantial metal braces. Running board shall be securely fastened to car and be made of a material which provides the same as or a greater degree of safety than wood of 1 1/8-inch thickness. When made of material other than wood, the tread surface shall be of anti-skid design and constructed with sufficient open space to prevent the accumulation of snow and ice on the tread surface.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Sill Steps</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>89</Label><Text>Four.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>90</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum cross-sectional area 1/2 inch by 1 1/2 inches, or equivalent, of wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum length of tread, 10, preferably 12, inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Minimum clear depth, eight inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>91</Label><Text>One near each end each side of car, so that there shall be not more than 18 inches from end of car to centre of tread of sill step. Outside edge of tread of step shall be not more than four inches inside of face of side of car, preferably flush with side of car. Tread shall be not more than 24, preferably not more than 22, inches above the top of rail.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>92</Label><Text>Sill steps exceeding 21 inches in depth shall have an additional tread. Sill steps shall be securely fastened with not less than 1/2-inch bolts with nuts outside (when possible) and riveted over, or with not less than 1/2-inch rivets.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Ladders</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>93</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>94</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum clear length of tread</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>side ladders, 16 inches;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>end ladders, 14 inches.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Maximum spacing between ladder treads, 19 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Top ladder tread shall be located not less than 12 nor more than 18 inches from roof at eaves.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Spacing of side ladder treads shall be uniform within a limit of two inches from top ladder tread to bottom tread of ladder.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>Maximum distance from bottom tread of side ladder to top tread of sill step, 21 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(6)</Label><Text>End ladder treads shall, where construction of car permits, be spaced to coincide with treads of side ladders, a variation of two inches being allowed; where construction of car will not permit the application of a tread of end ladder to coincide with bottom tread of side ladder, the bottom tread of end ladder shall coincide with second tread from bottom of side ladder.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(7)</Label><Text>One tread of end ladders shall be located below the bottom of the end sill.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(8)</Label><Text>Iron or steel treads, minimum diameter 5/8 inch.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(9)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance of treads, two, preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>95</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>96</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Ladder Clearance</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>97</Label><Text>No part of car above end sills within 30 inches from side of car, except buffer block, brake shaft, brake wheel, brake step, running board, or uncoupling lever shall extend to within 12 inches of vertical plane parallel with end of car and passing through the inside face of knuckle, when closed with the coupler horn against the buffer block or end sill, and the cushioning device at full buff, and no other part of end of car or fixtures on same above end sill, other than exceptions herein noted, shall extend beyond the outer face of buffer block.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Roof Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>98</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>99</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>100</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>101</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Side Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>102</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars. (Tread of side ladder is a side handhold.)</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>103</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>104</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>105</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Horizontal End Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>106</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars. (Tread of end ladder is an end handhold.)</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>107</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>108</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>109</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Uncoupling Levers</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>110</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>111</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Box and other House Cars Built New or Rebuilt After October 1, 1966, or Under Construction Prior Thereto, Except Cars Equipped with Roof Hatches</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Hand Brakes</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.1</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Each car shall be equipped with an efficient vertical wheel hand brake which shall operate in harmony with the power brake thereon.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The hand brake may be of any efficient design, but must provide a total braking force applied to brake shoes not less than the total force applied to the brake shoes by the brake cylinders at 50 pounds per square inch.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The brake wheel may be deep or shallow, of malleable iron, wrought iron, steel, or other material of equivalent strength.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Overall diameter of brake wheel nominally 22 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Depth of brake wheel hub shall be 2 5/8 inches with square taper shaft fit, taper two inches in 12 inches with small end of taper fit 7/8 inch.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Brake wheel and drum shall be arranged so that both will revolve when applying and gradually releasing the hand brake. Hand brake shall be provided with means to prevent application of the brake by winding in a counterclockwise direction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>All chains shall be not less than 9/16 inch BBB coil chain.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(6)</Label><Text>All hand brake rods shall be not less than 3/4 inch diameter.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The hand brake shall be so located that it can be safely operated from horizontal end platform while car is in motion.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The brake shaft shall be located on end of car, to the left of and not less than 17 nor more than 22 inches from centre and not less than 26 nor more than 40 inches above top of end platform tread.</Text><Provision first-line-indent="0" list-item="yes" subsequent-line-indent="4"><Label>NOTE:</Label><Text>Cars with roofs 16 feet 10 inches or more above top of rail, brake shaft to be located to left of centre and not more than 24 inches from left side of car.</Text></Provision></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.4</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>There shall be not less than four inches clearance around rim of brake wheel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Brake wheel shall be held in position on brake shaft by a nut on a threaded extended end of brake shaft, said threaded portion shall be not less than  3/4 inch in diameter; said nut shall be secured by riveting over or by the use of a lock-nut or suitable cotter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Outside edge of brake wheel shall be not less than four inches from a vertical plane parallel with end of car and passing through the inside face of knuckle when closed with coupler horn against the buffer block or end sill.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Hand brake housing shall be securely fastened to car.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>Brake shaft shall be arranged with a square fit at its outer end to secure the hand brake wheel; said square fit shall be not less than 7/8 inch square. Square fit taper; nominally 2 in 12 inches (See Plate A in Schedule II).</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Sill Steps</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.5</Label><Text>Four.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.6</Label><Text>Minimum cross-sectional area 1/2 inch by 1 1/2  inches, or equivalent, of wrought iron, steel, or other material of equivalent strength. Minimum length of tread, 10, preferably 12, inches. Minimum clear depth, eight inches.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.7</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>One near each end of each side of car, so that there shall be no more than 18 inches from end of car to centre of tread of sill step.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Outside edge of tread of step shall be not more than four inches inside of face of side of car, preferably flush with side of car.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Tread shall be not more than 24, preferably not more than 22, inches above the top of rail.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.8</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Sill steps exceeding 21 inches in depth shall have an additional tread.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Sill steps shall be securely fastened with not less than 1/2-inch bolts with nuts outside (when possible) and riveted over, or with not less than 1/2-inch rivets.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Appliances Clearance</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.9</Label><Text>No part of car above end sills within 30 inches from side of car, except buffer block, brake shaft, brake wheel, end platform, horizontal end handholds or uncoupling lever shall extend to within 12 inches of a vertical plane parallel with end of car and passing through the inside face of knuckle, when closed with the coupler horn against the buffer block or end sill and cushioning device (if used) at full buff, and no other part of end of car or fixtures on same above end sills, other than exceptions herein noted shall extend beyond outer face of buffer block.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Side Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.10</Label><Text>Sixteen.</Text></Section><Section><Label>112.11</Label><Text>Minimum diameter, 5/8 inch, wrought iron, steel, or other material of equivalent strength. Minimum clear length 16 inches, preferably 24 inches. Minimum clearance, two, preferably 2 1/2 inches.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.12</Label><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Horizontal</Emphasis>:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Four near each end and on each side of car spaced not more than 19 inches apart and with the bottom handhold located not more than 21 inches from top tread of sill step, and top handhold shall coincide in height with top end handhold, a variation of two inches being allowed. Spacing of side handholds shall be uniform within a limit of two inches from top handhold to bottom handhold.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Clearance of outer ends of handholds shall be not more than eight inches from end of car.</Text></Provision></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.13</Label><Text>Side handholds shall be securely fastened with not less than  1/2-inch bolts with nuts outside (when possible) and riveted over, or with not less than 1/2-inch rivets. Each bottom handhold shall have foot guard or upward projection not less than two inches in height near inside end.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.14</Label><Text>Sixteen.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.15</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter, 5/8 inch, wrought iron, steel, or other material of equivalent strength.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clear length, 16 inches, preferably 24 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance, two inches, preferably 2 i/2, inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.16</Label><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Horizontal</Emphasis>: Four near each side and on each end of car spaced not more than 19 inches apart and with the bottom handhold located not more than 21 inches from top tread of sill step, and top handhold shall coincide in height with end platform handholds, a variation of two inches being allowed. Clearance of outer ends of handholds shall be not more than eight inches from side of car.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.17</Label><Text>End handholds shall be securely fastened with not less than 1/2-inch bolts with nuts outside (when possible) and riveted over, or with not less than 1/2-inch rivets. Each bottom handhold shall have foot guard or upward projection not less than two inches in height near inside end.</Text><Provision first-line-indent="0" list-item="yes" subsequent-line-indent="4"><Label>NOTE:</Label><Text>Not required on cars with roofs 16 feet 10 inches or more above top of rail when vertical and horizontal end handholds as specified in note following section 112.25 of this Schedule are applied.</Text></Provision></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Platforms</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.18</Label><Text>Two.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.19</Label><Text>Width not less than eight inches, length not less that 60 inches.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.20</Label><Text>One centered on each end of car not more than eight inches above top of centre sill.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.21</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Each end platform shall be securely supported by not less than three metal braces having a minimum cross sectional area of 3/8 inch by 1 1/2 inches or equivalent, which shall be securely fastened to body of car with not less than 1/2-inch bolts or rivets.</Text><Provision first-line-indent="0" list-item="yes" subsequent-line-indent="4"><Label>NOTE:</Label><Text>Cars with roofs 16 feet 10 inches or more above top of rail will have end platforms not less than 10 inches in width, length, full width of car and supported by not less than four metal braces.</Text></Provision></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Where conventional draft gear or cushioning device having longitudinal travel less than six inches is used the outside edge of each end platform shall be not less than 12 inches from a vertical plane parallel with end of car and passing through the inside face of knuckle when closed with coupler horn against buffer block. Where cushioning device having longitudinal travel six inches or more is used, the outside edge of each end platform shall be not less than six inches from a vertical plane parallel with end of car and passing through the inside face of knuckle when closed with end sill and cushioning device at full buff. End platform shall be made of wood or material that provides the same or a greater degree of safety than wood, of 1 1/8-inch thickness. When made of material other than wood, the tread surface shall be of anti-skid design and constructed with sufficient open space to permit the elimination of snow and ice from the tread surface.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Horizontal End Platform Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.22</Label><Text>Two.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.23</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter, 5/8 inch, wrought iron, steel, or other material of equivalent strength.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance, two, preferably 2 1/2 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Minimum clear length 60 inches. When security of attachment requires, an extra supporting leg may be applied near centre of clear length.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.24</Label><Text>One on each end of car above end platform. Outer legs shall be not more than six inches from inner legs of top end handholds. Height above tread of end platform: not less than 48 nor more than 60 inches.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.25</Label><Text>End platform handholds shall be securely fastened with not less than 1/2-inch bolts with nuts outside (when possible) and riveted over, or with not less than 1/2-inch rivets.</Text><Provision first-line-indent="0" list-item="yes" subsequent-line-indent="4"><Label>NOTE:</Label><Text>Cars with roofs 16 feet 10 inches or more above top of rail will have horizontal end platform handholds extending across each end of car with clearance at each end of not more than four inches from side of car supported by an extra leg near centre of handholds, and with vertical and horizontal end handholds as follows:</Text></Provision><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Vertical End Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-6-5" language-align="yes"><Text>Four.</Text></Provision><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-5-4" language-align="yes"><Text>Minimum diameter 5/8 inch, wrought iron, steel, or other material of equivalent strength. Minimum clearance two, preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Provision><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-5-4" language-align="yes"><Text>One on each side of each end of car, not more than four inches from side of car, extending downward from end of horizontal end platform handhold to within eight inches above tread of end platform. One continuous handhold with two right angle handholds, may take the place of two specified vertical end handholds and one horizontal end platform handhold, provided the dimensions and location coincide, and extra legs at points of angle and centre are provided and securely fastened to car.</Text></Provision><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Horizontal End Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-6-5" language-align="yes"><Text>Four.</Text></Provision><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-5-4" language-align="yes"><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter 5/8 inch, wrought iron, steel, or other material of equivalent strength.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-5-4" language-align="yes"><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clear length, 16 inches, preferably 24 inches.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-5-4" language-align="yes"><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Notwithstanding subsection 2, a handhold 14 inches in length may be used where it is impossible to use one 16 inches in length.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-5-4" language-align="yes"><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance two, preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Provision><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-5-4" language-align="yes"><Text>One near each side of each end of car on outer edge of end platform projecting downward with clearance of outer end not more than 16 inches from side of car.</Text></Provision><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-5-4" language-align="yes"><Text>Horizontal end handholds shall be securely fastened with not less than 1/2-inch bolts with nuts outside (when possible) and riveted over, or with not less than 1/2-inch rivets.</Text></Provision></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Uncoupling Levers</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.26</Label><Text>Two.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.27</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Handles of uncoupling levers except those shown on Plate B of Schedule II or of similar design, shall be not more than six inches from sides of car.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Uncoupling levers of design shown on Plate B of Schedule II and of similar designs shall conform to the following prescribed limits:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>handles shall be not more than 12, preferably nine, inches from sides of cars;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>centre lift arms shall be not less than seven inches long;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>centre of eye at end of centre lift arm shall be not more than  3 1/2 inches beyond centre of eye of uncoupling pin of coupler when horn of coupler is against the buffer block or end sill (See Plate B of Schedule II);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>ends of handles shall extend not less than four inches below bottom of end sill or shall be so constructed as to give a minimum clearance of two inches around handle (See Plate B of Schedule II);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>minimum drop of handles shall be 12 inches, maximum, 15 inches overall (See Plate B of Schedule II);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>handles of uncoupling levers of the rocking or push down type shall be not less than 18 inches from top of rail when lock block has released knuckle, and a suitable stop shall be provided to prevent inside arm from flying up in case of breakage.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.28</Label><Text>One on each end of car. When single lever is used, it shall be placed on left side of end of car.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Painting and Stencilling</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.29</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>This section applies to cars with roofs 16 feet 10 inches or more above top of rail only.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>That portion of each end of car more than 15 feet above top of rail shall be painted with contrasting reflectorized paint and shall bear the words “NO RUNNING BOARD” to the left of centre and “EXCESS HEIGHT CAR” to the right of centre. Lettering to be not less than three inches high. On each side sill near end corner there shall be painted a yellow rectangular area with a 3/4-inch black border containing the words “THIS CAR EXCESS HEIGHT — NO RUNNING BOARD”. Lettering to be not less than 1 1/2 inches high. When a car is equipped with centre sill or underframe cushioning device having more than 12 inches longitudinal impact absorbing travel, and a part of the uncoupling device and/or brake pipe is located parallel to the exposed end of the centre sill, such part shall provide at least two inches of clearance near the coupler of sufficient length to permit use as a handhold during air hose coupling operation and the top of exposed ends of sliding centre sill shall be coated with anti-skid paint.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Existing Box and other House Cars Without Roof Hatches</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.30</Label><Text>Box and other house cars built on or before October 1, 1966 or under construction prior thereto shall be deemed equipped as nearly as possible within the intent of these requirements when</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the running board, roof handholds over side and end ladders at “A” end of car and ladder treads above the fourth tread from bottom of side and end ladder at “A” end are removed; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>one horizontal end platform handhold is applied on each end of car as specified in this section except the right hand end shall be not more than eight inches from side of car, or where car end contour makes impractical the use of a single continuous end handhold, there is applied the equivalent consisting of two handholds, the centre handhold to be a minimum of 30 inches in clear length and the handhold to the right to be a minimum of 19 inches in clear length and to extend to within eight inches of the right side of the car, such handholds to be not more than 12 inches apart; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>with hand brake operated near roof of car: a brake step shall be provided as specified in section 5 of this Schedule and lettering 1 1/2 inches high shall be painted on a yellow background on side sill near “B” end of car with a 3/4-inch black border containing the words “KEEP OFF ROOF — NO RUNNING BOARD”, or with hand brake operated from approximate level of top of end sill: roof handholds and side and end ladder treads above the fourth tread from the bottom of ladders at “B” end of car shall be removed and a brake step as specified by section 5 of this Schedule shall be used with top of tread surface being level with or not more than four inches below adjacent end handhold. Paragraph (b) shall not apply to cars equipped with end platforms and end platform handholds.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Box and Other House Cars with Roof Hatches</TitleText><TitleText>(Same as Specified for Box and other House Cars Without Roof Hatches Except for the Provisions of Sections 112.31 to 112.43 of this Schedule)</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Running Boards</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.31</Label><Text>Same as specified in sections 7 to 10 of this Schedule except: the end of longitudinal running board shall be not less than six inches from a vertical plane parallel with end of car and passing through the inside face of knuckle when closed with coupler horn against buffer block or end sill.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Ladders</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.32</Label><Text>Two.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.33</Label><Text>Minimum clear length of tread 16 inches; maximum spacing between treads 19 inches.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.34</Label><Text>One on each end of car not more than eight inches from left hand side.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.35</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 18 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Roof Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.36</Label><Text>Two, one  over each ladder.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.37</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 21 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.38</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 22 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.39</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 23 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Handholds</TitleText><TitleText><Emphasis style="regular">(Treads of end ladders are end handholds)</Emphasis></TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.40</Label><Text>Sixteen.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.41</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter, 5/8 inch, wrought iron, steel, or other material of equivalent strength.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clear length, 16 inches, preferably, 24 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance, two, preferably 21/2, inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.42</Label><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Horizontal</Emphasis>: Four near each side and on each end of car spaced not more than 19 inches apart and with the bottom handhold located not more than  21 inches from top tread of sill step, and top handhold shall coincide in height with end platform handholds, a variation of two inches being allowed. Clearance of outer ends of handholds shall be not more than eight inches from side of car.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.43</Label><Text>End handholds shall be securely fastened with not less than  1/2-inch bolts with nuts outside (when possible) and riveted over, or with not less than 1/2-inch rivets. Each bottom handhold shall have foot guard or upward projection not less than two inches in height near inside end.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Existing Box and other House Cars with Roof Hatches</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>112.44</Label><Text>Box and other house cars with roof hatches built on or before October 1, 1966, or under construction prior thereto, shall be deemed equipped as nearly as possible within the intent of these requirements when equipped with the same complement of safety appliances, depending upon type, as is specified in sections 112.31 to 112.43, for box and other house cars with roof hatches except</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the side ladder treads above the fourth tread from bottom of side ladder near “A” end of car and roof handhold over the side ladder near “A” end shall be removed;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>one end platform handhold shall be provided on each end of car as specified in paragraph 112.30 (b) of this Schedule and when hand brake is operated near roof of car a brake step shall be provided as specified by paragraph 112.30(c) of this Schedule or when hand brake is operated from approximate level of top of end sill the roof handhold over side ladder near “B” end and treads above the fourth tread from bottom of side ladder near “B” end shall be removed and a brake step as specified in paragraph 112.30(c) of this Schedule shall be used with top of tread surface level with or not more than four inches below adjacent end handhold.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Hopper Cars and High-Side Gondolas with Fixed Ends</TitleText><TitleText>(Cars with Sides more than 36 Inches above the Floor are High-side Cars)</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Hand Brakes</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>113</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 1 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>114</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 2 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>115</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Each hand brake shall be so located that it can be safely operated while car is in motion.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The brake shaft shall be located on end of car to the left of, and not more than 22 inches from centre.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>116</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 4 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Brake Step</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>117</Label><Text>Same as specified in sections 5 and 6 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText><FootnoteRef idref="footnote1_e">1</FootnoteRef>Sill Steps</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>118</Label><Text>Same as in sections 11, 12, 13 and 14 of this Schedule.</Text><Footnote id="footnote1_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>1</Label><Text><Emphasis style="regular">End sill steps, as specified for box and other house cars, are required for box and other house cars only.</Emphasis></Text></Footnote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Ladders</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>119</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 15 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>120</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 16, except that top ladder tread shall be located not more than four inches from top of car.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>121</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 17 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>122</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 18 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Side Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>123</Label><Text>Same as specified in sections 24, 25, 26 and 27 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Horizontal End Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>124</Label><Text>Same as specified in sections 28, 29, 30 and 31 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Vertical End Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>125</Label><Text>Same as specified in sections 32, 33, 34 and 35 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Uncoupling Levers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>126</Label><Text>Same as specified in sections 36, 37 and 38 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Ladder Clearance</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>127</Label><Text>No part of car above end sills within 30 inches from side of car except buffer block, brake shaft, brake wheel, brake step or uncoupling lever shall extend to within 12 inches of a vertical plane parallel with end of car and passing through the inside face of knuckle when closed with coupler horn against the buffer block or end sill, and no other part of end of car or fixtures on same above end sills, other than exceptions herein noted, shall extend beyond the outer face of buffer block.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Drop-end High-side Gondola Cars</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Hand Brakes</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>128</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 1 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>129</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 2 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>130</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Each hand brake shall be so located that it can be safely operated while car is in motion.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The brake shaft shall be located on end of car to the left of centre.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>131</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 4 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText><FootnoteRef idref="footnote1_e">1</FootnoteRef>Sill Steps</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>132</Label><Text>Same as specified in sections 11, 12, 13 and 14 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Ladders</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>133</Label><Text>Two.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>134</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 16 of this Schedule, except that top ladder tread shall be located not more than four inches from top of car.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>135</Label><Text>One on each side, not more than eight inches from right end of car, measured from inside edge of ladder-stile or clearance of ladder treads to corner of car.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>136</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 18 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Side Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>137</Label><Text>Same as specified in sections 24, 25, 26 and 27 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Horizontal End Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>138</Label><Text>Four.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>139</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 29 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>140</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>One near each side of each end of car on face of end sill.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Clearance of outer end of handhold shall be not more than 16 inches from side of car.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>141</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 31 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Uncoupling Levers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>142</Label><Text>Same as specified in sections 36, 37 and 38 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Ladder Clearance</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>143</Label><Text>No part of car above end sills within 30 inches from side of car, except buffer block, brake shaft, brake wheel or uncoupling lever shall extend to within 12 inches of a vertical plane parallel with end of car and passing through the inside face of knuckle when closed with coupler horn against the buffer block, or end sill, and no other part of end of car or fixtures on same above end sills, other than exceptions herein noted, shall extend beyond the outer face of buffer block.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Fixed-End, Low-Side Gondola and Low-Side Hopper Cars</TitleText><TitleText>(Cars with Sides 36 Inches or less above the Floor Are Low-side Cars)</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Hand Brakes</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>144</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 1 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>145</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 2 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>146</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Each hand brake shall be so located that it can be safely operated while car is in motion.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The brake shaft shall be located on end of car, to the left of and not more than 22 inches from centre.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>147</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 4 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Brake Step</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>148</Label><Text>Same as specified in sections 5 and 6 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText><FootnoteRef idref="footnote1_e">1</FootnoteRef>Sill Steps</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>149</Label><Text>Same as specified in sections 11, 12, 13 and 14 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Side Handhols</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>150</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 24 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>151</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 25 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>152</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Horizontal</Emphasis>: one near each end on each side of car, not less than 24 nor more than 30 inches above centre line of coupler if car construction will permit but handhold shall not project above top of side.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Clearance of outer end of handhold shall be not more than eight inches from end of car.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>153</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 27 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Horizontal End Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>154</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 28 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>155</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 29 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>156</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>One near each side on each end of car not less than 24 nor more than 30 inches above centre line of coupler, if car construction will permit. Clearance of outer end of handhold shall be not more than eight inches from side of car.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>One near each side of each end of car on face of end sill, projecting outward or downward. Clearance of outer end of handhold shall be not more than 16 inches from side of car.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>157</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 31 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Uncoupling Levers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>158</Label><Text>Same as specified in sections 36, 37 and 38 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Ladder Clearance</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>159</Label><Text>No part of car above end sills within 30 inches from side of car, except buffer block, brake shaft, brake step, brake wheel, or uncoupling lever shall extend to within 12 inches of a vertical plane parallel with end of car and passing through the inside face of knuckle when closed with coupler horn against the buffer block or end sill, and no other part of end of car or fixtures on same above end sills, other than exceptions herein noted, shall extend beyond the outer face of buffer block.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Drop-end Low-side Gondola Cars</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Hand Brakes</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>160</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 1 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>161</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 2 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>162</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Each hand brake shall be so located that it can be safely operated while car is in motion.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The brake shaft shall be located on end of car to the left of centre.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>163</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 4 of this Schedule, except that top brake shaft support may be omitted.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText><FootnoteRef idref="footnote1_e">1</FootnoteRef>Sill Steps</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>164</Label><Text>Same as specified in sections 11, 12, 13 and 14 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Side Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>165</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 24 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>166</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 25 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>167</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Horizontal</Emphasis>: one near each end on each side of car, not less than  24 nor more than 30 inches above centre line of coupler, if car construction will permit, but handhold shall not project above top of side.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Clearance of outer end of handhold shall be not more than eight inches from end of car.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>168</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 27 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>169</Label><Text>Four.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>170</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 29 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>171</Label><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Horizontal</Emphasis>: one near each side of each end of car on face of end sill. Clearance of outer end of handhold shall be not more than 16 inches from side of car.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>172</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 31 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Uncoupling Levers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>173</Label><Text>Same as specified in sections 36, 37 and 38 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Ladder Clearance</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>174</Label><Text>No part of car above end sills within 30 inches from side of car, except buffer block, brake shaft, brake wheel or uncoupling lever shall extend to within 12 inches of a vertical plane parallel with end of car and passing through the inside face of knuckle when closed with coupler horn against the buffer block or end sill, and no other part of end of car or fixtures on same above end sills, other than exceptions herein noted, shall extend beyond the outer face of buffer block.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Flat Cars</TitleText><TitleText>(Cars with Sides 12 Inches or less above the Floor may be Equipped the same as Flat Cars)</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Hand Brakes</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>175</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 1 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>176</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 2 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>177</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Each hand brake shall be so located that it can be safely operated while car is in motion.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The brake shaft shall be located on the end of car to the left of centre, or on side of car not more than 36 inches from right-hand end thereof.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>178</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 4 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText><FootnoteRef idref="footnote1_e">1</FootnoteRef>Sill Steps</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>179</Label><Text>Same as specified in sections 11, 12, 13 and 14 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Side Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>180</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 24 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>181</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 25 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>182</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Horizontal</Emphasis>: one on face of each side sill near each end.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Clearance of outer end of handhold shall be not more than 12 inches from end of car.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>183</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 27 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>184</Label><Text>Four.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>185</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 29 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>186</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Horizontal</Emphasis>: one near each side of each end of car on face of end sill.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Clearance of outer end of handhold shall be not more than 16 inches from side of car.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>187</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 31 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Uncoupling Levers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>188</Label><Text>Same as specified in sections 36, 37 and 38 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Tank Cars with Side Platforms</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Hand Brakes</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>189</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 1 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>190</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 2 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>191</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Each hand brake shall be so located that it can be safely operated while car is in motion.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The brake shaft shall be located on end of car to the left of centre.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>192</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 4 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText><FootnoteRef idref="footnote1_e">1</FootnoteRef>Sill Steps</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>193</Label><Text>Same as specified in sections 11, 12, 13 and 14 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Side Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>194</Label><Text>Four or more.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>195</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 25 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>196</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Horizontal</Emphasis>: one on face of each side sill near each end.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Clearance of outer end of handhold shall not be more than 12 inches from end of car.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>If side safety railings are attached to tank or tank bands, four additional vertical handholds shall be applied, one as nearly as possible over each sill step and securely fastened to tank or tank band.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>197</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 27 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>198</Label><Text>Four.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>199</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 29 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>200</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Horizontal</Emphasis>: one near each side of each end of car on face of end sill.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Clearance of outer end of handhold shall be not more than 16 inches from side of car.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>201</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 31 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Tank Head Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>202</Label><Text>Two. (Not required if safety railing runs around ends of tank.)</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>203</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter 5/8 inch, wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance two, preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Clear length of handholds shall extend to within six inches of outer diameter of tank at point of application.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>204</Label><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Horizontal</Emphasis>: one across each head of tank not less than 30 nor more than 60 inches above platform.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>205</Label><Text>Tank head handholds shall be securely fastened.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Safety Railings</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>206</Label><Text>Safety railing shall be</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>one continuous safety railing running around sides and ends of tank, securely fastened to tank or tank bands at ends and sides of tank; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>two running full length of tank at sides of car supported by posts.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>207</Label><Text>Not less than 3/4 inch, iron.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>208</Label><Text>Safety railing shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>run full length of tank at either side supported by posts; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>be securely fastened to tank or tank bands, not less than 30 nor more than 60 inches above platform.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>209</Label><Text>Safety railings shall be securely fastened to tank body, tank bands or posts.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Uncoupling Levers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>210</Label><Text>Same as specified in sections 36, 37 and 38 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Ladder Clearance</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>211</Label><Text>No part of car above end sills within 30 inches from side of car, except buffer block, brake shaft, brake shaft brackets, brake wheel or uncoupling lever shall extend to within 12 inches of a vertical plane parallel with end of car and passing through the inside face of knuckle when closed with coupler horn against the buffer block or end sill, and no other part of end of car or fixtures on same above end sills, other than exceptions herein noted, shall extend beyond the outer face of buffer block.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Tank Cars Without Side Sills and Tank Cars with Short Side Sills and End Platforms</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Hand Brakes</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>212</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 1 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>213</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 2 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>214</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Each hand brake shall be so located that it can be safely operated while car is in motion.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The brake shaft shall be located on end of car to the left of centre.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>215</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 4 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Running Boards</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>216</Label><Text>There shall be</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>one continuous running board around sides and ends; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>two running boards running full length of tank, one on each side.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>217</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum width on sides, 10 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum width on ends, six inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>218</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Continuous around sides and ends of cars.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>On tank cars having end platforms extending to bolsters, running boards shall extend from centre to centre of bolsters, one on each side.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>219</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>If side running boards are applied below centre of tank, outside edge of running boards shall extend not less than seven inches beyond bulge of tank.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The running boards at ends of car shall be not less than six inches from a point vertically above the inside face of knuckle when closed with coupler horn against the buffer block, end sill or back stop.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Running boards shall be securely fastened to tank or tank bands.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Running boards may be of a material other than wood if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the material and design is accepted by the A.A.R. and approved by the Commission; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the construction and installation is in accordance with A.A.R. requirements and acceptable to the Commission.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText><FootnoteRef idref="footnote1_e">1</FootnoteRef>Sill Steps</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>220</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 11 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>221</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 12 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>222</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>One near each end on each side under side handhold.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Outside edge of tread of step shall be not more than four inches inside of face of side of car, preferably flush with side of car.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Tread shall be not more than 24, preferably not more than 22, inches above the top of rail.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>223</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 14 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Ladders</TitleText><TitleText><Emphasis style="regular">(If running boards are so located as to  make ladders necessary)</Emphasis></TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>224</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Two on cars with continuous running boards.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Four on cars with side running boards.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>225</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum clear length of tread, 10 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Maximum spacing of treads, 19 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Hardwood treads, minimum dimensions, 1 1/2 by two inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Wrought iron or steel treads, minimum diameter, 5/8 inch.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance, two, preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>226</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>On cars with continuous running boards one at right end of each side.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>On cars with side running boards, one at each end of each running board.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>227</Label><Text>Ladders shall be securely fastened with not less than 1/2-inch bolts or rivets.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Side Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>228</Label><Text>Four or more.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>229</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 25 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>230</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>There shall be, where the side handholds are horizontal,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>one on face of each side sill near each end on tank cars with short side sills; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>one attached to top of running board projecting outward above sill steps or ladders on tank cars without side sills.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Clearance of outer end of handhold shall be not more than 12 inches from end of car.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>If side safety railings are attached to tank or tank bands, four additional vertical handholds shall be applied, one as nearly as possible over each sill step and securely fastened to tank or tank band.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>231</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 27 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>232</Label><Text>Four.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>233</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 29 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>234</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Horizontal</Emphasis>: one near each side of each end of car on face of end sill.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Clearance of outer end of handhold shall be not more than 16 inches from side of car.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>235</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 31 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Tank Head Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>236</Label><Text>Two (not required if safety railing runs around ends of tank).</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>237</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter 5/8 inch, wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance two, preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>238</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Horizontal</Emphasis>: one across each head of tank not less than 30 nor more than 60 inches above platform or running board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Clear length of handholds shall extend to within six inches of outer diameter of tank at point of application.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>239</Label><Text>Tank head handholds shall be securely fastened.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Safety Railing</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>240</Label><Text>There shall be</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>one safety railing running around sides and ends of tank; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>two safety railings running full length of tank.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>241</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter, 7/8 inch, wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance, 2 1/2 inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>242</Label><Text>Running full length of tank, not less than 30 nor more than  60 inches above platform or running board.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>243</Label><Text>Safety railings shall be securely fastened to tank or tank bands and secured against end shifting.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Uncoupling Levers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>244</Label><Text>Same as specified in sections 36, 37 and 38 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Ladder Clearance</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>245</Label><Text>No part of car above end sills within 30 inches from side of car, except buffer block, brake shaft, brake shaft brackets, brake wheel, running boards or uncoupling lever shall extend to within 12 inches of a vertical plane parallel with end of car and passing through the inside face of knuckle when closed with coupler horn against the buffer block or end sill, and no other part of end of car or fixtures on same, above end sills, other than exceptions herein noted, shall extend beyond the outer face of buffer block.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Tank Cars Without Underframes</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Hand Brakes</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>246</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>247</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>248</Label><Text>Each hand brake shall be so located that it can be safely operated while car is in motion. The hand brake shall be located on end of car to the left of centre.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>249</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Platforms</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>250</Label><Text>Two.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>251</Label><Text>Minimum width, 10 inches. Minimum thickness, wood platform, 1 3/4 inches. Platforms constructed of metal shall be of open grill anti-skid construction of a design approved by the Association of American Railroads and acceptable to the Canadian Transport Commission.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>252</Label><Text>One on each end extending across car a distance equal to or greater than any other portion of car. Outside edge of end platform shall extend not less than seven inches beyond bulge of tank head and safety railing.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>253</Label><Text>End platforms shall be securely fastened to the draft sills and be supported to prevent sagging.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText><FootnoteRef idref="footnote1_e">1</FootnoteRef>Sill Steps</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>254</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Platform Safety Railing</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>255</Label><Text>Two.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>256</Label><Text>Minimum of 7/8 inch diameter, wrought iron or steel, or one and 1 1/4 inch pipe. Minimum clearance, 2 1/2 inches.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>257</Label><Text>One safety railing at each  end of car shall extend horizontally across car not less than 36 inches nor more than 54 inches above end platform, and shall extend in a vertical direction down to end platform within three inches of the end of the platform. The safety railing shall be located not more than six inches from the inside edge of the platform.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>258</Label><Text>Safety railings shall be supported at the centre, and be securely attached to end platforms.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Side Railing</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>259</Label><Text>Two.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>260. 1</Label><Text>1/4-inch iron or steel pipe. Minimum clearance, 2 1/2 inches.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>261</Label><Text>One on each side of car, extending from end platform to end platform at a distance of not less than 51 inches from centre line of car, except that where break in side railing is necessary for side ladder or operating cabinet, the side railing shall be securely attached to such ladder and/or cabinet.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>262</Label><Text>Side railings shall be securely attached to end platforms, and be supported from the car at intervals not exceeding 10 feet.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Horizontal Side Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>263</Label><Text>Four.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>264</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>265</Label><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Horizontal</Emphasis>: One over each sill step on face of end platform, projecting downward or outward. Clearance of outer end of handhold shall be not more than 12 inches from end of car.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>266</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Vertical Side Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>267</Label><Text>Vertical portion of end platform safety railings shall be considered as side vertical handholds.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>268</Label><Text>Four.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>269</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>270</Label><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Horizontal</Emphasis>: One near each side of each end of car on face of end sill, projecting downward or outward. Clearance of outer end of handhold shall be not more than 16 inches from side of car.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>271</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Uncoupling Levers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>272</Label><Text>Same as specified for box and other house cars.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Ladder Clearance</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>273</Label><Text>No part of car above end sills within 30 inches from side of car, except buffer block, brake shaft, brake shaft brackets, brake wheel, running boards or uncoupling lever shall extend to within 12 inches of a vertical plane parallel with end of car and passing through the inside face of knuckle when closed with coupler horn against the buffer block or end sill, and no other part of end  of car or fixtures on same, above end sills, other than exceptions herein noted, shall extend beyond the outer face of the buffer block.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><Label>Operating Platform</Label></Heading><Section><Label /><Text /><Provision first-line-indent="0" list-item="yes" subsequent-line-indent="4"><Label>NOTE:</Label><Text>An operating platform is not required if all fittings used in the loading or unloading of the tank car are accessible from ground or end platform; but when an operating platform is required, sections 274 to 277 of this schedule apply.</Text></Provision></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>274</Label><Text>One.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>275</Label><Text>Minimum width, seven inches. Minimum thickness, wood platform,  1 3/4 inches. Platforms constructed of metal shall be of open grill anti-skid construction of a design approved by the Association of American Railroads and acceptable to the Canadian Transport Commission.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>276</Label><Text>Operating platform shall be so located that it will provide access to all operating fittings.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>277</Label><Text>The operating platform shall be properly supported to prevent sagging and be securely attached to the tank.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><Label>Operating Platform Safety Railing</Label></Heading><Section><Label /><Text /><Provision first-line-indent="0" list-item="yes" subsequent-line-indent="4"><Label>NOTE:</Label><Text>An operating platform is not required if all fittings used in the loading or unloading of the tank car are accessible from ground or end platform; but when an operating platform is required, sections 278 to 281 of this Schedule apply.</Text></Provision></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>278</Label><Text>One.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>279</Label><Text>1 1/4-inch iron or steel pipe.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>280</Label><Text>The safety railing shall enclose the operating platform, manway and fittings used in the loading and unloading of the tank. Railing shall be open only at the ladders where it shall extend in a vertical direction down to, and be securely attached to the platform. Maximum width of opening, 24 inches.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>281</Label><Text>The safety railing shall be securely attached to four stanchions or corner posts, which shall be securely attached to the tank or operating platform.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><Label>Operating Platform Ladders</Label></Heading><Section><Label /><Text /><Provision first-line-indent="0" list-item="yes" subsequent-line-indent="4"><Label>NOTE:</Label><Text>An operating platform is not required if all fittings used in the loading or unloading of the tank car are accessible from ground or end platform; but when an operating platform is required, sections 282 to 285 of this Schedule apply.</Text></Provision></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>282</Label><Text>Two.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>283</Label><Text>Ladder stiles, 3/8 inch by two inches or equivalent, wrought iron or steel. 1 1/4-inch extra heavy pipe will be considered equivalent. Ladder treads, minimum diameter 5/8 inch, wrought iron or steel. Minimum clear length of treads, 14 inches. Maximum spacing of treads, 19 inches. Minimum clearance of treads and ladder stiles, two, preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>284</Label><Text>Ladders to be located on sides of car at centre extending downward from operating platform to a point where the bottom treads shall be not more than 24 inches, preferably not more than 22 inches above top of rail.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>285</Label><Text>The ladders shall be securely fastened to the operating platform. The lower portions of the ladders shall be braced in such a manner as to prevent any movement.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Manner of Application of Safety Appliances on Tank Cars Covered With Jackets</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>286</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>On tanks covered with jackets, metal pads shall be securely attached to the shell proper, to which brackets shall be fastened for securing the safety appliances attached to the tanks; or the safety appliances (with the exception of the operating platform brackets) may be secured to the jackets reinforced with metal pads at the point of attachment, which pads shall extend at least two inches from the centre line of rivet holes. The operating platform brackets may be secured to the jacket when reinforced with suitable bands.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>When the safety appliances are attached to the jacket covering of the tank, the jacket shall be tightened so that there will be no danger of it slipping around.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Tank Cars Without End Sills</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Hand Brakes</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>287</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 1 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>288</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 2 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>289</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Each hand brake shall be so located that it can be safely operated while car is in motion.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The brake shaft shall be located on end of car to the left of centre.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>290</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 4 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Brake Step</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>291</Label><Text>Same as specified in sections 5 and 6 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Running Boards</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>292</Label><Text>One.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>293</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum width on sides, 10 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum width on ends, six inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>294</Label><Text>Continuous around sides and ends of tank.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>295</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>If running boards are applied below centre of tank, outside edge of running board shall extend not less than seven inches beyond bulge of tank.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Running boards at ends of car shall be not less than six inches from a point vertically above the inside face of knuckle when closed with coupler horn against the buffer block, end sill or back stop.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Running boards shall be securely fastened to tank or tank bands.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Running boards may be of a material other than wood if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the material and design are accepted by the American Association of Railroads and approved by the Canadian Transport Commission; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the construction and installation are in accordance with American Association of Railroads requirements and acceptable to the Canadian Transport Commission.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Sill Steps</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>296</Label><Text>Four (if tank has high running boards, making ladders necessary, sill steps must meet ladder requirements).</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>297</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 12 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>298</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>One near each end on each side, flush with outside edge of running board as near end of car as practicable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Tread not more than 24, preferably not more than 22, inches above the top of rail.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>299</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Steps exceeding 18 inches in depth shall have an additional tread and be laterally braced.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Sill steps shall be securely fastened with not less than 1/2-inch bolts with nuts outside (when possible) and riveted over, or with 1/2-inch rivets.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Side Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>300</Label><Text>Four or more.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>301</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 25 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>302</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Horizontal</Emphasis>: One near each end on each side of car over sill step, on running board, not more than two inches back from outside edge of running board, projecting downward or outward.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Where such side handholds are more than 18 inches from end of car, an additional handhold must be placed near each end on each side not more than 30 inches above centre line of coupler.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Clearance of outer end of handhold shall be not more than 12 inches from end of car.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>If safety railings are on tank, four additional vertical handholds shall be applied, one over each sill step on tank.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>303</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 27 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>304</Label><Text>Four.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>305</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 29 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>306</Label><Text>End handholds shall be located</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>where horizontal, one near each side on each end of car on running board, not more than two inches back from edge of running board projecting downward or outward; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>on end of tank not more than 30 inches above centre line of coupler.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>307</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 31 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Safety Railings</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>308</Label><Text>One.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>309</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter 7/8 inch, wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance 2 1/2 inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>310</Label><Text>Safety railings shall be continuous around sides and ends of car, not less than 30 nor more than 60 inches above running board.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>311</Label><Text>Safety railings shall be securely fastened to tank or tank bands, and secured against end shifting.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Uncoupling Levers</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>312</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 36 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>313</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 37 of this Schedule, except that minimum length of uncoupling lever shall be 42 inches, measured from centre line of end of car to handle of lever.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>314</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 38 of this Schedule, except that uncoupling lever shall be not more than 30 inches above centre line of coupler.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Ladder Clearance</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>315</Label><Text>No part of car above buffer block within 30 inches from side of car, except brake shaft, brake shaft brackets, brake wheel or uncoupling lever shall extend to within 12 inches of a vertical plane parallel with end of car and passing through the inside face of knuckle when closed with coupler horn against the buffer block or back stop, and no other part of end of car or fixtures on same, above buffer block, other than exceptions herein noted, shall extend beyond the face of buffer block.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Caboose Cars with Platforms</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Hand Brakes</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>316</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Each caboose car shall be equipped with an efficient hand brake which shall operate in harmony with the power brake thereon.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The hand brake may be of any efficient design, but shall provide the same degree of safety as the design shown on Plate A of Schedule II.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>317</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 2 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>318</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Each hand brake shall be so located that it can be safely operated while car is in motion.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The brake shaft on caboose cars with platforms shall be located on platform to the left of centre.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>319</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 4 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Running Boards</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>320</Label><Text>One longitudinal running board.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>321</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 8 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>322</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Full length of car, centre of roof (on caboose cars with cupolas, longitudinal running board shall extend from cupola to ends of roof).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Outside metal roof cars shall have latitudinal extensions leading to ladder locations.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>323</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 10 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Ladders</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>324</Label><Text>Two.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>325</Label><Text>None specified.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>326</Label><Text>One on each end.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>327</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 18 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Roof Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>328</Label><Text>One over each ladder, except that where stiles of ladders extend 12 inches or more above roof, no other roof handholds are required.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>329</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 21 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>330</Label><Text>On roof of caboose, in line with and running parallel to treads of ladder, not less than eight nor more than 15 inches from edge of roof.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>331</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 23 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Cupola Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>332</Label><Text>One or more.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>333</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter, 5/8 inch, wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance two, preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>334</Label><Text>Handholds on a cupola shall be</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>one continuous handhold extending around top of cupola not more than three inches from edge of cupola roof; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>four right-angle handholds, one at each corner, not less than 16 inches in clear length from point of angle may take the place of the one continuous handhold specified in paragraph (a) if locations coincide.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>335</Label><Text>Cupola handholds shall be securely fastened with</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>not less than 1/2-inch bolts with nuts outside and riveted over; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>not less than 1/2-inch rivets.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Side Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>336</Label><Text>Four.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>337</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter, 5/8 inch, wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clear length, 36 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance two, preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>338</Label><Text>One near each end on each side of car, curving downward toward centre of car from a point not less than 30 inches above platform to a point not more than eight inches from bottom of car. Top end of handhold shall be not more than eight inches from outside face of end sheathing.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>339</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 27 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>340</Label><Text>Four.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>341</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 29 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>342</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Horizontal</Emphasis>: One near each side on each end of car on face of platform end sill.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Clearance of outer end of handhold shall be not more than 16 inches from end of platform end sill.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>343</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 31 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Platform Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>344</Label><Text>Four.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>345</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter, 5/8 inch, wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance, two, preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>346</Label><Text>One right-angle handhold on each side of each end extending horizontally from door post to corner of car at approximate height of platform rail, then downward to within 12 inches of bottom of car.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>347</Label><Text>Handholds shall be securely fastened with bolts, screws, or rivets.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Caboose Platform Steps</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>348</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Safe and suitable open, or box, steps leading to caboose platforms to be provided at each corner of caboose.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Where open steps are used, the bottom tread of said steps to be provided with a right and left foot-stop at each end of tread, made of angle iron 3 1/2 inches by 2 1/2 inches by 1/4 inch; the 2 1/2-inch face of angle iron to be bolted to the step.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Uncoupling Levers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>349</Label><Text>Same as specified in sections 36, 37 and 38 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Caboose Cars with Platforms Built New or Rebuilt After January 1, 1967, and Caboose Cars with Platforms in Service After December 31, 1982</TitleText><HistoricalNote>[SOR/80-751, s. 4]</HistoricalNote></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Hand Brakes</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>349.1</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Each caboose car shall be equipped with an efficient hand brake which shall operate in harmony with the power brake thereon.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The hand brake may be of any efficient design, but must provide a total braking force applied to brake shoes not less than the total force applied to the brake shoes by the brake cylinders at 50 pounds per square inch.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>349.2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The brake wheel may be deep or shallow, of malleable iron, wrought iron, steel, or other material of equivalent strength.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Overall diameter of brake wheel nominally 22 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Depth of brake wheel hub shall be 2 5/8 inches with square taper shaft fit, taper 2 inches in 12 inches with small end of taper fit 7/8 inch.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Brake wheel and drum shall be arranged so that both will revolve when applying and gradually releasing the hand brake. Hand brake shall be provided with means to prevent application of the brake by winding in a counterclockwise direction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>All chains shall be not less than 9/16-inch BBB coil chain.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(6)</Label><Text>All hand brake rods shall be not less than 3/4 inch in diameter.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>349.3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The hand brake shall be so located that it can be safely operated from the end platform while car is in motion.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The brake shaft shall be located to the left of and not less than 17 nor more than 22 inches from centre of car and not less than 26 nor more than 40 inches above top of end platform.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>349.4</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>There shall be not less than four inches clearance around rim of brake wheel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Brake wheel shall be held in position on brake shaft by a nut on a threaded extended end of brake shaft, said threaded portion shall be not less than 3/4 inch in diameter; said nut shall be secured by riveting over or by the use of a lock-nut or suitable cotter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Outside edge of brake wheel shall be not less than four inches from a vertical plane parallel with end of car and passing through the inside face of knuckle when closed with coupler horn against the buffer block or end sill.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Hand brake housing shall be securely fastened to car.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>Brake shaft shall be arranged with a square fit at its outer end to secure the hand brake wheel; said square fit shall be not less than 7/8 inch square. Square-fit taper: nominally 2 in 12 inches (See Plate A in Schedule II)</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Side Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>349.5</Label><Text>Four.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>349.6</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter, 5/8 inch, wrought iron, steel, or other material of equivalent strength.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clear length, 36 inches; and</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance, two, preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>349.7</Label><Text>One near each end on each side of car, curving downward toward centre of car from a point not less than 30 inches above platform to a point not more than eight inches from bottom of car. Top end of handhold shall be not more than eight inches from outside face of end sheathing.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>349.8</Label><Text>Side handholds shall be securely fastened with not less than 1/2-inch bolts with nuts outside (when possible) and riveted over or with not less than 1/2-inch rivets.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>349.9</Label><Text>Four.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>349.10</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter, 5/8 inch, wrought iron, steel, or other material of equivalent strength.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clear length, 16 inches, preferably 24, inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Notwithstanding subsection (2), a handhold 14 inches in length may be used where it is impossible to use one 16 inches in length.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance, two, preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>349.11</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Horizontal</Emphasis>: one near each side on each end of car on face of platform end sill.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Clearance of outer end of handhold shall be not more than 16 inches from end of platform end sill.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>349.12</Label><Text>Horizontal end handholds shall be securely fastened with not less than 1/2-inch bolts with nuts outside (when possible) and riveted over, or with not less than 1/2-inch rivets.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Platform Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>349.13</Label><Text>Four.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>349.14</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter, 5/8 inch, wrought iron, steel, or other material of equivalent strength.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance, two, preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>349.15</Label><Text>One right-angle handhold on each side of each end extending horizontally from door post to corner of car at approximate height of platform rail, then downward to within 12 inches of bottom of car.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>349.16</Label><Text>Handholds shall be securely fastened with not less than 1/2-inch bolts with nuts outside (when possible) and riveted over or with not less than 1/2-inch rivets.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Caboose Platforms Steps</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>349.17</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Safe and suitable open or box steps leading to caboose platforms to be provided at each corner of caboose.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Where open steps are used, the bottom tread of said steps to be provided with a right and left foot-stop at each end of tread, made of angle iron 3 1/2 inches by 2 1/2 inches by 1/4 inch; the 2 1/2-inch face of angle iron to be bolted to the step.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Uncoupling Levers</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>349.18</Label><Text>Two.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>349.19</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Handles of uncoupling levers except those shown on Plate B of Schedule II or of similar design, shall be not more than six inches from sides of car.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Uncoupling levers of design shown on Plate B of Schedule II and of similar designs shall conform to the following prescribed limits:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>handles shall be not more than 12 inches, preferably nine inches, from sides of cars;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>centre lift arms shall be not less than seven inches long;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>centre of eye at end of centre lift arm shall be not more than 3 1/2 inches beyond centre of eye of uncoupling pin of coupler when horn of coupler is against the buffer block or end sill (See Plate B of Schedule II);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>ends of handles shall extend not less than four inches below bottom of end sill or shall be so constructed as to give a minimum clearance of two inches around handle (See Plate B of Schedule II);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>minimum drop of handles shall be 12 inches, maximum, 15 inches over all (See Plate B of Schedule II);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>handles of uncoupling levers of the rocking or push down type shall be not less than 18 inches from top of rail when lock block has released knuckle, and a suitable stop shall be provided to prevent inside arm from flying up in case of breakage.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>349.20</Label><Text>One on each end of car. When single lever is used, it shall be placed on left side of end of car.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Caboose Cars Without Platforms</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Hand Brakes</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>350</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 1 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>351</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 2 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>352</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Each hand brake shall be so located that it can be safely operated while car is in motion.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The brake shaft on caboose cars without platforms shall be located on end of car to the left of centre.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>353</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 4 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Brake Step</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>354</Label><Text>Same as specified in sections 5 and 6 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Running Boards</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>355</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 7 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>356</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 8 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>357</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Full length of car, centre of roof (on caboose cars with cupolas, longitudinal running boards shall extend from cupola to ends of roof).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Outside metal roof cars shall have latitudinal extensions leading to ladder locations.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>358</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 10 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText><FootnoteRef idref="footnote1_e">1</FootnoteRef>Sill Steps</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>359</Label><Text>Same as specified in sections 11 to 14 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Side Door Steps</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>360</Label><Text>Two (if caboose has side doors).</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>361</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum length, five feet.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum width, six inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Minimum thickness of tread, 1 1/2 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Minimum height of back stop, three inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>Maximum height from top of rail to top of tread, 24 inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>362</Label><Text>One under each side door.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>363</Label><Text>Side door steps shall be supported by two iron brackets having a minimum cross-sectional area 7/8 inch by three inches or equivalent, each of which shall be securely fastened to car by not less than 2 3/4-inch bolts.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Ladders</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>364</Label><Text>Four.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>365</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 12 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>366</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 13 of this Schedule, except that when caboose has side doors, the side ladders shall be located not more than eight inches from doors.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>367</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 14 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Ladder Clearance</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>368</Label><Text>No part of car above end sills within 30 inches from side of car, except buffer block, brake shaft, brake wheel, brake step, running board or uncoupling lever shall extend to within 12 inches of a vertical plane parallel with end of car and passing through the inside face of knuckle when closed with coupler horn against the buffer block, or end sill, and no other part of end of car or fixtures on same above end sills, other than exceptions herein noted, shall extend beyond the outer face of buffer block.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Roof Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>369</Label><Text>Four.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>370</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 21 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>371</Label><Text>One over each ladder, on roof in line with and running parallel to treads of ladder, not less than eight nor more than 15 inches from edge of roof, except that where stiles of ladders extend 12 inches or more above roof, no other roof handholds are required.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>372</Label><Text>Roof handholds shall be securely fastened with</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>not less than 1/2-inch bolts with nuts outside (when possible) and riveted over; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>not less than 1/2-inch rivets.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Cupola Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>373</Label><Text>One or more.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>374</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter, 5/8 inch, wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance, two, preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>375</Label><Text>Cupola handholds shall be</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>one continuous cupola handhold extending around top of cupola, not more than three inches from edge of cupola roof; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>four right-angle handholds, one at each corner, not less than 16 inches in clear length from point of angle, may take the place of the one continuous handhold specified in paragraph (a), if locations coincide.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>376</Label><Text>Cupola handholds shall be securely fastened with not less than 1/2-inch bolts with nuts outside and riveted over or with not less than 1/2-inch rivets.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Side Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>377</Label><Text>Four.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>378</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 25 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>379</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Horizontal</Emphasis>: one near each end on each side of car, not less than 24 nor more than 30 inches above centre line of coupler.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Clearance of outer end of handhold shall be not more than eight inches from end of car.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>380</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 27 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Side Door Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>381</Label><Text>Four; two curved, two straight.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>382</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter, 5/8 inch wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance, two, preferably 2 1/2 inches;</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>383</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>One  curved handhold, from a point at side of each door opposite ladder, not less than 36 inches above bottom of car, curving away from door downward to a point not more than six inches above bottom of car.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>One vertical handhold at ladder side of each door from a point not less than 36 inches above bottom of car to a point not more than six inches above level of bottom of door.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>384</Label><Text>Side door handholds shall be securely fastened with</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>not less than 1/2-inch bolts with nuts outside (when possible) and riveted over; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>not less than 1/2-inch rivets.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Horizontal End Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>385</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 28 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>386</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 29 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>387</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 30 of this Schedule, except that one additional end handhold shall be on each end of cars with platform end sills as heretofore described, unless car has door in centre of end. Said handhold shall be not less than 24 inches in length, located near centre of car, not less than 30 nor more than 60 inches above platform end sill.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>388</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 31 of this Schedule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 443(3) of this Schedule.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Vertical End Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>389</Label><Text>Same as specified in sections 32, 33, 34 and 35 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Uncoupling Levers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>390</Label><Text>Same as specified in sections 36, 37 and 38 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Boarding Cars</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>391</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Boarding cars with platforms shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>be provided with a full complement of safety appliances as prescribed for the original design of car; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>be equipped with safety appliances consistent with those prescribed for caboose cars with platforms (sections 242 to 275 of this Schedule).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Boarding cars similar in design to house freight cars in which employees are transported shall be equipped with a full complement of safety appliances as prescribed for box and other house cars with the following exceptions:</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Side Doors</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>392</Label><Text>All boarding cars, without end platforms, shall have two side doors.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Side Door Steps</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>393</Label><Text>Two.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>394</Label><Text>Standard side sill step as specified in section 12 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>395</Label><Text>One under each side door.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>396</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 14 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Roof Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>397</Label><Text>One over each ladder, on roof, in line with and running parallel to treads of ladder, not less than eight inches nor more than 15 inches from edge of roof.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>398</Label><Text>Roof handholds shall be securely fastened with</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>not less than 1/2-inch bolts with nuts outside and riveted over; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>not less than 1/2-inch rivets.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Side Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>399</Label><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Horizontal</Emphasis>: one near each end on each side of car, not less than 24 nor more than 30 inches above centre line of coupler. Clearance of outer end of handhold shall be not more than eight inches from end of car.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Side Door Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>400</Label><Text>Four; two straight on each side of car each side of door.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>401</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter 5/8 inch wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance two, preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>402</Label><Text>One vertical handhold at each side of door from a point not less than 36 inches above bottom of car to a point not more than six inches above level of bottom of door.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>403</Label><Text>Side door handholds shall be securely fastened with</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>not less than 1/2-inch bolts with nuts outside and riveted over; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>not less than 1/2-inch rivets.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Horizontal End Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>404</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 30 of this Schedule, except that one additional end handhold shall be on each end of cars with platform end sills as heretofore described, unless car has door in centre of end. Said handhold shall be not less than 24 inches in length, located near centre of car, not less than 30 nor more than 60 inches above platform end sill.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Vertical End Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>405</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 34 of this Schedule, except where boarding car has door in centre of end, without platform, there shall be one handhold on each side of door on door post, from a point not less than 36 inches above bottom of door to a point not more than 15 inches above level of bottom of door.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>406</Label><Text>Same as specified in section 35 of this Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Doors</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>407</Label><Text>Boarding cars equipped with end doors must have the words “DANGER, NO PLATFORM” stencilled on panel inside of end door.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Passenger-train Cars with Wide Vestibules</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Hand Brakes</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>408</Label><Text>Each passenger-train car shall be equipped with an efficient hand brake, which shall operate in harmony with the power brake thereon.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>409</Label><Text>Each hand brake shall be so located that it can be safely operated while car is in motion.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Side Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>410</Label><Text>Eight.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>411</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter, 5/8 inch, metal.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clear length, 16 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance, 1 1/4, preferably 1 1/2, inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>412</Label><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Vertical</Emphasis>: One on each vestibule door post.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>413</Label><Text>Side handholds shall be securely fastened with bolts, rivets or screws.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>414</Label><Text>Four.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>415</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter, 5/8 inch, wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clear length, 16 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance two, preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Handholds shall be flush with or project not more than one inch beyond vestibule face.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>416</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Horizontal</Emphasis>: One near each side on each end, projecting downward from face of vestibule end sill.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Clearance of outer end of handhold shall be not more than 16 inches from side of car.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>417</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>End handholds shall be securely fastened with bolts or rivets.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>When marker sockets or brackets are located so that they cannot be conveniently reached from platforms, suitable steps and handholds shall be provided for men to reach such sockets or brackets.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Uncoupling Levers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>418</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Uncoupling attachments shall be applied so they can be operated by a person standing on the ground.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum length of ground uncoupling attachment, 42 inches, measured from centre line of end of car to handle of attachment.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Passenger-train Cars with Open End Platforms</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Hand Brakes</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>419</Label><Text>Each passenger-train car shall be equipped with an efficient hand brake, which shall operate in harmony with the power brake thereon.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>420</Label><Text>Each hand brake shall be so located that it can be safely operated while car is in motion.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>421</Label><Text>Four.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>422</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter, 5/8 inch, wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clear length, 16 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance, two, preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Handholds shall be flush with or project not more than one inch beyond face of end sill.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>423</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Horizontal</Emphasis>: One near each side of each end on face of platform end sill, projecting downward.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Clearance of outer end of handhold shall be not more than 16 inches from end of end sill.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>424</Label><Text>End handholds shall be securely fastened with bolts or rivets.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Platform Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>425</Label><Text>Four (Cars equipped with safety gates do not require end platform handholds).</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>426</Label><Text>Minimum clearance, two, preferably 2 1/2, inches, metal.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>427</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Horizontal from or near door post to a point not more than 12 inches from corner of car, then approximately vertical to a point not more than six inches from top of platform.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Horizontal portion shall be not less than 24 inches in length nor more than 40 inches above platform.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>428</Label><Text>End platform handholds shall be securely fastened with bolts, rivets or screws.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Uncoupling Levers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>429</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Uncoupling attachments shall be applied so they can be operated by a person standing on the ground.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum length of ground uncoupling attachment, 42 inches, measured from centre of end of car to handle of attachment.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Passenger-train Cars Without End Platforms</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Hand Brakes</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>430</Label><Text>Each passenger-train car shall be equipped with an efficient hand brake which shall operate in harmony with the power brake thereon.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>431</Label><Text>Each hand brake shall be so located that it can be safely operated while car is in motion.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Sill Steps</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>432</Label><Text>Four.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>433</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum length of tread, 10, preferably 12, inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum cross-sectional area, 1/2 inch by 1 1/2 inches or equivalent, wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Minimum clear depth, eight inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>434</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>One near end on each side, not more than 24 inches from corner of car to centre of tread of sill step.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Outside edge of tread of step shall be not more than two inches inside of face of side of car.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Tread shall be not more than 24, preferably not more than 22, inches above the top of rail.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>435</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Steps exceeding 18 inches in depth shall have an additional tread and be laterally braced.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Sill steps shall be securely fastened with</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>not less than 1/2-inch bolts with nuts outside (when possible) and riveted over; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>not less than 1/2-inch rivets.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Side Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>436</Label><Text>Four.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>437</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter, 5/8 inch, wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clear length, 16, preferably 24, inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance, two, preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>438</Label><Text>One near each end on each side of car over sill step,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text><Emphasis style="italic">horizontal</Emphasis>: not less than 24 nor more than 30 inches above centre line of coupler; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text><Emphasis style="italic">vertical</Emphasis>: lower end not less than 18 nor more than 24 inches above centre line of coupler.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>439</Label><Text>Side handholds shall be securely fastened with bolts, rivets or screws.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>440</Label><Text>Four.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>441</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter, 5/8 inch, wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clear length, 16 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance, two, preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>442</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Horizontal</Emphasis>: One near each side on each end, projecting downward from face of end sill or sheathing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Clearance of outer end of handhold shall be not more than 16 inches from side of car.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>443</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Handholds shall be flush with or project not more than one inch beyond face of end sill.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>End handholds shall be securely fastened with bolts or rivets.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>When marker sockets or brackets are located so that they cannot be conveniently reached from platforms, suitable steps and handholds shall be provided for men to reach such sockets or brackets.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Handrails</TitleText><TitleText>(On cars with projecting end sills)</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>444</Label><Text>Four.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>445</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter, 5/8 inch, wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance, two, preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>446</Label><Text>One on each side of each end, extending horizontally from door post or vestibule frame to a point not more than six inches from corner of car, then approximately vertical to a point not more than six inches from top of platform end sill; horizontal portion shall be not less than 30 nor more than 60 inches above platform end sill.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>447</Label><Text>End hand rails shall be securely fastened with bolts, rivets or screws.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Side Door Steps</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>448</Label><Text>One under each door.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>449</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum length of tread, 10, preferably 12, inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum cross-sectional area, 1/2 inch by 1 1/2 inches or equivalent, wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Minimum clear depth, eight inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>450</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Outside edge of tread of step not more than two inches inside of face of side of car.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Tread not more than 24, preferably not more than 22, inches above the top of rail.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>451</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Steps exceeding 18 inches in depth shall have an additional tread and be laterally braced.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Side door steps shall be securely fastened with</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>not less than 1/2-inch bolts with nuts outside (when possible) and riveted over; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>not less than 1/2-inch rivets.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>A vertical handhold not less than 24 inches in clear length shall be applied above each side door step on door post.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Uncoupling Levers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>452</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Uncoupling attachments shall be applied so they can be operated by a person standing on the ground.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum length of ground uncoupling attachment, 42 inches, measured from centre line of end of car to handle of attachment.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Cars of Special Construction</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>453</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Cars of construction not covered specifically in the foregoing sections, relative to handholds, sill steps, ladders, hand brakes and running boards may be considered as of special construction, but shall have as nearly as possible the same complement of handholds, sill steps, ladders, hand brakes and running boards as are required for cars of the nearest approximate type.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>“RIGHT” or “LEFT” refers to side of person when facing end or side of car from ground.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>To provide for the usual inaccuracies of manufacturing and for wear, where sizes of metal are specified, a total variation of five per cent below size given is permitted.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Safety Appliances — Locomotive</TitleText><TitleText>Steam Locomotives Used in Road Service</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Tender Sill Steps</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>454</Label><Text>Four on tender.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>455</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Bottom tread not less than eight by 12 inches, metal (may have wooden treads).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>If stirrup-steps are used, clear length of tread shall be not less than 10, preferably 12, inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>456</Label><Text>One near each corner of tender on sides.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>457</Label><Text>Tender sill steps shall be securely fastened with bolts or rivets.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Pilot-Beam Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>458</Label><Text>Two.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>459</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter, 5/8 inch, wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clear length, 14, preferably 16, inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance, 2 1/2 inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>460</Label><Text>One on each end of buffer beam. (If uncoupling lever extends across front end of locomotive to within eight inches of end of buffer beam, and is 7/8 inch or more in diameter, securely fastened, with a clearance of 2 1/2 inches, it is a handhold).</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>461</Label><Text>Pilot-beam handholds shall be securely fastened with bolts or rivets.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Side Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>462</Label><Text>Six.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>463</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>if horizontal, 5/8 inch;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>if vertical, 7/8 inch, wrought iron or steel.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Horizontal, minimum clear length, 16 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Vertical, clear length equal to approximate height of tank.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance two, preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>464</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Side handholds shall be</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>if vertical, one on each side of tender within six inches of rear or on corner;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>if horizontal, same as specified in section 26 of this Schedule.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>One on each side of tender near gangway.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>One on each side of locomotive at gangway; applied vertically.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>465</Label><Text>Side handholds shall be securely fastened with not less than 1/2-inch bolts or rivets.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Rear End Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>466</Label><Text>Two.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>467</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter, 5/8 inch, wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clear length, 14 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance two, preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>468</Label><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Horizontal</Emphasis>: One near each side of rear end of tender on face of end sill. Clearance of outer end of handhold shall be not more than 16 inches from side of tender.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>469</Label><Text>Rear end handholds shall be securely fastened with not less than 1/2-inch bolts or rivets.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Steam Locomotives Used in Switching Service</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Sill Steps</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>470</Label><Text>Two or more.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>471</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Lower tread of step shall be not less than eight by 12 inches, metal (May have wooden treads).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>If stirrup-steps are used, clear length of tread shall be not less than  10, preferably  12, inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>472</Label><Text>One or more on each side at gangway secured to locomotive or tender.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>473</Label><Text>Sill-steps shall be securely fastened with bolts or rivets.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>474</Label><Text>Two.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>475</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter, one inch, wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance, four inches, except at coupler casting or braces, when minimum clearance shall be two inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>476</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>One on pilot buffer beam.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>One on rear end of tender, extending across front end of locomotive and rear end of tender.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Ends of handholds shall be not more than six inches from ends of buffer beam or end sill, securely fastened at ends.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>If the uncoupling levers meet all specified requirements for end handholds, they are handholds.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>477</Label><Text>End handholds shall be securely fastened with bolts or rivets.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Side Handholds</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>478</Label><Text>Four.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>479</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Minimum diameter, 7/8 inch, wrought iron or steel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Clear length equal to approximate height of tank.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Minimum clearance, two, preferably 2 1/2, inches.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>480</Label><Text>Vertical</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>one on each side of tender near front corner; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>one on each side of locomotive gangway.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>481</Label><Text>Side handholds shall be securely fastened with bolts or rivets.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Handrails and Steps for Headlights</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>482</Label><Text>Switching locomotives with sloping tenders with manhole or headlight located on sloping portion of tender shall be equipped with secure steps and handrail or with platform and handrail leading to such manhole or headlight.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Specifications Common to All Steam Locomotives</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Hand Brakes</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>483</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Hand brakes will not be required on locomotives nor on tenders when attached to locomotives.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>If tenders are detached from locomotives and used in special service, they shall be equipped with efficient hand brakes.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Running Boards</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>484</Label><Text>Two.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>485</Label><Text>Not less than 10 inches wide. If of wood not less than 1 1/2 inches in thickness; if of metal not less than 3/16 inch, properly supported. Providing that, in the case of locomotives of such dimensions, in the diameter of that portion of the boiler between the front of cab and the forward end of the course adjoining the fire box a 10-inch width cannot be obtained without extending beyond the side clearance allowance, the width of running-board may be reduced to a minimum of 5 1/2 inches widening to 10 inches as the reducing diameter of the boiler permits. Pipes or other appurtenances must be so located as will provide for not less than the minimum widths of running board above prescribed.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>486</Label><Text>One on each side of boiler, extending from cab to front end near pilot beam. Running boards may be in sections where necessary to provide for the location of air compressors, water pumps or heaters, reservoirs, or other appurtenances. (Flat top steam chests may form section of running board). Where necessary, section shall be placed over the top of the power reverse gear or similar devices located on or projecting through running boards; all sections to provide the minimum widths prescribed. Where the difference in elevation between sections is 20 inches or more, an auxiliary step shall be provided.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>487</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Running boards shall be securely fastened with bolts, rivets or studs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Locomotives having Wootten type boilers with cab located on top of boiler more than 12 inches forward from boiler head shall have suitable running boards running from cab to rear of locomotive, with hand railing not less than 20 nor more than 48 inches above outside edge of running boards, securely fastened with bolts, rivets or studs.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Handrails</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>488</Label><Text>Two or more.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>489</Label><Text>Not less than one inch in diameter, wrought iron or steel.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>490</Label><Text>One on each side of boiler extending from near cab to near front end of boiler, and extending across front end of boiler, not less than 24 nor more than 66 inches above running board.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>491</Label><Text>Handrails shall be securely fastened to boiler.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Handrails and Footrests on Outside of Cabs</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>492</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>All locomotives of 100,000 pounds or over shall be equipped with handrails on the sides of the cabs above the windows, near the top of cab, and running the entire length of same, and to continue across the front of the cab. Where it is not practicable to extend the railing across the front of the cab, suitable handholds shall be provided; the rails to have a clearance of two inches between the inner side of the rail and the outside wall of the cab, and to be supported by columns to make them secure.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Where the running boards do not project beyond the sides of the cab, an additional piece must be added, to project not less than one inch from the side of cab, and to run full length of same.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Locomotives of United States railways operated into Canada in international service may, upon application, be exempted by Order of the Commission from complying with this section.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Handrails on Tenders</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>493</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>All locomotive tenders of the coal-hopper type, equipped with hoppers 24 inches and over, shall have a handrail on both sides of the coal hopper, to run the full length of the same and across the back end, the same to have a clearance of not less than two inches between the inner side of the rail and the outside wall of the fuel well, and to be located near the top, but not to project above. Hoppers less than 24 inches high shall be equipped with a railing on both sides and across the back, on the top of the hopper, to measure eight inches over all from top of hopper, back walls sloping towards the front of hoppers excepted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>When necessary to renew equipment now in service, and for all future construction, coal hoppers shall be designed so as to provide a sidewalk the full length of the hopper, with a minimum width of eight inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>All locomotive tenders of the open-top type shall be equipped with a railing on both sides, on top of the coping, to measure eight inches over all from top of coping, the same rails to run the full length of the fuel storage well, or clear of the back coal wall, on the tender.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>On the spaces back of the coal wall, where the water man hole is located, a railing shall be provided projecting eight inches above the top of the tank and running around both sides and back of the tank, except that the coping will be accepted as a railing where tenders of engines are equipped with a coping eight inches high on the space back of the coal wall.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>The railings provided in subsections (3) and (4) shall not be less than one inch in diameter supported by columns if made of round iron.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(6)</Label><Text>The top of the tender behind the fuel space and the running boards on the coal-hopper type shall be kept clean; suitable covers shall be provided for the filling holes; and, where a coping is in use behind the fuel space, means shall be provided to carry off waste water.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Tenders of Vanderbilt Type</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>494</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Tenders known as the Vanderbilt type shall be equipped with running boards; one on each side of tender not less than 10 inches in width and one on top of tender not less than 48 inches in width, extending from coal space to rear of tender.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>There shall be a handrail on each side of top running board, extending from coal space to rear of tank, not less than one inch in diameter and not less than 20 inches in height above running board from coal space to manhole.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>There shall be a handrail extending from coal space to within 12 inches of rear of tank, attached to each side of tank above side running board, not less than 30 nor more than 66 inches above running board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>There shall be one vertical end handhold on each side of Vanderbilt type of tender, located within eight inches of rear of tank extending from within eight inches of top of end sill to within eight inches of side handrail. Post supporting rear end of side running board, if not more than two inches in diameter and properly located, may form section of handhold.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>An additional horizontal end handhold shall be applied on rear end of all Vanderbilt type of tenders that are not equipped with vestibules. Handhold to be located not less than 30 nor more than 66 inches above top of end sill. Clear length of handhold to be not less than 48 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(6)</Label><Text>Ladders shall be applied at forward ends of side running boards.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(7)</Label><Text>On tenders of the Vanderbilt type, with three filling holes, there shall be a hand rail four inches above the level of the top running board not less than one inch in diameter, extending from the present hand rail, which extends from the coal space to within 20 inches of the first filling hole, to the rear end of the tender at each side of the top running board.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>End Ladder Clearance</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>495</Label><Text>No part of locomotive or tender except draft-rigging, coupler and attachments, safety chains, buffer block, foot board, brake pipe, signal pipe, steam-heat pipe or arms of uncoupling lever shall extend to within 14 inches of a vertical plane passing through the inside face of knuckle when closed with horn of coupler against buffer block or end sill.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Uncoupling Levers</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>496</Label><Text>Two double levers, operative from either side.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>497</Label><Text>Rear end levers shall extend across end of tender with handles not more than 12, preferably nine, inches from side of tender with a guard bent on handle to give not less than two inches clearance around handle.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>498</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>One on rear end of tender and one on front end of locomotive.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Handles of front end levers shall be not more than 12, preferably nine, inches from ends of buffer beam, and shall be so constructed as to give a minimum clearance of two inches around handle.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>499</Label><Text>Uncoupling levers shall be securely fastened with bolts or rivets.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Couplers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>500</Label><Text>Locomotives shall be equipped with automatic couplers at rear of tender and front of locomotive.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Handrails and Steps for Headlights</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>501</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Locomotives having headlights which cannot be safely and conveniently reached from pilot beam or steam chests shall be equipped with secure handrails and steps suitable for the use of men in getting to and from such headlights and headlight equipment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A suitable metal end or side ladder shall be applied to all tanks more than 48 inches in height, measured from the top of end sill, and securely fastened with bolts or rivets.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Safety Appliances</TitleText><TitleText>All Locomotive Types</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Pilots</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>502</Label><Text>Locomotives in Road Service (normal road operation) shall be equipped with a pilot that</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>is located at the front;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>has a minimum height above the rail of not less than three inches and a maximum of not more than six inches;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>is securely attached and adequately braced; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>is maintained in a safe and suitable condition for service.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Pilot Steps</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>503</Label><Text>Two.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>504</Label><Text>One at right and left side of each pilot.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Dimensions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>505</Label><Text>Pilot steps shall be of sufficient width and depth for a man to stand on.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Manner of Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>506</Label><Text>Pilot step shall be securely fastened with bolts or rivets.</Text></Section><Section><Label>507</Label><Text>Locomotives of a design capable of normal operation in either direction, such as Diesel electric or electric units, or any type of locomotive regularly assigned to such road service as to necessitate the running of tender first shall be equipped at the front and rear with a pilot or combination pilot and footboards, except that in the case of Diesel “A” and “B” units application is required only on the front end of “A” units.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Footboards</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>508</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Locomotives in yard switching and transfer service shall be equipped with footboards at the front and rear.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The height from the top of rail to top of tread shall be not more than 12 inches, nor less than nine inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>On locomotives in yard switching service,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>footboards may be constructed in two sections if the majority of horizontal space on each side of the coupler is protected by the footboards;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>footboards shall be securely fastened to two one-inch by four-inch metal brackets, if footboard is not cut or notched at any point;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>if footboard is cut or notched or in two sections not less than four one-inch by three-inch metal brackets shall be used, two located on each side of coupler;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>each bracket shall be secured to the buffer-beam, end-sill, frame or plate forming the end structure of the locomotive or tender by not less than two 7/8-inch bolts.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Metal of serrated anti-skid design, constructed with sufficient open area to prevent accumulation of snow and ice on the tread surface shall be used.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>If wood, preferably two inches thick but not less than 1 1/2 inches in thickness, is used, the footboard shall not be cut or notched at any point, outer corners may be radiused or slightly beveled.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(6)</Label><Text>The footboards shall be</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>of sufficient width to provide adequate foot space, notwithstanding projecting grab irons or other devices; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>not less than 10 inches wide and three feet in length.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(7)</Label><Text>Footboards shall be located at front and rear, extending not less than 18 inches outside gauge of straight track.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(8)</Label><Text>Foot stops, not less than four inches in height, shall be applied above the tread, at the back and each inner end.</Text><Provision first-line-indent="0" list-item="yes" subsequent-line-indent="4"><Label>NOTE:</Label><Text>It is preferable that any openings between the footboards and underside of buffer beam or frame be covered for the protection of employees.</Text></Provision></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Combination Pilot and Footboards</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>509</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Locomotives operating in road and yard switching services shall be equipped at the front and rear with combination pilots and footboards.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Footboards shall be metal, serrated anti-skid design, constructed with sufficient open area to prevent accumulation of snow and ice on the tread surface.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The combination pilot, footboards and associated supports shall be of adequate strength and of an appropriate design acceptable to the Commission for the requirements of road service, maintained in a safe and satisfactory operating condition.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Couplers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>510</Label><Text>All locomotives shall be equipped with automatic couplers at front and rear.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Uncoupling Levers</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Number</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>511</Label><Text>Two double levers operative from both sides.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Location</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>512</Label><Text>One on front and one on rear of each locomotive.</Text></Section><Section><Label>513</Label><Text>Uncoupling lever handles shall be not more than 12, preferably nine, inches from side of unit and shall be so constructed as to give a minimum clearance of two inches around handle.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Locomotives of Special Construction</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>514</Label><Text>Locomotive units of untried type or locomotives not covered specifically in the foregoing sections, relative to sill steps, hand holds, ladders, running boards, and other safety appliances may be considered as being of special construction. All such units shall be equipped as near as possible with a full complement of suitable safety appliances as required for locomotives of approximately the same type.</Text></Section></RegulationPiece></Schedule><Schedule spanlanguages="yes" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE II</Label><OriginatingRef>(ss. 1, 4, 37, 112.4, 112.27, 316, 349.4 and 349.19 of Sch. I)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><ImageGroup position="center" width="38pc"><AlternateText>Illustration, measurements and specifications for Plate A</AlternateText><Caption position="over" justification="center">Plate A</Caption><Image source="CRC1171img\CRC1171_e001.jpg" /></ImageGroup><Provision format-ref="centered" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>(Any efficient arrangement of ratchet-wheel and pawl may be used.)</Text></Provision><PageBreak /><ImageGroup position="center" width="38pc"><AlternateText>Illustration, measurements and specifications for Plate B</AlternateText><Caption position="over" justification="center">Plate B</Caption><Image source="CRC1171img\CRC1171_e002.jpg" /></ImageGroup><Provision format-ref="centered" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>Application to outside endsill cars.</Text></Provision></Schedule></Regulation>