<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 1384</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>28</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CANADA TRANSPORTATION ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Victoria Jubilee Bridge Traffic By-law</ShortTitle><LongTitle>By-Law Regulating Vehicular Traffic upon the Victoria Jubilee Bridge, Montreal, and the Approaches Thereto (C.N.R. By-Law Number 27)</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This By-law may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Victoria Jubilee Bridge Traffic By-law</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In this By-law, <DefinedTermEn>company</DefinedTermEn> means the Canadian National Railway Company.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Traffic Allowed</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>Subject to the weight, height and other restrictions hereinafter set out, the use of the bridge roadways is limited to</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>motor vehicles having not more than two axles, nor more than six tires;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>trailers or other vehicles in tow, having not more than two axles and not more than four tires; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>tractor-trailer combination units if the operator is in possession of a weight slip indicating gross vehicle weight not in excess 13 1/2 tons (27,000 lb.) of which not more than nine tons (18,000 lb.) may be on one axle.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Traffic Prohibited</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>The use of a bridge roadway by any motor vehicle is prohibited if such vehicle, together with trailer or other vehicle in tow, if any,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>is not equipped with pneumatic tires;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>is carrying dynamite or other high explosive or any substance on fire;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>has a gross weight (including load) in excess of 13 1/2 tons (27,000 lb.); the operator of any vehicle shall supply a weight certificate if requested to do so by a bridge attendant;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>has a height (including load) in excess of 12 feet; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>has a width (including load) in excess of 8 feet.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Speed Limit</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>No motor vehicle shall be driven over a bridge roadway at a speed that is unsafe or unreasonable, nor shall such speed in any case exceed 30 miles per hour.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Passage Restrictions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>No motor vehicle shall overtake or pass a moving autobus on a bridge roadway.</Text></Section><Section><Label>7</Label><Text>Autobuses or motor trucks equipped with more than four tires shall not under any condition attempt to pass an autobus or such a truck, whether in motion or stopped, on the bridge roadways at any time.</Text></Section><Section><Label>8</Label><Text>Motor vehicles, other than autobuses, having more than four tires are not permitted to use the traffic lanes (St. Lambert to Montreal) between 7 a.m. and 9.30 a.m. nor traffic lanes (Montreal to St. Lambert) between 4 p.m. and 6.30 p.m.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Stalled Vehicles</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>9</Label><Text>Any motor vehicle that becomes stalled on the bridge will be immediately towed to a convenient location beyond the exit of the bridge, and if such towing service can be performed by a company vehicle, a fee of $2 will be assessed, but if towing service is performed by other than a company vehicle, the actual expense as assessed by the party performing the towing service will be paid by the owner of the vehicle.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Closing of Bridge</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>10</Label><Text>The bridge roadways may be closed to traffic by means of notices, gates, or otherwise, either during a period of emergency or for work or maintenance to be done on the roadways, for such period of time as the operating officers of the company may deem necessary, and during such period, no vehicle shall pass upon the roadways unless the operator holds a special permit issued for such purpose by the company.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Penalty</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>11</Label><Text>Every person who violates this By-law shall be liable on summary conviction to a penalty not exceeding $40.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>