<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 83</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2011</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AERONAUTICS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Gander Airport Zoning Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting Zoning at Gander International Airport</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Gander International Airport Zoning Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/95-560, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>airport</DefinedTermEn> means the Gander International Airport, in the District of Gander-Twillingate, in the Province of Newfoundland; (<DefinedTermFr>aéroport</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>airport reference point</DefinedTermEn> means the point described in Part I of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>point de repère de l’aéroport</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>approach surface</DefinedTermEn> means an imaginary inclined plane extending upward and outward from each end of a strip, along and at right angles to the projected centre line thereof, which approach surface is more particularly described in Part III of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>surface d’approche</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Minister</DefinedTermEn> means the Minister of Transport; (<DefinedTermFr>ministre</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>outer surface</DefinedTermEn> means an imaginary surface located above and in the immediate vicinity of the airport, which outer surface is more particularly described in Part IV of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>surface extérieure</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>strip</DefinedTermEn> means the rectangular portion of the landing area of the airport including the runway prepared for the take-off and landing of aircraft in a particular direction, which strip is more particularly described in Part V of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>bande</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>transitional surface</DefinedTermEn> means an imaginary inclined plane extending upward and outward from the lateral limits of a strip and its approach surfaces, which transitional surface is more particularly described in Part VI of the schedule. (<DefinedTermFr>surface de transition</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><HistoricalNote>SOR/95-560, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>For the purposes of these Regulations, the airport reference point is deemed to be 450 feet above sea level.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>These Regulations apply to all lands and lands under water, including public road allowances, adjacent to or in the vicinity of the airport, the outer limits of which are described in Part II of the schedule, except land that from time to time forms part of the airport.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/95-560, s. 5(F).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>No person shall erect or construct, on any land to which these Regulations apply, any building, structure or object, or any addition to any existing building, structure or object, the highest point of which will exceed in elevation at the location of that point any of the following surfaces that project immediately over and above the surface of the land at that location, namely,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the approach surfaces;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the outer surface; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the transitional surfaces.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/95-560, s. 5(F).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Aeronautical Facilities</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>No owner or lessee of any land to which these Regulations apply shall permit any part of that land to be used or developed in a manner that causes interference with any signals or communications to and from</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any aircraft; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any facilities used to provide services relating to aeronautics.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/81-171, s. 1; SOR/95-560, s. 4.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Natural Growth</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>7</Label><Text>Where an object of natural growth that is on any land to which these Regulations apply grows to a height that exceeds in elevation at the location of the object any of the surfaces referred to in section 5, the Minister may require that the owner or lessee of the land remove the excess growth.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/95-560, s. 4.</HistoricalNote></Section></Body><Schedule bilingual="no" spanlanguages="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label><OriginatingRef>(Sections 2 and 4)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><Heading level="1"><Label>PART I</Label><TitleText>Airport Reference Point</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Being a point distant five hundred (500) feet measured southeasterly at right angles to the centre line of runway 09-27, from a point distant three thousand five hundred (3,500) feet measured along the centre line of that runway from its intersection with the centre line of runway 04-22.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART II</Label><TitleText>Description of Outer Limits of Lands</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>A circular area having a radius of thirteen thousand (13,000) feet, the centre of which coincides with the airport reference point.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART III</Label><TitleText>Description of Each Approach Surface</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Being a surface abutting each end of</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>each strip associated with runways 04-22 and 14-32 consisting of an inclined plane having a ratio of one (1) foot measured vertically to fifty (50) feet measured horizontally, rising to an imaginary horizontal line drawn at right angles to the projected centre line of each strip one thousand (1,000) feet measured vertically above the elevation at the end of each strip and fifty thousand (50,000) feet measured horizontally from the end of each strip, the outer ends of each imaginary horizontal line being eight thousand (8,000) feet from each projected centre line, and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the strip associated with runway 09-27 consisting of an inclined plane having a ratio of one (1) foot measured vertically to forty (40) feet measured horizontally, rising to an imaginary horizontal line drawn at right angles to the projected centre line of each strip two hundred (200) feet measured vertically above the elevation at the end of each strip and ten thousand (10,000) feet measured horizontally from the end of each strip, the outer ends of each imaginary horizontal line being one thousand two hundred and fifty (1,250) feet from each projected centre line,</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>which surfaces are shown on Department of Transport Plan MT-1593, dated August 25, 1975.</Text></Provision></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART IV</Label><TitleText>Description of the Outer Surface</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Being an imaginary surface consisting of</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a common plane established at a constant elevation of one hundred and fifty (150) feet above the assigned elevation of the airport reference point, and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>where the common plane described in paragraph (a) is less than thirty (30) feet above the surface of the ground, an imaginary surface located thirty (30) feet above the surface of the ground,</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>which outer surface is shown on Department of Transport Plan MT-1593, dated August 25, 1975.</Text></Provision></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART V</Label><TitleText>Description of Each Strip</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Each strip is described as follows:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the strip associated with runway 04-22 is one thousand (1,000) feet in width, five hundred (500) feet being on each side of the centre line of the runway, and ten thousand nine hundred (10,900) feet in length,</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the strip associated with runway 09-27 is five hundred (500) feet in width, two hundred and fifty (250) feet being on each side of the centre line of the runway, and six thousand five hundred and eighty (6,580) feet in length,</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the strip associated with runway 14-32 is one thousand (1,000) feet in width, five hundred (500) feet being on each side of the centre line of the runway, and nine thousand three hundred (9,300) feet in length,</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>which strips are shown on Department of Transport Plan MT-1593, dated August 25, 1975.</Text></Provision></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART VI</Label><TitleText>Description of Each Transitional Surface</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Being a surface consisting of an inclined plane rising at a ratio of one (1) foot measured vertically to seven (7) feet measured horizontally at right angles to the centre line and centre line production of each strip, and extending upward and outward from the lateral limits of each strip and its approach surfaces to an intersection with the outer surface or another transitional surface of an adjoining strip, all as shown on Department of Transport Plan MT-1593, dated August 25, 1975.</Text></Provision><HistoricalNote>SOR/95-560, s. 5(F).</HistoricalNote></Schedule></Regulation>