<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 1319</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>26</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">FOREIGN MISSIONS AND INTERNATIONAL ORGANIZATIONS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>UNESCO Remission Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order for the Remission of Certain Duties and Taxes on Goods Imported or Purchased by UNESCO</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">UNESCO Remission Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Free Entry, Refund or Remission</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>Authority is hereby granted, effective January 22, 1948, for free entry, refund or remission of the following customs duties and the consumption or sales tax imposed under the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal> and the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Excise Act</XRefExternal>, respectively, on printed matter and official publications and articles and materials used in the production thereof, when imported into Canada or purchased in Canada, either for sale or free distribution by the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization, or its duly authorized agents, subject to compliance with the conditions and procedures set out in the schedule.</Text></Section></Body><Schedule bilingual="no" spanlanguages="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label><OriginatingRef>(s. 2)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><TableGroup pointsize="7.5" topmarginspacing="4"><table frame="topbot"><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colname="1" /><colspec colname="2" /><colspec colname="3" /><thead><row topdouble="yes"><entry align="center" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Taxing Authority</entry><entry align="center" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Conditions</entry><entry align="center" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Procedure</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>1</Label><Text>The <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal> and the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Excise Tax Act</XRefExternal>:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>Customs duty, including the consumption or sales tax on printed matter, official publications and articles and materials used in the production thereof.</Text></Provision></Provision></entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>When printed matter, official publications and articles and materials used in the production thereof are imported under appropriate certificate.</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>The B.1 customs entry should bear a certificate across its face to the effect that the importer is either:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" topmarginspacing="0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>A senior executive officer of the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization, or</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" topmarginspacing="0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a duly authorized agent of the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization, and that the</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" topmarginspacing="0"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>printed matter or publications have been <XRefExternal reference-type="other">bona fide</XRefExternal> printed, published or issued by or on behalf of the Organization, or</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" topmarginspacing="0"><Label>(d)</Label><Text>articles and materials will be used exclusively in the production of printed matter and/or publications of the Organization, in all of which instances the articles described are entitled to exemption from customs duty and</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>2</Label><Text>Part XIII of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Excise Tax Act</XRefExternal>. The sales tax on printed matter and official publications of the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization and articles and materials used or consumed in the production thereof.</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>When printed matter or official publications of the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization, and articles and materials used or consumed in the production thereof are purchased under appropriate certificate.</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>A senior executive officer or a duly authorized agent of the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization should, when ordering the goods, include a certificate over his signature to the effect that the account is to be paid with the funds of that Organization and that the exemption is properly allowable under the provisions of this Order.</Text></Provision></entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Schedule></Regulation>