<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 1448</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>8</MM><DD>4</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CANADA SHIPPING ACT, 2001</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Minor Waters Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Specifying Certain Waters on the Sea Coasts of Canada as Minor Waters</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Minor Waters Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Minor Waters</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>The following sheltered waters on the sea coasts of Canada are hereby specified as minor waters of Canada:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in British Columbia,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>Alberni Inlet and the eastern channel of Barclay Sound as far west as Bamfield Inlet,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>Quatsino Sound and all waters connected therewith as far west as Koprino Harbour,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>False Creek, Vancouver, east of Burrard Bridge,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>Jervis Inlet inside a line drawn between Thunder Point and Ball Point and all waters connected therewith not seaward of Fox Island in Telescope passage, including the Agamemnon Channel and Pender Harbour inside a line drawn between Fearney Point and Moore Point, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(v)</Label><Text>Prince Rupert Harbour as far south as Charles Point;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in New Brunswick,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>Saint John Harbour inside the southern breakwater and inside a line drawn between the southern extremity of the northern breakwater and the most easterly point of Partridge Island,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>Shediac Harbour westward of a line drawn between Pointe du Chêne and Caissie Point,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>Miramichi Bay westward of a line drawn from the eastern shore of Neguac Beach to the eastern shores of Portage and Fox Islands and thence to the western point of Preston Beach,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>Nepisiquit Bay inside a line drawn between Alston and Carron Points,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(v)</Label><Text>Dalhousie Harbour and the Restigouche River westward of a line drawn from Maguacha Point in the Province of Quebec to the mouth of Charlo River,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(vi)</Label><Text>Shippigan Sound inside the breakwater at Shippigan Gulley and south of a line drawn between Grasse Point and Pokesudi Point,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(vii)</Label><Text>Miscou Harbour east of a line drawn between Herring Point and Mya Point, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(viii)</Label><Text>Passamoquoddy Bay as far as Campobello Island and inside a line drawn at the northern entrance between east Quoddy Head and Deadman Head;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>in Newfoundland,</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-2-2" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>Humber Arm, east of a line drawn from Frenchman’s Head triangulation station to McIver’s Point triangulation station;</Text></Provision></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>in Nova Scotia,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>Bras d’Or Lake, Great Bras d’Or and all waters connected therewith inside a line joining Carey and Noir Points, and northwards of the seaward end of St. Peters Canal,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>Annapolis Basin and Digby Gut inside a line between Prim Point lighthouse and Victoria Beach at the entrance to Digby Gut, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>Halifax Harbour and the waters inside a line joining the triangulation station on Osborne Head and the eastern extremity of Chebucto Head;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>in the Northwest Territories,</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-2-2" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>Kugmallit Bay, south of a line drawn from the northern tip of the peninsula adjoining Kidluit Bay to Toker Point; and</Text></Provision></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>in Prince Edward Island,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>Charlottetown Harbour inside Canseaux and Battery Points,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>Summerside Harbour inside a line between Phelan Point and Indian Head Breakwater, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>Cardigan Bay inside a line drawn between Panmure Head and Red Point.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/82-843, s. 1; SOR/84-942, s. 1(F); SOR/85-540, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section></Body></Regulation>