<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 99</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2012</YYYY><MM>2</MM><DD>9</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AERONAUTICS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>North Bay Airport Zoning Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting Zoning at North Bay Airport</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">North Bay Airport Zoning Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>airport</DefinedTermEn> means North Bay Airport, in the City of North Bay, in the District of Nipissing, in the Province of Ontario; (<DefinedTermFr>aéroport</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>airport reference point</DefinedTermEn> means the point described in Part I of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>point de repère de l’aéroport</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>approach surface</DefinedTermEn> means an imaginary inclined plane extending upward and outward from the end of a strip along and at right angles to the projected centre line thereof, which approach surface is more particularly described in Part III of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>surface d’approche</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>horizontal surface</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Revoked, SOR/83-498, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Minister</DefinedTermEn> means the Minister of Transport; (<DefinedTermFr>ministre</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>outer surface</DefinedTermEn> means an imaginary surface located above and in the immediate vicinity of the airport, which outer surface is more particularly described in Part IV of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>surface extérieure</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>strip</DefinedTermEn> means a rectangular portion of the landing area of the airport, including the runway prepared for the take-off and landing of aircraft in a particular direction, which strip is more particularly described in Part V of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>bande</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>transitional surface</DefinedTermEn> means an imaginary inclined plane extending upward from the lateral limits of a strip and its approach surfaces, which transitional surface is more particularly described in Part VI of the schedule. (<DefinedTermFr>surface de transition</DefinedTermFr>) </Text></Definition><HistoricalNote>SOR/83-498, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>For the purposes of these Regulations, the airport reference point is deemed to be 1,180 feet above sea level.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (2), these Regulations apply to all the lands adjacent to or in the vicinity of the airport, including public road allowances, the outer limits of which are described in Part II of the schedule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>These Regulations do not apply to such of those lands, the outer limits of which are described in Part II of the schedule, as form part of the airport from time to time.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>No person shall erect or construct, on any land to which these Regulations apply, any building, structure or object or any addition to any existing building, structure or object, the highest point of which will exceed in elevation at that point any of the surfaces hereinafter set out that project immediately over and above the surface of the land at that location, namely,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the approach surfaces;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the outer surface; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the transitional surfaces.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/83-498, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Natural Growth</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>Where an object of natural growth on any land to which these Regulations apply exceeds in elevation any of the surfaces set out in paragraphs 5(a) to (c), the Minister may make a direction that the owner or occupier of the land on which that object is growing remove the excessive growth thereof.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/79-896, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>7</Label><Text><Repealed>[Revoked, SOR/79-896, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Disposal of Waste</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>8</Label><Text>No owner or occupier of any land or land under water to which these Regulations apply shall permit such land or any part thereof to be used for the disposal or accumulation thereon of any waste, material or substance edible by or attractive to birds.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/79-89, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section></Body><Schedule bilingual="no" spanlanguages="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label><OriginatingRef>(Sections 2 and 4)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><Heading level="1"><Label>PART I</Label><TitleText>Airport Reference Point</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Being a point distant five hundred (500) feet measured Northerly from and at right angles to the centre line of runway 08-26 from a point thereon distant eleven hundred (1,100) feet measured westerly along the said centre line from the intersection of the said centre line with the centre line of runway 13-31.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART II</Label><TitleText>Description of Outer Limits of Lands</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>COMMENCING at the Southwesterly corner of Lot 22, in Concession A, in the Township of Widdifield; THENCE, Northerly along the western boundary of Lot 22, in Concession A, to the Northwesterly corner of the said lot, being also the Southwesterly corner of Lot 22, in Concession 1; THENCE, Northerly along the western boundary of Lot 22, in Concession 1, to the Northwesterly corner of the said Lot; THENCE, Easterly along the northern boundary of Lot 22, in Concession 1, to the Southwesterly Corner of Lot 21, in Concession 2; THENCE, Northerly along the western boundary of Lot 21, in Concession 2, to the Northwesterly corner of the said Lot; THENCE, Easterly along the northern boundary of Lot 21 and Lot 20, in Concession 2, to the Southwesterly corner of Lot 19, in Concession 3; THENCE, Northerly along the western boundary of said Lot 19, in Concession 3, to the Northwesterly corner of the said Lot; THENCE, Easterly along the northern boundary of Lots 19, 18 and 17, in Concession 3, to the Northeasterly corner of said Lot 17; THENCE, Southerly along the eastern boundary of Lot 17, in Concession 3, to the Southeasterly corner of the said Lot, being also the Northwesterly corner of Lot 16, in Concession 2; THENCE, Easterly along the northern boundary of Lots 16, 15, 14, 13, 12 and 11, in Concession 2, to the Northeasterly corner of said Lot 11; THENCE, Southerly along the eastern boundary of Lot 11, in Concession 2, to the Southeasterly corner of the said Lot, being also the Northeasterly corner of Lot 11, in Concession 1; THENCE, Southerly along the eastern boundary of Lot 11, in Concession 1, to the Southeasterly corner of the said Lot, being also the Northeasterly corner of Lot 11, in Concession A; THENCE, Southerly along the eastern boundary of Lot 11, in Concession A, to the Southeasterly corner of said Lot 11, being also the Northeasterly corner of Lot 11, in Concession B; THENCE, Southerly along the eastern boundary of the North half of Lot 11, in Concession B, to the Southeasterly corner of the said North half of the said Lot; THENCE, Westerly along the Southern boundary of the North half of Lots 11, 12, 13 and 14, in Concession B, to the eastern boundary of Lot 15, in Concession B; THENCE, Southerly along the said Easterly boundary of Lot 15, in Concession B, to the intersection thereof with the northern limit of the right-of-way of the Ontario Northland Railway; THENCE, Westerly along the said northern limit of the said right-of-way through Lot 15 in Concession B and through the North half of Lots 15 and 16 in Concession C, to the intersection thereof with the Southern limit of North Bay and Trout Lake Colonization Road through said Lot 16, in Concession C; THENCE, in a general Westerly direction along the said Southern limit of said Road to the intersection thereof with the western boundary of said Lot 16; THENCE, Northerly along the western boundary of said Lot 16, to the Northwesterly corner of the said Lot; THENCE, Westerly along the Southern boundary of Lot 17, in Concession B, to the intersection thereof with the northern limit of the said Road through said Lot 17; THENCE, in a general Westerly direction along the said northern limit of the said Road through Lots 17 and 18, in Concession B, to the intersection thereof with the western boundary of Lot 18, in Concession B; THENCE, Northerly along the western boundary of Lot 18, to the intersection thereof with the Southern boundary of the North half of Lot 19, in Concession B; THENCE, Westerly along the Southern boundary of the North half of Lots 19, 20, 21 and 22, in Concession B, to the western boundary of said Lot 22; THENCE, Northerly along the western boundary of Lot 22, to the point of commencement, which lands are shown on Department of Transport Plan No. T2743, dated June 22, 1970.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART III</Label><TitleText>Description of the Approach Surfaces</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Being a surface abutting each end of the strips associated with the runways designated 08-26, 18-36 and 13-31 and more particularly described as follows:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a surface abutting the end of the strip associated with runway approach 08 consisting of an inclined plane having a ratio of one (1) foot measured vertically to fifty (50) feet measured horizontally rising to an imaginary horizontal line drawn at right angles to the projected centre line of the strip two hundred (200) feet measured vertically above the elevation at the end of the strip and ten thousand (10,000) feet measured horizontally from the end of the strip, the outer ends of the imaginary horizontal line being two thousand (2,000) feet from the projected centre line;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a surface abutting the end of the strip associated with runway approach 13 consisting of an inclined plane having a ratio of one (1) foot measured vertically to fifty (50) feet measured horizontally rising to an imaginary horizontal line drawn at right angles to the projected centre line of the strip two hundred (200) feet measured vertically above the elevation at the end of the strip and ten thousand (10,000) feet measured horizontally from the end of the strip, the outer ends of the imaginary horizontal line being two thousand (2,000) feet from the projected centre line;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a surface abutting the end of the strip associated with runway approach 18 consisting of an inclined plane having a ratio of one (1) foot measured vertically to fifty (50) feet measured horizontally rising to an imaginary horizontal line drawn at right angles to the projected centre line of the strip one hundred and fifty-six (156) feet measured vertically above the elevation at the end of the strip and seven thousand eight hundred (7,800) feet measured horizontally from the end of the strip, the outer ends of the imaginary horizontal line being one thousand and thirty (1,030) feet from the projected centre line;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a surface abutting the end of the strip associated with runway approach 26 consisting of an inclined plane having a ratio of one (1) foot measured vertically to fifty (50) feet measured horizontally rising to an imaginary horizontal line drawn at right angles to the projected centre line of the strip two hundred (200) feet measured vertically above the elevation at the end of the strip and ten thousand (10,000) feet measured horizontally from the end of the strip, the outer ends of the imaginary horizontal line being two thousand (2,000) feet from the projected centre line;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(e)</Label><Text>a surface abutting the end of the strip associated with runway approach 31 consisting of an inclined plane having a ratio of one (1) foot measured vertically to fifty (50) feet measured horizontally rising to an imaginary horizontal line drawn at right angles to the projected centre line of the strip two hundred (200) feet measured vertically above the elevation at the end of the strip and ten thousand (10,000) feet measured horizontally from the end of the strip, the outer ends of the imaginary horizontal line being two thousand (2,000) feet from the projected centre line; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(f)</Label><Text>a surface abutting the end of the strip associated with runway approach 36 consisting of an inclined plane having a ratio of one (1) foot measured vertically to fifty (50) feet measured horizontally rising to an imaginary horizontal line drawn at right angles to the projected centre line of the strip one hundred and fifty-seven (157) feet measured vertically above the elevation at the end of the strip and seven thousand eight hundred and fifty (7,850) feet measured horizontally from the end of the strip, the outer ends of the imaginary horizontal line being one thousand and thirty-five (1,035) feet from the projected line,</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>which surfaces are shown on Department of Transport Plan No. T-2743 dated June 22, 1970.</Text></Provision></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART IV</Label><TitleText>Description of the Outer Surface</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Being an imaginary surface located at a common plane established at a constant elevation of one hundred and fifty (150) feet above the assigned elevation of the airport reference point except where that common plane is less than thirty (30) feet above the surface of the ground, the imaginary surface is located at thirty (30) feet above the surface of the ground, which imaginary surface is shown on Department of Transport Plan No. T-2743 dated June 22, 1970.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART V</Label><TitleText>Description of the Strips</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The strips are described as:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the strip associated with runway 08-26 is one thousand (1,000) feet in width, five hundred (500) feet being on each side of the centre line of the runway, and ten thousand six hundred (10,600) feet in length;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the strip associated with runway 18-36 is five hundred (500) feet in width, two hundred and fifty (250) feet being on each side of the centre line of the runway, and four thousand eight hundred and seventy-four (4,874) feet in length; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the strip associated with runway 13-31 is one thousand (1,000) feet in width, five hundred (500) feet being on each side of the centre line of the runway, and six thousand five hundred and eighty-nine (6,589) feet in length,</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>which strips are shown on Department of Transport Plan No. T-2743, dated June 22, 1970.</Text></Provision></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART VI</Label><TitleText>Description of Each Transitional Surface</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Each transitional surface is a surface consisting of an inclined plane rising at a ratio of one (1) foot measured vertically to seven (7) feet measured horizontally at right angles to the centre line and centre line produced of each strip extending upward and outward from the lateral limits of each strip and its approach surfaces to an intersection with the outer surface or another transitional surface of an adjoining strip, all as shown on Department of Transport Plan No. T-2743, dated June 22, 1970.</Text></Provision><HistoricalNote>SOR/83-498, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Schedule></Regulation>