<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 772</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>11</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Involuntary Retirements Remission Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Granting Remission of Taxes Payable in Respect of Persons Involuntarily Retired from the Public Service</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Involuntary Retirements Remission Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In this Order,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Superannuation Act</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>employee</DefinedTermEn> means a person who is or was employed in the public service of Canada; (<DefinedTermFr>employé</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>pension</DefinedTermEn> means an annuity within the meaning of the Act; (<DefinedTermFr>pension</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>settlement</DefinedTermEn> means an amount received in respect of a loss of salary or pension benefits arising from the termination of employment of an employee; (<DefinedTermFr>paiement</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>termination of employment</DefinedTermEn> means, with respect to an employee, the termination of his employment pursuant to subsection 20(12) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Public Service Superannuation Regulations</XRefExternal>, as that subsection read on October 19, 1972. (<DefinedTermFr>cessation d’emploi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Remission</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Where, in the 1972 or any subsequent taxation year, a settlement was or is received by an employee or his legal representative because of the termination of employment, remission is hereby granted of the amount by which</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the income tax payable by him or his legal representative for the taxation year</Text></Paragraph><ContinuedSectionSubsection><Text>exceeds</Text></ContinuedSectionSubsection><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the aggregate of</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the tax that would have been payable by him or his legal representative for the taxation year if the settlement had not been received, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the tax that, if the salary or pension in respect of which the settlement was paid had in fact been received by him or his legal representative in the taxation years in respect of which the settlement was paid, would have been payable less the tax that was so paid in respect of those years</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><ContinuedSectionSubsection><Text>together with the interest, if any, payable on that amount.</Text></ContinuedSectionSubsection></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Subsection (1) applies to the widow or child of an employee, as the circumstances require.</Text></Subsection></Section></Body></Regulation>