<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 648</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>14</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">FARM PRODUCTS AGENCIES ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Agencies’ Orders and Regulations Approval Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Respecting the Classes of Orders and Regulations of Agencies to which Paragraph 7(1)(d) of the Farm Products Agencies Act is Applicable and the Procedure for their Approval</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Agencies’ Orders and Regulations Approval Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application of Paragraph 7(1)(d) of the Farm Products Agencies Act</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>Paragraph 7(1)(d) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Farm Products Agencies Act</XRefExternal> applies to the classes of orders and regulations made by an agency that</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>establish a quota system by which quotas are assigned to members of classes of producers of a farm product;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>impose levies or charges on persons engaged in the production of a farm product or the marketing thereof; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>regulate the price at which a farm product is marketed in a province other than the province in which the farm product is produced.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Procedure for Approval</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>Five copies of every order and regulation of a class described in section 2 that is proposed to be made by an agency shall be submitted to the Council for approval in both official languages at least two weeks before the day on which the order or regulation is proposed to be made.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>