<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 743</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>7</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Ballet Shoes Remission Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Respecting the Remission of Customs Duty and Sales Tax on Ballet Shoes</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Ballet Shoes Remission Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Remission</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>Remission is hereby granted of all customs duties paid or payable under the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal> on ballet shoes of the type commonly known as pointe shoes or block toe shoes imported during the period commencing July 1, 1970 and ending June 30, 1988, by or for resale to the National Ballet School, Toronto, the George Brown School of Dance, Toronto, and the Quinte Dance Centre, Belleville, Ontario, for the use of their students, or by or for resale to the National Ballet Guild of Canada, Toronto, les Grands Ballets Canadiens, Montreal, the Royal Winnipeg Ballet, Winnipeg, the Theatre Ballet of Canada, Ottawa, Ballet British Columbia, Vancouver, the Alberta Ballet Company, Edmonton, la Compagnie de danse Eddy Toussaint, Montreal and the Goh Ballet Company, Vancouver, for the use of professional dancers in their employ. </Text><HistoricalNote>SI/78-153, s. 1; SI/80-155, s. 1; SI/81-35, s. 1; SI/83-89, s. 1; SI/87-243, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>Remission is hereby granted of the sales tax paid or payable under the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Excise Tax Act</XRefExternal> on the ballet shoes in respect of which customs duties are remitted by this Order in an amount equal to the amount of the difference between the sales tax calculated on the duty-paid value of the shoes and the sales tax calculated on the value for duty of the shoes.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>