<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 716</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>11</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>National Defence Official Mementos Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting Official Mementos for Visiting Foreign Dignitaries, Military Representatives and Other Officials</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">National Defence Official Mementos Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Minister</DefinedTermEn> means the Minister of National Defence; (<DefinedTermFr>ministre</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>official memento</DefinedTermEn> means any item of public property of a distinctly Canadian character and manufacture, including contemporary arts and crafts and articles, representative of all or part of the Canadian Forces or of Canadian culture or Canadian manufacturing. (<DefinedTermFr>souvenir officiel</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>Subject to section 4 and to any limitations prescribed by the Minister, an official memento may be transferred to a foreign dignitary, a military representative of the forces of another country, a visiting lecturer or other visiting official in appreciation of professional assistance or social hospitality extended, either inside or outside Canada, in support of programs of the Department of National Defence or the Canadian Forces.</Text></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (2), the Minister, the Chief of the Defence Staff, or an officer designated by the Chief of the Defence Staff may approve the transfer of an official memento.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The Chief of the Defence Staff shall not approve a transfer of an official memento where its value exceeds $200 and an officer designated by the Chief of the Defence Staff shall not approve a transfer where the value of the official memento exceeds $75.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/81-614, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section></Body></Regulation>