<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 135</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>3</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS MARKETING ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Alberta Turkey Marketing Levies Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Providing for the Fixing, Imposing and Collecting of Levies from Certain Turkey Producers in Alberta</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Alberta Turkey Marketing Levies Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In this Order,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means <XRefExternal reference-type="act">The Marketing of Agricultural Products Act</XRefExternal> of Alberta; (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Commodity Board</DefinedTermEn> means the Alberta Turkey Growers’ Marketing Board established pursuant to the Act; (<DefinedTermFr>Office de commercialisation</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>market allotment</DefinedTermEn> means the total quantity of turkey meat that a producer is entitled to market in intraprovincial, interprovincial and export trade pursuant to the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Canadian Turkey Marketing Quota Regulations</XRefExternal> and the Orders made by the Commodity Board pursuant to the Plan; (<DefinedTermFr>allocation de commercialisation</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Plan</DefinedTermEn> means the Alberta Turkey Growers’ Marketing Plan, established and amended from time to time pursuant to the Act and any Regulations made thereunder to give effect to the Plan; (<DefinedTermFr>Plan</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>producer</DefinedTermEn> means any person engaged in the production of turkeys in the Province of Alberta; (<DefinedTermFr>producteur</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>turkey</DefinedTermEn> means a turkey of any variety, grade or class that is raised or kept for slaughter within the Province of Alberta and sold for slaughter. (<DefinedTermFr>dindon</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Levies</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>Every producer shall pay to the Commodity Board, in addition to the licence fees set out under the Plan, levies at the following rates:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>$0.50 for each broiler turkey sold by him that is in excess of his annual or periodic market allotment;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>$0.77 for each heavy breed hen turkey sold by him that is in excess of his annual or periodic market allotment;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>$1.27 for each heavy breed tom turkey sold by him that is in excess of his annual or periodic market allotment; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>$1.02 for each heavy breed turkey sold by him as part of an unsexed flock that is in excess of his annual or periodic market allotment.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Method of Payment</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Every person who buys turkeys from a producer shall deduct from the moneys payable to the producer for the turkeys all levies payable by the producer to the Commodity Board under section 3 and shall pay such levies to the Commodity Board at its office at 11826-100th Avenue, Edmonton, Alberta, not later than the 15th day of the month next following the month in which the levies were deducted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Every producer shall pay to the Commodity Board at its office at 11826-100th Avenue, Edmonton, Alberta, all levies payable by him under section 3 that were not deducted and paid to the Commodity Board in the manner prescribed in subsection (1), not later than the 15th day of the month next following the month in which the turkeys in respect of which the levies are payable were sold.</Text></Subsection></Section></Body></Regulation>