<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 632</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>6</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">EXPORT AND IMPORT PERMITS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Import of Specimens (Personal or Household) Permit</ShortTitle><LongTitle>General Import Permit No. 17</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Permit may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Import of Specimens (Personal or Household) Permit</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>Any person may, under the authority of this General Import Permit, import into Canada from any country, except Argentina, any specimen listed in Appendix I, II or III of the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Import Control List</XRefExternal>, that are personal or household effects, except</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>specimens of a species included in Appendix I of the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Import Control List</XRefExternal> that were acquired by the owner outside Canada; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>specimens of species included in Appendix II or III of the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Import Control List</XRefExternal> acquired by the owner outside Canada by removal from the wild in a country where the export of such specimens requires the prior grant and presentation of an export permit from that country.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SI/82-116, Sch. III, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>Any person may, under the authority of this General Import Permit, import into Canada from any country, except Rhodesia, any specimen listed in Appendix I of the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Import Control List</XRefExternal> upon presentation to the collector of customs at the Canadian port of entry of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>an Export Permit, a Re-Export Permit or Certificate issued by the exporting country, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>an Import Permit issued by the Canadian Wildlife Service of the Department of the Environment</Text></Paragraph><ContinuedSectionSubsection><Text>in the form prescribed by the Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species of Wild Fauna and Flora, as ratified by Canada on April 10, 1975.</Text></ContinuedSectionSubsection></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>Any person may, under the authority of this General Import Permit, import into Canada from any country, except Rhodesia, any specimen listed in Appendix II or III of the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Import Control List</XRefExternal> upon presentation to the collector of customs at the Canadian port of entry of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>an Export Permit, a Re-Export Permit or Certificate issued by the exporting country, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in case of a specimen introduced from the sea, a permit approving the importation of the specimen issued by the Canadian Wildlife Service of the Department of the Environment</Text></Paragraph><ContinuedSectionSubsection><Text>in the form prescribed by the Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species of Wild Fauna and Flora, as ratified by Canada on April 10, 1975.</Text></ContinuedSectionSubsection></Section><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>Any scientist or scientific institution recognized by the Canadian Wildlife Service of the Department of the Environment may, under the authority of this General Import Permit, import into Canada from any country, except Rhodesia, for the purpose of a non-commercial loan, donation or exchange between scientists or scientific institutions, herbarium specimens, other preserved, dried, or embedded museum specimens and live plant material listed in Appendix I, II or III of the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Import Control List</XRefExternal> if a certificate of approval, issued by the Canadian Wildlife Service of the Department of the Environment, is presented to the collector of customs at the Canadian port of entry.</Text></Section><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>Any person may, under the authority of this General Import Permit, import into Canada from any country, except Rhodesia, any specimen of fauna or flora listed in Appendix I, II or III of the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Import Control List</XRefExternal> that forms part of a travelling zoo, circus, menagerie, plant exhibition or other travelling exhibition if a permit approving the importation is obtained from the Canadian Wildlife Service of the Department of the Environment.</Text></Section><Section><Label>7</Label><Text>Where completion and validation of a customs entry form is required with respect to any specimens that are imported under the authority of this General Import Permit, that form shall be endorsed "Imported under the authority of General Import Permit No. 17" or "Importé en vertu de la Licence générale d'importation n<Sup>o</Sup> 17".</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>