<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 522</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2006</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>4</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CUSTOMS TARIFF</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Customs Diplomatic Privileges Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting Customs Diplomatic Privileges</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Customs Diplomatic Privileges Regulations.</XRefExternal></Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>chief officer of customs</DefinedTermEn>, with respect to an area or place, means the manager of the customs office or customs offices that serve that area or place; (<DefinedTermFr>agent en chef des douanes</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>collector</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Revoked, SOR/88-86, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>duty</DefinedTermEn> or <DefinedTermEn>duties</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Revoked, SOR/88-86, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Deputy Minister</DefinedTermEn> means the Deputy Minister of National Revenue for Customs and Excise; (<DefinedTermFr>sous-ministre</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>of career</DefinedTermEn> means that persons so designated are nationals or citizens of the country they represent, and are not engaged in any business or profession other than their diplomatic or consular duties. (<DefinedTermFr>de carrière</DefinedTermFr>) </Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>tax</DefinedTermEn> or <DefinedTermEn>taxes</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Revoked, SOR/88-86, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><HistoricalNote>SOR/88-86, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Baggage Examination</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text><Repealed>[Revoked, SOR/88-86, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Importation at Free Rates of Customs Duties</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>Subject to sections 5 and 6, the privilege of importation at free rates of customs duties of articles for their personal or family use is extended to</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>ambassadors, ministers, high commissioners and consuls general of career representing their countries in Canada;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>members of the diplomatic corps and staffs of high commissioners’ offices eligible for inclusion in the diplomatic list published by the Department of External Affairs;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>consuls of career;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>vice consuls of career;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>trade commissioners of career; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>assistant trade commissioners of career.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/88-86, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>Application for the importation at free rates of customs duties of goods, other than motor vehicles, shall be made in writing to the chief officer of customs, a separate application being made for each importation.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/88-86, s. 4.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>6</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Application for importation at free rates of customs duties of motor vehicles imported subsequent to first arrival in Canada, shall be made in the form set out in the schedule, and be forwarded by the applicant to the Deputy Minister.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>On approval of the application and receipt of the Free Rate of Customs Duties Importation Authorization in duplicate, the applicant shall present the Authorization, in duplicate, to the chief officer of customs at the customs office where the motor vehicles were reported.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/88-86, s. 5.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>7</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Applications by persons specified in paragraph 4(b) shall be approved by, or in the name of, the appropriate ambassador, minister or high commissioner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Applications by persons specified in paragraphs 4(c) to (f) shall be signed as follows:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>when made by consuls of career, by the appropriate consul general or by the consul in charge in offices where there is no consul general;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>when made by vice consuls of career, by the appropriate consul general or consul in charge in offices where there is no consul general, or by the vice consul in charge where there is no consul;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>when made by trade commissioners of career, by the senior trade commissioner or by the trade commissioner in charge in offices where there is no senior trade commissioner; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>when made by assistant trade commissioners of career, by the trade commissioner in charge of the office or by the assistant trade commissioner in charge in offices where there is no trade commissioner.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Importation at Free Rates of Customs Duties on First Arrival Only</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>8</Label><Text>The privilege of importation at free rates of customs duties of personal and household effects, including motor vehicles, but not including spirituous liquors, is extended on their first arrival to representatives of foreign governments sent by their governments to posts in Canada, and their families.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/88-86, s. 6.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Resale</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>9</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (2), goods that have been imported at free rates of customs duties under these Regulations may be sold or disposed of in Canada without payment of customs duties where the goods have been in the use and possession of the importer in Canada for a period of at least one year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Motor vehicles that have been imported at free rates of customs duties under these Regulations may be sold or disposed of in Canada without payment of customs duties where the motor vehicles have been in the use and possession of the importer in Canada for a period of at least two years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>In the event of the decease or transfer away from Canada of a person referred to in section 4 before the expiration of the two-year period mentioned in subsection (2), waiver of payment of customs duties may be authorized by the Minister on the recommendation of the Secretary of State for External Affairs.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/88-86, s. 7.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Articles for Official Use</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>10</Label><Text>Uniforms, office equipment, stationery and similar supplies sent by the government of any foreign country for the official use of any of its officers in Canada shall be imported at free rates of customs duties.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/88-86, s. 7.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>11 and 12</Label><Text><Repealed>[Revoked, SOR/88-86, s. 7]</Repealed></Text></Section></Body><Schedule spanlanguages="yes" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 6)</OriginatingRef><TitleText>Application for Free Rates of Customs Duties on Imported Motor Vehicles</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><Provision format-ref="right-align"><Text><FormBlank width="20pc">Place<Leader length="5pc" />Date</FormBlank></Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="10"><Label>1</Label><Text>To: the Deputy Minister, National Revenue (Customs and Excise) <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /></Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>I, <FormBlank width="6pc">(<Emphasis style="italic">full name</Emphasis>)</FormBlank>, having been officially notified to the Department of External Affairs, Ottawa, as <FormBlank width="20pc">(<Emphasis style="italic">official designation</Emphasis>)<Leader length="5pc" />(<Emphasis style="italic">located at</Emphasis>)</FormBlank>, I apply for importation at free rates of customs duties of the motor vehicle described below, in accordance with the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Customs Diplomatic Privileges Regulations</XRefExternal>. I declare that I have purchased the following motor vehicle:</Text><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Description</TitleText></Heading><TableGroup pointsize="8" spanlanguages="yes" topmarginspacing="10"><table frame="none"><tgroup cols="7"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="6.98*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="13.50*" /><colspec colname="3" colwidth="12.43*" /><colspec colname="4" colwidth="22.70*" /><colspec colname="5" colwidth="14.92*" /><colspec colname="6" colwidth="13.19*" /><colspec colname="7" colwidth="13.25*" /><tbody><row rowsep="0" valign="bottom"><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0">2</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0">Year</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0">Make</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0">Country of Manufacture</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0">Model</entry><entry colname="6" colsep="0" rowsep="0">Serial No.</entry><entry colname="7" colsep="0" rowsep="0">Purchase Price</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="10"><Label>3</Label><Text>Name of Sales Agency <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /></Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="10"><Text>Address <LeaderRightJustified leader="dot" /></Text></Provision></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>4</Label><Text>The above described motor vehicle is being acquired for my personal, family and official use and not for sale, and I am aware that it may not be sold or otherwise disposed of in Canada within a period of two years after the date of its acquisition, except on payment of customs duties as applicable on the appraised value at the time of sale. If for any reason it becomes necessary to sell or dispose of this vehicle within two years after the date of acquisition, I undertake to give advance notification in writing to the Department of National Revenue, Customs and Excise, Planning and Administration Division, Excise Branch, Ottawa, K1A 0L5, and to pay the said customs duties as required.</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-2-2" topmarginspacing="10"><Text>Signature of Applicant <LeaderRightJustified leader="solid" /></Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-2-2" topmarginspacing="10"><Text>Official Designation <LeaderRightJustified leader="solid" /></Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-2-2" topmarginspacing="10"><Text>Street Address <LeaderRightJustified leader="solid" /></Text></Provision><Provision first-line-indent="2" subsequent-line-indent="5"><Label><Emphasis style="italic">Note</Emphasis>:</Label><Text>If the applicant is other than the Head of the Mission, this application should also be signed by the Head of Mission as indicating approval.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-2-2" topmarginspacing="10"><Text>Signature of Head of Mission <LeaderRightJustified leader="solid" /></Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-2-2" topmarginspacing="10"><Text>Official Designation <LeaderRightJustified leader="solid" /></Text></Provision></Provision><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Seal</TitleText></Heading><Provision first-line-indent="2" subsequent-line-indent="5"><Label><Emphasis style="italic">Note</Emphasis>:</Label><Text>Three completed copies of this application with customer’s order or sales invoice attached shall be delivered to the local Customs and Excise Office for approval and processing.</Text></Provision><HistoricalNote>SOR/88-86, s. 8.</HistoricalNote></Schedule></Regulation>