<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 972</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2006</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>3</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">DEPARTMENT OF INDUSTRY ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Metric Commission Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order to Establish a Preparatory Commission for Conversion to the Metric System</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order maybe cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Metric Commission Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In this Order,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Commission</DefinedTermEn> means the Preparatory Commission for Metric Conversion established pursuant to section 3; (<DefinedTermFr>Commission</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Minister</DefinedTermEn> means the Minister of Consumer and Corporate Affairs. (<DefinedTermFr>Ministre</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><HistoricalNote>SI/82-25.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Establishment of Commission</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>A committee is hereby established to be known as the Preparatory Commission for Metric Conversion, consisting of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a full-time member who shall be the Chairman of the Commission, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>not more than 20 part-time members.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>The Commission may make such rules as may be necessary for the conduct of its meetings and the performance of its duties.</Text></Section><Section><Label>5</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The Governor in Council may, upon the request of the Commission, provide the Commission with the services of such officers and employees employed by or in any department of the Government of Canada as are necessary for the proper conduct of the business of the Commission, and the Commission may obtain the advice and assistance of any department or agency of the Government of Canada.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The Commission may engage such organizations or persons having a technical or specialized knowledge on any matter relating to the work of the Commission to advise and assist the Commission in the performance of its duties.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Purposes and Powers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>The Commission is established for the purpose of advising the Minister on plans for conversion to the metric system, and for such purpose, the Commission may</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>initiate, coordinate and undertake investigations, surveys and studies relating to the implications of conversion to the metric system in different sectors of the Canadian economy;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>prepare, in consultation and cooperation with any department or agency of the Government of Canada, any department or agency of the government of any province, the Standards Council of Canada, or other interested parties an overall program for conversion to the metric system which will ensure, as far as possible, that any programs for such conversion in the different sectors of the Canadian economy are phased and coordinated in order that</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the benefits of conversion to the metric system are achieved at minimal cost, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>conversion to the metric system as a whole is effected to the best advantage to Canada; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>furnish, publish and disseminate information concerning conversion to the metric system.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>7</Label><Text>The Commission shall advise the Minister on the need for legislation or any other action that may be required to facilitate conversion to the metric system.</Text></Section><Section><Label>8</Label><Text>The Commission shall make such reports on its activities from time to time as the Minister may require.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Oath</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>9</Label><Text>Each member of the Commission shall, before taking up his duties, take and subscribe an oath or affirmation in the following form:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>“I, <Leader leader="dot" length="4pc" />, solemnly and sincerely swear (or affirm) that I will faithfully and honestly fulfil the duties that devolve upon me by reason of my appointment as a member of the Preparatory Commission for Metric Conversion and that I will not, without due authority in that behalf, disclose or make known any matter that comes to my knowledge by reason of such appointment.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>(In the case where an oath is taken add, “So help me God”)”.</Text></Provision></Section></Body></Regulation>