<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 182</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>05</MM><DD>26</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS MARKETING ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Ontario Egg Marketing Levies Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Providing for the Fixing, Imposing and Collecting of Levies from Certain Egg Producers in Ontario</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Ontario Egg Marketing Levies Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In this Order,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means <XRefExternal reference-type="act">The Farm Products Marketing Act</XRefExternal> of Ontario; (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>allotment</DefinedTermEn> means the total number of dozens of eggs that a producer is entitled to market in intraprovincial, interprovincial and export trade pursuant to the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Canadian Egg Marketing Agency Quota Regulations</XRefExternal> and the orders made by the Commodity Board under the Plan; (<DefinedTermFr>production autorisée</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Commodity Board</DefinedTermEn> means The Ontario Egg Producers’ Marketing Board established pursuant to the Act; (<DefinedTermFr>Office de commercialisation</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>eggs</DefinedTermEn> means eggs of a domestic hen produced in Ontario; (<DefinedTermFr>oeufs</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Plan</DefinedTermEn> means The Ontario Egg Producers’ Marketing Plan, established and amended from time to time pursuant to the Act, and any Regulations made pursuant to the Act to give effect to the Plan; (<DefinedTermFr>Plan</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>producer</DefinedTermEn> means any person engaged in the production of eggs in the Province of Ontario. (<DefinedTermFr>producteur</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Levies</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Every producer shall pay to the Commodity Board, in addition to the service charges set out under the Plan, levies at the rate of $0.05 per dozen of eggs sold by him.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Every producer shall pay to the Commodity Board, in addition to the service charges set out under the Plan, levies at the rate of $0.35 per dozen of eggs sold by him that is in excess of his allotment.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Method of Payment</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Every operator of an egg grading station who buys eggs from a producer shall deduct from the moneys payable to the producer for the eggs all levies payable by the producer to the Commodity Board under section 3 and shall pay such levies to the Commodity Board at its office, 5799 Yonge Street, Willowdale, Ontario, not later than 10 days from the last day of the week in which the eggs were bought.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Every producer shall pay to the Commodity Board at its office, 5799 Yonge Street, Willowdale, Ontario, all levies payable by him under section 3 that were not deducted and paid to the Commodity Board in the manner prescribed by subsection (1) in respect of eggs sold by him in any month not later than the 15th day of the month next following.</Text></Subsection></Section></Body></Regulation>