<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 16</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>3</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AERONAUTICS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>United States Service Aircraft Over-Flight Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting Flights of United States Service Aircraft Over Canadian Territory</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">United States Service Aircraft Over-Flight Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>Aircraft belonging to the United States and operated by the United States armed services or the Department of Defence of the United States may, on a reciprocal basis and subject to these Regulations and in compliance with orders and directions issued by the Minister of National Defence, fly in or over, land in and take off from Canada and the territorial waters thereof.</Text></Section><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>Subject to such exceptions and conditions as may be prescribed by the Minister of National Defence, the flight of aircraft referred to in section 2 over areas that are or may be prescribed as prohibited or restricted areas by or with the approval of the Governor in Council and such other areas as are designated by the Minister is prohibited.</Text></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>Unless the Minister of National Defence otherwise directs, aircraft referred to in section 2, while in or over Canada and the territorial waters thereof, are subject to the same rules and regulations for the safe and proper operation of aircraft in Canada that apply to Canadian Forces aircraft and are under the control of the same agencies as are Canadian Forces aircraft.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>