<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 80</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2011</YYYY><MM>10</MM><DD>24</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AERONAUTICS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Chilliwack Airport Zoning Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting Zoning at Chilliwack Airport</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Chilliwack Airport Zoning Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>airport</DefinedTermEn> means Chilliwack Airport, Township of Chilliwack, in the Province of British Columbia; (<DefinedTermFr>aéroport</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>airport reference point</DefinedTermEn> means the point determined in the manner set out in Part I of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>point de repère de l’aéroport</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>approach surface</DefinedTermEn> means an imaginary inclined plane extending upward and outward from each end of a strip along and at right angles to the projected centre line thereof, which approach surface is more particularly described in Part II of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>surface d’approche</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Minister</DefinedTermEn> means the Minister of Transport; (<DefinedTermFr>ministre</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>strip</DefinedTermEn> means the rectangular portion of the landing area of the airport including the runway prepared for the take-off and landing of aircraft in a particular direction, which strip is more particularly described in Part III of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>bande</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>transitional surface</DefinedTermEn> means an imaginary inclined plane extending upward and outward from the lateral limits of the strip and its approach surfaces, which transitional surface is more particularly described in Part IV of the schedule. (<DefinedTermFr>surface de transition</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>For the purposes of these Regulations, the airport reference point is deemed to be 27 feet above sea level.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>These Regulations apply to all the lands and lands under water, including public road allowances, adjacent to or in the vicinity of the airport that are situated vertically beneath the approach surfaces and the transitional surfaces, other than such lands as from time to time form part of the airport.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>No person shall erect or construct, on any land to which these Regulations apply, any building, structure or object or any addition to any existing building, structure or object, the highest point of which will exceed in elevation at the location of that point any of the surfaces hereinafter set out that project immediately over and above the surface of the land at that location, namely</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the approach surfaces; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the transitional surfaces.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Natural Growth</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>Where an object of natural growth on any land to which these Regulations apply exceeds in elevation any of the surfaces referred to in section 5, the Minister may make a direction that the owner or occupier of the land on which that object is growing remove the excessive growth.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/81-169, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>7</Label><Text><Repealed>[Revoked, SOR/81-169, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Section></Body><Schedule bilingual="no" spanlanguages="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 2)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><Heading level="1"><Label>PART I</Label><TitleText>Airport Reference Point</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Being a point five hundred (500) feet measured northerly at right angles from a point on the centre line of runway 07-25 distant one thousand (1,000) feet measured easterly along that centre line from the westerly end of that runway.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART II</Label><TitleText>Description of Each Approach Surface</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Being a surface abutting each end of the strip associated with runway 07-25 and more particularly described as follows:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a surface abutting the end of the strip associated with runway approach 07 consisting of an inclined plane having a ratio of one (1) foot measured vertically to forty (40) feet measured horizontally rising to an imaginary horizontal line drawn at right angles to the projected centre line of the strip, two hundred and fifty (250) feet measured vertically above the elevation at the end of the strip and distant ten thousand (10,000) feet measured horizontally from the end of the strip, the outer ends of the imaginary horizontal line being fourteen hundred (1,400) feet from the projected centre line, and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a surface abutting the end of the strip associated with runway approach 25 consisting of an inclined plane having a ratio of one (1) foot measured vertically to forty (40) feet measured horizontally rising to an imaginary horizontal line drawn at right angles to the projected centre line of the strip two hundred and fifty (250) feet measured vertically above the elevation at the end of the strip and distant ten thousand (10,000) feet measured horizontally from the end of the strip, the outer ends of the imaginary horizontal line being fourteen hundred (1,400) feet from the projected centre line,</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>which approach surfaces are shown outlined blue on Department of Transport Plan B.C. 1123, dated December 10, 1975.</Text></Provision></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART III</Label><TitleText>Description of Strip</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The strip associated with runway 07-25 is three hundred (300) feet in width, one hundred and fifty (150) feet being on each side of the centre line of the runway, and four thousand four hundred (4,400) feet in length, which strip is shown outlined green on Department of Transport Plan B.C. 1123, dated December 10, 1975.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART IV</Label><TitleText>Description of Each Transitional Surface</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Being a surface consisting of an inclined plane rising at a ratio of one (1) foot measured vertically to seven (7) feet measured horizontally at right angles to the centre line and centre line produced of the strip, extending upward and outward from the lateral limits of the strip and its approach surfaces to an elevation of one hundred and fifty (150) feet, measured vertically above the assigned elevation of the airport reference point, which transitional surface is shown outlined red on Department of Transport Plan B.C. 1123, dated December 10, 1975.</Text></Provision></Schedule></Regulation>