<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 1472</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>8</MM><DD>4</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CANADA SHIPPING ACT, 2001</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Ship Radio Inspection Fees Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting Fees to be Charged for Ship Radio Inspections</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Ship Radio Inspection Fees Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Shipping Act</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>certificate</DefinedTermEn> means a Safety Convention certificate as described in the Act or a radio inspection certificate that is issued to a ship required to be fitted with a radio installation pursuant to the Act or regulations made thereunder; (<DefinedTermFr>certificat ou brevet</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Department</DefinedTermEn> means the Department of Transport. (<DefinedTermFr>ministère</DefinedTermFr>) </Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>life boat radio inspection</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Revoked, SOR/78-668, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>radiotelegraph inspection</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Revoked, SOR/78-668, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>radiotelephone inspection</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Revoked, SOR/78-668, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><HistoricalNote>SOR/78-668, s. 1; 1987, c. 7, s. 84(F).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>These Regulations apply to Canadian ships and to ships registered elsewhere than in Canada.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Fees for Inspection</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>A fee shall be payable for an inspection carried out by a radio inspector of the Department comprising</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the amount of every expense for which the inspector would be reimbursed in accordance with the Treasury Board Travel Directive, as amended or revised from time to time; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>where any part of the inspection takes place outside the inspector’s regular working hours, an amount equal to the compensation that would be payable to the inspector in respect of the period of time occupied by that part of the inspection under the Agreement signed the 26th August, 1977 and made between the Treasury Board and the International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 2228, Electronics Group (all employees) or any subsequent agreement between those parties that replaces that Agreement.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/78-668, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Payment of Fees</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Where a Canadian ship is inspected, the fee prescribed by section 4 shall be paid by the owner of the ship upon receipt of an invoice in respect of the inspection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Where a ship registered elsewhere than in Canada is inspected, no document certifying that the ship complies with the radio requirements of the Act or regulations made thereunder shall be issued until the radio inspector who made the inspection has received from</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the master of the ship or a person authorized by the master, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the owner or agent of the ship,</Text></Paragraph><ContinuedSectionSubsection><Text>a written authorization for the fee prescribed by section 4 to be paid by the owner.</Text></ContinuedSectionSubsection></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/78-668, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Exemption</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>Notwithstanding anything in these Regulations, the fee prescribed by section 4 does not apply to a ship registered in the United States where the ship’s radiotelephone installation has been inspected for the purpose of issuing a certificate valid for a period that will enable the ship to proceed to a Great Lakes’ port in the United States for inspection by an officer of the government of the United States pursuant to the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Agreement between Canada and the United States for the Promotion of Safety on the Great Lakes by Means of Radio</XRefExternal>.</Text><HistoricalNote>1987, c. 7, s. 84(F).</HistoricalNote></Section></Body><Schedule bilingual="no" spanlanguages="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label></ScheduleFormHeading><Repealed>[Revoked, SOR/78-668, s. 4]</Repealed></Schedule></Regulation>