<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 803</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>11</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">FRESHWATER FISH MARKETING ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Carrier Exemption Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Exempting Certain Carriers from Application of Paragraphs 21(1)(b) and (c) of the Freshwater Fish Marketing Act</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Carrier Exemption Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations, “Act” means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Freshwater Fish Marketing Act</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Exemption</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>Subject to section 4, carriers to which the legislative authority of the Parliament of Canada extends are exempted from the provisions of paragraphs 21(1)(b) and (c) of the Act.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The exemption referred to in section 3 shall apply only when the exempted carriers are requested to send, convey or carry, or to receive for carriage and delivery, fish as defined in the Act by the Corporation or an agent of the Corporation or by a person or persons licensed by the Corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Where a carrier is exempted pursuant to section 3, the bills of lading or other contracts for carriage issued by the carrier to carry and deliver fish, shall bear the number of the licence issued to the sender or vendor by the Corporation or shall bear a signed statement attesting that the sender or vendor is an authorized agent of the Corporation.</Text></Subsection></Section></Body></Regulation>