<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 275</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>27</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS MARKETING ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Saskatchewan Hog Farm Registration (Interprovincial and Export) Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting the Registration of the Farm of Certain Persons Engaged in the Marketing in Interprovincial and Export Trade of Hogs Produced in Saskatchewan</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Saskatchewan Hog Farm Registration (Interprovincial and Export) Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means <XRefExternal reference-type="act">The Natural Products Marketing Act, 1972</XRefExternal> of Saskatchewan; (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Commission</DefinedTermEn> means the Saskatchewan Hog Marketing Commission established pursuant to the Act and the Plan; (<DefinedTermFr>Commission</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>hog</DefinedTermEn> means any member of the species <Language xml:lang="la">Sus Scrofa L.</Language> (domestic pig) produced in Saskatchewan; (<DefinedTermFr>porc</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Plan</DefinedTermEn> means the Saskatchewan Hog Marketing Plan established and amended from time to time pursuant to the Act; (<DefinedTermFr>Plan</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>producer</DefinedTermEn> means</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any person engaged in producing or feeding hogs and making them available for slaughter and includes the employer of any such person,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any person who, under any lease or agreement, is entitled to a share of the hogs produced or fed by a person referred to in paragraph (a), and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>any person who takes possession of any hogs from any person under any form of security for a debt. (<DefinedTermFr>producteur</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>These Regulations apply only to the marketing of hogs in interprovincial and export trade and to persons and property situated in the Province of Saskatchewan.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Farm Unit Registration</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>No producer shall market hogs unless he has been allocated a farm unit registration number by the Commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A producer may apply to the Commission for a farm unit registration number at the time of marketing his first shipment of hogs through the Commission.</Text></Subsection></Section></Body></Regulation>