<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 162</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>10</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS MARKETING ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>New Brunswick Egg Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Granting Authority to Fix, Impose and Collect a Levy on the Marketing of Eggs Produced in New Brunswick</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">New Brunswick Egg Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In this Order,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Natural Products Control Act</XRefExternal> of New Brunswick; (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Commodity Board</DefinedTermEn> means the New Brunswick Egg Marketing Board established pursuant to the Act; (<DefinedTermFr>Office de commercialisation</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>egg</DefinedTermEn> means the egg of a hen produced in New Brunswick; (<DefinedTermFr>oeuf</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>hen</DefinedTermEn> means the hen of any class of the domestic chicken belonging to the species <Language xml:lang="la">Gallus Domesticus</Language>. (<DefinedTermFr>poule</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Levies</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>The Commodity Board is authorized</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/80-90]</Repealed></Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in relation to the powers that may be granted to it with respect to the marketing of eggs in interprovincial and export trade</Text></Paragraph><ContinuedSectionSubsection><Text>to make orders fixing, imposing and collecting levies or charges from persons situated within the Province of New Brunswick who are engaged in the marketing of eggs and, for such purpose, classifying such persons into groups and fixing the levies or charges payable by the members of the different groups in different amounts and the Commodity Board may use such levies or charges for its purposes, including the creation of reserves and the payment of expenses and losses resulting from the sale or disposal of eggs and the equalization or adjustment among the producers of eggs of moneys realized from the sale thereof during such period or periods of time as it may determine.</Text></ContinuedSectionSubsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/80-90.</HistoricalNote></Section></Body></Regulation>