<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 1482</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>8</MM><DD>5</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CANADA SHIPPING ACT, 2001</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Ships’ Elevator Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting Elevators in Ships</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Ships’ Elevator Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>competent person</DefinedTermEn> means an elevator inspector employed as such in Canada by  a provincial government or a company engaged in the manufacture of elevators or escalators that meet the requirements of the C.S.A. Code;</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>C.S.A. Code</DefinedTermEn> means the Canadian Standards Association Code B 44 entitled <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Safety Code for Elevators, Dumbwaiters, Escalators and Moving Walks</XRefExternal>;</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>inspector</DefinedTermEn> means a steamship inspector appointed pursuant to Part VIII of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Shipping Act</XRefExternal>.</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>These Regulations apply to elevators and escalators that are used primarily  to carry persons, and that are installed on Canadian ships or ships engaged in the coasting trade of Canada.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Elevators and Escalators</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The design, construction, installation, inspection, testing and alteration of every elevator or escalator shall comply with the applicable provisions of the C.S.A. Code that was in force at the time that the elevator or escalator was installed except that elevators or escalators installed after January 1, 1976 shall comply with C.S.A. Code B 44-1975.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>When an inspection of elevators or escalators is performed by a competent person, the owner of the elevator or escalator shall provide the inspector with a document duly signed by the competent person that states that the elevator or escalator complies with the provisions of the applicable C.S.A. Code.</Text></Subsection></Section></Body></Regulation>