<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 217</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>31</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS MARKETING ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Ontario Milk Marketing Levies Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Providing for the Fixing, Imposing and Collecting of Levies From Certain Milk Producers in Ontario</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Ontario Milk Marketing Levies Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In this Order,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Commodity Board</DefinedTermEn> means The Ontario Milk Marketing Board established by Order of the Lieutenant-Governor in Council of Ontario pursuant to <XRefExternal reference-type="act">The Milk Act</XRefExternal> of Ontario; (<DefinedTermFr>Office de commercialisation</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>milk</DefinedTermEn> means milk from cows; (<DefinedTermFr>lait</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>producer</DefinedTermEn> means a producer who sells milk to the Commodity Board; (<DefinedTermFr>producteur</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>quota</DefinedTermEn> means a quota in pounds of milk fixed and allotted by the Commodity Board to a producer in relation to the volume of sales of the Commodity Board of Classes 3, 4, 5 and 6 milk as established by Ontario Regulation 139/70. (<DefinedTermFr>contingent</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Levies</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Every producer shall pay to the Commodity Board, in addition to the licence fees set out in The Ontario Milk Marketing Plan, levies at the rate of $1.20 for 100 pounds of milk or $0.3429 per pound of butterfat sold by him to the Commodity Board that is not in excess of the quota fixed and allotted to him.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Every producer shall pay to the Commodity Board, in addition to the licence fees set out in the Ontario Milk Marketing Plan, levies at the rate of $7 for each 100 pounds of milk or $2 per pound of butterfat sold by him to the Commodity Board that is in excess of the quota fixed and allotted to him.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The Commodity Board shall deduct from the moneys payable to a producer all levies payable by the producer to the Commodity Board under subsection (1) or (2).</Text></Subsection></Section></Body></Regulation>