<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 270</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>27</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS MARKETING ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Saskatchewan Egg Marketing Levies Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Providing for the Fixing, Imposing and Collecting of Levies From Certain Egg Producers in Saskatchewan</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Saskatchewan Egg Marketing Levies Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In this Order,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means <XRefExternal reference-type="act">The Natural Products Marketing Act</XRefExternal> of Saskatchewan; (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Commodity Board</DefinedTermEn> means The Saskatchewan Commercial Egg Producers’ Marketing Board established pursuant to the Act; (<DefinedTermFr>Office de commercialisation</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>eggs</DefinedTermEn> means any shell eggs of the domestic hen offered for sale for human consumption and produced in Saskatchewan; (<DefinedTermFr>oeufs</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>layer</DefinedTermEn> means a female chicken over six months of age that may produce eggs; (<DefinedTermFr>pondeuse</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>period</DefinedTermEn> means a period of three consecutive calendar months commencing on January 1st, April 1st, July 1st or October 1st in any year; (<DefinedTermFr>période</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Plan</DefinedTermEn> means the Saskatchewan Commercial Egg Producers’ Marketing Plan established and amended from time to time pursuant to the Act; (<DefinedTermFr>Plan</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>producer</DefinedTermEn> means any person operating facilities for the production of eggs in the Province of Saskatchewan and marketing the production of 300 or more layers at any time during the calendar year; (<DefinedTermFr>producteur</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>quota</DefinedTermEn> means the number of layers the eggs of which a producer may market pursuant to quota orders made by the Commodity Board. (<DefinedTermFr>contingent</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Levies</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Every producer shall pay to the Commodity Board, in addition to service charges set forth under the Plan, levies at the rate of $0.0125 per period for each layer in each period when the layer</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>is available for production at any given time during that period; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>is not in excess of the quota fixed and allotted to him.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>No levy is payable during any period for a layer that replaces another layer in respect of which a levy referred to in subsection (1) is payable or has been paid during that period.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>Every producer shall, in respect of every period, pay to the Commodity Board, not later than the 15th day of the month following the month in which the period commenced, the levies referred to in section 3.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>