<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 378</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>30</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">BROADCASTING ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Direction to the CRTC (Reservation of Cable Channels)</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Direction Issued to the Canadian Radio-Television and Telecommunications Commission Respecting the Reservation of Cable Channels</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Direction to the CRTC (Reservation of Cable Channels)</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Directions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>The Canadian Radio-television and Telecommunications Commission is hereby directed that on or after March 19, 1970, a licence to operate a broadcasting receiving undertaking may not be issued or renewed in respect of any such undertaking situated in a province where the provincial authority of the province has given notice in writing to the Commission that it desires that cable transmission facilities of that undertaking be reserved for the use of the provincial authority for the purpose of broadcasting, at times stipulated in the notice, the types of programming defined in the appendix, and has satisfied the Commission that it has the present intention of using such facilities within a reasonable period of time, unless the Commission stipulates that at least one channel of the undertaking be reserved for the use of the provincial authority for that purpose.</Text></Section><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>In this Direction, "provincial authority" means a provincial authority as defined in the appendix.</Text></Section></Body><Schedule bilingual="no" spanlanguages="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><TitleText>Appendix Definition of the Reservation of Educational Broadcasting Time and Facilities</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><RegulationPiece><Body><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>Where, within its jurisdiction, the Canadian Radio-television and Telecommunications Commission, on the direction of the Governor in Council, stipulates that at least one channel of a cable transmission facility be set aside for the use of a provincial authority for educational broadcasting or where the Canadian Broadcasting Corporation acts as agent of Her Majesty in right of Canada in providing a transmission facility for the use of a provincial authority for educational broadcasting, the time reserved on such channel or transmission facility for the provincial authority shall be used for broadcasting the following types of programming:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>programming designed to be presented in such a context as to provide a continuity of learning opportunity aimed at the acquisition or improvement of knowledge or the enlargement of understanding of members of the audience to whom such programming is directed and under circumstances such that the acquisition or improvement of such knowledge or the enlargement of such understanding is subject to supervision or assessment by the provincial authority by any appropriate means; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>programming providing information on the available courses of instruction or involving the broadcasting of special education events within the educational system.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>2</Label><Text><DefinedTermEn>Provincial authority</DefinedTermEn>, in relation to any province, means such person, body or authority as may be designated by the lieutenant governor in council of that province as the provincial authority for that province for the purposes of this definition.</Text></Section><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>The intention of this Appendix is to ensure that such programming, taken as a whole, shall be designed to furnish educational opportunities and shall be distinctly different from general broadcasting available on the public or private channels.</Text></Section></Body></RegulationPiece></Schedule></Regulation>