<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 394</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>30</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CANADIAN BILL OF RIGHTS</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Canadian Bill of Rights Examination Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting the Examination of Bills and Regulations Pursuant to the Canadian Bill of Rights</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Canadian Bill of Rights Examination Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations, <DefinedTermEn>Minister</DefinedTermEn> means the Minister of Justice.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Examination of Bills</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>In the case of every Bill introduced in or presented to the House of Commons by a Minister of the Crown, the Minister shall, forthwith upon receipt of two copies of the Bill from the Clerk of the House of Commons,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>examine the Bill in order to determine whether any of the provisions thereof are inconsistent with the purposes and provisions of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canadian Bill of Rights</XRefExternal>, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>cause to be affixed to each of the copies thereof so received from the Clerk of the House of Commons a certificate, in a form approved by the Minister and signed by the Deputy Minister of Justice, stating that the Bill has been examined as required by the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canadian Bill of Rights</XRefExternal>,</Text></Paragraph><ContinuedSectionSubsection><Text>and one each of the copies thereof so certified shall thereupon be transmitted to the Clerk of the House of Commons and the Clerk of the Privy Council.</Text></ContinuedSectionSubsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/85-782, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Examination of Regulations</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>The Clerk of the Privy Council shall, on receipt of a regulation transmitted to him for registration pursuant to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Statutory Instruments Act</XRefExternal> but not examined as a proposed regulation in accordance with section 3 of that Act, forward a copy thereof to the Minister.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/85-782, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>The Minister shall, forthwith upon receipt of a copy of a regulation forwarded to him by the Clerk of the Privy Council pursuant to section 4,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>examine the regulation in order to determine whether any of the provisions thereof are inconsistent with the purposes and provisions of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canadian Bill of Rights</XRefExternal>, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>cause to be affixed to the copy thereof so received from the Clerk of the Privy Council a certificate, in a form approved by the Minister and signed by the Deputy Minister of Justice, stating that the regulation has been examined as required by the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canadian Bill of Rights</XRefExternal>,</Text></Paragraph><ContinuedSectionSubsection><Text>and the copy so certified shall thereupon be returned to the Clerk of the Privy Council.</Text></ContinuedSectionSubsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Report of the Minister</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>Where any of the provisions of any Bill examined by the Minister pursuant to section 3 or any of the provisions of any regulation examined by him pursuant to section 5 are ascertained by the Minister to be inconsistent with the purposes and provisions of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canadian Bill of Rights</XRefExternal>, the Minister shall make a report in writing of the inconsistency and shall cause such report to be deposited with the Clerk of the House of Commons in accordance with the Standing Orders of the House of Commons at the earliest convenient opportunity.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/85-782, s. 3; SOR/86-41, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>7</Label><Text>A copy of every report made by the Minister pursuant to section 6 shall, where such report relates to a regulation, be transmitted to the Clerk of the Privy Council forthwith upon the making thereof.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>