<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 1283</InstrumentNumber><LastAmendedDate><Date><YYYY>2004</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>29</DD></Date></LastAmendedDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>7</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CANADA POST CORPORATION ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Materials for the Use of the Blind Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting the Conditions Under Which Materials for the Use of the Blind may be Sent by Post Free of Postage</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Materials for the Use of the Blind Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText><HistoricalNote>[SOR/2000-199, s. 3(F)]</HistoricalNote></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>The following definitions apply in these Regulations.</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>material for the use of the blind</DefinedTermEn> means</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>matter impressed in Braille or similar raised type;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>plates for manufacturing matter described in paragraph (a),</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>tapes, records and other sound recordings posted by the blind in Canada; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>tapes, records, other sound recordings and special paper intended solely for the use of the blind if mailed by or addressed to a recognized institution for the blind. (<DefinedTermFr>documentation à l’usage des aveugles</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>postage</DefinedTermEn> means the charge payable for the handling and conveyance of material for the use of the blind. (<DefinedTermFr>affranchissement</DefinedTermFr>) </Text></Definition><HistoricalNote>SOR/83-800, s. 1; SOR/86-245, s. 1; SOR/94-203, s. 1; SOR/2000-199, s. 4; SOR/2003-379, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Limits of Size</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>Material for the use of the blind sent by post in Canada may be sent free of postage if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for delivery in Canada,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the combined length, width and depth of the material does not exceed 2 m with the greatest measurement not exceeding 1 m, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the material is not less than 10 cm in length and 7 cm in width;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for delivery outside Canada,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the combined length, width and depth of the material does not exceed 90 cm with the greatest measurement not exceeding 60 cm, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the material is not less than 14 cm in length and 9 cm in width.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/79-194, s. 1; SOR/2003-379, s. 1; SOR/2008-285, s. 1(F).</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>4 and 5</Label><Text><Repealed>[Revoked, SOR/83-800, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Maximum Weight</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>The maximum weight of any item of material for the use of the blind that may be sent by post under these Regulations is 7 kg.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/79-194, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Conditions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>7</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Every item of material for the use of the blind shall, if for delivery in Canada,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>by means of marking, printing or labelling, bear the words “Literature for the blind” or “Documentation à l’usage des aveugles” in the upper right corner on the address side of the item; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>bear on the address side of the item a label in a form approved by the Corporation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Every item of material for the use of the blind shall, if for delivery outside of Canada,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>by means of marking, printing or labelling, bear the words “Cécogrammes” or “Cécogrammes (Literature for the blind)” in the upper right corner on the address side of the item; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>bear on the address side of the item a label in a form approved by the Corporation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Every item referred to in subsection (2) shall meet all applicable customs documentation requirements as described in the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">International Letter-Post Items Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Every item of material for the use of the blind shall be prepared for posting in such a way that its contents are sufficiently protected while permitting quick and easy verification.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>Every item of material for the use of the blind shall be accepted for registered mail or, in Canada, Xpresspost<Sup>TM</Sup> mail at no charge.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/81-387, s. 1; SOR/94-203, s. 2; SOR/2003-379, s. 2; SOR/2004-297, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section></Body><Schedule bilingual="no" spanlanguages="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label></ScheduleFormHeading><Repealed>[Revoked, SOR/82-28, s. 2]</Repealed></Schedule></Regulation>