<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 732</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>11</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Search, Reproduction and Certification of Documents Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Prescribing the Fees for the Search, Reproduction and Certification of Documents</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Search, Reproduction and Certification of Documents Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>copy</DefinedTermEn> means a reproduction in any form of a document contained in the files of the Department or an extract therefrom; (<DefinedTermFr>copie</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Department</DefinedTermEn> means the Department of National Revenue; (<DefinedTermFr>ministère</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>document</DefinedTermEn> means an invoice, entry or other customs form relating to a specific importation or exportation; (<DefinedTermFr>document</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>search</DefinedTermEn> means the act of obtaining a document or information from a document contained in the files of the Department in response to a request by an importer or an exporter or any person lawfully acting on behalf thereof. (<DefinedTermFr>compulsation</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Fees</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>A fee of $0.75 shall be paid</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for each search required to obtain a document for perusal by an importer or an exporter or any person lawfully acting on behalf thereof or to confirm the accuracy of information appearing on copies of a document submitted for certification; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for certification of each document.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/86-217, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>In addition to the fees specified in section 3, a fee of $3.00 shall be paid for the reproduction of a document by the Department.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/86-217, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>Notwithstanding sections 3 and 4, no fee shall be paid for a search or for reproduction or certification of a document where that search, reproduction or certification is performed at the request of a foreign government.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>