<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 109</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2012</YYYY><MM>2</MM><DD>27</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AERONAUTICS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Sault Ste. Marie Airport Zoning Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting Zoning at Sault Ste. Marie Airport</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Sault Ste. Marie Airport Zoning Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>airport</DefinedTermEn> means Sault Ste. Marie Airport, in the District of Algoma, in the Province of Ontario; (<DefinedTermFr>aéroport</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>airport reference point</DefinedTermEn> means the point described in Part I of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>point de repère de l’aéroport</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>approach surface</DefinedTermEn> means an imaginary inclined plane extending outward and upward from the end of a strip at a ratio of 50 feet measured horizontally to 1 foot measured vertically, the lower ends of which plane is a horizontal line at right angles to the centre line of the strip at the strip ends, which approach surface is shown on Plan No. T2557, dated February 28, 1969, on record in the Department of Transport at Ottawa; (<DefinedTermFr>surface d’approche</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>horizontal surface</DefinedTermEn> means an imaginary horizontal plane located 150 feet above the assigned elevation of the airport reference point; (<DefinedTermFr>surface horizontale</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Minister</DefinedTermEn> means the Minister of Transport; (<DefinedTermFr>ministre</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>strip</DefinedTermEn> means a rectangular portion of the landing area of the airport including the runway especially prepared for the take-off and landing of aircraft in a particular direction, the dimensions of which strip are set out in Part II of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>bande</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>transitional surface</DefinedTermEn> means an imaginary inclined plane extending upward and outward at a ratio of 7 feet measured horizontally to 1 foot measured vertically from the outer lateral limits of a strip and its approach surface to an intersection with the horizontal surface or other transitional surfaces, which transitional surfaces are shown on Plan No. T2557, dated February 28, 1969, on record in the Department of Transport at Ottawa. (<DefinedTermFr>surface de transition</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>For the purposes of these Regulations, the airport reference point is deemed to be 611 feet above sea level.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (2), these Regulations apply to all the lands, including public road allowances, adjacent to or in the vicinity of the airport, the outer limits of which are more particularly described as follows:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>COMMENCING at the northeasterly corner of Section 1, in the Township of Parke; THENCE, westerly along the northern boundary of Sections 1, 2, 3, 4 and the northeast quarter of Section 5 to the intersection thereof with the waters edge of Lake Superior; THENCE, in a general southeasterly, easterly and northeasterly direction along the waters edge of Lake Superior and of St. Mary’s River to the intersection thereof with the eastern boundary of Section 12, in the Township of Parke; THENCE, northerly along the eastern boundary of Section 12 and Section 1 to the point of commencement, which lands are shown on Plan No. T2557, dated February 28, 1969, on record in the Department of Transport at Ottawa.</Text></Provision></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>These Regulations do not apply with respect to such of those lands referred to in subsection (1) that form part of the airport from time to time.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>Subject to section 6, no person shall erect or construct, on any land to which these Regulations apply, any building, structure or object or any addition to any existing building, structure or object, the highest point of which will exceed in elevation at the location of the highest point any of the surfaces hereinafter set out that project immediately over and above the surface of the land at that location, namely,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the horizontal surface;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the approach surfaces abutting each end of the strips designated as 04-22 and 11-29 and extending outward therefrom, the dimensions of which approach surfaces are five hundred (500) feet on each side of the centre line of the strips at the strip ends and two thousand (2,000) feet on each side of the projected centre line of the strips at the outer ends, the said outer ends being two hundred (200) feet above the elevations at the strip ends and measured horizontally ten thousand (10,000) feet from the strip ends; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the transitional surfaces.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>A person may erect or construct any building, structure or object or any addition to any existing building, structure or object, the highest point of which will not exceed in elevation the elevation at that point of any approach surface or transitional surface referred to in section 5 that projects immediately over and above the surface of the land at that point but will exceed in elevation the elevation at that point of the horizontal surface, if the highest point of such building, structure or object or addition to such existing building, structure or object, will not extend more than thirty feet (30) above the surface of the land at that point.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Natural Growth</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>7</Label><Text>Where an object of natural growth on any land to which these Regulations apply exceeds in elevation any of the surfaces set out in paragraphs 5(a) to (c), the Minister may make a direction that the owner or occupier of the land on which that object is growing remove the excessive growth thereof.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/79-899, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>8</Label><Text><Repealed>[Revoked, SOR/79-899, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Section></Body><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label><OriginatingRef>(Sections 2 and 4)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><Heading level="1"><Label>PART I</Label><TitleText>Airport Reference Point</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Being the point of intersection of a line drawn parallel to the centre line of runway 04-22, distant five hundred (500) feet measured southeasterly therefrom and at right angles thereto with a line drawn parallel to the centre line of runway 11-29 distant five hundred (500) feet measured northeasterly therefrom and at right angles thereto.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART II</Label><TitleText>Dimensions of Each Strip</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The strips associated with runway 04-22 and runway 11-29 are one thousand (1,000) feet in width, five hundred (500) feet being on each side of the centre line of the runway, and eighty-six hundred (8,600) feet in length as shown on Plan No. T2557, dated February 28, 1969, on record in the Department of Transport at Ottawa.</Text></Provision></Schedule></Regulation>