<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 611</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>6</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">EXPORT AND IMPORT PERMITS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Export of Goods for Special and Personal Use Permit</ShortTitle><LongTitle>General Export Permit No. Ex. 1</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Permit may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Export of Goods for Special and Personal Use Permit</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to section 4, any person may, under the authority of this General Export Permit, export from Canada to any country any goods that have a value of $100 or less.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Subsection (1) does not authorize the exportation of goods that are separated into units the aggregate value of which exceeds $100.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SI/89-131, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>Subject to section 4, any person may, under the authority of this General Export Permit, export from Canada to any country</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>casual gifts, including those sent by parcel mail, that have a value not exceeding $50 and that are sent to a consignee for the consignee's personal use, but not exceeding one such casual gift per month to the same consignee;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>goods consigned to embassies, legations, high commissioners, trade commissioners or consular offices of Canada or the United Kingdom;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>personal or settler's effects taken or shipped by an individual on leaving Canada and solely for his own use or that of his immediate family and not for resale and being</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>household articles,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>personal effects,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>articles of business equipment, instruments, tools of trade or machinery, if such articles have been used by him in his occupation or employment, are his personal property and will continue to be used by him in his occupation or employment, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>a passenger automobile that is the personal property of the person who is leaving Canada;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>goods returned as being "not as ordered" under the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Goods Not as Ordered Remission Order</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>goods that have been imported into Canada under the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Articles for Special Use Regulations</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>goods in Group 1 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Export Control List</XRefExternal> that have been exported from Canada under a valid export permit and have subsequently been returned to Canada for repair, overhaul or testing, on condition that the exporter presents a copy of the original export permit at the time the goods are exported;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>parts or components for the repair of goods in Group 1 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Export Control List</XRefExternal> that were previously exported under a valid export permit, on condition that the exporter presents a copy of the original export permit at the time the goods are exported and on condition that the repair does not upgrade or otherwise transform the original function of the exported goods; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>goods in Group 1 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Export Control List</XRefExternal> that are being returned to their original manufacturer as unwanted goods or for repair, overhaul or testing, on condition that the goods have not been transformed, remanufactured or otherwise modified in Canada.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SI/89-131, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>This General Export Permit does not authorize</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the export of radioactive goods;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>exports to any country listed on the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Area Control List</XRefExternal>; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>exports of helicopters and their parts as described in item 1460 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Export Control List</XRefExternal>.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SI/89-131, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>Where completion and validation of a customs entry form is required with respect to any goods that are exported under the authority of this General Export Permit, that form shall be endorsed "Exported under the authority of General Export Permit No. Ex. 1" or "Exporté en vertu de la Licence générale d'exportation n<Sup>o</Sup> Ex. 1".</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>