<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 1044</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>19</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">NATIONAL CAPITAL ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>National Capital Commission Traffic and Property Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting the Property of the National Capital Commission and the Operation of Vehicles Thereon</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">National Capital Commission Traffic and Property Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>commercial vehicle</DefinedTermEn> means a vehicle that</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>has attached thereto a truck or delivery body or other attachment for use in the delivery of goods,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>is specially designed or equipped for the delivery of goods,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>bears any sign or lettering advertising the business or wares of any person or organization or displays the name or device of any person or organization by whom the vehicle is owned or on whose behalf the vehicle is operated, other than the name or device of the Royal Canadian Mounted Police, a Department of the Government of Canada or of any corporation established to perform any function or duty on behalf of the Government of Canada,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>is a tractor, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>is a bus, taxicab or other vehicle used or designed for the carrying of passengers for hire; (<DefinedTermFr>véhicule commercial</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Commission</DefinedTermEn> means the National Capital Commission; (<DefinedTermFr>Commission</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>driveway</DefinedTermEn> means that part of the property of the Commission designed and intended for the use of vehicles; (<DefinedTermFr>promenade</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>liquor</DefinedTermEn> means beer, wines, spirits or any other alcoholic beverages; (<DefinedTermFr>boisson</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>motor vehicle</DefinedTermEn> means a vehicle that is capable of being propelled or driven otherwise than by muscular power but does not include an over-snow vehicle; (<DefinedTermFr>véhicule automobile</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>operator</DefinedTermEn> means the driver or the person who is in actual physical control of the vehicle; (<DefinedTermFr>conducteur</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>over-snow vehicle</DefinedTermEn> means a vehicle that is capable of being propelled or driven otherwise than by muscular power, that runs on tracks or skis or on tracks and skis and that is designed for operation on snow or ice; (<DefinedTermFr>véhicule de type auto-neige</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>park</DefinedTermEn> means the standing of a vehicle, whether occupied or not, otherwise than momentarily or under circumstances that are not under the control of the person operating the vehicle; (<DefinedTermFr>laisser en stationnement</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>peace officer</DefinedTermEn> means a peace officer as defined in the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Criminal Code</XRefExternal> and any person authorized by the Commission to enforce or carry out these Regulations; (<DefinedTermFr>agent de la paix</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>vehicle</DefinedTermEn> means a device in, or by means of, which a person or property is or may be transported upon a highway, except any such device used exclusively upon stationary rails or tracks. (<DefinedTermFr>véhicule</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>For the purpose of these Regulations, a trailer is a separate vehicle and does not form part of the vehicle by which it is drawn.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Nothing in these Regulations shall be held to constitute a dedication of any driveway to the public.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/98-389, s. 1(F).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART I</Label><TitleText>Operation of Vehicles</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Registration and Permits</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>No person shall operate a vehicle on a driveway unless</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>he holds all the licences and permits that he is required to hold in order to operate the vehicle in the province and municipality in which the driveway is situated; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the vehicle is registered and equipped as required by the laws of the province and municipality in which the driveway is situated.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Compliance with Provincial and Municipal Laws</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>No person shall operate a vehicle, or cause or permit a vehicle that he has the right to control to be operated, on a driveway otherwise than in accordance with the laws of the province and municipality in which the driveway is situated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>No person shall park a vehicle on a driveway except in compliance with the laws of the province and municipality in which the driveway is situated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>In this section, the expression “laws of the province and municipality” does not include laws that are inconsistent with or repugnant to any of the provisions of these Regulations.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Traffic Control, Parking and Speed Limit</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>No person shall operate a vehicle on a driveway at a rate of speed, in kilometres per hour, that is greater than the speed posted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Where no rate of speed is posted on a driveway, no person shall operate a vehicle on that driveway at a rate of speed greater than 60 kilometres per hour.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Notwithstanding subsections (1) and (2), where traffic on a driveway is controlled by a peace officer, every person operating a vehicle on that driveway shall do so at the rate of speed indicated by that peace officer.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/85-99, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>No person shall operate or park a vehicle, or permit a vehicle under his control to remain parked, on property of the Commission otherwise than in accordance with the directions set out on a traffic sign or device erected under the authority of these Regulations and applicable to such person.</Text></Section><Section><Label>7</Label><Text>Except as expressly authorized by the Commission, no person shall park a vehicle on any property of the Commission other than in an area designated by a sign or device erected under the authority of these Regulations as an area in which parking is permitted.</Text></Section><Section><Label>8</Label><Text>Sections 5, 6 and 7 do not apply to</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>operators of police vehicles engaged in the chase of persons charged with or suspected, on reasonable grounds, of being violators of the law; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>operators of police vehicles, fire vehicles or ambulances who believe, on reasonable grounds, that the conduct that would otherwise be an offence is justified by an emergency.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>9</Label><Text>The operator of a vehicle and the person in control of a parked vehicle on any property of the Commission shall obey all reasonable instructions given by any peace officer.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Pedestrians</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>10</Label><Text>No pedestrian shall proceed onto property of the Commission at a place where a sign or device has been erected under the authority of these Regulations otherwise than in accordance with the instructions indicated by such sign or device.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Commercial Vehicles</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>11</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>No person shall operate a commercial vehicle on a driveway without the consent of the Commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Subsection (1) does not apply to</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a person engaged in the delivery or collection of goods or persons to or from any property adjoining a driveway to which there is no other means of entry or exit if</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the commercial vehicle operated by such person enters and leaves the driveway by the intersecting street that is nearest to that property, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the operation of the commercial vehicle on the driveway occurs between midnight and noon;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a person operating a commercial vehicle in the course of the business of the Commission;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a person operating a taxicab;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a person operating a commercial vehicle that</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>is being used as a camper van, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>has no advertising displayed thereon;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>a person operating a light van or pick-up truck that</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>is used for personal transportation only,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>has a gross registered weight not exceeding 5,000 pounds, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>has no advertising, or lettering, other than the name of the owner thereof, displayed thereon; or</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>a person operating a commercial vehicle that has a gross registered weight not exceeding 8,000 pounds over the Portage Bridge between the City of Hull and Wellington Street in the City of Ottawa.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Reporting of Accidents</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>12</Label><Text>Every operator, owner or person in charge of a vehicle that is involved in an accident on property of the Commission shall report the accident forthwith to a member of the Royal Canadian Mounted Police and furnish him with such information concerning the accident as he may require.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>General Prohibitions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>13</Label><Text>No person shall operate</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a motor vehicle on any property of the Commission other than a driveway unless authorized by the Commission; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>an over-snow vehicle on any property of the Commission that is not designated by a sign or device erected by order of the Commission as an area in which the operation of an over-snow vehicle is permitted.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>14</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>No person shall construct any private road, entranceway, gate or other structure or facility as a means of access to any driveway except with the consent in writing of the Commission and in accordance with such conditions as are specified by the Commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>No person operating a vehicle shall enter upon a driveway except at a place at which public access to the driveway is provided.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Subsection (2) does not apply to prohibit entrance upon a driveway from any private road or entranceway constructed</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>on or before September 30, 1960; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>after September 30, 1960 with the consent in writing of the Commission.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>15</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2002-165, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>16</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>No person shall ride a bicycle on property of the Commission other than a driveway or on a bicycle path set aside by the Commission for the purpose.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>No person shall ride a bicycle on a driveway abreast of another bicycle or vehicle.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>17</Label><Text>Unless authorized by the Commission, no person shall race any vehicle or animal on property of the Commission.</Text></Section><Section><Label>18</Label><Text>No person shall use any blasphemous or indecent language, or behave in an offensive manner, upon any property of the Commission.</Text></Section><Section><Label>19</Label><Text>No person shall throw, deposit or leave on a driveway any glass, nails, tacks or scraps of metal or other material that may be injurious to the tires of vehicles using the driveway.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>20</Label><Text>A peace officer, upon finding a vehicle parked contrary to these Regulations, may, at the expense of the owner thereof, cause that vehicle to be moved or taken to and placed or stored in a suitable place.</Text></Section><Section><Label>21</Label><Text>Except as provided by these Regulations, no person shall remove, alter or deface any traffic sign or device erected by the Commission.</Text></Section><Section><Label>22</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The Chairman, General Manager, Chief Engineer or Secretary of the Commission may order the erection on or removal from property of the Commission of traffic signs and devices.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The Superintendent of Gatineau Park may order the erection or removal of traffic signs and devices within the area of the Park.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Any traffic sign or device erected by order of a person mentioned in subsections (1) and (2) shall be deemed to be erected by order of the Commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Any traffic sign or device erected on property of the Commission shall, unless the contrary is established, be presumed to have been erected by order of the Commission.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>23</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/95-445, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART II</Label><TitleText>Protection of Commission Property</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>24</Label><Text>No person shall enter on property of the Commission other than property on which the public is permitted entry.</Text></Section><Section><Label>25</Label><Text>No person shall throw, deposit or leave any refuse or debris on property of the Commission other than in such places as are specifically designated for that purpose.</Text></Section><Section><Label>26</Label><Text>No person shall, without the authority of the Commission,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>cut, break, injure, deface or defile any building, fence, bridge, sign, light or other work that is the property of the Commission;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>cut, break, injure, deface or defile any rock, tree, shrub, plant, flower or turf on property of the Commission;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>remove any thing described in paragraphs (a) and (b) or any soil, gravel or other part of the property of the Commission, or cause or permit such removal; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>have in his possession any property of the Commission.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>27</Label><Text>No person shall disturb or injure, or cause or permit to be disturbed or injured, any wild animal or any bird, bird’s nest or bird’s eggs on property of the Commission.</Text></Section><Section><Label>28</Label><Text>No person shall throw stones or fire or discharge any missile, firearm, airgun, B.B. gun, fireworks or torpedo on any property of the Commission except in areas specifically designated by the Commission for that purpose.</Text></Section><Section><Label>29</Label><Text>No person, other than a peace officer engaged in the discharge of his duties, shall, without the written approval of the commission, carry any firearm or other weapon or any trap on property of the Commission otherwise than in a vehicle.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/86-260, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>30</Label><Text>No person shall make, light or feed a fire on any property of the Commission not specifically designated for that purpose and no person shall leave a fire unattended.</Text></Section><Section><Label>31</Label><Text>No person shall bathe in any waters on property of the Commission except as permitted by the Commission, and no person shall make use of any property of the Commission for the purpose of bathing in waters not on property of the Commission, except in such places as are specifically designated for such use.</Text></Section><Section><Label>32</Label><Text>No person shall sell or offer or expose for sale any drink, goods or wares, or post or display any signs, placards, flags or advertising devices, or solicit subscriptions or contributions on or in any property of the Commission without first obtaining permission in writing from the Commission to do so.</Text></Section><Section><Label>33</Label><Text>No person shall expose on or in any property of the Commission any cards, dice, table, wheel or other device upon, with or by which any game of chance may be played, and no person shall play any such game upon, with or by such device on or in any property of the Commission.</Text></Section><Section><Label>34</Label><Text>No person shall play at golf, tennis, baseball, football or soccer on any property of the Commission except in those parts thereof that have been designated by the Commission for that purpose.</Text></Section><Section><Label>35</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>No person shall hunt, take or kill any game or fish on property of the Commission except in those parts thereof that have been designated by the Commission for that purpose.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>No person shall hunt, take or kill any game, or fish for any fish or engage in any activity relating to hunting or fishing in any designated area referred to in subsection (1) otherwise than in accordance with the laws of the province in which that area is situated.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>36</Label><Text>No person shall have liquor in his possession on or in the property of the Commission other than in accordance with the laws of the province in which the Commission property is situated.</Text></Section><Section><Label>37</Label><Text>Except with the written approval of the Commission, no person shall obstruct any stream or body of water on the property of the Commission.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/98-389, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>38</Label><Text>No person shall camp, picnic or erect a tent on any property of the Commission not specifically designated by the Commission for that purpose.</Text></Section><Section><Label>39</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The following definitions apply in this section.</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Commission land</DefinedTermEn> means real property or immovables owned by the Commission or under the control and management of the Commission. (<DefinedTermFr>terrain de la Commission</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>domestic animal</DefinedTermEn> means an animal of a species of vertebrates, other than fish, that has been domesticated by humans so as to live in a tame condition and depend on humans for survival. (<DefinedTermFr>animal domestique</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>keeper</DefinedTermEn> means the owner of a domestic animal or the person having charge of the animal, except where the owner or the person is a minor, in which case <DefinedTermEn>keeper</DefinedTermEn> means the father or mother of the minor or another adult responsible for the minor. (<DefinedTermFr>responsable</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>leased recreational property</DefinedTermEn> means Commission land, of which the Commission is the lessor, that is leased for recreational purposes to a municipality. (<DefinedTermFr>terrain récréatif loué</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (3), no person who is the keeper of a domestic animal shall have the animal on Commission land except in accordance with the bylaws of the municipality in which the Commission land is situated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Subsection (2) does not apply to</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>Commission land that is, by virtue of section 2 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">National Capital Commission Animal Regulations</XRefExternal>, subject to those Regulations; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>leased recreational property.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2002-165, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART III</Label><TitleText>Penalties</TitleText><HistoricalNote>[SOR/95-445, s. 2]</HistoricalNote></Heading><Section><Label>40</Label><Text>Every person who contravenes a provision of these Regulations is liable on summary conviction to a fine not exceeding $500 or to imprisonment for a term not exceeding six months, or to both.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/98-389, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>41 and 42</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/95-445, s. 3]</Repealed></Text></Section></Body></Regulation>