<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 1242</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">OATHS OF ALLEGIANCE ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Oaths of Office Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting the Taking of Oaths of Office</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Oaths of Office Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>Every person appointed to or holding an office that is under the legislative authority of the Parliament of Canada shall, in compliance with any lawful requirement made of him, in any case in which the form of such oath is not prescribed by any existing law in force in Canada, take an oath for the faithful performance of the duties of such office in the form set out in the schedule.</Text></Section><Section><Label>3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Any person allowed by law in civil cases, in any part of Canada, to affirm instead of making oath, shall be permitted to take an affirmation of office in the like terms, <Language xml:lang="la">mutatis mutandis</Language>, as the oath of office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>An affirmation of office, taken before the proper officer, shall in all cases be accepted from a person described in subsection (1) in lieu of an oath of office and shall, as to such affirmants, have the like effect as the oath of office.</Text></Subsection></Section></Body><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 2)</OriginatingRef><TitleText>Oath of Office</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>I, <Leader leader="dot" length="6pc" />, do solemnly and sincerely swear that I will truly and faithfully and to the best of my skill and knowledge execute and perform the duties that devolve upon me as a <Leader leader="dot" length="6pc" /> including the duty not to disclose or make known, without due authority in that behalf, any matter that comes to my knowledge by reason of my holding that office. So help me God.</Text></Provision></Schedule></Regulation>