<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 516</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>4</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CUSTOMS TARIFF</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Canadian Film Certification Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting the Certification of Canadian Films and Related Products</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Canadian Film Certification Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>The National Film Board is hereby charged with the duty of certifying on behalf of Her Majesty moving picture films, separate sound film track, filmstrips and slides, videotape and sound recordings, model, wall charts, maps and posters produced in Canada or produced abroad by persons normally resident in Canada as being of an international educational, scientific or cultural character.</Text></Section><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>Where a product referred to in section 2 is submitted to the National Film Board for certification, the Board shall certify it as being of an international educational, scientific or cultural character if, in the opinion of the Board, the product</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>interprets the life of a country or any part thereof in such a way as to promote understanding; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>may be used for teaching or training purposes to contribute to the development of technical efficiencies and is not advertising material.</Text></Paragraph></Section></Body></Regulation>