<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>C.R.C., c. 208</InstrumentNumber><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>31</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS MARKETING ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Ontario Greenhouse Vegetable Marketing (Interprovincial and Export) Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting the Marketing in Interprovincial and Export Trade of Greenhouse Vegetables Produced in Ontario</LongTitle></Identification><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Ontario Greenhouse Vegetable Marketing (Interprovincial and Export) Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>appointed shipper</DefinedTermEn> means a shipper in possession of a valid and subsisting certificate of appointment issued by the Commodity Board pursuant to the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Ontario Greenhouse Vegetable Appointed Shippers’ Procedures (Interprovincial and Export) Regulations</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>expéditeur désigné</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Commodity Board</DefinedTermEn> means The Ontario Greenhouse Vegetable Producers’ Marketing Board; (<DefinedTermFr>Office de commercialisation</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>greenhouse vegetables</DefinedTermEn> means tomatoes, cucumbers and lettuce produced in the Province of Ontario in a greenhouse or any other enclosure under glass, plastic or other material used for the purpose of controlling temperature and providing protection for growing plants; (<DefinedTermFr>légumes de serre</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>producer</DefinedTermEn> means a person engaged in the production of greenhouse vegetables; (<DefinedTermFr>producteur</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>product</DefinedTermEn> means any quantity of greenhouse vegetables; (<DefinedTermFr>produit</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>retailer</DefinedTermEn> means any person who sells or offers to sell a product directly to the consumer and includes the operator of a roadside stand; (<DefinedTermFr>détaillant</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>shipper</DefinedTermEn> means any person who offers for sale, sells, receives, assembles, packs, ships for sale or transports a product but does not include</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a servant employed by and driving a vehicle owned by a producer or an appointed shipper,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a railway company, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a person who transports the product by motor vehicle as agent of the producer; (<DefinedTermFr>expéditeur</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>wholesaler</DefinedTermEn> means a person who buys a product through the Commodity Board and who offers for sale or sells the product to a retailer. (<DefinedTermFr>grossiste</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>These Regulations apply only to</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the marketing of a product in interprovincial and export trade;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>persons and property situated in the Province of Ontario; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a product produced in the Counties of Essex, Kent and Lambton in the Province of Ontario.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Exemption</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>A producer who sells a product directly to a consumer or a consumer who buys a product directly from a producer is, in respect of that product, exempt from these Regulations.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Sale of Product</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>No person other than</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a producer who sells or offers for sale a product through the Commodity Board,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a wholesaler who buys a product through the Commodity Board for resale, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a producer authorized under a licence issued by the Commodity Board to sell or offer for sale a product</Text></Paragraph><ContinuedSectionSubsection><Text>shall sell the product or offer the product for sale.</Text></ContinuedSectionSubsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Purchase of Product</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>No person other than</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a wholesaler who buys a product through the Commodity Board for resale in the normal course of his business, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a retailer who buys a product through the Commodity Board or from a wholesaler for resale in the normal course of his business</Text></Paragraph><ContinuedSectionSubsection><Text>shall buy a product.</Text></ContinuedSectionSubsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Transportation of Product</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>7</Label><Text>No person other than</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>an appointed shipper who ships a product for a producer,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a wholesaler who buys a product through the Commodity Board for resale in the normal course of his business,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a railway company, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a producer authorized to transport a product under a licence issued by the Commodity Board</Text></Paragraph><ContinuedSectionSubsection><Text>shall transport a product.</Text></ContinuedSectionSubsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Shipping of Product</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>8</Label><Text>No person other than</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>an appointed shipper who ships a product for a producer,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a wholesaler who buys a product through the Commodity Board for resale in the normal course of his business, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a producer authorized to ship a product under a licence issued by the Commodity Board</Text></Paragraph><ContinuedSectionSubsection><Text>shall ship a product.</Text></ContinuedSectionSubsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Licences to Producers</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>9</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A licence may be issued to a producer by the Commodity Board to sell, transport or ship a product otherwise than through the Commodity Board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A licence issued pursuant to subsection (1) shall expire on December 31st of the year for which the licence is issued.</Text></Subsection></Section></Body></Regulation>