<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/97-480</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1997</YYYY><MM>10</MM><DD>23</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>10</MM><DD>29</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CUSTOMS TARIFF</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Order Respecting the Remission of Anti-Dumping Duties on Certain Hot-Dipped Galvannealed Steel Sheet for use in the Manufacture of Non-Exposed Motor Vehicle Parts</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1997-1524 </OrderNumber><Date><YYYY> 1997</YYYY><MM>10</MM><DD>23</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Finance, pursuant to section 101 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-97-480_e_hq_5758">a</FootnoteRef>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Order Respecting the Remission of Anti-Dumping Duties on Certain Hot-Dipped Galvannealed Steel Sheet for use in the Manufacture of Non-Exposed Motor Vehicle Parts</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fn_SOR-97-480_e_hq_5758" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>R.S., c. 41 (3rd Supp.)</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Remission</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>Subject to sections 2 and 3, remission is hereby granted of the anti-dumping duties paid or payable on imports of certain hot-dipped galvannealed steel sheet, coating weight 45/45 g/m<Sup>2</Sup>, 1.0 mm thick by 101 mm wide by coil, 390 MPa/mm<Sup>2</Sup> hi-tensile, with a minimum elongation of 40%, for use in the manufacture of non-exposed motor vehicle parts.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Conditions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>Remission is granted pursuant to section 1 on condition that:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the goods on which remission is granted are imported on or after July 1, 1997;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a claim for remission is made to the Minister of National Revenue within two years after the day on which this Order comes into force; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the importer files such evidence as National Revenue may require that the subject steel has been, or is to be, used in the manufacture of motor vehicle parts.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>This Order comes into force on October 23, 1997.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>