<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en" in-force="yes"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2016-307</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2016</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>2</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2016</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>14</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">MARINE LIABILITY ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Marine Liability and Information Return Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2016-1082</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>2016</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>2</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Transport, pursuant to subsections 74.4(3)<FootnoteRef idref="nbp_1139f_tc_4736">a</FootnoteRef> and 117(1.5)<FootnoteRef idref="fn_959e_tc_1819">b</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Marine Liability Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_959e_tc_1820">c</FootnoteRef>, makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Marine Liability and Information Return Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="nbp_1139f_tc_4736" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 2014, c. 29, s. 36</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="fn_959e_tc_1819" placement="page" status="official"><Label>b</Label><Text>S.C. 2014, c. 29, s. 50(3)</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="fn_959e_tc_1820" placement="page" status="official"><Label>c</Label><Text>S.C. 2001, c. 6</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Definitions</MarginalNote><Label>1</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The following definitions apply in these Regulations.</Text><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Marine Liability Act</XRefExternal>. (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Administrator</DefinedTermEn> means the Administrator of the Ship-source Oil Pollution Fund. (<DefinedTermFr>administrateur</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>receive</DefinedTermEn>, in respect of contributing oil, means to receive the oil into tankage or storage immediately after carriage by a ship. (<DefinedTermFr>recevoir</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Interpretation</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>For greater certainty, and for the purposes of these Regulations, contributing oil and contributing cargo are considered to be imported by sea or shipped by sea if they have been carried to or from a place that is seaward of a straight line drawn</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>from Cap-des-Rosiers to West Point, Anticosti Island; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>from Anticosti Island to the north shore of the St. Lawrence River along the meridian of longitude 63° W.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 1</Label><TitleText>Ship-source Oil Pollution Fund</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Consumer price index</MarginalNote><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>For the purposes of paragraphs 110(3)(b) and 113(3)(b) of the Act, the average of the Consumer Price Index for any 12-month period must be calculated by dividing by twelve the aggregate of the Consumer Price Indexes, excluding the food and energy components, for each month in that 12-month period.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Fraction</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>If the quotient obtained contains a fraction, the fraction must be expressed as a decimal fraction rounded to one digit after the decimal point as follows:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>if the second digit after the decimal point is less than five, that digit shall be dropped; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>if the second digit is five or greater than five, the first digit after the decimal point must be increased by one and the second digit must be dropped.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 2</Label><TitleText>International Fund and Supplementary Fund</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Application</MarginalNote><Label>3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>This section applies in respect of contributing oil, as defined in paragraph 3 of Article 1 of the Fund Convention, that</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>has been imported by sea into Canada, in bulk as cargo on a ship, and is to be unloaded at a terminal installation or port in Canada;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>has been shipped by sea to a port in the United States, in bulk as cargo on a ship, has subsequently been imported into Canada by a mode of transport other than a ship, and is to be unloaded at an installation in Canada; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>has been shipped by sea from a place in Canada or from an offshore installation in the exclusive economic zone of Canada, in bulk as cargo on a ship, and is to be unloaded at a terminal installation or port in Canada.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Information return</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Any person who receives, in a calendar year, contributing oil in a quantity exceeding 150 000 metric tons must file with the Administrator, no later than February 28 of the following calendar year, an information return in respect of that oil.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Associated persons</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>For the purposes of subsection (2), the quantity of contributing oil is the aggregate of the quantity received by the person and the quantities received by associated persons.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Content</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The information return must include</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the name, mailing address, email address, phone number and fax number of the person;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the total quantity of contributing oil received in that calendar year; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>where applicable, the name and address of associated persons that have received contributing oil.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 3</Label><TitleText>International Hazardous and Noxious Substances Fund</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Application</MarginalNote><Label>4</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>This section applies in respect of contributing cargo that</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>has been imported by sea into Canada and is to be unloaded at a terminal installation or port in Canada; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>has been shipped by sea from a place in Canada or from an offshore installation in the exclusive economic zone of Canada, and is to be unloaded at a terminal installation or port in Canada.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Information return</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A receiver who receives, in a calendar year, the following types and quantities of contributing cargo must file with the Minister, no later than February 28 of the following calendar year, an information return respecting that cargo:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>liquefied natural gases referred to in paragraph 2(b) of Article 16 of the Hazardous and Noxious Substances Convention, in any quantity;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>liquefied petroleum gases referred to in paragraph 2(c) of Article 16 of the Hazardous and Noxious Substances Convention, in a quantity exceeding 17 000 metric tons; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>any hazardous and noxious substances referred to in paragraphs 5(a)(ii), (iii), (v), (vi) and (vii) of Article 1 of the Hazardous and Noxious Substances Convention, in a quantity exceeding 17 000 metric tons.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Non-persistent oil</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>A receiver who receives, in a calendar year, contributing cargo in the form of oils referred to in paragraph 1(a)(ii) of Article 19 of the Hazardous and Noxious Substances Convention, in a quantity exceeding 17 000 metric tons, must file with the Administrator, no later than February 28 of the following calendar year, an information return respecting that cargo.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Associated persons</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>For the purposes of subsections (2) and (3), the quantity of contributing cargo is the aggregate of the quantity received by the receiver and the quantities received by associated persons.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Content</MarginalNote><Label>(5)</Label><Text>The information return referred to in subsections (2) and (3) must include</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the name, mailing address, email address, phone number and fax number of the receiver;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the type of contributing cargo, and the total quantity of each type of contributing cargo received in that calendar year;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>if the receiver received contributing cargo as an agent or mandatary for a principal or mandator, the name of the principal or mandator, and the type and quantity of cargo received;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>if the receiver received contributing cargo from an agent or mandatary, the name of the agent or mandatary and the type and quantity of cargo received; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>where applicable, the name and address of associated persons that have received contributing cargo.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Repeal</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>[Repeal]</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section type="transitional"><MarginalNote>Registration</MarginalNote><Label>6</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on the day on which they are registered.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>