<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/87-403</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1987</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>30</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>27</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS MARKETING ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Saskatchewan Pulse Crop Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Granting Authority to Regulate the Marketing in Interprovincial and Export Trade of Pulse Crops Produced in Saskatchewan</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1987-1360</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1987</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>30</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Agriculture, pursuant to section 2<FootnoteRef idref="footnote_e">*</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Agricultural Products Marketing Act</XRefExternal>, is pleased hereby to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Order granting authority to regulate the marketing in interprovincial and export trade of pulse crops produced in Saskatchewan</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="footnote_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>S.C. 1984, c. 40, s. 4</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Saskatchewan Pulse Crop Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In this Order,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means <XRefExternal reference-type="act">The Natural Products Marketing Act</XRefExternal> of the Province of Saskatchewan; (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Board</DefinedTermEn> means the Saskatchewan Pulse Crop Development Board established pursuant to the Act; (<DefinedTermFr>Office</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Plan</DefinedTermEn> means the Saskatchewan Pulse Crop Development Plan established pursuant to the Act and any regulations made under the Act to give effect to the Saskatchewan Pulse Crop Development Plan; (<DefinedTermFr>plan</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>pulse</DefinedTermEn> means the edible seeds of peas, beans fababeans, chick peas, broad beans or lentils; (<DefinedTermFr>légumineuses en graines</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>sale</DefinedTermEn> means sale for any consideration including barter or future delivery of pulse crops. (<DefinedTermFr>vente</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><HistoricalNote>SOR/88-477, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interprovincial and Export Trade</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>The Board hereby is authorized to regulate the marketing of pulse crops in interprovincial and export trade and for such purposes may, with respect to pulse crops grown within the Province of Saskatchewan, exercise all or any powers like the powers exercisable by it in relation to the marketing of pulse crops locally within the Province under the Act and the Plan.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Levies or Charges</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>The Board may, in relation to the powers granted to it by section 3 with respect to the marketing of pulse crops in interprovincial and export trade,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>fix and impose, by order, and collect levies or charges on persons situated in the Province of Saskatchewan who are engaged in the production or marketing of pulse crops and, for that purpose, classify, those persons into groups and fix, by order, the levies or charges payable by the members of the different groups in different amounts; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>use the levies or charges collected pursuant to paragraph (a) for the purposes of the Board, including the creation of reserves, the payment of expenses and losses resulting from the sale or disposal of pulse crops and the equalization or adjustment among producers of pulse crops of monies realized from the sale of pulse crops during such period or periods of time as the Board may determine.</Text></Paragraph></Section></Body></Regulation>