<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en" in-force="yes"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2017-173</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2017</YYYY><MM>9</MM><DD>1</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2017</YYYY><MM>9</MM><DD>12</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">EXPORT AND IMPORT PERMITS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Export Allocations Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2017-1122</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>2017</YYYY><MM>8</MM><DD>31</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Foreign Affairs, pursuant to section 12<FootnoteRef idref="fn_a">a</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Export and Import Permits Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_b">b</FootnoteRef>, makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Export Allocations Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision><Footnote id="fn_a" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 2006, c. 13, s. 115</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="fn_b" placement="page" status="official"><Label>b</Label><Text>R.S., c. E-19</Text></Footnote></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Definition of <DefinitionRef>product</DefinitionRef></MarginalNote><Label>1</Label><Text>In these Regulations, <DefinedTermEn>product</DefinedTermEn> means any product referred to in items 5201 to 5210 of Group 5 of the schedule to the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Export Control List</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Export Allocations</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Application</MarginalNote><Label>2</Label><Text>An application under paragraph 6.2(2)(b) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Export and Import Permits Act</XRefExternal> for an export allocation with respect to a product shall include, in the form provided by the Minister,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the name, address, telephone number and email address of the exporter and of any agent or mandatary applying on the exporter’s behalf;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>if the exporter or agent or mandatary is a corporation, the name of a contact person for the corporation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the official language selected for communications with the agent or mandatary and the exporter;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a description of the product, including the item number assigned to the product in the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Export Control List</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>an indication of whether the exporter and, if applicable, the agent or mandatary are residents of Canada; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>any other information requested by the Minister for clarification purposes related to the application.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Considerations to be taken into account</MarginalNote><Label>3</Label><Text>The Minister shall take the following considerations into account when deciding whether to issue an export allocation:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>whether the exporter or, if applicable, the agent or mandatary has furnished the information required by these Regulations;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>whether the exporter has complied with the provisions of the Act, or the regulations made under the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Export and Import Permits Act</XRefExternal>, or any condition of an export allocation or export permit; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>whether the exporter has furnished false or misleading information in connection with any reports required by the Act, or the regulations made under the Act, or in connection with any term or condition of an export allocation or export permit.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Information to be supplied</MarginalNote><Label>4</Label><Text>Every person to whom an export allocation has been issued shall provide the Minister with the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any information required by the Minister for clarification purposes related to the export allocation; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a detailed report of the circumstances of the person or of any other person who has failed or will likely fail to comply with the requirements of these Regulations with respect to a product to which the allocation relates or with the terms or conditions of the allocation as soon as the holder becomes aware of those circumstances.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Issuance of export allocation</MarginalNote><Label>5</Label><Text>When an application for an export allocation has been approved by the Minister, the written approval of the Minister becomes a valid export allocation.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label><FootnoteRef idref="fn_Ind4F2E_hq_20652">*</FootnoteRef>6</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on the day on which section 15 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada–European Union Comprehensive Economic and Trade Agreement Implementation Act</XRefExternal>, chapter 6 of the Statutes of Canada, 2017, comes into force, but if they are registered after that day, they come into force on the day on which they are registered.</Text><Footnote id="fn_Ind4F2E_hq_20652" placement="section" status="editorial"><Label>*</Label><Text>[Note: Regulations in force September 21, 2017, <Emphasis style="italic">see</Emphasis> SI/2017-47.]</Text></Footnote></Section></Body></Regulation>