<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en" in-force="yes"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2013-38</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2013</YYYY><MM>3</MM><DD>8</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2013</YYYY><MM>3</MM><DD>27</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">YUKON ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Yukon Borrowing Limits Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2013-270</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>2013</YYYY><MM>3</MM><DD>7</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Finance, pursuant to subsection 23(5)<FootnoteRef idref="a_11">a</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Yukon Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="b_11">b</FootnoteRef>, makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Yukon Borrowing Limits Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="a_11" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 2012, c. 19, s. 216(2)</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="b_11" placement="page" status="official"><Label>b</Label><Text>S.C. 2002, c. 7</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Definition</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Definition of <DefinitionRef>government</DefinitionRef></MarginalNote><Label>1</Label><Text>In these Regulations, <DefinedTermEn>government</DefinedTermEn> means the government reporting entity — as defined in the section dealing with the government reporting entity in the <XRefExternal reference-type="standard">CPA Canada Public Sector Accounting Handbook</XRefExternal>, as amended from time to time — of Yukon.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2017-114, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Borrowing</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Meaning</MarginalNote><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (2), for the purposes of subsections 23(2) and (4) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Yukon Act</XRefExternal>, each of the following constitutes or is deemed to constitute borrowing:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>an obligation incurred as a result of any loan of money received by the government, including a loan made by the issuance and sale of bonds, debentures, notes or any other evidence of indebtedness;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>an obligation incurred as a result of any capital lease entered into by the government if the value of the obligation, determined in accordance with paragraph <XRefInternal>3</XRefInternal>(b), exceeds the threshold for disclosure that is required in the Yukon Public Accounts;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a liability incurred as a result of any sale-leaseback transaction entered into by the government if the government acquires a leased tangible capital asset and the value of the liability, determined in accordance with paragraph <XRefInternal>3</XRefInternal>(c), exceeds the threshold for disclosure that is required in the Yukon Public Accounts; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a contingent liability incurred as a result of any loan guarantee provided by the government.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Exclusion — obligation within government</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>An obligation, liability or contingent liability incurred as a result of any transaction referred to in subsection (1) between any two parties within the government does not constitute or is deemed not to constitute borrowing.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Value of Borrowing</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Manner to determine value of borrowing</MarginalNote><Label>3</Label><Text>For the purposes of subsections 23(2) and (4) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Yukon Act</XRefExternal>,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the value of the obligation incurred as a result of a loan referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>2</XRefInternal>(1)(a) is equal to the sum of any outstanding principal and any accrued interest — or the principal repayable at maturity in the case of a loan made by the issuance and sale of a discount bond — but excludes the amount of any custodial account that is outside the control of the government and in which money is deposited on a regular basis, as required by a loan agreement, for the repayment of the loan;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the value of the obligation incurred as a result of a capital lease referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>2</XRefInternal>(1)(b) is determined in accordance with the <XRefExternal reference-type="standard">CPA Canada Public Sector Accounting Handbook</XRefExternal>, as amended from time to time;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the value of the liability incurred as a result of a sale-leaseback transaction referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>2</XRefInternal>(1)(c) is determined in accordance with the <XRefExternal reference-type="standard">CPA Canada Public Sector Accounting Handbook</XRefExternal>, as amended from time to time; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the value of the contingent liability incurred as a result of a loan guarantee referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>2</XRefInternal>(1)(d) is equal to the full amount of that contingent liability that is to be disclosed in the Yukon Public Accounts.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2017-114, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>S.C. 2012, c. 19</MarginalNote><Label><FootnoteRef idref="fn_IndFC2F_hq_14126">*</FootnoteRef>4</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on the day on which Division 4 of Part 4 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Jobs, Growth and Long-term Prosperity Act</XRefExternal> comes into force, but if they are registered after that day, they come into force on the day on which they are registered.</Text><Footnote id="fn_IndFC2F_hq_14126" placement="section" status="editorial"><Label>*</Label><Text>[Note: Regulations in force March 8, 2013, <Emphasis style="italic">see</Emphasis> SI/2013-25.]</Text></Footnote></Section></Body></Regulation>