<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2000-1</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1999</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>14</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>3</MM><DD>13</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">PUBLIC SERVICE SUPERANNUATION ACT</XRefExternal><XRefExternal reference-type="act">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Certain Canada Port Authorities Divestiture Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>T.B.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>827750</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1999</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>9</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The Treasury Board, on the recommendation of the President of the Treasury Board, pursuant to paragraph 42.1(1)(u)<FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-2000-1_e_hq_4100">a</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Superannuation Act</XRefExternal> and paragraph 7(2)(a) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Financial Administration Act</XRefExternal>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Certain Canada Port Authorities Divestiture Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fn_SOR-2000-1_e_hq_4100" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 1992, c. 46, s. 22</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>The definitions in this section apply in these Regulations.</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Superannuation Act</XRefExternal>. (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>new employer</DefinedTermEn> means a person or body who, under letters patent of incorporation issued by the Minister of Transport, carries out the activities that were formerly carried out by a Local Port Corporation or a Non-Corporate Port of Canada Ports Corporation and includes a person who acts for or on behalf of that person or body. (<DefinedTermFr>nouvel employeur</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (2) and section 3, these Regulations apply to a person who was deemed to be part of the public service under the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Divestiture of Service Transitional Coverage Regulations</XRefExternal> and who, for the purposes of the Act, ceases to be employed in the public service and becomes employed by the new employer on or after January 1, 2000.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>These Regulations do not apply to a person who subsequently becomes re-employed by the new employer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Sections 4 to 9 do not apply to a person who has exercised an option under subsection 3(2).</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2016-203, s. 74(E).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Applicable Provisions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Sections 12, 13 and 13.01 of the Act only apply to a person on and after the date on which that person ceases to be employed by the new employer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Despite subsection (1), where, on or after January 1, 2000, a person would be eligible, were it not for these Regulations, to exercise an option under subsection 12(3) or section 13.01 of the Act, the person may exercise such an option no later than one year after the date on which the person ceases to be employed in the public service and becomes employed by the new employer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>A person who has exercised an option under subsection (2) is deemed not to have become employed by the new employer for the purposes of these Regulations and of sections 83 to 99 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Public Service Superannuation Regulations</XRefExternal> and is not entitled to exercise an option pursuant to subsection (1) when the person ceases to be employed by the new employer.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2016-203, s. 74(E).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Survivor and Children</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>For the purposes of subsection 12(8) of the Act, the survivor and children of a person who dies while employed by the new employer are entitled to a death benefit equal to a return of contributions.</Text></Section><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>For the purposes of subsection 13(3) of the Act, the survivor and children of a person who dies while employed by the new employer are entitled to an allowance as described in paragraphs 12(4)(a) and (b) of the Act, subject to the limitations set out in subsections 12(4) and (5) of the Act.</Text></Section><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>For the purposes of subsection 26(2) of the Act, a child who was born to or adopted by a person or became the stepchild of the person during the period that begins on the date on which the person ceases to be employed in the public service and that ends on the date on which that person ceases to be employed by the new employer is entitled to an allowance under Part I of the Act.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2016-203, s. 74(E).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Adaptation of Subsection 10(5) of the Act</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>7</Label><Text>For the purposes of subsection 10(5) of the Act, the one year period referred to in paragraph 10(5)(a) of the Act shall begin on the date on which the person ceases to be employed by the new employer.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Adaptation of Sections 12 and 13 of the Act</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>8</Label><Text>For the purposes of sections 12 and 13 of the Act, pensionable service includes the period of service with the new employer that begins on the date on which the person ceases to be employed in the public service and that ends on the date on which the person ceases to be employed by the new employer.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2016-203, s. 74(E).</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>9</Label><Text>For the purposes of sections 12 and 13 of the Act, the age of a person when the person ceases to be employed in the public service is the age of the person on the day on which that person ceases to be employed by the new employer.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2016-203, s. 74(E).</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>9.1</Label><Text>A contributor to whom these Regulations apply is considered to be a Group 1 contributor.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2016-203, s. 73.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>10</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on January 1, 2000.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>