<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/88-125</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1988</YYYY><MM>2</MM><DD>4</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2011</YYYY><MM>2</MM><DD>3</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AERONAUTICS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Pembroke Airport Zoning Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting Zoning at Pembroke Airport</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1988-187</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1988</YYYY><MM>2</MM><DD>4</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas, pursuant to section 4.5 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Aeronautics Act</XRefExternal>, a copy of the proposed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Zoning Regulations respecting Pembroke Airport</XRefExternal>, substantially in the form set out in the schedule hereto, was published in two successive issues of the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>, Part I, on October 17th and 24th, 1987, and in two successive issues of the Pembroke Observer on October 24th and 26th, 1987, and two successive issues of <Language xml:lang="fr">Le Droit</Language> on October 2nd and 9th, 1987, and a reasonable opportunity was thereby afforded to interested persons to make representations to the Minister of Transport with respect thereto.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Therefore, Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Transport, pursuant to section 4.4 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Aeronautics Act</XRefExternal>, is pleased hereby to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting Zoning at Pembroke Airport</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Pembroke Airport Zoning Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>airport</DefinedTermEn> means the Pembroke Airport at Petawawa, in the Township of Petawawa, in the Province of Ontario; (<DefinedTermFr>aéroport</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>airport reference point</DefinedTermEn> means the point described in Part I of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>point de repère de l’aéroport</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>approach surface</DefinedTermEn> means an imaginary inclined plane that extends upward and outward from each end of a strip, which approach surface is more particularly described in Part II of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>surface d’approche</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Minister</DefinedTermEn> means the Minister of Transport; (<DefinedTermFr>ministre</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>outer surface</DefinedTermEn> means an imaginary surface located above and in the immediate vicinity of the airport, which outer surface is more particularly described in Part III of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>surface extérieure</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>strip</DefinedTermEn> means the rectangular portion of the landing area of the airport, including the runway, prepared for the take-off and landing of aircraft in a particular direction, which strip is more particularly described in Part IV of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>bande</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>transitional surface</DefinedTermEn> means an imaginary inclined plane that extends upward and outward from the lateral limits of a strip and its approach surfaces, which transitional surface is more particularly described in Part V of the schedule. (<DefinedTermFr>surface de transition</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>For the purposes of these Regulations, the elevation of the airport reference point is 160 m above sea level.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-170, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>These Regulations apply to all the lands, including public road allowances, adjacent to or in the vicinity of the airport, which lands are more particularly described in Part VI of the schedule.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-170, s. 2(F).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>No person shall erect or construct on any land to which these Regulations apply, any building, structure or object or any addition to any existing building, structure or object, the highest point of which will exceed in elevation at the location of that point</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the approach surfaces;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the outer surface; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the transitional surfaces.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Natural Growth</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>Where an object of natural growth on any land to which these Regulations apply exceeds in elevation any of the surfaces referred to in paragraphs 4(a) to (c), the Minister may require that the owner or occupier of the land on which that object is growing remove the excessive growth.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-170, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Disposal of Waste</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>No owner or occupier of any land to which these Regulations apply shall permit that land or any part of it to be used for the disposal of any waste edible by or attractive to birds.</Text></Section></Body><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label></ScheduleFormHeading><Heading level="1"><Label>PART I</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 2)</OriginatingRef><TitleText>Description of Airport Reference Point</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The airport reference point, shown on Pembroke Airport Zoning Plan No. 47-074 84-131, Sheet 5, dated August 21, 1986, is a point which may be located by:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>Commencing at Button 17 being the northerly end of Runway 17-35 at said Airport;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>Thence southerly along the centre line of said Runway 917.82 m to a point;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>Thence westerly and perpendicular to the said Runway centre line 196.26 m to the airport reference point having universal transverse mercator co-ordinates of 5 081 022.677 N and 325 079.673 E.</Text></Provision></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART II</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 2)</OriginatingRef><TitleText>Description of the Approach Surfaces</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The approach surfaces, as shown on Pembroke Airport Zoning Plan No. 47-074 84-131, Sheets 4, 5, 6, 10, 11, 12 and 13, dated August 21, 1986, are surfaces abutting each end of the strip associated with the runway designated 17-35 and are described as follows:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a surface abutting the end of the strip associated with runway approach 17 consisting of an inclined plane having a ratio of 1 m measured vertically to 50 m measured horizontally rising to an imaginary horizontal line drawn at right angles to the projected centre line of the strip and distant 15 000 m measured horizontally from the end of the strip; the outer ends of the imaginary horizontal line being 2 400 m from the projected centre line; said imaginary horizontal line being 300 m measured vertically above the elevation at the end of the strip; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a surface abutting the end of the strip associated with runway approach 35 consisting of an inclined plane having a ratio of 1 m measured vertically to 50 m measured horizontally rising to an imaginary horizontal line drawn at right angles to the projected centre line of the strip and distant 15 000 m measured horizontally from the end of the strip; the outer ends of the imaginary horizontal line being 2 400 m from the projected centre line; the said imaginary horizontal line being 300 m measured vertically above the elevation at the end of the strip.</Text></Provision></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART III</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 2)</OriginatingRef><TitleText>Description of the Outer Surface</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The outer surface, as shown on Pembroke Airport Zoning Plan No. 47-074 84-131, Sheets 1 to 9 inclusive, 11 and 12, dated August 21, 1986, is an imaginary surface located at a common plane established at a constant elevation of 45 m above the elevation of the airport reference point, except that, where that common plane is less than 9 m above the surface of the ground, the outer surface is an imaginary surface located at 9 m above the surface of the ground.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART IV</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 2)</OriginatingRef><TitleText>Description of the Strip</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The strip associated with runway 17-35, as shown on Pembroke Airport Zoning Plan No. 47-074 84-131, Sheet 5, dated August 21, 1986, is 300 m in width, 150 m on each side of the centre line of the runway, and 1 643.41 m in length.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART V</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 2)</OriginatingRef><TitleText>Description of the Transitional Surface</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The transitional surface associated with runway 17-35, as shown on Pembroke Airport Zoning Plan No. 47-074 84-131, Sheets 4, 5, 6, 11 and 12, dated August 21, 1986, is a surface consisting of an inclined plane rising at a ratio of a 1 m measured vertically to 7 m measured horizontally at right angles to the centre line and projected centre line of the strip and extending upward and outward from the lateral limits of the strip and its approach surfaces to an intersection with the outer surface.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART VI</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 3)</OriginatingRef><TitleText>Description of the Lands to Which These Regulations Apply</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>The boundary of the outer limits of lands, as shown on Pembroke Airport Zoning Plan No. 47-074 84-131, dated August 21, 1986, is described as follows:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>All and singular those certain parcels or tracts of land situated lying and being in the Township of Alice, the Township of Petawawa, the Village of Petawawa and the Township of Buchanan, all in the County of Renfrew;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Commencing at the southeastern corner of Lot 15, Concession 1 of the Township of Petawawa;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence westerly along the southern limit of Lots 15 and 14 in Concession 1 to the southwestern corner of Lot 14, Concession 1;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence northerly along the western limit of Lot 14, Concession 1 to the northwestern corner of the said lot;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence westerly along the line between Concessions 1 and 2 across Lot 13 to the southwestern corner of Lot 13, Concession 2;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence northerly along the western limit of Lot 13, Concession 2 to the northwestern corner of the said lot;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence northerly in a straight line across the road allowance between Concessions 2 and 3 to the southwestern corner of Lot 13, Concession 3;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence northerly along the western boundary of Lot 13, Concession 3 to the northwestern corner of the said lot;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence along the line between Concessions 3 and 4 to the southwestern corner of Lot 13, Concession 4;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence northerly along the western boundary of Lot 13, Concession 4 to the northwestern corner of the said lot;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence northerly in a straight line across the road allowance between Concessions 4 and 5 to the southwestern corner of Lot 13, Concession 5;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence northerly along the western boundary of Lot 13, Concession 5 to the northwestern corner of the said lot;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence easterly along the line between Concessions 5 and 6 across Lots 13 and 14 to the southwestern corner of Lot 15, Concession 6;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence northerly along the western boundary of Lot 15, Concession 6 to the northwestern corner of the said lot;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence easterly along the northern boundary of Lot 15, Concession 6 to the northeastern corner of the said lot;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence easterly in a straight line across the road allowance between Lots 15 and 16, Concession 6 to the northwestern corner of Lot 16, Concession 6;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence easterly along the northern boundary of Lots 16 and 17, Concession 6 to the northeastern corner of Lot 17, Concession 6;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence northerly in a straight line across the road allowance between Concessions 6 and 7 to the southwestern corner of Lot 18, Concession 7;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence northerly along the western boundary of Lot 18, Concession 7 to the northwestern corner of the said lot;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence easterly along the northern boundary of Lots 18, 19 and 20, Concession 7 to the northeastern corner of Lot 20, Concession 7;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence easterly in a straight line across the road allowance between Lots 20 and 21, Concession 7 to the northwestern corner of Lot 21, Concession 7;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence easterly along the northern boundary of Lot 21, Concession 7 to its intersection with the westerly limit of the approach surface of runway approach 17;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence along the western limit of the said approach surface on an azimuth of 332°15′34″ to a point being the northwestern corner of the said approach surface, the coordinates of which are 5,095,385.072 N and 317,741.850 E;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence easterly along the northern limit of the said approach surface on an azimuth of 70°47′25″ a distance of 4 800 metres to a point being the northeastern corner of said approach surface, the coordinates of which are 5,096,964.326 N, and 322,274.371 E;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence southerly along the eastern limit of the said approach surface on an azimuth of 169°19′16″ to its intersection with the northern boundary of Lot 17, Range C in the Township of Petawawa;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence easterly along the northern boundary of Lot 17, Range C to the northeastern corner of the said lot;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence easterly in a straight line across the road allowance between Range C and the Lake Range to the northwestern corner of Lot 17, Lake Range;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence easterly along the northern boundary of Lot 17, Lake Range to the northeastern corner of the said lot;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence southerly along the eastern boundary of Lots 17, 16, and 15 in the Lake Range being also the western limit of the shore road allowance along the Ottawa River, to its intersection with an arc drawn on a radius of 4 000 metres measured from the Airport Reference Point the coordinates of which are 5,081,022.667 N and 325,079.673 E;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence easterly and southerly along the said arc to its intersection with the western limit of the shore road allowance along the Ottawa River, being also the eastern boundary of Lot 5, Lake Range in the Township of Petawawa;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence southerly along the eastern boundary of Lots 5, 4 and 3 in the Lake Range to the southeastern corner of Lot 3, Lake Range;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence westerly along the southern boundary of Lot 3, Lake Range to the southwestern corner of the said lot;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence southerly along the western boundary of Lots 2 and 1, Lake Range to the southwestern corner of the said Lot 1;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence westerly in a straight line across the road allowance between Lake Range and Range A to the southeastern corner of Lot 1, Range A;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence westerly along the southerly boundary of Lot 1, Range A to the point where it is met by the northerly production across the road allowance between the Township of Petawawa and the Township of Alice of the line between Lots 29 and 30, Concession 16 in the Township of Alice;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence southerly along the said production across the road allowance between the Townships of Petawawa and Alice to the northeastern corner of Lot 29, Concession 16 in the Township of Alice;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence southerly along the eastern boundary of Lot 29, Concession 16 to the southeastern corner of the said lot;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence westerly along the line between Concessions 15 and 16 across Lots 29, 28, 27 and 26 to the southwestern corner of Lot 26, Concession 16;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence westerly in a straight line across the road allowance between Lots 25 and 26, Concession 15 to the northeastern corner of Lot 25, Concession 15;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence southerly along the eastern boundary of Lot 25, Concession 15 to the southeastern corner of the said lot;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence westerly along the southern boundary of Lot 25, Concession 15 to its intersection with the easterly limit of the approach surface for runway approach 35;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence southerly along the eastern limit of the said approach surface on an azimuth of 152°15′34″ to a point being the southeastern corner of the said approach surface the coordinates of which are 5,067,084.235 N and 332,685.406 E;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence westerly along the southern limit of the said approach surface on an azimuth of 250°47′25″ a distance of 4 800 metres to a point being the southwestern corner of the said approach surface, the coordinates of which are 5,065,504.981 N and 328,152.884 E;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence northerly along the western limit of the said approach surface on an azimuth of 349°19′16″ to its intersection with the southern limit of Lot 21, Concession 15 in the Township of Alice;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence westerly along the southern limit of Lot 21, Concession 15 to the southwestern corner of the said lot;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence northerly along the western boundary of Lot 21, Concession 15 to the northwestern corner of the said lot;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence westerly in a straight line across the road allowance between Lots 20 and 21, Concession 15 to the southeastern corner of Lot 20, Concession 16;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence westerly along the line between Concessions 15 and 16 across Lots 20, 19, 18, 17 and 16 to the southwestern corner of Lot 16, Concession 16;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence northerly along the western limit of Lot 16, Concession 16 to the northwestern corner of the said lot;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence westerly in a straight line across the road allowance between Lots 15 and 16 in Concession 16 to the northeastern corner of Lot 15, Concession 16;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Thence northerly in a straight line across the road allowance between the Township of Alice and the Township of Petawawa to the southeastern corner of Lot 15, Concession 1 of the Township of Petawawa, being the POINT OF COMMENCEMENT.</Text></Provision></Provision><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-170, ss. 4(E), 5 and 6(E); SOR/94-375, s. 2(E).</HistoricalNote></Schedule></Regulation>