<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2001-480</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2001</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>1</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>9</MM><DD>26</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">BANK ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Supervisory Information (Bank Holding Companies) Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2001-2024</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>2001</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>1</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision language-align="yes" format-ref="indent-0-0" list-item="no"><Text>Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Finance, pursuant to sections 956<FootnoteRef idref="footnotea_e">a</FootnoteRef> and 978<FootnoteRef idref="footnotea_e">a</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Bank Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="footnoteb_e">b</FootnoteRef>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Supervisory Information (Bank Holding Companies) Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="footnotea_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 2001, c. 9, s. 183</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="footnoteb_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>b</Label><Text>S.C. 1991, c. 46</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Supervisory Information</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>For the purposes of section 956 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Bank Act</XRefExternal>, the following information or any component of that information is prescribed supervisory information in relation to a bank holding company:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any rating assigned by the Superintendent to the bank holding company to assess its financial condition and any other such rating that is substantially based on information obtained from the Superintendent;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any stage of intervention assigned to the bank holding company on the basis of the principles set out in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Guide to Intervention for Federal Financial Institutions</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>any order made in respect of the bank holding company under subsection 949(3) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Bank Act</XRefExternal>, any prudential agreement entered into by the bank holding company under section 959 of that Act or any direction issued to it under section 960 of that Act; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>any report prepared by or at the request of the Superintendent or any recommendation made by the Superintendent as a result of an annual or special examination or other supervisory review of the bank holding company, including any related correspondence to or from the directors or officers of the bank holding company.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>For the purposes of section 956 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Bank Act</XRefExternal>, the information prescribed by the following regulations is prescribed supervisory information in relation to an affiliate of a bank holding company:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Supervisory Information (Banks) Regulations</XRefExternal>, if the affiliate is a bank to which the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Bank Act</XRefExternal> applies;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Supervisory Information (Authorized Foreign Banks) Regulations</XRefExternal>, if the affiliate is an authorized foreign bank to which the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Bank Act</XRefExternal> applies;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Supervisory Information (Cooperative Credit Associations) Regulations</XRefExternal>, if the affiliate is an association to which the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Cooperative Credit Associations Act</XRefExternal> applies;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Supervisory Information (Insurance Companies) Regulations</XRefExternal>, if the affiliate is a company, society, foreign company or provincial company to which the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Insurance Companies Act</XRefExternal> applies;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Supervisory Information (Insurance Holding Companies) Regulations</XRefExternal>, if the affiliate is an insurance holding company to which the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Insurance Companies Act</XRefExternal> applies; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Supervisory Information (Trust and Loan Companies) Regulations</XRefExternal>, if the affiliate is a company to which the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Trust and Loan Companies Act</XRefExternal> applies.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2011-196, s. 9.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Prohibited Disclosure</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>Subject to sections 3 and 4, a bank holding company shall not, directly or indirectly, disclose information referred to in section 1.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2011-196, s. 10.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Limited Disclosure</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>A bank holding company may disclose information referred to in section 1 to its affiliates or to its directors, officers, employees, auditors, securities underwriters or legal advisors, or to those of its affiliates, if the bank holding company ensures that the information remains confidential.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2011-196, s. 10.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>A bank holding company or any of its affiliates may disclose information referred to in paragraph 1(1)(c) if the bank holding company or affiliate considers the information to contain a material fact or material change that is required by the securities laws of the relevant jurisdiction to be disclosed.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2011-196, s. 11(E).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section type="transitional"><Label>5</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on the day on which they are registered.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>