<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/97-64</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1996</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>30</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>10</MM><DD>28</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CUSTOMS TARIFF</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>CIFTA Tariff Preference Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1996-2076 </OrderNumber><Date><YYYY> 1996</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>30</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Finance, pursuant to paragraph 13(2)(b)<FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-97-64_e_hq_5667">a</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-97-64_e_hq_5668">b</FootnoteRef>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">CIFTA Tariff Preference Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fn_SOR-97-64_e_hq_5667" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 1993, c. 44, s. 113(2)</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="fn_SOR-97-64_e_hq_5668" placement="page" status="official"><Label>b</Label><Text>R.S., c. 41 (3rd Supp.)</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>For the purposes of subsection 50(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal>, goods are entitled to the benefit of the Canada-Israel Free Trade Agreement Tariff if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the goods are shipped from Israel or another CIFTA beneficiary, without shipment through another country, to Canada</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>on a through bill of lading, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>without a through bill of lading and the importer provides, where requested by an officer, documentary evidence that indicates the shipping route and all points of shipment and transhipment prior to the importation of the goods;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the case of goods, except for goods listed in any of Chapters 50 through 63 of the List of Tariff Provisions, that are shipped to Canada from Israel or another CIFTA beneficiary through the United States, the importer provides, if requested by an officer, documentary evidence that indicates that the goods have not undergone</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>further production in the territory of the United States other than minor processing, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>any processing in the territory of the United States that increased the transaction value of the goods by greater than 10%; or</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>in case of goods listed in any of Chapters 50 through 63 of the List of Tariff Provisions that are shipped to Canada from Israel or another CIFTA beneficiary through the United States, the importer provides, if requested by an officer,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>documentary evidence that indicates the shipping route and all points of shipment and transhipment prior to the importation of the goods, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>a copy of the customs control documents that demonstrate that the goods remained under customs control while in the United States; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>in the case of goods that are shipped to Canada from Israel or another CIFTA beneficiary through another country, other than the United States, the importer provides, if requested by an officer,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>documentary evidence that indicates the shipping route and all points of shipment and transhipment prior to the importation of the goods, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>a copy of the customs control documents that demonstrate that the goods remained under customs control while in that other country.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2002-251, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>1.1</Label><Text>For the purpose of section 1, <DefinedTermEn>territory</DefinedTermEn>, with respect to the United States, has the same meaning as in subsection 2(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">NAFTA Rules of Origin Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2002-251, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label><FootnoteRef idref="fn_Ind771_hq_16391">*</FootnoteRef>2</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on the day on which section 45 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada-Israel Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act</XRefExternal>, chapter 33 of the Statutes of Canada, 1996, comes into force.</Text><Footnote id="fn_Ind771_hq_16391" placement="section" status="editorial"><Label>*</Label><Text>[Note: Regulations in force January 1, 1997, <Emphasis style="italic">see</Emphasis> SI/97-9.]</Text></Footnote></Section></Body></Regulation>