<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en" in-force="yes"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2013-88</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2013</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>2</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2013</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>22</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CANADIAN ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION ACT, 1999</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Export of Substances on the Export Control List Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2013-523</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>2013</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>2</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas, pursuant to subsection 332(1)<FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-2013-88_e_hq_12012">a</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canadian Environmental Protection Act, 1999</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-2013-88_e_hq_12013">b</FootnoteRef>, the Minister of the Environment published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>, Part I, on August 6, 2011, a copy of the proposed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Export of Substances on the Export Control List Regulations</XRefExternal>, substantially in the annexed form, and persons were given an opportunity to file comments with respect to the Regulations or to file a notice of objection requesting that a board of review be established and stating the reasons for the objection;</Text><Footnote id="fn_SOR-2013-88_e_hq_12012" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 2004, c. 15, s. 31</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="fn_SOR-2013-88_e_hq_12013" placement="page" status="official"><Label>b</Label><Text>S.C. 1999, c. 33</Text></Footnote></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Therefore, His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of the Environment and the Minister of Health, pursuant to subsection 102(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canadian Environmental Protection Act, 1999</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-2013-88_e_hq_12013">b</FootnoteRef>, makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Export of Substances on the Export Control List Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Definitions</MarginalNote><Label>1</Label><Text>The following definitions apply in these Regulations.</Text><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canadian Environmental Protection Act, 1999</XRefExternal>. (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>CAS registry number</DefinedTermEn> means the identification number assigned to a chemical substance by the Chemical Abstracts Service Division of the American Chemical Society. (<DefinedTermFr>numéro d’enregistrement CAS</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>designated national authority</DefinedTermEn> means an authority designated by a Rotterdam Party under Article 4 of the Rotterdam Convention to act on its behalf in the performance of the administrative functions required by the Rotterdam Convention. (<DefinedTermFr>autorité nationale désignée</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Export Control List</DefinedTermEn> means the Export Control List in Schedule 3 to the Act. (<DefinedTermFr>Liste des substances d’exportation contrôlée</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Minamata Convention</DefinedTermEn> means the Minamata Convention on Mercury, as amended from time to time. (<DefinedTermFr>Convention de Minamata</DefinedTermFr>) </Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>pesticide</DefinedTermEn> means a pest control product as defined in subsection 2(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Pest Control Products Act</XRefExternal>. (<DefinedTermFr>produit antiparasitaire</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>PIC Circular</DefinedTermEn> means the circular that is published by the Rotterdam Secretariat and that contains a compilation of import responses from Rotterdam Parties, provided in accordance with Article 10 of the Rotterdam Convention, and a list of the substances subject to the prior informed consent procedure. (<DefinedTermFr>Circulaire PIC</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Rotterdam Convention</DefinedTermEn> means the Rotterdam Convention on the Prior Informed Consent Procedure for Certain Hazardous Chemicals and Pesticides in International Trade, as amended from time to time. (<DefinedTermFr>Convention de Rotterdam</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Rotterdam Party</DefinedTermEn> means a State or regional economic integration organization for which the Rotterdam Convention is in force. (<DefinedTermFr>Partie à la Convention de Rotterdam</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Rotterdam Secretariat</DefinedTermEn> means the Secretariat for the Rotterdam Convention established under Article 19 of that Convention. (<DefinedTermFr>Secrétariat de Rotterdam</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Stockholm Convention</DefinedTermEn> means the Stockholm Convention on Persistent Organic Pollutants, as amended from time to time. (<DefinedTermFr>Convention de Stockholm</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Stockholm Party</DefinedTermEn> means a State or regional economic integration organization for which the Stockholm Convention is in force. (<DefinedTermFr>Partie à la Convention de Stockholm</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>substance subject to the prior informed consent procedure</DefinedTermEn> means a substance specified in Annex III of the Rotterdam Convention that is destined for use in the category specified in that Annex. (<DefinedTermFr>substance soumise à la procédure de consentement préalable</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><HistoricalNote>SOR/2017-11, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Purpose</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Purpose</MarginalNote><Label>2</Label><Text>The purpose of these Regulations is to establish regulatory conditions applicable to the export of substances specified in the Export Control List and to implement the Stockholm Convention, Rotterdam Convention and Minamata Convention in relation to the export of those substances.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2017-11, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Background</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Notice</MarginalNote><Label>3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>These Regulations set out the content of the notice of proposed export that is required under subsection 101(1) of the Act for substances specified in Schedule 3 to the Act, and the period within which and manner in which the notice must be provided.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Conditions of export</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>These Regulations also set out</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for the purposes of subsection 101(3) of the Act, the conditions applicable to the export of a substance that is specified in Part 2 or 3 of Schedule 3 to the Act and that is also targeted by the Stockholm Convention or the Minamata Convention; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for the purposes of subsections 101(2) and (3) of the Act, the conditions applicable to the export of a substance that is specified in Schedule 3 to the Act to a Rotterdam Party, including permit, liability insurance and labelling requirements.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2017-11, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Application</MarginalNote><Label>4</Label><Text>These Regulations apply to the export of substances specified in the Export Control List.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Notice of Proposed Export</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Deadline</MarginalNote><Label>5</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The notice of proposed export that is required under subsection 101(1) of the Act must be provided to the Minister by the person proposing the export of a substance at least</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>if the person holds a permit to export the substance issued under paragraph 185(1)(b) of the Act or under the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Ozone-depleting Substances and Halocarbon Alternatives Regulations</XRefExternal>, seven days before the export; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in any other case, 15 days before the export.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Effective date</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The notice is considered to be provided to the Minister</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>on the day on which it is delivered, if it is delivered personally;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>on the day on which it is postmarked, if it is sent by mail; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>on the date that is indicated by the sending apparatus, if it is sent by electronic mail or by facsimile.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Content of notice</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The notice of proposed export must</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>provide the information set out in Schedule 1; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>be accompanied by a certification, dated and signed by the person proposing the export, or by their duly authorized representative, stating that the information provided in the notice is accurate and complete.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Electronic or paper submission</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The notice of proposed export and the certification may be submitted either in writing or in an electronic format that is compatible with the one that is used by the Minister and the documents must bear the signature of the person proposing the export or their duly authorized representative.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Notification of changes</MarginalNote><Label>(5)</Label><Text>The exporter must notify the Minister in writing of any change to the information provided in a notice of proposed export within 30 days after learning of it.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2017-11, s. 4.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Conditions Relative to the Stockholm Convention</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Persistent organic pollutant</MarginalNote><Label>6</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>In this section, <DefinedTermEn>persistent organic pollutant</DefinedTermEn> means a substance listed in Annex A or B of the Stockholm Convention, other than one added to that Convention by an amendment that is not in force for Canada.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>POP specified in Part 2 or 3 of Schedule 3 to Act</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A person that has provided a notice of proposed export under subsection 101(1) of the Act may export a persistent organic pollutant that is specified in Part 2 or 3 of the Export Control List under the following conditions, unless the export of that persistent organic pollutant is prohibited by any other regulation made under the Act:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>if a specific exemption or acceptable purpose is listed in Annex A or B of the Stockholm Convention for that persistent organic pollutant and the export is to a Stockholm Party,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>that Party has registered a specific exemption or acceptable purpose in the relevant Register established under the Stockholm Convention and the export complies with the terms of that specific exemption or acceptable purpose,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>in the case of a persistent organic pollutant added to the Stockholm Convention by an amendment that is not in force for that Party, an annual certification for the year in question regarding that Party that is in accordance with paragraph 2 (b) (iii) of Article 3 of the Stockholm Convention has been transmitted by Canada to the Secretariat established under that Convention, and the export complies with the terms of the specific exemption or acceptable purpose listed in those Annexes;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>if a specific exemption or acceptable purpose is listed in Annex A or B of the Stockholm Convention for that persistent organic pollutant and the export is to a State or regional economic integration organization that is not a party to the Stockholm Convention, an annual certification for the year in question regarding that State or organization that is in accordance with paragraph 2 (b) (iii) of Article 3 of the Stockholm Convention has been transmitted by Canada to the Secretariat established under that Convention, and the export complies with the terms of the specific exemption or acceptable purpose listed in those Annexes;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the persistent organic pollutant is exported in accordance with paragraph 1 (d) of Article 6 of the Stockholm Convention;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the persistent organic pollutant is exported for use in a laboratory for analysis, in scientific research or as a laboratory analytical standard and the total quantity exported by the person during the calendar year in question does not exceed 10 kg;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the persistent organic pollutant is incidentally present in trace amounts in the product that is being exported; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>the persistent organic pollutant is contained in a product</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>that was manufactured on or before the entry into force for Canada of a provision of the Stockholm Convention prohibiting, under Annex A, or restricting, under Annex B, the production or use of that persistent organic pollutant, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>in respect of which a notification has been provided by Canada in accordance with note (ii) to Annex A or B of the Stockholm Convention and the notification has been made publicly available in accordance with that note by the Secretariat established under the terms of that Convention.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Non-application</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Subsection (2) does not apply to a persistent organic pollutant that is, or is contained in, a hazardous waste or hazardous recyclable material regulated by the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Export and Import of Hazardous Waste and Hazardous Recyclable Material Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2017-11, s. 5.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Conditions Relative to the Rotterdam Convention</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>General Provisions</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Application</MarginalNote><Label>7</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to section 23, sections 8 to 22 set out the additional conditions applicable to the export of a substance specified in the Export Control List if that export is to a Rotterdam Party.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Non-application</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Sections <XRefInternal>8</XRefInternal> to <XRefInternal>22</XRefInternal> do not apply to a substance that</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>is contained in a manufactured item that during manufacture is formed into a specific physical shape or design and has for its final use a function or functions wholly or partly dependent on its shape or design;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>is, or is contained in, a hazardous waste or hazardous recyclable material regulated by the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Export and Import of Hazardous Waste and Hazardous Recyclable Material Regulations</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>is, or is contained in, a controlled substance as defined in subsection 2(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Controlled Drugs and Substances Act</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>is, or is contained in, a nuclear substance as defined in section 2 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Nuclear Safety and Control Act</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>is, or is contained in, a chemical weapon as defined by the Convention on the Prohibition of the Development, Production, Stockpiling and Use of Chemical Weapons and on Their Destruction, signed at Paris, France, on January 13, 1993, as amended from time to time;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>is, or is contained in, a food or drug as defined in section 2 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Food and Drugs Act</XRefExternal> or a food additive as defined in Part B of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Food and Drug Regulations</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>is contained in a product at a concentration of less than 0.1% by weight;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>is exported for the personal use of the individual who imports it, if the total quantity exported by the exporter during the calendar year in question does not exceed 10 kg; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>is exported for use in a laboratory for analysis, in scientific research or as a laboratory analytical standard, if the total quantity exported by the exporter during the calendar year in question does not exceed 10 kg.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2017-11, s. 6.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Exports Not Requiring a Permit</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Substances not subject to prior informed consent procedure</MarginalNote><Label>8</Label><Text>A person that has provided a notice of proposed export under subsection 101(1) of the Act may export a substance — other than a substance specified in Part 1 of the Export Control List — that is specified in Annex III of the Rotterdam Convention, but that is destined for use in a category other than the category specified for that substance in that Annex, if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>that person is a resident of Canada or, in the case of a corporation, has a place of business in Canada; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>that person meets the requirements of sections <XRefInternal>20</XRefInternal> to <XRefInternal>22</XRefInternal>.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2017-11, s. 7.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Direction issued by Minister</MarginalNote><Label>9</Label><Text>If a person is required to export a substance specified in Part 1 of the Export Control List in compliance with a direction issued by the Minister under subparagraph 99(b)(iii) of the Act, that person must meet the requirements of sections <XRefInternal>20</XRefInternal> to <XRefInternal>22</XRefInternal> in addition to providing the notice of proposed export required under subsection 101(1) of the Act.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Exports Requiring a Permit</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Conditions of Export</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Substances in question</MarginalNote><Label>10</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to section 9, any person proposing to export any of the following substances must hold an export permit:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a substance that is specified in Part 2 or 3 of the Export Control List and Annex III of the Rotterdam Convention and that is destined for use in the category specified for that substance in that Annex;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a substance that is specified in Part 1 of the Export Control List whether or not it is specified in Annex III of the Rotterdam Convention; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a substance that is specified in Part 3 of the Export Control List and that is not specified in Annex III of the Rotterdam Convention.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Additional conditions</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Any person referred to in subsection (1) that has provided the Minister with a notice of proposed export under subsection 101(1) of the Act must</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>be a resident of Canada or, in the case of a corporation, have a place of business in Canada;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>meet the requirements of sections <XRefInternal>20</XRefInternal> to <XRefInternal>22</XRefInternal>; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>include a copy of the export permit with each shipment of the substance.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2017-11, s. 8.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Permit Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Content of application</MarginalNote><Label>11</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The application for an export permit must include the information listed in Schedule 2 and be accompanied by</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a written undertaking dated and signed by the exporter, or by their duly authorized representative, stating that the exporter assumes full responsibility for the removal of the substance from the country of destination and any related costs, including the transportation, care, control and storage of the substance, in the event that the exporter exports the substance in contravention of any conditions set out in the export permit or if the export takes place after the export permit has expired or been cancelled;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the case referred to in subparagraph 12(1)(c)(iii), documentation confirming that the substance has been used in or imported into the country of destination in the last 10 years;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>in the case referred to in subparagraph 12(1)(c)(iv), the written consent of the designated national authority of the country of destination to the import of the substance; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a certification dated and signed by the exporter, or by their duly authorized representative, stating that the information provided in the application is accurate and complete.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Electronic or paper submission</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The application and the documents referred to in subsection (1) may be submitted either in writing or in an electronic format that is compatible with the one that is used by the Minister.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Combined notice and permit application</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>If the notice of proposed export and the application for an export permit in relation to a particular substance are provided to the Minister at the same time, the exporter does not need to provide the information referred to in items 1, 2 and 4 to 8 of Schedule 2 if that information is provided in the notice.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2017-11, s. 9.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Issuance of Export Permits</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Substances subject to prior informed consent procedure</MarginalNote><Label>12</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to section 16, in the case of the export of a substance subject to the prior informed consent procedure that is specified in Part 1 of the Export Control List and destined for destruction or a substance subject to the prior informed consent procedure that is specified in Part 2 or 3 of the Export Control List, the Minister must issue an export permit if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the permit application is received before the Rotterdam Secretariat has first informed the Rotterdam Parties through the PIC Circular of the country of destination’s response with respect to the import of the substance or of its failure to transmit that response;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the permit application is received after the Rotterdam Secretariat has first informed the Rotterdam Parties through the PIC Circular that the country of destination has given consent to the import of the substance; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the permit application is received after the Rotterdam Secretariat has first informed the Rotterdam Parties through the PIC Circular that the country of destination has failed to transmit a response with respect to the import of the substance and</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the permit application is received before the end of the six-month period that begins on the date of publication of that PIC Circular,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the permit application is received after the end of the 18-month period that begins on the date of publication of that PIC Circular,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>no regulatory action has been taken by the country of destination to prohibit the use of the substance and the substance has been used in or imported into the country of destination in the last 10 years, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>the designated national authority of the country of destination has given written consent to the import of the substance.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Conditions of import</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>An export permit issued under subsection (1) must specify the conditions of import imposed by the country of destination as set out in the PIC Circular or as may be specified in the designated national authority’s written consent, if applicable.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2017-11, s. 10.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Other substances — Part 1 of Export Control List</MarginalNote><Label>13</Label><Text>Subject to section <XRefInternal>16</XRefInternal>, in the case of an export for destruction of a substance — other than a substance subject to the prior informed consent procedure — specified in Part 1 of the Export Control List, the Minister must issue an export permit on receipt of the permit application.</Text></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Other substances — Part 3 of Export Control List</MarginalNote><Label>14</Label><Text>Subject to section 16, the Minister must, on receipt of a permit application, issue an export permit for the export of a substance specified in Part 3 of the Export Control List that is not specified in Annex III of the Rotterdam Convention.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2017-11, s. 11.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Expiry of permit</MarginalNote><Label>15</Label><Text>An export permit expires at the end of the calendar year for which it is issued.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Refusal to Issue Permit</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Reasonable grounds</MarginalNote><Label>16</Label><Text>The Minister must refuse to issue an export permit if the Minister believes on reasonable grounds that</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the exporter is not able to export the substance in compliance with the Act, these Regulations or the conditions imposed by the country of destination;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the export would contravene the Act, any regulations made under the Act or any other measure taken under the Act; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the exporter provided false or misleading information in the notice of proposed export, in the permit application or in any document provided under paragraph 11(1)(b) or (c).</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2017-11, s. 12.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Cancellation, Amendment or Suspension of Permit</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Consent for import not provided</MarginalNote><Label>17</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>If the Rotterdam Secretariat advises the Rotterdam Parties through the PIC Circular that a country of destination does not consent to the import of a substance for which an export permit has been issued, the Minister must cancel the permit and the cancellation takes effect on the day that is six months after the date of publication of that PIC Circular.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Revocation of consent</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>If a designated national authority advises the Minister that it revokes its written consent to the import of a substance for which an export permit has been issued, the Minister must cancel the permit and the cancellation takes effect on the day that is 30 days after the day on which the Minister is advised of the revocation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Failure to transmit response</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>If the Rotterdam Secretariat advises the Rotterdam Parties for the first time through the PIC Circular that a country of destination has failed to transmit a response with respect to the import of a substance for which an export permit has been issued under paragraph <XRefInternal>12</XRefInternal>(1)(a) or subparagraph <XRefInternal>12</XRefInternal>(1)(c)(i), the Minister must cancel the permit and the cancellation takes effect on the day that is six months after the date of publication of that PIC Circular.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Modification of conditions of import — PIC Circular</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>If the Rotterdam Secretariat advises the Rotterdam Parties through the PIC Circular that a country of destination has modified the conditions of import of a substance for which an export permit has been issued, the Minister must amend the permit in accordance with the new conditions and the amendment takes effect on the day that is six months after the date of publication of that PIC Circular.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Modification of conditions of import — designated national authority</MarginalNote><Label>(5)</Label><Text>If a designated national authority advises the Minister that it has modified the conditions of import of a substance for which an export permit has been issued, the Minister must amend the permit in accordance with the new conditions and the amendment takes effect 30 days after the day on which the Minister is advised of the modifications.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Obligations of Minister</MarginalNote><Label>(6)</Label><Text>The Minister may cancel or amend an export permit under this section only if a notice giving reasons for the amendment or cancellation has been sent to the exporter by mail, electronic mail or facsimile.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Reasonable grounds</MarginalNote><Label>18</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The Minister must cancel an export permit if the Minister believes on reasonable grounds that</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the exporter is not able to export the substance in compliance with the Act, these Regulations or the conditions set out in the export permit;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the export contravenes the Act, any regulations made under the Act or any other measure taken under the Act;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the exporter failed to comply with a condition set out in the export permit;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the exporter failed to comply with the undertaking provided under paragraph 11(1)(a); or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the exporter provided false or misleading information in the notice of proposed export, in the permit application or in any document provided under paragraph 11(1)(b) or (c).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Notice of proposed cancellation</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The Minister must, before cancelling an export permit under this section, notify the exporter of the proposed cancellation by mail, electronic mail or facsimile.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Content of notice</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The notice of proposed cancellation must</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>indicate the reasons for the proposed cancellation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>inform the exporter of the interim suspension of the permit; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>inform the exporter that it may make written representations concerning the proposed cancellation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Interim suspension of permit</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The export permit is suspended for the period beginning on the day on which the notice of the proposed cancellation is received and ending on the day on which the Minister makes a decision respecting the proposed cancellation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Written representations</MarginalNote><Label>(5)</Label><Text>The exporter may, within 15 days after the day on which the notice is received, make written representations concerning the proposed cancellation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Date of receipt</MarginalNote><Label>(6)</Label><Text>The notice of proposed cancellation is considered to have been received by the exporter</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>on the day on which it is delivered, if it is delivered personally;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>on the 10th day after the day on which it is postmarked, if it is sent by mail; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>on the date that is indicated by the sending apparatus, if it is sent by electronic mail or by facsimile.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2017-11, s. 13.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Retention of Records</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Period of retention</MarginalNote><Label>19</Label><Text>An exporter must keep at the exporter’s principal place of business in Canada, for a period of five years after the end of the calendar year for which the export permit is issued,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the export permit;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a copy of the application for the export permit and the documents required under paragraphs 11(1)(a) to (d) if the originals were submitted to the Minister or, if copies were submitted to the Minister, the original of the application and documents;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>for each export of a substance, proof of liability insurance coverage as required under section <XRefInternal>20</XRefInternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>for each export of a substance, a copy of the label referred to in section <XRefInternal>21</XRefInternal> and the safety data sheet referred to in section <XRefInternal>22</XRefInternal>; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>any shipping documents or any other documents that substantiate the date of the export and the exact quantity of the substance that was exported.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-19, s. 3(F); SOR/2017-11, s. 14.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Liability Insurance</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Amount</MarginalNote><Label>20</Label><Text>The exporter must have liability insurance in an amount of not less than $5,000,000 for each export in respect of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any damages arising from the export for which the exporter could become liable; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any costs that could be imposed on the exporter under the applicable laws for cleaning up the environment as a result of the substance being released into the environment during export.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Labelling</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Information to appear on label</MarginalNote><Label>21</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>An exporter must affix to any container in which a substance is exported a label that includes the following information in both official languages and, as far as practicable, at least one of the official languages of the country of destination:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the name of the substance as it appears on the Export Control List and the commodity code of the substance as it is identified in the Harmonized Commodity Description and Coding System;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a description of the hazards to the environment or human health that can arise from the nature of the substance or, if applicable, the product that contains it; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the precautionary measures to be followed when handling, using or being exposed to the substance or, if applicable, the product that contains it, and the first aid measures to be administered in case of exposure.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Bulk shipment</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>In the case of a bulk shipment, the exporter must either affix a label in accordance with subsection (1) or include with each shipment a label or a document that contains the information required to be included on the label.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Definition of <DefinitionRef>bulk shipment</DefinitionRef></MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>For the purposes of subsection (2), <DefinitionRef>bulk shipment</DefinitionRef> means the shipment of a substance without any packaging or containment other than containment in</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a vessel having a water capacity of more than 454 L;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a freight container or a portable tank;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a road vehicle or a railway vehicle; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the hold of a ship.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2017-11, s. 15.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Safety Data Sheet</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Information required</MarginalNote><Label>22</Label><Text>The exporter must include with each export of the substance, in both official languages and, as far as practicable, at least one of the official languages of the country of destination, a safety data sheet as defined in section 2 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Hazardous Products Act</XRefExternal> that meets the requirements of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Hazardous Products Regulations</XRefExternal> in respect of the substance or, if applicable, the product that contains it.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-19, s. 4.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Conditions Relative to the Minamata Convention</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Restrictions</MarginalNote><Label>23</Label><Text>A person that has provided a notice of proposed export under subsection 101(1) of the Act may export a mixture that contains elemental mercury (CAS 7439-97-6) at a concentration of 95% or more by weight only if the mixture</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>is, or is contained in, a hazardous waste or hazardous recyclable material regulated by the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Export and Import of Hazardous Waste and Hazardous Recyclable Material Regulations</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>is exported for use in a laboratory for analysis, in scientific research or as a laboratory analytical standard, if the total quantity exported by the exporter during the calendar year in question does not exceed 10 kg; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>is contained in a manufactured item that during manufacture is formed into a specific physical shape or design and has for its final use a function or functions wholly or partly dependent on its shape or design.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2017-11, s. 16.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>24</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2017-11, s. 16]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>25</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2017-11, s. 16]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>26</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2017-11, s. 16]</Repealed></Text></Section></Body><Schedule><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 1</Label><OriginatingRef>(Subsection <XRefInternal>5</XRefInternal>(3))</OriginatingRef><TitleText>Information To Be Provided in Notice of Proposed Export</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><RegulationPiece><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>The name, civic and postal addresses, telephone number and, if any, fax number and email address, in Canada, of the person proposing to export a substance.</Text></Section><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>The name, title, civic and postal addresses, telephone number and, if any, fax number and email address of the duly authorized representative, if applicable.</Text></Section><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>For each substance exported, by country of destination,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the name of the substance as it appears on the Export Control List;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the country of destination;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the expected date or dates of export;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the estimated quantity of the substance to be exported;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>an indication</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>that the export is for the purpose of destroying the substance, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>that the substance is intended for either industrial, pesticidal or another use;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>an indication of whether the substance is exported under the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Export and Import of Hazardous Waste and Hazardous Recyclable Material Regulations</XRefExternal>, if applicable; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>in the case of a substance specified in Part 2 or 3 of the Export Control List and also listed in Annex A or B of the Stockholm Convention,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>if the substance is exported under paragraph 6(2)(a) or (b), an indication of the specific exemption or acceptable purpose that applies to the substance,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>an indication of whether the substance is exported under paragraph 6(2)(c) and, if so, the name and civic address of the facility at which the disposal or recycling will take place and the method that will be used to dispose of or recycle the substance,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>an indication of whether the substance is exported for use in a laboratory for analysis, in scientific research or as a laboratory analytical standard,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>an indication of whether the substance is incidentally present in trace amounts in the product that is being exported, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(v)</Label><Text>an indication of whether the substance is exported under paragraph 6(2)(f) and, if so, the date of manufacture of the product that is being exported.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Section></RegulationPiece><HistoricalNote>SOR/2017-11, s. 17.</HistoricalNote></Schedule><Schedule><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 2</Label><OriginatingRef>(Subsections 11(1) and (3))</OriginatingRef><TitleText>Information To Be Provided in Application for Export Permit</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><RegulationPiece><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>The name, civic and postal addresses, telephone number and, if any, fax number and email address, in Canada, of the exporter.</Text></Section><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>The name, title, civic and postal addresses, telephone number and, if any, fax number and email address of the duly authorized representative, if applicable.</Text></Section><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>The name, civic and postal addresses, telephone number and, if any, fax number and email address of the importer.</Text></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>The name of the substance as it appears on the Export Control List.</Text></Section><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>The expected date or dates of export.</Text></Section><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>The estimated quantity of the substance to be exported.</Text></Section><Section><Label>7</Label><Text>The country of destination.</Text></Section><Section><Label>8</Label><Text>An indication</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>that the export is for the purpose of destroying the substance; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>that the substance is intended for either industrial, pesticidal or another use.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>9</Label><Text>The common name and trade name of the substance, if applicable.</Text></Section><Section><Label>10</Label><Text>The CAS registry number of the substance, if applicable.</Text></Section><Section><Label>11</Label><Text>The commodity code for the substance set out in the Harmonized Commodity Description and Coding System prepared by the World Customs Organization, as amended from time to time, if applicable.</Text></Section><Section><Label>12</Label><Text>If the substance is contained in a product,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the name of the product; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the concentration of the substance in the product.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>13</Label><Text>The following information respecting the export:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the customs office through which it is expected to be exported from Canada, if known;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the countries through which the substance will transit, if known; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the proposed number of exports for the calendar year, if known.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>14</Label><Text>The safety data sheet for the substance or, if applicable, for the product that contains the substance.</Text></Section></RegulationPiece><HistoricalNote>SOR/2015-19, s. 5; SOR/2017-11, ss. 18, 19.</HistoricalNote></Schedule><Schedule id="RelatedProvs"><ScheduleFormHeading type="amending"><TitleText>RELATED PROVISIONS</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><RegulationPiece><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2015-19, s. 7</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>7.</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>In this section, <DefinedTermEn>former Regulations</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Export of Substances on the Export Control List Regulations</XRefExternal> as they read immediately before the day on which these Regulations come into force.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>These Regulations do not apply to an exporter if the exporter exports a substance on or after the first day on which both sections 114 and 115 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Economic Action Plan 2014 Act, No. 1</XRefExternal> are in force, but before a day to be fixed by order of the Governor in Council for the purposes of sections 131, 134 and 136 of that Act, and if the exporter would not, were the former Regulations in force at the time, be in contravention of the former Regulations.</Text></Subsection></Section></RegulationPiece></Schedule></Regulation>