<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/95-552</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1995</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>23</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>28</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">TERRITORIAL LANDS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Government Employees Land Acquisition Order, 1995, No. 3</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Authorizing a Certain Employee of the Government of Canada to Acquire an Interest in Territorial Lands in the Northwest Territories</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1995-1949 </OrderNumber><Date><YYYY> 1995</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>23</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Indian Affairs and Northern Development, pursuant to paragraph 29(1)(a) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Territorial Lands Act</XRefExternal>, is pleased hereby to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Order authorizing a certain employee of the Government of Canada to acquire an interest in territorial lands in the Northwest Territories</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Government Employees Land Acquisition Order, 1995, No. 3</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Authorization</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>The employee of the Government of Canada named in the schedule is hereby authorized to acquire an interest in territorial lands in the Northwest Territories as described in the schedule.</Text></Section></Body><Schedule bilingual="no" spanlanguages="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label></ScheduleFormHeading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>To Frank Albert Tsetso, of the Village of Fort Simpson in the Northwest Territories, Peace Officer, a member of the Royal Canadian Mounted Police, to lease, for a trapper’s cabin, the whole of a parcel of land situated on the northerly shore of Cli Lake, at approximately 61°59′ North Latitude and 123°17′ West Longitude, in Quad numbered 95 G/14 in the Northwest Territories, as said parcel is shown outlined in red on a sketch plan on file 33-1-12 in the Land Management Division of the Department of Indian Affairs and Northern Development at Ottawa, saving and excepting therefrom and reserving thereout all mines and minerals, including hydrocarbons, whether solid, liquid or gaseous and the right to work them.</Text></Provision></Schedule></Regulation>