<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/89-30a</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1988</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>27</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2011</YYYY><MM>3</MM><DD>25</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">PUBLIC SERVICE EMPLOYMENT ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Employment Equity Programs Exclusion Approval Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Approving the Exclusion by the Public Service Commission of Certain Persons and Positions from the Operation of Certain Provisions of the Public Service Employment Act for the Purposes of the Employment Equity Programs during the Period Beginning on January 1, 1989 and Ending on March 31, 1993</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1988-2798</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1988</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>22</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas the Public Service Commission has decided that it is not practicable nor in the best interests of the Public Service</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>to apply section 10 and subsection 12(3) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal> to positions identified pursuant to the employment equity programs to which target group members coming from outside the Public Service are to be appointed;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>to apply subsection 12(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal> in relation to selection standards other than language skills to training positions identified pursuant to the employment equity programs to which members of a target group coming from outside the Public Service are to be appointed;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>to apply section 10 and subsection 12(3) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal> to positions other than those identified pursuant to the employment equity programs to which target group members, who were appointed to the Public Service for a specified period to a training position identified pursuant to the employment equity programs, are to be appointed; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(d)</Label><Text>to apply subsection 21(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal> to persons who would otherwise have a right to appeal under that subsection against the appointment of target group members, who were appointed to the Public Service for a specified period to a training position identified pursuant to the employment equity programs, to positions other than those identified pursuant to the employment equity programs;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>during the period beginning on January 1, 1989 and ending on March 31, 1993.</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas the Public Service Commission is of the opinion that it is desirable to make the annexed Regulations respecting the appointment of target group members to positions within the employment equity programs during the period beginning on January 1, 1989 and ending on March 31, 1993.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas the Public Service Commission recommends that, pursuant to subsection 41(2) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal>, the Governor in Council approve the revocation by the Public Service Commission of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Northern Careers Exclusion of Native Persons Approval Order</XRefExternal>, C.R.C., c. 1347;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas, pursuant to subsection 37(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal>, the Public Service Commission recommends that the Governor in Council revoke the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Northern Careers Appointments Regulations</XRefExternal>, C.R.C., c. 1346;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas the Public Service Commission recommends that, pursuant to subsection 41(2) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal>, the Governor in Council approve the revocation by the Public Service Commission of the exclusion of certain provisions of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal> for the purposes of the Visible Minority Employment Program during the period beginning on December 22, 1986 and ending on March 31, 1989 approved by Order in Council P.C. 1986-2859 of December 18, 1986<FootnoteRef idref="fn_1e">*</FootnoteRef> and in consequence thereof to revoke the said Order in Council;</Text><Footnote id="fn_1e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>SOR/87-22, 1987 <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal> Part II, p. 229</Text></Footnote></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas, pursuant to subsection 37(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal>, the Public Service Commission recommends that the Governor in Council revoke the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Visible Minority Employment Program Regulations</XRefExternal>, P.C. 1986-2859 of December 18, 1986<FootnoteRef idref="fn_1e">*</FootnoteRef>;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas the Public Service Commission recommends that, pursuant to subsection 41(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal>, the Governor in Council make in substitution therefor the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Order approving the exclusion by the Public Service Commission of certain persons and positions from the operation of certain provisions of the Public Service Employment Act for the purposes of the employment equity programs during the period beginning on January 1, 1989 and ending on March 31, 1993</XRefExternal>;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>And whereas, pursuant to subsection 37(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal>, the Public Service Commission recommends that the Governor in Council make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting the appointment of target group members to positions within the employment equity programs during the period beginning on January 1, 1989 and ending on March 31, 1993</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Therefore, Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Secretary of State, is pleased hereby</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>pursuant to subsection 41(2) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal>, to approve the revocation by the Public Service Commission of <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Northern Careers Exclusion of Native Persons Approval Order</XRefExternal>, C.R.C., c. 1347;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>pursuant to subsection 37(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal>, to revoke the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Northern Careers Appointment Regulations</XRefExternal>, C.R.C., c. 1346;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>pursuant to subsection 41(2) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal>, to approve the revocation by the Public Service Commission of the exclusion of certain provisions of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal> for the purposes of the Visible Minority Employment Program during the period beginning on December 22, 1986 and ending on March 31, 1989 approved by Order in Council P.C. 1986-2859 of December 18, 1986<FootnoteRef idref="fn_1e">*</FootnoteRef> and in consequence thereof to revoke the said Order in Council;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(d)</Label><Text>pursuant to subsection 37(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal>, to revoke the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Visible Minority Employment Program Regulatoins</XRefExternal>, P.C. 1986-2859 of December 18, 1986<FootnoteRef idref="fn_1e">*</FootnoteRef>;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(e)</Label><Text>pursuant to subsection 41(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal>, to make in substitution therefor the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Order approving the exclusion by the Public Service Commission of certain persons and positions from the operation of certain provisions of the Public Service Employment Act for the purposes of the employment equity programs during the period beginning on January 1, 1989 and ending on March 31, 1993</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(f)</Label><Text>pursuant to subsection 37(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal>, to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting the appointment of target group members to positions within the employment equity programs during the period beginning on January 1, 1989 and ending on March 31, 1993</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Employment Equity Programs Exclusion Approval Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In this Order,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>aboriginal peoples</DefinedTermEn> means persons who are</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>Canadian Status Indians,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>Canadian non-Status Indians,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>Canadian Inuit, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>Canadian Métis; (<DefinedTermFr>autochtones</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>disabled persons</DefinedTermEn> means persons who, for purposes of employment, consider themselves, or who believe that a potential employer would likely consider them, disadvantaged by reason of any persistent physical, mental, psychiatric, learning or sensory impairment; (<DefinedTermFr>personnes handicapées</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>employment equity programs</DefinedTermEn> means the following programs</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>Access Program for Disabled Persons approved by the Treasury Board under T.B. minutes number 789462 of July 14, 1983, number 802603 of June 19, 1986 and number 807057 of November 26, 1987,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>National Indigenous Development Program approved by the Treasury Board under T.B. minutes number 789462 of July 14, 1983 and number 807057 of November 26, 1987,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>Northern Careers Program approved by the Treasury Board under T.B. minutes number 739310 of November 20, 1975 and number 807057 of November 26, 1987,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>Visible Minority Employment Program approved by the Treasury Board under T.B. minutes number 802603 of June 19, 1986 and number 807057 of November 26, 1987,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>Non-Traditional Occupations Program for Women approved by the Treasury Board under T.B. minutes number 802603 of June 19, 1986 and number 807057 of November 26, 1987; (<DefinedTermFr>programmes d’équité en matière d’emploi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>members of visible minority groups</DefinedTermEn> means persons who are, because of their race or colour, in a visible minority in Canada; (<DefinedTermFr>membres des minorités visibles</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>target group members</DefinedTermEn> means disabled persons, members of visible minority groups, aboriginal peoples or women. (<DefinedTermFr>membres des groupes-cibles</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Approval</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>The exclusion by the Public Service Commission from the operation of section 10 and subsection 12(3) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal> of positions identified pursuant to the employment equity programs to which target group members coming from outside the Public Service are to be appointed during the period beginning on January 1, 1989 and ending on March 31, 1993, is hereby approved.</Text></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>The exclusion by the Public Service Commission from the operation of subsection 12(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal> in relation to selection standards other than language skills of training positions identified pursuant to the employment equity programs to which target group members coming from outside the Public Service are to be appointed during the period beginning on January 1, 1989 and ending on March 31, 1993, is hereby approved.</Text></Section><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>The exclusion by the Public Service Commission from the operation of section 10 and subsection 12(3) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal> of positions other than those identified pursuant to the employment equity programs to which target group members who were appointed to the Public Service for a specified period to a training position identified pursuant to these programs, are to be appointed during the period beginning on January 1, 1989 and ending on March 31, 1993, is hereby approved.</Text></Section><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>The exclusion by the Public Service Commission from the operation of subsection 21(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal> of all persons who, but for this Order, would have a right to appeal under that subsection against the appointment of target group members, who were appointed to the Public Service for a specified period to a training position identified pursuant to the employment equity programs, to other positions than those identified pursuant to the employment equity programs during the period beginning on January 1, 1989 and ending on March 31, 1993, is hereby approved.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>