<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en" in-force="yes"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2007-63</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2007</YYYY><MM>3</MM><DD>22</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2007</YYYY><MM>4</MM><DD>5</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CONFLICT OF INTEREST ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Service of Documents Required or Authorized to be Served Under Sections 53 to 57 of the Conflict of Interest Act Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2007-415</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>2007</YYYY><MM>3</MM><DD>22</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Prime Minister, pursuant to section 54 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Conflict of Interest Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="footnotea_e">a</FootnoteRef>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Service of Documents Required or Authorized To Be Served Under Sections 53 to 57 of the Conflict of Interest Act Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="footnotea_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 2006, c. 9, s. 2</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Service of Documents</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Methods of service</MarginalNote><Label>1</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A document required or authorized to be served on a public office holder under sections 53 to 57 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Conflict of Interest Act</XRefExternal> may be served</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>personally, by delivering a copy of it</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>to the public office holder at any place, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>if the public office holder cannot conveniently be found, to a person who appears to be at least 18 years of age at the public office holder’s last known address or usual place of residence;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>by registered mail or courier to the public office holder’s last known address, usual place of residence or place of work; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>by electronic transmission, including by fax or e-mail, to the public office holder’s last known address, usual place of residence or place of work.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>When a copy required to be sent by registered mail</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>If a document is served by electronic transmission, a copy of it shall also be sent by registered mail.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2011-323, s. 1(F).</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Date of service</MarginalNote><Label>2</Label><Text>The date of service of a document is</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>if the document is delivered personally, the day on which it is delivered;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>if the document is served by registered mail or by courier, the 10th day after the date indicated in the receipt issued to the sender by the postal or courier service, as the case may be; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>if the document is served by electronic transmission, the day on which it is sent.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Proof of service</MarginalNote><Label>3</Label><Text>Any of the following documents constitute proof of service:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>an acknowledgment of service signed by or on behalf of the person served; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>an affidavit of service stating the name of the person who served the document and the date, place and manner of service.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section type="normal"><MarginalNote>Coming into force</MarginalNote><Label><FootnoteRef idref="fnstar_e">*</FootnoteRef>4</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on the day on which section 54 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Conflict of Interest Act</XRefExternal> as enacted by section 2 of Chapter 9 of the Statutes of Canada, 2006, comes into force or, if it is later, on the day on which they are registered.</Text><Footnote id="fnstar_e" placement="section" status="editorial"><Label>*</Label><Text>[Note: Regulations in force July 9, 2007, <Emphasis style="italic">see</Emphasis> SI/2007-75.]</Text></Footnote></Section></Body></Regulation>