<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/93-581</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1993</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>14</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>9</MM><DD>8</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CUSTOMS TARIFF</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Textile and Apparel Extension of Benefit Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Respecting the Extension of the Benefit of the Mexico Tariff and the United States Tariff to Certain Textile and Apparel Goods</LongTitle></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The Minister of Finance, pursuant to subsection 25.2(7)<FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-93-581_e_hq_5240">*</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-93-581_e_hq_5241">**</FootnoteRef>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Order respecting the extension of the benefit of the Mexico Tariff and the United States Tariff to certain textile and apparel goods</XRefExternal>, effective on the day on which subsection 117(3) of <XRefExternal reference-type="act">An Act to implement the North American Free Trade Agreement</XRefExternal>, being chapter 44 of the Statutes of Canada, 1993, comes into force.</Text><Footnote id="fn_SOR-93-581_e_hq_5240" placement="page" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>S.C. 1993, c. 44, s. 117(3)</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="fn_SOR-93-581_e_hq_5241" placement="page" status="official"><Label>**</Label><Text>R.S., c. 41 (3rd Supp.)</Text></Footnote></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Ottawa, December 14, 1993</Text></Provision><Provision language-align="yes"><SignatureBlock justification="right" width="20pc"><SignatureName justification="right" topmarginspacing="10">PAUL MARTIN</SignatureName><SignatureTitle justification="right"><Emphasis style="italic">Minister of Finance</Emphasis></SignatureTitle></SignatureBlock></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Textile and Apparel Extension of Benefit Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In this Order,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>apparel</DefinedTermEn> means goods referred to in Chapters 61 and 62 of Schedule I to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal> that are cut or knit to shape and are sewn or otherwise assembled in Mexico or the United States from fabric or yarn produced or obtained outside the free trade area; (<DefinedTermFr>vêtements</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>fabric and made-up goods</DefinedTermEn> means</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>cotton or man-made fibre fabric or cotton or man-made fibre made-up textile goods referred to in Chapters 52 to 55 of Schedule I to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal>, other than goods containing 36% or more by weight of wool or fine animal hair, and in Chapters 58, 60 and 63 of Schedule I to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal> that are woven or knitted in Mexico or the United States from yarn produced or obtained outside the free trade area or that are knitted in Mexico or the United States from yarn spun in Mexico or the United States from fibre produced or obtained outside the free trade area, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>goods of subheading No. 9404.90 of Schedule I to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal> that are finished and cut and sewn or otherwise assembled from fabrics referred to in any of subheading Nos. 5208.11 to 5208.29, 5209.11 to 5209.29, 5210.11 to 5210.29, 5211.11 to 5211.29, 5212.11, 5212.12, 5212.21, 5212.22, 5407.41, 5407.51, 5407.71, 5407.81, 5407.91, 5408.21, 5408.31, 5512.11, 5512.21, 5512.91, 5513.11 to 5513.19, 5514.11 to 5514.19, 5516.11, 5516.21, 5516.31, 5516.41 and 5516.91 of Schedule I to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal> that are produced or obtained outside the free trade area; (<DefinedTermFr>tissus et articles confectionnés</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>free trade area</DefinedTermEn> means the area comprising Canada, Mexico and the United States; (<DefinedTermFr>zone de libre-échange</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>spun yarn</DefinedTermEn> means cotton or man-made fibre yarns referred to in any of heading Nos. 52.05 to 52.07 or 55.09 to 55.11 of Schedule I to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal> that are spun in Mexico or the United States from fibre referred to in any of heading Nos. 52.01 to 52.03 or 55.01 to 55.07 of Schedule I to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal> that is produced or obtained outside the free trade area. (<DefinedTermFr>filés</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Extension of Benefit</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>Subject to section 4, the benefit of the United States Tariff and the Mexico Tariff is extended to apparel, fabric and made-up goods and spun yarn imported into Canada from the United States and Mexico, respectively, in an amount not exceeding the respective annual quantitative limits for each of those goods set out in Schedules 6.B.1, 6.B.2 and 6.B.3 to Appendix 6 of Annex 300-B to Chapter Three of the North American Free Trade Agreement.</Text></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>The benefit referred to in section 3 is extended on the condition that the importer or owner provides to the officer, at the request of the officer,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>at the time that the apparel, fabric and made-up goods or spun yarn referred to in that section are accounted for under subsection 32(1), (3) or (5) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Act</XRefExternal> or are the subject of an application for a refund under paragraph 74(1)(c.2) of that Act, a written declaration, in English or French, indicating that the certification referred to in paragraph (b) is in the possession of the importer or owner; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>at the time that the apparel, fabric and made-up goods or spun yarn referred to in that section are released, or at any other time after the importer or owner provides a declaration referred to in paragraph (a) in respect of the goods,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>a certification of the exporter, in English, French or Spanish, containing the statement set out in, and the information requested by, the form set out in the schedule, accompanied by a copy of the applicable invoice or sales agreement, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>where the certification referred to in subparagraph (i) is in Spanish, at the further request of the officer, a translation of the certification into English or French.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Section></Body><Schedule bilingual="no" spanlanguages="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 4)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><FormGroup><ScheduleFormHeading><TitleText>Exporter’s Certification of Non-Originating Textile Goods</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>I, the exporter of the textile or apparel goods referred to in the attached invoice or sales agreement, hereby certify that those goods comply with the requirements specified in respect of those goods in Appendix 6 of Annex 300-B to Chapter Three of the North American Free Trade Agreement.</Text></Provision><TableGroup pointsize="9" topmarginspacing="4"><table frame="none"><tgroup cols="2"><colspec colname="COLSPEC1" colwidth="0.41*" /><colspec colname="COLSPEC2" colwidth="1.07*" /><tbody><row rowsep="0"><entry colsep="0">NAME:</entry><entry colsep="1"><LeaderRightJustified leader="solid" /></entry></row><row rowsep="0"><?PubTbl row rht="0.34in"?><entry colsep="0">TITLE:</entry><entry colsep="1"><LeaderRightJustified leader="solid" /></entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colsep="0">COMPANY:</entry><entry colsep="1"><LeaderRightJustified leader="solid" /></entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colsep="0">TELEPHONE:</entry><entry colsep="1"><LeaderRightJustified leader="solid" /></entry></row><row rowsep="0"><?PubTbl row rht="0.38in"?><entry colsep="0">FAX:</entry><entry colsep="1"><LeaderRightJustified leader="solid" /></entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text><FormBlank width="6.5pc">Signature of exporter</FormBlank><LeaderRightJustified leader="none" /><FormBlank width="4pc">Date</FormBlank></Text></Provision></FormGroup></Schedule></Regulation>