<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/99-86</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1999</YYYY><MM>2</MM><DD>10</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2014</YYYY><MM>9</MM><DD>26</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">VISITING FORCES ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Proclamation Designating Certain Countries as Designated States for Purposes of the Act and Designating the Civilian Personnel of the Designated States</LongTitle></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><SignatureBlock width="16pc"><SignatureName>ROMÉO LEBLANC</SignatureName><SignatureTitle>[L.S.]</SignatureTitle></SignatureBlock></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Canada</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-1" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Elizabeth the Second, by the Grace of God of the United Kingdom, Canada and Her other Realms and Territories QUEEN, Head of the Commonwealth, Defender of the Faith.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-1" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>To All To Whom these Presents shall come or whom the same may in any way concern,</Text></Provision><Provision justification="right" language-align="yes"><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Greeting</Emphasis>:</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><SignatureBlock justification="left" width="16 pc"><SignatureName justification="left">MORRIS ROSENBERG</SignatureName><SignatureTitle justification="left"><Emphasis style="italic">Deputy Attorney General</Emphasis></SignatureTitle></SignatureBlock></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>A Proclamation</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Whereas section 4 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Visiting Forces Act</XRefExternal>, chapter V-2 of the Revised Statutes of Canada, 1985, provides that the Governor in Council may by proclamation designate any country as a designated state for the purposes of that Act, declare the extent to which that Act is applicable in respect of any designated state and designate civilian personnel as a civilian component of a visiting force;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Now Know You that We, by and with the advice of Our Privy Council for Canada, pursuant to Order in Council P.C. 1999-21 of January 21, 1999, do by this Our Proclamation</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>designate the Republic of Albania, the Republic of Austria, the Azerbaijani Republic, the Republic of Bulgaria, the Republic of Finland, the Republic of Georgia, the Republic of Kazakhstan, the Republic of Moldova, the Republic of Slovenia, the Kingdom of Sweden, the former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia, the Republic of Uzbekistan and the Kingdom of Spain as designated states for the purposes of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Visiting Forces Act</XRefExternal>,</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>declare that the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Visiting Forces Act</XRefExternal>, with the exception of Part VI, is applicable in respect of the designated states referred to in paragraph (a),</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>designate, for the purposes of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Visiting Forces Act</XRefExternal>, the civilian personnel of the designated states referred to in paragraph (a) as a civilian component of a visiting force if the personnel are in the employ of that force and are not stateless persons, nationals of any state that is not a designated state, or citizens of or residents of Canada,</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(d)</Label><Text>designate, for the purposes of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Visiting Forces Act</XRefExternal>, the civilian personnel of the designated states of the Czech Republic, the Republic of Hungary, the Republic of Poland, the Slovak Republic and Ukraine, which states were designated by Our Proclamation dated May 19, 1993 and registered as SOR/93-264, as a civilian component of a visiting force if the personnel are in the employ of that force and are not stateless persons, nationals of any state that is not a designated state, or citizens of or residents of Canada, and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(e)</Label><Text>designate, for the purposes of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Visiting Forces Act</XRefExternal>, the civilian personnel of the designated states of the Republic of Estonia, the Republic of Latvia, the Republic of Lithuania and Romania, which states were designated by Our Proclamation dated December 28, 1995 and registered as SOR/96-78, as a civilian component of a visiting force if the personnel are in the employ of that force and are not stateless persons, nationals of any state that is not a designated state, or citizens of or residents of Canada.</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Of All Which Our Loving Subjects and all others whom these Presents may concern are hereby required to take notice and to govern themselves accordingly.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-1" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>In Testimony Whereof, We have caused these Our Letters to be made Patent and the Great Seal of Canada to be hereunto affixed. Witness: Our Right Trusty and Well-beloved Roméo A. LeBlanc, a Member of Our Privy Council for Canada, Chancellor and Principal Companion of Our Order of Canada, Chancellor and Commander of Our Order of Military Merit, Governor General and Commander-in-Chief of Canada.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-1" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>At Our Government House, in Our City of Ottawa, this tenth day of February in the year of Our Lord one thousand nine hundred and ninety-nine and in the forty-eighth year of Our Reign.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="right-align" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><SignatureBlock justification="right" width="16 pc"><SignatureName justification="right">By Command,</SignatureName><SignatureName justification="right" topmarginspacing="1pc">KEVIN G. LYNCH</SignatureName><SignatureTitle justification="right"><Emphasis style="italic">Deputy Registrar General of Canada</Emphasis></SignatureTitle></SignatureBlock></Provision></Order></Regulation>