<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2003-374</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2003</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>19</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>05</MM><DD>27</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">PERSONAL INFORMATION PROTECTION AND ELECTRONIC DOCUMENTS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Organizations in the Province of Quebec Exemption Order</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2003-1842</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>2003</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>19</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision language-align="yes" format-ref="indent-0-0" list-item="no"><Text>Whereas the Governor in Council is satisfied that <XRefExternal reference-type="act">An Act respecting the protection of personal information in the private sector</XRefExternal>, R.S.Q., c. P-39.1, of the Province of Quebec which is substantially similar to Part 1 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="footnotea_e">a</FootnoteRef>, applies to the organizations referred to in the annexed Order;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>Therefore, Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Industry, pursuant to paragraph 26(2)(b) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef>a</FootnoteRef>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Organizations in the Province of Quebec Exemption Order</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="footnotea_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 2000, c. 5</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Exemption</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>Any organization, other than a federal work, undertaking or business, that carries on an enterprise within the meaning of section 1525 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Civil Code of Québec</XRefExternal> and to which <XRefExternal reference-type="act">An Act respecting the protection of personal information in the private sector</XRefExternal>, R.S.Q., c. P-39.1, applies is exempt from the application of Part 1 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act</XRefExternal> in respect of the collection, use and disclosure of personal information that occurs within the Province of Quebec.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section type="transitional"><Label>2</Label><Text>This Order comes into force on the day on which it is registered.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>