<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2010-138</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2010</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>17</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2010</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>15</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CANADIAN ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION ACT, 1999</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Regulations Prescribing Circumstances for Granting Waivers Pursuant to Section 147 of the Act</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2010-763</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>2010</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>17</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas, pursuant to subsection 332(1)<FootnoteRef idref="a">a</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canadian Environmental Protection Act, 1999</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="b">b</FootnoteRef>, the Minister of the Environment published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>, Part I, on November 14, 2009, a copy of the proposed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations Prescribing Circumstances for Granting Waivers Pursuant to Section 147 of the Act</XRefExternal>, substantially in the annexed form, and persons were given an opportunity to file comments with respect to the proposed Regulations or to file a notice of objection requesting that a board of review be established and stating the reasons for the objection;</Text><Footnote id="a" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 2004, c. 15, s. 31</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="b" placement="page" status="official"><Label>b</Label><Text>S.C. 1999, c. 33</Text></Footnote></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Therefore, Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of the Environment, pursuant to section 145 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canadian Environmental Protection Act, 1999</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="b">b</FootnoteRef>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations Prescribing Circumstances for Granting Waivers Pursuant to Section 147 of the Act</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Prescribed Circumstances</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>The circumstances in which the Minister may, pursuant to section 147 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canadian Environmental Protection Act, 1999</XRefExternal>, grant the waiver provided for under that section are</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>an actual or anticipated shortage of fuel exists and one of the following measures has been made or issued:</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>a proclamation by the Governor in Council under subsection 6(1), 17(1), 28(1) or 38(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Emergencies Act</XRefExternal>,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>an order by the Governor in Council under subsection 15(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Energy Supplies Emergency Act</XRefExternal>,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>an order by the Lieutenant Governor in Council or the Premier, under section 7.0.1 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Emergency Management and Civil Protection Act</XRefExternal> of Ontario, R.S.O. 1990, c. E-9, as amended from time to time,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>a declaration by the Government or the Minister of Public Security, under section 88 or 89 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Civil Protection Act</XRefExternal> of Quebec, R.S.Q., c. S-2.3, as amended from time to time,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(v)</Label><Text>a declaration by the Minister of Emergency Management, under subsection 12(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Emergency Management Act</XRefExternal> of Nova Scotia, S.N.S. 1990, c. 8, as amended from time to time,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(vi)</Label><Text>a declaration by the Minister of Public Safety, under subsection 11(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Emergency Measures Act</XRefExternal> of New Brunswick, S.N.B. 1978, c. E-7.1, as amended from time to time,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(vii)</Label><Text>a declaration by the responsible Minister, under section 10 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Emergency Measures Act</XRefExternal> of Manitoba, C.C.S.M. c. E80, as amended from time to time,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(viii)</Label><Text>an order by the responsible Minister or the Lieutenant Governor in Council, under section 9 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Emergency Program Act</XRefExternal> of British Columbia, R.S.B.C. 1996, c. 111, as amended from time to time,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ix)</Label><Text>a declaration by the responsible Minister, under subsection 9(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Emergency Measures Act</XRefExternal> of Prince Edward Island, R.S.P.E.I. 1988, c. E-6.1, as amended from time to time,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(x)</Label><Text>an order by the Lieutenant Governor in Council, under section 17 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Emergency Planning Act</XRefExternal> of Saskatchewan, S.S. 1989-90, c. E-8.1, as amended from time to time,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(xi)</Label><Text>an order by the Lieutenant Governor in Council, under section 18 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Emergency Management Act</XRefExternal> of Alberta, R.S.A. 2000, c. E-6.8, as amended from time to time,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(xii)</Label><Text>a declaration by the Lieutenant-Governor in Council, under subsection 11(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Emergency Services Act</XRefExternal> of Newfoundland and Labrador, S.N.L. 2008, c. E-9.1, as amended from time to time,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(xiii)</Label><Text>a declaration by the Commissioner in Executive Council, under section 6 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Civil Emergency Measures Act</XRefExternal> of Yukon, R.S.Y. 2002, c. 34, as amended from time to time,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(xiv)</Label><Text>an order by the responsible Minister, under section 11 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Civil Emergency Measures Act</XRefExternal> of the Northwest Territories, R.S.N.W.T. 1988, c. C-9, as amended from time to time, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(xv)</Label><Text>a declaration by the responsible Minister, under section 11 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Emergency Measures Act</XRefExternal> of Nunavut, S.Nu. 2007, c. 10, as amended from time to time; or</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>an actual or anticipated shortage of fuel exists and the Minister of National Defence advised the Minister in writing that the actual or anticipated shortage of fuel affects or could affect the Government of Canada’s ability to protect national security, support humanitarian relief efforts, participate in multilateral military or peace-keeping activities under the auspices of international organizations or defend a member state of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on the day on which they are registered.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>