<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2015-36</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2015</YYYY><MM>2</MM><DD>6</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2015</YYYY><MM>2</MM><DD>25</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">RADIOCOMMUNICATION ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Radiocommunication Act (Subsection 4(4) and Paragraph 9(1)(<Emphasis style="regular">b</Emphasis>)) Exemption Order, No. 2015-1</LongTitle></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>The Minister of Industry, pursuant to subsection 14(1)<FootnoteRef idref="fn_a">a</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Radiocommunication Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_b">b</FootnoteRef>, makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Radiocommunication Act (Subsection 4(4) and Paragraph 9(1)(b)) Exemption Order, No. 2015-1</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Ottawa, February 3, 2015</Text><SignatureBlock justification="right" width="20pc"><SignatureName justification="right" topmarginspacing="8">JAMES MOORE</SignatureName><SignatureTitle justification="right"><Emphasis style="italic">Minister of Industry</Emphasis></SignatureTitle></SignatureBlock></Provision><Footnote id="fn_a" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 2014, c. 39, s. 181</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="fn_b" placement="page" status="official"><Label>b</Label><Text>R.S., c. R-2; S.C. 1989, c. 17, s. 2</Text></Footnote></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Definition of <DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn></MarginalNote><Label>1</Label><Text>In this Order, <DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Radiocommunication Act</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Exemption</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>RCMP employees</MarginalNote><Label>2</Label><Text>Subject to sections 3 to 7, employees of the Royal Canadian Mounted Police Technical Investigation Services Branch, as well as other employees of the Royal Canadian Mounted Police who are required, as part of their duties or training, to install, use, possess, manufacture or import a jammer and to follow any applicable directives from that Branch in relation to jammers, are exempt from the application of subsection 4(4) and paragraph 9(1)(b) of the Act during the period beginning on the day on which this Order comes into force and ending five years after that day in respect of their installation, use, possession, manufacturing or importation of any jammer, if they are trained in relation to those activities or are in the process of receiving such training.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Conditions</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Permitted purposes</MarginalNote><Label>3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The exemption applies only if, in the case of an exemption from the application of subsection 4(4) of the Act, the jammer is installed, used, possessed, manufactured or imported or, in the case of an exemption from the application of paragraph 9(1)(b) of the Act, the radiocommunication is interfered with or obstructed, for any of the following purposes:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>national security;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>public safety;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>international relations;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the investigation or prosecution of offences in Canada, including the preservation of evidence; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the protection of property or the prevention of serious harm to any person.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Limitation</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Every reasonable effort must be made to restrict the jammer’s interference with or obstruction of radiocommunications to the smallest physical area, the fewest number of frequencies, the appropriate power level and the minimum duration required to accomplish the intended purpose.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Jammer characteristics</MarginalNote><Label>4</Label><Text>The jammer must allow for adjustments to power levels and affected frequencies.</Text></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Installation and use</MarginalNote><Label>5</Label><Text>An employee who installs or uses a jammer must do so in a manner that minimizes unwanted emissions and radio interference as well as the exposure of any person to radiofrequency fields.</Text></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Possession</MarginalNote><Label>6</Label><Text>An employee who possesses a jammer must</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>ensure that it is turned off and stored in a secure location when it is not in use, including when it is being transported; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>at all times prevent access to it by a person who is not exempt from the application of subsection 4(4) of the Act.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Information to Industry Canada</MarginalNote><Label>7</Label><Text>The Royal Canadian Mounted Police must</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>maintain records of when and where jammers are used by its employees and allow those records to be examined on request by Industry Canada; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>provide to Industry Canada, on request, any information that Industry Canada requires for the purpose of investigating any cases of radio interference that may be the result of jammer use by Royal Canadian Mounted Police employees.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Registration</MarginalNote><Label>8</Label><Text>This Order comes into force on the day on which it is registered.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>