<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en" in-force="yes"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2006-104</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2006</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>18</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2006</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>16</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CANADIAN ENVIRONMENTAL ASSESSMENT ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Crown Corporations Involved in the Provision of Commercial Loans Environmental Assessment Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2006-403</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>2006</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>18</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of the Environment, pursuant to paragraph 59(j.2)<FootnoteRef idref="footnotea_e">a</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canadian Environmental Assessment Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="footnoteb_e">b</FootnoteRef>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Crown Corporations Involved in the Provision of Commercial Loans Environmental Assessment Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="footnotea_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 2003, c. 9, s. 29(4)</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="footnoteb_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>b</Label><Text>S.C. 1992, c. 37</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>The following definitions apply in these Regulations.</Text><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canadian Environmental Assessment Act</XRefExternal>. (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>responsible authority</DefinedTermEn> means the Business Development Bank of Canada continued and named in subsection 3(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Business Development Bank of Canada Act</XRefExternal> and Farm Credit Canada continued and named in subsection 3(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Farm Credit Canada Act</XRefExternal>. (<DefinedTermFr>autorité responsable</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>These Regulations apply in respect of projects for which the responsible authority exercises a power or performs a duty or function referred to in paragraph 5(1)(b) of the Act.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Variations</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The registry requirements set out in subsections 55.1(2) and 55.3(1) and (2) of the Act are varied in accordance with the schedule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Subsections 20(3) and (4) of the Act apply only if the responsible authority gives or is required to give the public an opportunity to participate in the screening in accordance with subsection 18(3) of the Act.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2007-264, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section type="transitional"><Label>4</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on June 11, 2006.</Text></Section></Body><Schedule><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label><OriginatingRef>(Subsection 3(1))</OriginatingRef><TitleText>Variations</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><RegulationPiece><Section type="amending"><Label>1</Label><Subsection type="amending"><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The requirement set out in paragraph 55.1(2)(a) of the Act is varied as follows:</Text><AmendedText><SectionPiece><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>within 14 days after the commencement of an environmental assessment, notice of its commencement, except if a class screening report is used under subsection 19(5) or (6) or if the screening is to be conducted without public participation;</Text></Paragraph></SectionPiece></AmendedText></Subsection><Subsection type="amending"><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The requirement set out in paragraph 55.1(2)(c) of the Act is varied as follows:</Text><AmendedText><SectionPiece><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a description of the scope of the project in relation to which an environmental assessment is to be conducted as determined under section 15, except when the screening is to be conducted without public participation;</Text></Paragraph></SectionPiece></AmendedText></Subsection><Subsection type="amending"><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The requirements set out in subsection 55.1(2) of the Act are varied by adding the following after paragraph (d) of that subsection:</Text><AmendedText><SectionPiece><Paragraph><Label>(d.1)</Label><Text>a statement of the projects in respect of which a responsible authority takes a course of action under subsection 20(1);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d.2)</Label><Text>before the responsible authority takes a course of action under subsection 20(1), any environmental assessment policies, procedures and guidance materials it used in the conduct of the environmental assessment;</Text></Paragraph></SectionPiece></AmendedText></Subsection><Subsection type="amending"><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The requirement set out in paragraph 55.1(2)(f) of the Act is varied as follows:</Text><AmendedText><SectionPiece><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>in the case of a screening conducted with public participation or a comprehensive study, notice of termination of an environmental assessment by a responsible authority under section 26;</Text></Paragraph></SectionPiece></AmendedText></Subsection><Subsection type="amending"><Label>(5)</Label><Text>The requirement set out in paragraph 55.1(2)(k) of the Act is varied as follows:</Text><AmendedText><SectionPiece><Paragraph><Label>(k)</Label><Text>the screening or comprehensive study report taken into consideration by a responsible authority for the purpose of a course of action under section 20 or 37 or a description of how a copy of the report may be obtained, except if a class screening report is used under subsection 19(5) or (6) or if the screening is conducted without public participation;</Text></Paragraph></SectionPiece></AmendedText></Subsection><Subsection type="amending"><Label>(6)</Label><Text>The requirements set out in paragraphs 55.1(2)(r) and (s) of the Act are varied as follows:</Text><AmendedText><SectionPiece><Paragraph><Label>(r)</Label><Text>except if a class screening report is used under subsection 19(5) or (6) or if the screening is conducted without public participation, the course of action of a responsible authority, made under section 20 or 37 concerning the environmental effects of the project, and a statement of any mitigation measures the implementation of which the responsible authority took into account in making its decision;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(s)</Label><Text>in the statement of projects referred to in paragraph (d.1), a notice of any follow-up program considered appropriate pursuant to subsection 38(1) if the screening is conducted without public participation;</Text></Paragraph></SectionPiece></AmendedText></Subsection></Section><Section type="amending"><Label>2</Label><Text>The requirements set out in subsections 55.3(1) and (2) of the Act are varied as follows:</Text><AmendedText><Section><Label>55.3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A responsible authority shall ensure that the records referred to in paragraphs 55.1(2)(s) and (t) and, in the case of a screening or comprehensive study, the records or information referred to in paragraphs 55.1(2)(h) and (u) and any record or information referred to in paragraph 55.1(2)(v) are included in the Internet site as well as the records referred to in</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>paragraphs 55.1(2)(a), (c), (f), (j), (k) and (r), in the case of a screening conducted with public participation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>paragraph 55.1(2)(d.2), in the case of a screening conducted without public participation; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>paragraphs 55.1(2)(a), (c), (f), (k) and (r), in the case of a comprehensive study</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A responsible authority shall ensure that the statements referred to in paragraphs 55.1(2)(d) and (d.1) are included in the Internet site every three months or with any other greater frequency to which it agrees with the Agency.</Text></Subsection></Section></AmendedText></Section></RegulationPiece></Schedule></Regulation>