<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/99-182</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1999</YYYY><MM>4</MM><DD>15</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>10</MM><DD>27</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">INSURANCE COMPANIES ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Insurance Companies Assessed Expenses Recovery Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1999-649 </OrderNumber><Date><YYYY> 1999</YYYY><MM>4</MM><DD>15</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Finance, pursuant to section 692<FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-99-182_e_hq_5604">a</FootnoteRef> and paragraph 703(a) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Insurance Companies Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-99-182_e_hq_5605">b</FootnoteRef>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Insurance Companies Assessed Expenses Recovery Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fn_SOR-99-182_e_hq_5604" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 1997, c. 15, s. 328</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="fn_SOR-99-182_e_hq_5605" placement="page" status="official"><Label>b</Label><Text>S.C. 1991, c. 47</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>In the French version of these Regulations, <DefinedTermFr>société</DefinedTermFr> has the meaning assigned to it by section 663 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Insurance Companies Act</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Reduction of Assessments</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>Money in an amount equal to or less than $1,000,000 that is paid to or recovered by Her Majesty in any period beginning on April 1 in any year and ending on March 31 in the next year under section 691 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Insurance Companies Act</XRefExternal> or paragraph 161(1)(d) or (6)(c) or subparagraph 161(8)(b)(iv) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Winding-up and Restructuring Act</XRefExternal> in respect of a company, society, foreign company or provincial company shall be applied on a pro rata basis to reduce the assessments under section 23 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Office of the Superintendent of Financial Institutions Act</XRefExternal> against companies, societies, foreign companies and provincial companies that have been assessed under subsection 687(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Insurance Companies Act</XRefExternal> in respect of that company, society, foreign company or provincial company.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Payment</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsections (2) and (3), money in an amount greater than $1,000,000 that is paid to or recovered by Her Majesty in any period beginning on April 1 in any year and ending on March 31 in the next year under section 691 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Insurance Companies Act</XRefExternal> or paragraph 161(1)(d) or (6)(c) or subparagraph 161(8)(b)(iv) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Winding-up and Restructuring Act</XRefExternal> in respect of a company, society, foreign company or provincial company shall be paid on a pro rata basis to the companies, societies, foreign companies and provincial companies that have been assessed under subsection 687(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Insurance Companies Act</XRefExternal> in respect of that company, society, foreign company or provincial company.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Expenses incurred to find a company, society, foreign company or provincial company in respect of which a payment is to be made, or to find its successors or beneficiaries, shall be deducted from the amount payable to that company, society, foreign company or provincial company.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>No payment shall be made if the amount of the payment would be less than $10.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>If a company, society, foreign company or provincial company in respect of which a payment is to be made, or its successors or beneficiaries, cannot be found after reasonable attempts have been made to do so, the amount of the payment determined under section 3 shall be applied on a pro rata basis to reduce the assessments under section 23 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Office of the Superintendent of Financial Institutions Act</XRefExternal> against companies, societies, foreign companies and provincial companies.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on the day on which they are registered.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>