<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/87-315</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1987</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>4</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2009</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>10</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">FAMILY ORDERS AND AGREEMENTS ENFORCEMENT ASSISTANCE ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Release of Information for Family Orders and Agreements Enforcement Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1987-1151</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1987</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>4</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Justice, pursuant to section 22 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Family Orders and Agreements Enforcement Assistance Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-87-315_e_hq_8169">*</FootnoteRef>, is pleased hereby to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting the release of information that may assist in locating defaulting spouses and other persons</XRefExternal>, effective on the day Part I of the said Act comes into force.</Text><Footnote id="fn_SOR-87-315_e_hq_8169" placement="page"><Label>*</Label><Text>S.C. 1986, c. 5</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Section><Label>1</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2002-278, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations, <DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Family Orders and Agreements Enforcement Assistance Act</XRefExternal>. (<Emphasis style="italic">Loi</Emphasis>)</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Designated Information Banks</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>For the purposes of section 15 of the Act, the following information banks are designated as information banks that may be searched under Part I of the Act:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>information banks controlled by the Department of Employment and Social Development, namely,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>Canada Pension Plan Record of Earnings (ESDC/PPU-140),</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>Canada Pension Plan — Retirement, Disability, Survivors and Death Benefits (individuals) (ESDC/PPU-146),</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>International Social Security — Domestic and Foreign Benefits — Computer Master Benefit Data (ESDC/PPU-175), and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>Employment Insurance Program Investigation (ESDC/PPU-171);</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>information banks controlled by the Canada Employment Insurance Commission, namely,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>Record of Employment (Third Copy) (ESDC/PPU-171),</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>Benefit and Overpayment File (ESDC/PPU-180), and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>Social Insurance Number Register (ESDC/PPU-390);</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>information banks controlled by the Canada Revenue Agency, namely,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>Individual Returns and Payment Processing (CRA/PPU-005), and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>Business Number and Program Account Registration (CRA/PPU-223).</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/97-178, s. 1; SOR/2018-63, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application Form and Affidavit</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>An application under section 13 of the Act for the release of information shall be</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in the form set out in Schedule 1;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>accompanied by an affidavit in the form set out in Schedule 2 and the supporting documentation required under section 14 of the Act; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>mailed to</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-2-2" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>The Minister of Justice,</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-2-2" language-align="no" list-item="no" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>Department of Justice,</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-2-2" language-align="no" list-item="no" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>Family Orders and Agreements Enforcement Assistance Unit,</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-2-2" language-align="no" list-item="no" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>Ottawa, Ontario</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-2-2" language-align="no" list-item="no" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>K1A 0H8.</Text></Provision></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>For the purposes of subsection 14(3) of the Act, where an application under section 13 of the Act is made by a provincial enforcement service, the application and accompanying affidavit may also be sent by the means of electronic communication that has been agreed upon by the provincial enforcement service and the Department of Justice.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/97-178, s. 2; SOR/2013-104, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Search Request</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>The Minister shall, on receiving an application referred to in section 4 together with the supporting documents required under section 14 of the Act, request that the Chairman of the Canada Employment Insurance Commission provide or verify the social insurance number of the person who is the subject of that application, and shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>where he receives the social insurance number or verification thereof, transmit a search request in respect of that person to the information bank directors; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>where he is informed by the Chairman of the Canada Employment Insurance Commission that the social insurance number cannot be provided or verified, inform the applicant that the search cannot be carried out.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/97-178, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Search of Designated Information Banks</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>For the purpose of section 17 of the Act and subject to section 7 of these Regulations, an information bank director shall, on receiving a search request from the Minister, search the designated information banks under the control of the information bank director for such information concerning the person who is the subject of the search request as may be released under section 16 of the Act.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Release of Information Between Information Bank Directors</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>7</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>An information bank director who receives a search request from the Minister may, before or while carrying out the search referred to in section 6, make a request to the other information bank director for such additional information as may be necessary in order to conduct that search.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>An information bank director who receives a request referred to in subsection (1) for additional information shall search the designated information banks under his control and shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>if the additional information requested is found, communicate the information to the requesting director; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>if the additional information requested is not found, report that result to the requesting director.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Release of Information to the Minister</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>8</Label><Text>An information bank director shall transmit to the Minister</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the information referred to in section 6; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>where the information referred to in section 6 has not been found, a report of that result.</Text></Paragraph></Section></Body><Schedule spanlanguages="yes" bilingual="yes"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 1 / <Language xml:lang="fr">ANNEXE 1</Language></Label><OriginatingRef>(Paragraph 4(1)(a)) / <Language xml:lang="fr">(alinéa 4(1)a))</Language></OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><ImageGroup bilingual="yes" position="center" width="35pc"><AlternateText>T01 Application: Release of Information under Part I of the Family Orders and Agreements Enforcement Assistance Act form</AlternateText><Image source="SOR-87-315img\SOR-87-315_ef005.JPG" /></ImageGroup><ImageGroup bilingual="yes" position="center" width="35pc"><AlternateText>Continued T01 Application: Release of Information under Part I of the Family Orders and Agreements Enforcement Assistance Act form</AlternateText><Image source="SOR-87-315img\SOR-87-315_ef006.JPG" /></ImageGroup><HistoricalNote>SOR/97-178, s. 5; SOR/2013-104, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Schedule><Schedule spanlanguages="yes" bilingual="yes"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 2 / <Language xml:lang="fr">ANNEXE 2</Language></Label><OriginatingRef>(Paragraph 4(1)(b)) / <Language xml:lang="fr">(alinéa 4(1)b))</Language></OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><ImageGroup bilingual="yes" position="center" width="35pc"><AlternateText>T02 Affidavit in Support of an Application under Part I of the Family Orders and Agreements Enforcement Assistance Act form</AlternateText><Image source="SOR-87-315img\SOR-87-315_ef007.JPG" /></ImageGroup><ImageGroup bilingual="yes" position="center" width="35pc"><AlternateText>Continued T02 Affidavit in Support of an Application under Part I of the Family Orders and Agreements Enforcement Assistance Act form</AlternateText><Image source="SOR-87-315img\SOR-87-315_ef008.JPG" /></ImageGroup><HistoricalNote>SOR/97-178, s. 5; SOR/2013-104, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Schedule></Regulation>