<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/85-154</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1985</YYYY><MM>2</MM><DD>8</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>7</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">FOREIGN MISSIONS AND INTERNATIONAL ORGANIZATIONS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>World Meteorological Organization Privileges and Immunities Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Respecting the Privileges and Immunities in Canada of the World Meteorological Organization</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1985-356 </OrderNumber><Date><YYYY> 1985</YYYY><MM>2</MM><DD>7</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Secretary of State for External Affairs, pursuant to section 3<FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-85-154_e_hq_6022">*</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Privileges and Immunities (International Organizations) Act</XRefExternal> is pleased hereby to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Order respecting the Privileges and Immunities in Canada of the World Meteorological Organization</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fn_SOR-85-154_e_hq_6022" placement="page" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>S.C. 1974-75-76, c. 69, s. 2</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">World Meteorological Organization Privileges and Immunities Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In this Order,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Convention</DefinedTermEn> means the Convention on the Privileges and Immunities of the United Nations; (<DefinedTermFr>Convention</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Organization</DefinedTermEn> means the World Meteorological Organization. (<DefinedTermFr>Organisation</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Privileges and Immunities</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The Organization shall have in Canada the legal capacities of a body corporate and shall, to such extent as may be required for the performance of its functions, have the privileges and immunities set forth in Articles II and III of the Convention.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Representatives of states and governments that are members of the Organization shall have in Canada, to such extent as may be required for the performance of their functions, the privileges and immunities set forth in Article IV of the Convention for representatives of Members.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Officials of the Organization shall have in Canada, to such extent as may be required for the performance of their functions, the privileges and immunities set forth in Article V of the Convention for officials of the United Nations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Experts performing missions for the Organization shall have in Canada, to such extent as may be required for the performance of their functions, the privileges and immunities set forth in Article VI of the Convention for experts on missions for the United Nations.</Text></Subsection></Section></Body></Regulation>