<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/94-721</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1994</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>15</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>28</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS MARKETING ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Saskatchewan Milk Order</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1994-1878</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1994</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>15</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision language-align="yes" format-ref="indent-0-0" list-item="no"><Text>His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Agriculture, pursuant to section 2<FootnoteRef idref="footnote1_e">*</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Agricultural Products Marketing Act</XRefExternal>, is pleased hereby to repeal the Saskatchewan Milk Order, C.R.C., c. 278, and to make the annexed Order granting authority to The Milk Control Board of Saskatchewan to regulate the marketing in interprovincial and export trade of milk produced in Saskatchewan, in substitution therefor.</Text><Footnote id="footnote1_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>S.C. 1991, c. 34, s. 2</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Section><Label>1</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2001-16, s. 48]</Repealed></Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In this Order,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means <XRefExternal reference-type="act">The Milk Control Act, 1992</XRefExternal> of Saskatchewan; (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Commodity Board</DefinedTermEn> means The Milk Control Board of Saskatchewan established pursuant to the Act; (<DefinedTermFr>Office</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>milk</DefinedTermEn> means milk or cream from cows, produced for consumer use in liquid form in Canada; (<DefinedTermFr>lait</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Plan</DefinedTermEn> means a plan for the marketing of milk, established and amended from time to time pursuant to the Act. (<DefinedTermFr>plan</DefinedTermFr>) </Text></Definition><HistoricalNote>SOR/2001-16, s. 49.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2.1</Label><Text>This Order applies in respect of milk produced in the Province of Saskatchewan and milk referred to in paragraph 3(1)(b) produced in the Provinces of Alberta and Manitoba.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2001-16, s. 50.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interprovincial Trade</TitleText><HistoricalNote>[SOR/2001-16, s. 51]</HistoricalNote></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (2), the Commodity Board is authorized to regulate the marketing of milk in interprovincial trade and for that purpose may exercise all or any powers like the powers exercisable by the Commodity Board in relation to the marketing of milk locally within the province under the Act and a Plan, with respect to</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>persons and property situated within the Province of Saskatchewan, except in respect of milk produced in that Province and marketed in the Provinces of Alberta or Manitoba pursuant to a milk quota granted by the Alberta Milk Control Board or the Manitoba Milk Producers in accordance with the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Alberta Milk Order</XRefExternal> or the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Manitoba Milk Order</XRefExternal>, respectively; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>persons situated within the Provinces of Alberta and Manitoba who ship milk produced in those provinces to the Province of Saskatchewan, and who have been given milk quota pursuant to this Order.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The authority to regulate the marketing of milk in interprovincial trade does not include any power that is exercised by the Canadian Dairy Commission under the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canadian Dairy Commission Act</XRefExternal> in relation to the marketing of milk in interprovincial trade.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2001-16, s. 52.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Levies or Charges</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>The Commodity Board may, in relation to the powers granted to it under section 3,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>fix and impose levies or charges on milk or any component of milk and collect those levies or charges from persons described in subsection 3(1) who are engaged in the production or marketing of milk and for that purpose may classify those persons into groups and fix the levies or charges payable by the members of the different groups in different amounts; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>use the levies or charges for the purposes of the Commodity Board, including the creation of reserves, the payment of expenses and losses resulting from the sale or disposal of milk and the equalization or adjustment among producers of milk of moneys realized from the sale of milk during such period or periods of time as the Commodity Board may determine.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2001-16, s. 53.</HistoricalNote></Section></Body></Regulation>