<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2013-141</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2013</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>20</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2013</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>4</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">NAVIGABLE WATERS PROTECTION ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Proclamation Exempting the Mink Arm portion of South McMahon Lake from the Operation of Section 22 of the Act</LongTitle></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>DAVID JOHNSTON</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>[L.S.]</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Canada</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-1" language-align="yes"><Text>ELIZABETH THE SECOND, by the Grace of God of the United Kingdom, Canada and Her other Realms and Territories QUEEN, Head of the Commonwealth, Defender of the Faith.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-1" language-align="yes"><Text>TO ALL TO WHOM these Presents shall come or whom the same may in any way concern,</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="right-align" language-align="yes"><Text><Emphasis style="italic">Greeting</Emphasis>:</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><SignatureBlock justification="left" width="15pc"><SignatureName justification="left">WILLIAM PENTNEY</SignatureName><SignatureTitle justification="left"><Emphasis style="italic">Deputy Attorney General</Emphasis></SignatureTitle></SignatureBlock></Provision><Provision format-ref="centered"><Text>A PROCLAMATION</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas section 23 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Navigable Waters Protection Act</XRefExternal> provides that when it is shown to the satisfaction of the Governor in Council that the public interest would not be injuriously affected thereby, the Governor in Council may, by proclamation, declare any rivers, streams or waters in respect of which section 22 of that Act applies, or any parts thereof, exempt in whole or in part from the operation of that section;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas the Governor in Council is satisfied that the public interest would not be injuriously affected by exempting the Mink Arm portion of South McMahon Lake, located in Saskatchewan, from the operation of section 22 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Navigable Waters Protection Act</XRefExternal>;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>And whereas, by Order in Council P.C. 2013-614 of May 30, 2013, the Governor in Council directed that a proclamation do issue declaring that the Mink Arm portion of South McMahon Lake, located in Saskatchewan, be exempt from the operation of section 22 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Navigable Waters Protection Act</XRefExternal>;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Now know you that We, by and with the advice of Our Privy Council for Canada, do by this Our proclamation direct that the Mink Arm portion of South McMahon Lake, located in Saskatchewan, be exempt from the operation of section 22 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Navigable Waters Protection Act</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Of all which Our Loving Subjects and all others whom these presents may concern are required to take notice and to govern themselves accordingly.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-1" language-align="yes"><Text>In testimony whereof, We have caused this Our proclamation to be published and the Great Seal of Canada to be hereunto affixed. WITNESS: Our Right Trusty and Well-beloved David Johnston, Chancellor and Principal Companion of Our Order of Canada, Chancellor and Commander of Our Order of Military Merit, Chancellor and Commander of Our Order of Merit of the Police Forces, Governor General and Commander-in-Chief of Canada.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-1" language-align="yes"><Text>AT OUR GOVERNMENT HOUSE, in Our City of Ottawa, this seventeenth day of June in the year of Our Lord two thousand and thirteen and in the sixty-second year of Our Reign.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><SignatureBlock justification="right" width="20pc"><SignatureLine justification="right">By Command,</SignatureLine><SignatureName justification="right" topmarginspacing="4">JOHN KNUBLEY</SignatureName><SignatureTitle justification="right"><Emphasis style="italic">Deputy Registrar General of Canada</Emphasis></SignatureTitle></SignatureBlock></Provision><Provision format-ref="centered" topmarginspacing="25"><Text>GOD SAVE THE QUEEN</Text></Provision></Order></Regulation>