<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/79-418</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1979</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>22</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2011</YYYY><MM>2</MM><DD>3</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS MARKETING ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Ontario Pork Producers’ Marketing Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Granting Authority to Regulate the Marketing of Hogs in Ontario</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1979-1476</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1979</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>17</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Agriculture, pursuant to section 2 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Agricultural Products Marketing Act</XRefExternal>, is pleased hereby to revoke the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Ontario Hog Producers’ Marketing Order</XRefExternal> made by Order in Council P.C. 1967-1033 of 25th May, 1967<FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-79-418_e_hq_10330">1</FootnoteRef>, and to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Order granting authority to regulate the marketing of hogs in Ontario</XRefExternal> in substitution thereof.</Text><Footnote id="fn_SOR-79-418_e_hq_10330" placement="page" status="official"><Label>1</Label><Text>SOR/67-267, <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal> Part II, Vol. 101, No. 11, June 14, 1967 and C.R.C., c. 214</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Ontario Pork Producers’ Marketing Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In this Order,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means <XRefExternal reference-type="act">The Farm Products Marketing Act</XRefExternal> of Ontario; (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Board</DefinedTermEn> means The Farm Products Marketing Board of Ontario, established pursuant to the Act; (<DefinedTermFr>Régie</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Commodity Board</DefinedTermEn> means The Ontario Pork Producers’ Marketing Board, established pursuant to the Act; (<DefinedTermFr>Office</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>hogs</DefinedTermEn> means hogs produced in Ontario; (<DefinedTermFr>porcs</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Plan</DefinedTermEn> means any plan for the marketing of hogs, established and amended from time to time pursuant to the Act, and any regulations made pursuant to the Act to give effect to the Plan. (<DefinedTermFr>plan</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interprovincial and Export Trade</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>The Commodity Board and the Board are each authorized to regulate the marketing of hogs in interprovincial and export trade and for such purposes may, with respect to persons and property situated in the Province of Ontario, exercise all or any powers like the powers exercisable by each of them in relation to the marketing of hogs locally in that Province under the Act and the Plan.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/86-240, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Levies or Charges</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>The Commodity Board may, in relation to the powers granted to it by section 3 with respect to the marketing of hogs in interprovincial and export trade,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>fix and impose by order and collect levies or charges from persons situated in the Province of Ontario who are engaged in the production or marketing of hogs and for that purpose classify those persons into groups and, by order, fix the levies or charges payable by the members of the different groups in different amounts; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>use the levies or charges collected pursuant to paragraph (a) for the purposes of the Commodity Board, including the creation of reserves, and the payment of expenses and losses resulting from the sale or disposal of hogs, and the equalization or adjustment among producers of hogs of moneys realized from the sale of hogs during such period or periods of time as the Commodity Board may determine.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/86-240, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section></Body></Regulation>