<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/93-195</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1993</YYYY><MM>4</MM><DD>14</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>13</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS MARKETING ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Quebec Maple Syrup Producers’ Levy (Interprovincial and Export Trade) Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Providing for the Fixing, Imposing and Collecting of Levies from Producers in the Province of Quebec who are Engaged in the Production or Marketing in Bulk of Maple Syrup in Interprovincial and Export Trade</LongTitle></Identification><Order><Provision language-align="yes" format-ref="indent-0-0" list-item="no"><Text>The Fédération des producteurs acéricoles du Québec, pursuant to sections 3 and 4 of the Quebec Maple Sap and Maple Syrup Order, made by <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Order in Council P.C. 1993-606 of March 30, 1993</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="footnote1_e">*</FootnoteRef>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Order providing for the fixing, imposing and collecting of levies from producers in the Province of Quebec who are engaged in the production or marketing in bulk of maple syrup in interprovincial and export trade</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>Longueuil, Quebec, April 14, 1993</Text><Footnote id="footnote1_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>SOR/93-154, 1993 <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal> Part II, p. 1602</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Quebec Maple Syrup Producers’ Levy (Interprovincial and Export Trade) Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In this Order,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>buyer</DefinedTermEn> means a person who buys or receives maple syrup in bulk from a producer; (<DefinedTermFr>acheteur</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Commodity Board</DefinedTermEn> means the Fédération des producteurs acéricoles du Québec; (<DefinedTermFr>Fédération</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>maple syrup</DefinedTermEn> means any maple syrup produced in the Province of Quebec and marketed in bulk; (<DefinedTermFr>sirop d’érable</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>producer</DefinedTermEn> means a person who owns, leases or otherwise operates a sugar bush in the Province of Quebec and who produces, directly or through or on behalf of another person, maple syrup to market in bulk in interprovincial or export trade. (<DefinedTermFr>producteur</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Levy</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>Every producer shall pay to the Commodity Board a levy of $0.12 per pound of maple syrup that is marketed in bulk in interprovincial and export trade.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/95-263, s. 1; SOR/2012-19, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Method of Payment</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>Subject to section 5, the producer shall remit to the Commodity Board at its headquarters in Longueuil, Quebec, before the 15th day of each month, the levy payable pursuant to section 3 in respect of the preceding month.</Text></Section><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>Where levies are not remitted by the producer, the buyer shall deduct, from the moneys payable to a producer for maple syrup, the levy payable by the producer to the Commodity Board pursuant to section 3, and shall remit the levy directly to the Commodity Board at its headquarters in Longueuil, Quebec, before the 15th day of each month, in accordance with sections 4 to 7 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Règlement sur le prélèvement des contributions des producteurs acéricoles</XRefExternal>, <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Gazette officielle du Québec</XRefExternal> Part 2, February 24, 1993, p. 1151.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>