<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en" in-force="yes"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2012-139</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2012</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>29</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2012</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>19</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">FISHERIES ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Wastewater Systems Effluent Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2012-942</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>2012</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>28</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Fisheries and Oceans, pursuant to subsection 36(5) and paragraphs 43(g.1)<FootnoteRef idref="fn_a">a</FootnoteRef>, (g.2)<FootnoteRef idref="fn_a">a</FootnoteRef> and (h) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Fisheries Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_b">b</FootnoteRef>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Wastewater Systems Effluent Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fn_a" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 1991, c. 1, s. 12(2)</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="fn_b" placement="page" status="official"><Label>b</Label><Text>R.S., c. F-14</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Definitions</MarginalNote><Label>1</Label><Text>The following definitions apply in these Regulations.</Text><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Fisheries Act</XRefExternal>. (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>acutely lethal</DefinedTermEn>, in relation to effluent, means that the effluent at 100% concentration kills, during a 96-hour period, more than 50% of the rainbow trout subjected to it. (<DefinedTermFr>létalité aiguë</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>aquatic species</DefinedTermEn> includes an aquatic species as defined in subsection 2(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Species at Risk Act</XRefExternal>. (<DefinedTermFr>espèce aquatique</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>authorization officer</DefinedTermEn>, in respect of a province set out in column 1 of Schedule 1 and for each type of owner set out in column 2 of a wastewater system located in the province, means the holder of the position set out in column 3. (<DefinedTermFr>agent d’autorisation</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>blackwater</DefinedTermEn> means used water from sanitary appliances that contains human fecal matter or human urine. (<DefinedTermFr>eaux-vannes</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>carbonaceous biochemical oxygen demanding matter</DefinedTermEn> or <DefinedTermEn>CBOD matter</DefinedTermEn> means carbonaceous matter that consumes, by biochemical oxidation, oxygen dissolved in water. (<DefinedTermFr>matières exerçant une demande biochimique en oxygène de la partie carbonée</DefinedTermFr> ou <DefinedTermFr>matière exerçant une DBOC</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>combined sewer</DefinedTermEn> means a sewer that is designed to collect surface runoff and stormwater in such a manner that it mixes with wastewater referred to in any of paragraphs (a) to (c) of the definition <DefinitionRef>wastewater</DefinitionRef> or any combination of wastewater referred to in those paragraphs. (<DefinedTermFr>égout unitaire</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>effluent</DefinedTermEn> means wastewater that is deposited from a wastewater system. (<DefinedTermFr>effluent</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>final discharge point</DefinedTermEn> means the point, other than an overflow point, of a wastewater system beyond which its owner or operator no longer exercises control over the quality of the wastewater before it is deposited as effluent in water or a place. (<DefinedTermFr>point de rejet final</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>greywater</DefinedTermEn> means used water, other than blackwater, from sanitary appliances or from other appliances in a kitchen or laundry. (<DefinedTermFr>eaux grises</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>hydraulic retention time</DefinedTermEn>, in relation to a wastewater system, means the average period during which wastewater is retained for treatment within the wastewater system. (<DefinedTermFr>temps de rétention hydraulique</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>influent</DefinedTermEn> means wastewater entering a wastewater system. (<DefinedTermFr>affluent</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>overflow point</DefinedTermEn> means a point of a wastewater system via which excess wastewater may be deposited in water or a place and beyond which its owner or operator no longer exercises control over the quality of wastewater before it is deposited as effluent. (<DefinedTermFr>point de débordement</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>point of entry</DefinedTermEn>, in relation to the final discharge point or an overflow point of a wastewater system, means</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the point where effluent is deposited in water frequented by fish via the final discharge point or the overflow point, as the case may be; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any point where the effluent enters that water from the place where it was deposited via the final discharge point or the overflow point, as the case may be. (<DefinedTermFr>point d’entrée</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>previous calendar year</DefinedTermEn>, in respect of a given period and a wastewater system, means the most recent calendar year during which effluent was deposited via the system’s final discharge point that ended before the given period. (<DefinedTermFr>année civile précédente</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>previous month</DefinedTermEn>, in respect of a given period and a wastewater system, means the most recent month during which effluent was deposited via the system’s final discharge point that ended before the given period. (<DefinedTermFr>mois précédent</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>previous quarter</DefinedTermEn>, in respect of a given period and a wastewater system, means the most recent quarter during which effluent was deposited via the system’s final discharge point that ended before the given period. (<DefinedTermFr>trimestre précédent</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Procedure for pH Stabilization EPS 1/RM/50</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="standard">Procedure for pH Stabilization During the Testing of Acute Lethality of Wastewater Effluent to Rainbow Trout</XRefExternal> (EPS 1/RM/50), March 2008, published by the Department of the Environment, as amended from time to time. (<DefinedTermFr>Procédure de stabilisation du pH SPE 1/RM/50</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>protected species</DefinedTermEn> means a wildlife species as defined in subsection 2(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Species at Risk Act</XRefExternal> that is</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a species at risk as defined in subsection 2(1) of that Act or is a species that is listed in Schedule 1 to that Act; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a species that is protected, or classified as an endangered species or a threatened species as defined in subsection 2(1) of that Act, under the laws of a province. (<DefinedTermFr>espèce protegée</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>quarter</DefinedTermEn>, in respect of a year, means any of the four periods of three months that begin on the first day of January, April, July and October. (<DefinedTermFr>trimestre</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Reference Method EPS 1/RM/13</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="standard">Biological Test Method: Reference Method for Determining Acute Lethality of Effluents to Rainbow Trout</XRefExternal> (EPS 1/RM/13 Second Edition), December 2000 with May 2007 amendments, published by the Department of the Environment, as amended from time to time. (<DefinedTermFr>Méthode de Référence SPE 1/RM/13</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>sanitary sewer</DefinedTermEn> means a sewer that is designed to collect wastewater referred to in any of paragraphs (a) to (c) of the definition <DefinitionRef>wastewater</DefinitionRef> or any combination of wastewater referred to in those paragraphs. (<DefinedTermFr>égout sanitaire</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>suspended solids</DefinedTermEn> means any solid matter contained in effluent that is retained on a filter of 2.0 micrometre (μm) or smaller pore size. (<DefinedTermFr>matières en suspension</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>total residual chlorine</DefinedTermEn> means the sum of free chlorine and combined chlorine, including inorganic chloramines. (<DefinedTermFr>chlore résiduel total</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>wastewater</DefinedTermEn> means</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>blackwater;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>greywater that is mixed with blackwater;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>used water — other than blackwater and greywater — from an industrial, commercial or institutional facility that is mixed with blackwater; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>surface runoff and stormwater that is mixed with blackwater. (<DefinedTermFr>eaux usées</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>wastewater system</DefinedTermEn> means any work or undertaking, at least part of which is located on land, that is used for the collection and deposit of wastewater, whether or not the wastewater is treated, and includes a site that contains a wastewater lagoon. (<DefinedTermFr>système d’assainissement</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Application</MarginalNote><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>These Regulations apply in respect of a wastewater system that, when it deposits effluent via its final discharge point, deposits a deleterious substance prescribed in section <XRefInternal>5</XRefInternal> in water or a place referred to in subsection 36(3) of the Act and that</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>is designed to collect an average daily volume of 100 m<Sup>3</Sup> or more of influent; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>during any calendar year, collects an average daily volume of 100 m<Sup>3</Sup> or more of influent.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Annual exceptions</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Despite paragraph (1)(a), these Regulations do not, for the subsequent calendar year, apply in respect of a wastewater system referred to in that paragraph that, during a calendar year, collected an average daily volume of less than 100 m<Sup>3</Sup> of influent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Non‑applica­tion — areas</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>These Regulations do not apply in respect of a wastewater system located</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in the Northwest Territories;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in Nunavut; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>north of the 54th parallel in Quebec or Newfoundland and Labrador.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Non‑applica­tion — industrial, commercial or institutional influent</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>These Regulations do not apply in respect of a wastewater system that is located on the site of an industrial, commercial or institutional facility if the wastewater system is designed to collect influent whose volume consists of less than 50% blackwater and greywater combined.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Non‑applica­tion — pulp and paper mills</MarginalNote><Label>(5)</Label><Text>These Regulations do not apply in respect of a mill as defined in section 2 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Pulp and Paper Effluent Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Types of wastewater systems</MarginalNote><Label>3</Label><Text>For the purpose of these Regulations, there are two types of wastewater systems, as follows:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>an intermittent wastewater system, namely, one with a hydraulic retention time of at least 90 days that deposits effluent via its final discharge point during at most four periods per calendar year, each of which is separated from every other period by at least seven clear days during which no deposit occurs; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a continuous wastewater system, namely, any wastewater system other than an intermittent wastewater system.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Consolidated wastewater systems</MarginalNote><Label>4</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>If an owner of at least 10 wastewater systems — none of which treats its wastewater in a manner that would permit the deposit of effluent via its final discharge point that meets the condition set out in paragraph <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(1)(a) or (b) (referred to in these Regulations as an “original wastewater system”) — plans to consolidate those original wastewater systems into one or more wastewater systems (referred to in these Regulations as a “planned consolidated wastewater system”), the original wastewater systems that constitute each of those planned consolidated wastewater systems are, on the receipt by an authorization officer of a consolidation plan referred to in subsection (3), deemed to be a single wastewater system (referred to in these Regulations as a “fictional consolidated wastewater system”).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Final discharge point</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The final discharge point for each fictional consolidated wastewater system is deemed to be the final discharge point of the original wastewater system — among all of the original wastewater systems that constitute that fictional consolidated wastewater system — that is allocated the greatest number of points under the table to Schedule 2.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Consolidation plan</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The consolidation plan must contain the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a description of the modifications to be made to each of the original wastewater systems so that the effluent deposited via the final discharge point for the planned consolidated wastewater system is not acutely lethal and meets the conditions for authorization set out in paragraphs <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(1)(a) and (b), along with a schedule for implementation of the plan;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a statement identifying the final discharge point of each of the original wastewater systems that are, under the plan, to be eliminated, including the information referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(1)(e) for each of those final discharge points; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the information referred to in paragraphs <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(1)(f) and (g) in respect of the final discharge point and the overflow points for the planned consolidated wastewater system.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 1</Label><TitleText>Authorization to Deposit</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Effluent Containing Deleterious Substances</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Prescribed deleterious substances</MarginalNote><Label>5</Label><Text>For the purpose of the definition <DefinitionRef>deleterious substance</DefinitionRef> in subsection 34(1) of the Act, the following substances or classes of substances are prescribed as deleterious substances:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>carbonaceous biochemical oxygen demanding matter;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>suspended solids;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>total residual chlorine; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>un-ionized ammonia.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Authorization to deposit</MarginalNote><Label>6</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>For the purpose of paragraph 36(4)(b) of the Act, the owner or operator of a wastewater system may — during a given calendar year, quarter or month, determined in accordance with subsection (2) — deposit or permit the deposit of effluent that contains any of the deleterious substances prescribed in section <XRefInternal>5</XRefInternal> via the system’s final discharge point in any water or place referred to in subsection 36(3) of the Act if the effluent is not acutely lethal as determined in accordance with section <XRefInternal>15</XRefInternal> and if — during the previous calendar year, previous quarter or previous month, determined in accordance with subsection (2) — the effluent met the following conditions:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the average carbonaceous biochemical oxygen demand due to the quantity of CBOD matter in the effluent did not exceed 25 mg/L;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the average concentration of suspended solids in the effluent did not exceed 25 mg/L;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the average concentration of total residual chlorine in the effluent did not exceed 0.02 mg/L, if chlorine, or one of its compounds, was used in the treatment of wastewater; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the maximum concentration of un-ionized ammonia in the effluent was less than 1.25 mg/L, expressed as nitrogen (N), at 15°C ± 1°C.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Averaging period</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The averages referred to in paragraphs (1)(a) to (c) and the maximum referred to in paragraph (1)(d) must be determined on the following basis:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>each calendar year, if the average daily volume of effluent deposited via the final discharge point during the previous calendar year was</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>less than or equal to 17 500 m<Sup>3</Sup>, for an intermittent wastewater system, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>less than or equal to 2 500 m<Sup>3</Sup>, for a continuous wastewater system with a hydraulic retention time of five or more days;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>each quarter, if the average daily volume of effluent deposited via the final discharge point during the previous calendar year was</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>greater than 2 500 m<Sup>3</Sup> and less than or equal to 17 500 m<Sup>3</Sup>, for a continuous wastewater system with a hydraulic retention time of five or more days, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>less than or equal to 17 500 m<Sup>3</Sup>, for any other continuous wastewater system; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>each month, if the average daily volume of effluent deposited via the final discharge point during the previous calendar year was greater than 17 500 m<Sup>3</Sup>.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Determination of averages and maximum</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The averages referred to in paragraphs (1)(a) and (b) and the maximum referred to in paragraph (1)(d) must be determined</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for an intermittent wastewater system, based on samples of effluent referred to in subsections <XRefInternal>10</XRefInternal>(1) and, if applicable, <XRefInternal>10</XRefInternal>(5), in accordance with subsection <XRefInternal>10</XRefInternal>(4); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for a continuous wastewater system, based on samples of effluent referred to in, as the case may be subsection <XRefInternal>10</XRefInternal>(2) or (3) and, if applicable, subsection <XRefInternal>10</XRefInternal>(5), in accordance with subsection <XRefInternal>10</XRefInternal>(4).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Determinations for additional samples</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>A determination made under subsection <XRefInternal>10</XRefInternal>(4) or (5), as the case may be, for any sample beyond the number of samples required under subsection <XRefInternal>10</XRefInternal>(1), (2) or (3) must, if that determination were made by an accredited laboratory referred to in section <XRefInternal>16</XRefInternal>, be included when determining an average or the maximum under subsection (3).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Determination of SS average during July, August, September or October</MarginalNote><Label>(5)</Label><Text>For an intermittent wastewater system or a continuous wastewater system with a hydraulic retention time of five or more days, the determination of the average referred to in paragraph (1)(b) is not to take into account the result of any determination of the concentration of suspended solids in a sample of effluent referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>10</XRefInternal>(4)(b) that was taken during the month of July, August, September or October, if that result is greater than 25 mg/L.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>When SS average is deemed to be 0 mg/L</MarginalNote><Label>(6)</Label><Text>If subsection (5) applies to every sample referred to in paragraph (3)(a) that is used to determine the average referred to in paragraph (1)(b), that average is deemed to be 0 mg/L.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Conditions</MarginalNote><Label>(7)</Label><Text>The authorization granted to an owner or operator under subsection (1) is conditional on the owner or operator</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>determining the average daily volume of effluent deposited annually via the final discharge point in accordance with section <XRefInternal>7</XRefInternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for an intermittent wastewater system, either installing, maintaining and calibrating the monitoring equipment referred to in subparagraph <XRefInternal>7</XRefInternal>(2)(a)(i) in accordance with section <XRefInternal>9</XRefInternal> or establishing a method of estimation referred to in subparagraph <XRefInternal>7</XRefInternal>(2)(a)(ii) in accordance with subsection <XRefInternal>7</XRefInternal>(4) and maintaining it;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>for a continuous wastewater system, installing, maintaining and calibrating the monitoring equipment referred to in subparagraph <XRefInternal>7</XRefInternal>(2)(b)(i) or (ii), as the case may be, in accordance with section <XRefInternal>9</XRefInternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>monitoring effluent in accordance with sections <XRefInternal>10</XRefInternal> and <XRefInternal>11</XRefInternal> and sending a monitoring report in accordance with section <XRefInternal>19</XRefInternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>keeping the record required under section <XRefInternal>17</XRefInternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>sending an identification report in accordance with section <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>sending the overflow report, if applicable, required under section <XRefInternal>20</XRefInternal> in accordance with subsections <XRefInternal>19</XRefInternal>(4) and (5).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Volume of Effluent</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Average daily volume deposited annually</MarginalNote><Label>7</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a wastewater system must, for each calendar year, calculate the average daily volume of effluent deposited via the system’s final discharge point by</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>determining, in accordance with subsection (2), for each day during that calendar year when effluent was deposited, the volume of effluent deposited via the final discharge point, expressed in m<Sup>3</Sup>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>calculating the sum of the daily volumes of effluent referred to in paragraph (a); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>dividing that sum by the number of days in that calendar year.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Daily volumes</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The volume of effluent during each day referred to in paragraph (1)(a) must be determined</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for an intermittent wastewater system,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>by using monitoring equipment referred to in section <XRefInternal>9</XRefInternal> that provides</Text><Clause><Label>(A)</Label><Text>a continuous measure of the volume of influent, or effluent deposited via the final discharge point, during that day, or</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(B)</Label><Text>a measure of the rate of flow of the influent or that effluent upon which that daily volume may be estimated, or</Text></Clause></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>by using a method of estimation in accordance with subsection (4);</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for a continuous wastewater system, by using monitoring equipment referred to in section <XRefInternal>9</XRefInternal> that provides</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>a continuous measure of the volume of influent, or effluent deposited via the final discharge point, during that day, if the average daily volume of effluent deposited via the final discharge point during the previous calendar year was more than 2 500 m<Sup>3</Sup>, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>a continuous measure of that volume or a measure of the rate of flow of that influent or effluent upon which that daily volume of effluent may be estimated, in any other case.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Estimate of daily volume based on measured rate of flow</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The estimation of the volume of effluent deposited during a day referred to in paragraph (1)(a) based on a measured rate of flow, referred to in clause (2)(a)(i)(B) or subparagraph (2)(b)(ii), is to be done as follows:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>measure the rate of flow of influent, or effluent deposited via the final discharge point, in any chosen unit of volume for any chosen unit of time; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>calculate that volume based on that rate of flow for the duration of the deposits of effluent made on that day and, if applicable, convert it to m<Sup>3</Sup>.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Method of estimation — intermittent wastewater systems</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of an intermittent wastewater system who has established a method of estimation of the volume of effluent must ensure that it is based on generally accepted engineering practices and use it to estimate the daily volume of effluent deposited via the final discharge point with a margin of error of ±15%.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Default measurement</MarginalNote><Label>8</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>If the average daily volume of effluent deposited via the final discharge point of a wastewater system for a previous calendar year cannot be determined under paragraph <XRefInternal>7</XRefInternal>(2)(a) or (b), as the case may be, that average daily volume must be determined on the basis of the system’s average design rate of flow of influent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>One-time use of default measurement</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>If subsection (1) has been applied in respect of a wastewater system for a calendar year, it is not to be applied in respect of the wastewater system for any subsequent calendar year.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Monitoring</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Monitoring Equipment</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Requirements</MarginalNote><Label>9</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a continuous wastewater system must — by January 1, 2013 — have installed monitoring equipment that provides</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a continuous measure of the volume of influent or effluent, if, during the previous calendar year, the average daily volume of effluent deposited via the system’s final discharge point determined in accordance with section <XRefInternal>7</XRefInternal> or <XRefInternal>8</XRefInternal>, as the case may be, was more than 2 500 m<Sup>3</Sup>; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>either a continuous measure of the volume of the influent or effluent or a measure of the rate of flow of the influent or effluent, if, during the previous calendar year, the average daily volume of effluent deposited via the system’s final discharge point determined in accordance with section <XRefInternal>7</XRefInternal> or <XRefInternal>8</XRefInternal>, as the case may be, was 2 500 m<Sup>3</Sup> or less.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Maintenance and calibration</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a wastewater system who has installed monitoring equipment must maintain and calibrate that equipment so that it may be used to determine the volume of effluent deposited via the final discharge point in accordance with, as the case may be, subparagraph <XRefInternal>7</XRefInternal>(2)(a)(i) or paragraph <XRefInternal>7</XRefInternal>(2)(b).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Frequency of calibration</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The owner or operator must calibrate the monitoring equipment at least once in every calendar year and at least five months after a previous calibration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Accuracy</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The monitoring equipment must determine the volume or rate of flow with a margin of error of ±15%.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Composition of the Effluent</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Taking of samples — intermittent wastewater system</MarginalNote><Label>10</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of an intermittent wastewater system must, during each period referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>3</XRefInternal>(a), take at the system’s final discharge point a grab or composite sample of effluent at the following minimum frequency:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>if the period is more than 30 days, every two weeks but at least seven days after any other sample; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in any other case, once.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Taking of samples — continuous wastewater system</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a continuous wastewater system that — during the previous calendar year in respect of the calendar year, quarter or month in question — deposited via the system’s final discharge point an average daily volume of effluent set out in column 1 of the table to this subsection must, for that calendar year, quarter or month, take at the final discharge point a sample of effluent of the type set out in column 2 at the minimum frequency set out in column 3.</Text><TableGroup pointsize="8" topmarginspacing="10"><Caption position="over">TABLE</Caption><table frame="topbot"><tgroup cols="4"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="8.86*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="25.58*" /><colspec colname="3" colwidth="20.92*" /><colspec colname="4" colwidth="23.09*" /><thead><row rowsep="0" topdouble="yes"><entry colname="1" morerows="1" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Item</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 1</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 2</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 3</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Average Daily Volume Deposited Annually (m<Sup>3</Sup>)</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Type of Sample to be Taken</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="left" valign="bottom">Minimum Sampling Frequency</entry></row></thead><tbody><row height="10pt"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">1</entry><entry rowheader="yes" colsep="0" rowsep="0">≤ 2 500</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Grab or composite</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Monthly but at least 10 days after any other sample</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2</entry><entry rowheader="yes" colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">&gt; 2 500 and ≤ 17 500</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Composite</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Every two weeks but at least seven days after any other sample</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">3</entry><entry rowheader="yes" colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">&gt; 17 500 and ≤ 50 000</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Composite</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Weekly but at least five days after any other sample</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">4</entry><entry rowheader="yes" colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">&gt; 50 000</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Composite</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Three days per week but at least one day after any other sample</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Sampling and frequency for certain continuous systems</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Despite subsection (2), the owner or operator of a continuous wastewater system with a hydraulic retention time of five or more days must</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>take a grab or composite sample; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>reduce the minimum sampling frequency to quarterly, but at least 60 days after any other sample was taken, if the system deposited via its final discharge point an average daily volume of less than or equal to 2500 m<Sup>3</Sup> of effluent during the previous calendar year referred to in subsection (2).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Determination of certain deleterious substances</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The owner or operator must, for each sample taken under subsection (1), (2) or (3), determine, or cause the determination of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the carbonaceous biochemical oxygen demand due to the quantity of CBOD matter in the effluent, in accordance with section <XRefInternal>12</XRefInternal>; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the concentration of suspended solids in the effluent, in accordance with section <XRefInternal>13</XRefInternal>.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Before July 1, 2014 — additional determination</MarginalNote><Label>(5)</Label><Text>Until July 1, 2014, the owner or operator must, for each sample taken under subsection (1), (2) or (3), determine, or cause the determination of, the concentration of un-ionized ammonia in the effluent, in accordance with the formula and a test method referred to in section <XRefInternal>14</XRefInternal>.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Acute Lethality Testing</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Taking samples</MarginalNote><Label>11</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a wastewater system that — during the previous calendar year in respect of the calendar year, quarter or month in question — deposited via the system’s final discharge point an average daily volume of effluent set out in column 1 of the table to this subsection must, for that calendar year, quarter or month, take at the final discharge point a grab sample of effluent at the minimum frequency set out in column 2.</Text><TableGroup pointsize="8" topmarginspacing="10"><Caption position="over">TABLE</Caption><table frame="topbot"><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="6.45*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="24.13*" /><colspec colname="4" colwidth="26.48*" /><thead><row rowsep="0" topdouble="yes"><entry colname="1" morerows="1" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Item</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" valign="top">Column 1</entry><entry colsep="0" valign="top">Column 2</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Average Daily Volume Deposited Annually (m<Sup>3</Sup>)</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Minimum Sampling Frequency</entry></row></thead><tbody><row height="10pt"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">1</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">&gt; 2 500 and ≤ 50 000</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Quarterly but at least 60 days after any other sample</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">&gt; 50 000</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Monthly but at least 21 days after any other sample</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Acute lethality</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The owner or operator must, for each sample taken under subsection (1), determine, or cause the determination of, whether or not it is acutely lethal in accordance with section <XRefInternal>15</XRefInternal>.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Additional test</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>If a sample is determined to be acutely lethal in accordance with section <XRefInternal>15</XRefInternal>, the owner or operator must take a grab sample twice a month, but at least seven days after any previous sample, and determine, or cause the determination of, whether or not it is acutely lethal in accordance with section <XRefInternal>15</XRefInternal>.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Consecutive samples — not acutely lethal</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>If three consecutive samples are, under subsection (3), determined not to be acutely lethal, subsections (1) and (2) apply to subsequent samples.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Subsequent samples</MarginalNote><Label>(5)</Label><Text>For greater certainty, subsection (3) applies to any subsequent sample referred to in subsection (4) that is determined to be acutely lethal when tested under subsection (2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Change in sampling frequency</MarginalNote><Label>(6)</Label><Text>The minimum sampling frequency set out in column 2 of the table to subsection (1) is reduced</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for item 1, to yearly, but at least six months after any other sample, if samples were taken under subsection (1) for each of four consecutive quarters and those samples were tested under subsection (2) and determined not to be acutely lethal; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for item 2, to quarterly, but at least 60 days after any other sample, if samples were taken under subsection (1) for each of 12 consecutive months and those samples were tested under subsection (2) and determined not to be acutely lethal.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Test Methods</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>CBOD matter</MarginalNote><Label>12</Label><Text>The demand due to the quantity of carbonaceous biochemical oxygen demanding matter in the effluent must be determined in accordance with a five-day biochemical oxygen demand test with nitrification inhibition.</Text></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Suspended solids</MarginalNote><Label>13</Label><Text>The concentration of suspended solids in the effluent must be determined in accordance with a total suspended solids test.</Text></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Un-ionized ammonia</MarginalNote><Label>14</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The concentration of un-ionized ammonia in the effluent must be determined in accordance with the following formula:</Text><FormulaGroup><Formula><FormulaText>total ammonia × <Fraction><Numerator>1</Numerator><Denominator>1 +<MSup><Base>10</Base><Superscript>9.56 – pH</Superscript></MSup></Denominator></Fraction></FormulaText></Formula><FormulaConnector>where</FormulaConnector><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>total ammonia</FormulaTerm><Text>is the concentration of total ammonia — namely, un-ionized ammonia (NH<Sub>3</Sub>) plus ionized ammonia (NH<Sub>4</Sub><Sup>+</Sup>) — determined in accordance with subsection (2), expressed in mg/L as nitrogen (N); and</Text></FormulaDefinition><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>pH</FormulaTerm><Text>is the pH of the effluent adjusted to 15°C ± 1°C and determined in accordance with subsection (3).</Text></FormulaDefinition></FormulaGroup></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Concentration of total ammonia</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The concentration of total ammonia in the effluent must be determined by using an aliquot of the same sample of effluent from which the pH of the effluent was determined and testing it in accordance with a total ammonia test.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>pH</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The pH of the effluent must be determined by using an aliquot of the same sample of effluent from which the concentration of total ammonia of the effluent was determined and testing it in accordance with a pH test.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Acute lethality</MarginalNote><Label>15</Label><Text>The acute lethality of the effluent must be determined in accordance with</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>Reference Method EPS 1/RM/13 using the procedure set out in section 5 or 6 of that Method; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>paragraph (a) using the Procedure for pH Stabilization EPS 1/RM/50.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Accredited Laboratory</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Accredited laboratory</MarginalNote><Label>16</Label><Text>A determination referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>10</XRefInternal>(4) or (5) or <XRefInternal>11</XRefInternal>(2) or (3), paragraph <XRefInternal>34</XRefInternal>(1)(a) or (b) or (4)(a) and any determination necessary to make that determination — other than the determination of pH of water necessary to make the determination referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>34</XRefInternal>(3) — must be made</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>by a laboratory</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>that is accredited under the International Organization for Standardization standard ISO/IEC 17025:2005 entitled <XRefExternal reference-type="standard">General requirements for the competence of testing and calibration laboratories</XRefExternal>, as amended from time to time, by an accrediting body that is a signatory to the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">International Laboratory Accreditation Cooperation (ILAC) Mutual Recognition Arrangement</XRefExternal>, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>whose accreditation includes the analytical method used to make the determination; or</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>by a laboratory</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>that is accredited under the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Environment Quality Act</XRefExternal>, R.S.Q., c. Q-2, as amended from time to time, by an accreditation body that is recognized in accordance with that Act, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>whose accreditation includes the analytical method used to make the determination.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Record Keeping</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Information to be recorded</MarginalNote><Label>17</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a wastewater system must keep the report on each determination made by an accredited laboratory referred to in section <XRefInternal>16</XRefInternal> and a record that contains the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for the final discharge point,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the date of each day on which effluent was not deposited via the final discharge point,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the date of each day on which effluent was deposited via the final discharge point, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>for each of the days referred to in subparagraph (ii)</Text><Clause><Label>(A)</Label><Text>for a wastewater system whose daily volume of effluent referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>7</XRefInternal>(1)(a) was determined using monitoring equipment referred to in section <XRefInternal>9</XRefInternal></Text><Subclause><Label>(I)</Label><Text>the daily volume of the effluent, expressed in m<Sup>3</Sup>, if that volume is yielded by a continuous measure, and</Text></Subclause><Subclause><Label>(II)</Label><Text>the estimated daily volume, expressed in m<Sup>3</Sup>, as determined in accordance with subsection <XRefInternal>7</XRefInternal>(3) and the results of the measurement and the calculation referred to in paragraphs <XRefInternal>7</XRefInternal>(3)(a) and (b), in any other case, and</Text></Subclause></Clause><Clause><Label>(B)</Label><Text>for an intermittent wastewater system whose daily volume of effluent referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>7</XRefInternal>(1)(a) was determined using a method of estimation in accordance with subsection <XRefInternal>7</XRefInternal>(4), the estimated daily volume, expressed in m<Sup>3</Sup>, and</Text></Clause></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>the average daily volume of effluent deposited annually, expressed in m<Sup>3</Sup>, determined in accordance with subsection <XRefInternal>8</XRefInternal>(1), if applicable;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each combined sewer overflow point via which effluent is deposited because of precipitation, including the melting of snow or ice, that resulted in excess wastewater in the wastewater system,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the date of each day on which effluent was deposited via the overflow point,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>for each of those days, the duration or estimated duration, expressed in hours, of the deposit, along with an indication of whether it is the duration or an estimated duration and</Text><Clause><Label>(A)</Label><Text>the daily volume of the effluent deposited, expressed in m<Sup>3</Sup>, if that volume is yielded by a continuous measure, and</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(B)</Label><Text>the estimated daily volume of the effluent deposited, expressed in m<Sup>3</Sup>, in any other case,</Text></Clause></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>the volume or estimated volume, expressed in m<Sup>3</Sup>, of effluent for each month during which effluent was deposited via the overflow point, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>the number of days in each of those months during which effluent was deposited via the overflow point;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>for any monitoring equipment referred to in section <XRefInternal>9</XRefInternal>,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>a description, including its type,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>if applicable, the manufacturer’s specifications, the year of manufacture and the model number,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>each date on which the equipment was calibrated and its degree of accuracy after each calibration, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>the date on which the equipment was installed and, if applicable, the date on which it ceased to be used for monitoring and on which it was replaced;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>for each sample referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>10</XRefInternal>(1), (2) or (3), as the case may be, and, if applicable, subsection <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(4),</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the results of the determinations referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>10</XRefInternal>(4), and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>a statement as to whether the sample is a grab sample or a composite sample and the date on which the sample was taken;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>for each sample referred to in subsections <XRefInternal>10</XRefInternal>(5) and, if applicable <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(4),</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the results of the determination referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>10</XRefInternal>(5),</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the results of the determination of the concentration of total ammonia in the effluent and of the pH of the effluent referred to in subsections <XRefInternal>14</XRefInternal>(2) and (3), respectively, that were used to make the determination referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>10</XRefInternal>(5), and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>a statement as to whether the sample is a grab sample or a composite sample and the date on which the sample was taken;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>for each sample referred to in section <XRefInternal>11</XRefInternal> whose acute lethality was determined in accordance with section <XRefInternal>15</XRefInternal>, the information referred to in section 8 of Reference Method EPS 1/RM/13 and, if the acute lethality of the effluent was determined in accordance with that method used with the Procedure for pH Stabilization EPS 1/RM/50, section 3 of that procedure;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>if the owner or operator holds of a temporary authorization issued under subsection <XRefInternal>36</XRefInternal>(1),</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>for each sample referred to in paragraph (d),</Text><Clause><Label>(A)</Label><Text>the result of the determination referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>38</XRefInternal>(b),</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(B)</Label><Text>the results of the determination of the concentration of total ammonia in the effluent and of the pH of the effluent referred to in subsections <XRefInternal>14</XRefInternal>(2) and (3), respectively, that were used to make the determination referred to in clause (A),</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(C)</Label><Text>a statement as to whether the sample is a grab sample or a composite sample and the date on which the sample was taken, and</Text></Clause></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the result of the determination referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>38</XRefInternal>(c) for each August and a description of how that determination was made.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Reporting</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Identification Report</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Required information</MarginalNote><Label>18</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a wastewater system must send to the authorization officer an identification report that contains the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the owner’s and the operator’s name, civic and postal addresses, telephone number and, if any, email address and fax number;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the name, title, civic and postal addresses, telephone number and, if any, email address and fax number, of a contact person;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>if any, the wastewater system’s name and civic address;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>with respect to the wastewater system:</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>a statement indicating whether it is an intermittent or continuous wastewater system,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>for a continuous wastewater system, a statement indicating whether its hydraulic retention time is five days or more,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>a statement indicating whether the system is owned or operated, or both, by one or several of the following:</Text><Clause><Label>(A)</Label><Text>Her Majesty in right of Canada or another federal body,</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(B)</Label><Text>Her Majesty in right of a province or another provincial body,</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(C)</Label><Text>a municipality or another local authority,</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(D)</Label><Text>an Aboriginal organization, including an Indian, an Inuit or a Métis government or the <DefinitionRef>council of the band</DefinitionRef>, as defined in subsection 2(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Indian Act</XRefExternal>, or</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(E)</Label><Text>an entity other than one referred to in clauses (A) to (D), and</Text></Clause></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>the type of wastewater treatment, if any, including whether chlorine, or one of its compounds, is used, and a description of the type;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the latitude and longitude of the final discharge point;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>for a point of entry in relation to the final discharge point,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>its latitude and longitude,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>a description of the water frequented by fish into which effluent is deposited, including</Text><Clause><Label>(A)</Label><Text>a description of its use, if any, and</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(B)</Label><Text>its name, if any, and the name, if any, of the body of water that includes that water, and</Text></Clause></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>a statement as to whether the effluent is deposited in water frequented by fish via the final discharge point or from a place where it was deposited via the final discharge point;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>the number of overflow points for each of the combined sewers and sanitary sewers of the wastewater system and the latitude and longitude of each of those overflow points;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>for a point of entry in relation to each overflow point, a description of the water frequented by fish into which effluent is deposited, including</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>a description of its use, if any, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>its name, if any, and the name, if any, of the body of water that includes that water; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>for the calendar year before the calendar year in which the identification report is sent, the average daily volume, expressed in m<Sup>3</Sup>, of effluent deposited via the wastewater system’s final discharge point — calculated in accordance with subsection <XRefInternal>7</XRefInternal>(1) or by using another method based on measurements or, if not so calculated, determined on the basis of the system’s average design rate of flow of influent — and a statement of the method of calculation or determination used and, if the method was another method of calculation based on measurements, a brief description of that method.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Required information — fictional consolidated wastewater system</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Despite subsection (1), an owner or operator of a fictional consolidated wastewater system must send an identification report that contains</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for each of the original wastewater systems that constitute the fictional consolidated wastewater system, the information referred to in paragraphs (1)(a) to (c), (e), (g) and (h); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for the fictional consolidated wastewater system, the information referred to in paragraphs (1)(a) to (g) and (i).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Latitude and longitude</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The latitude and longitude of a point referred to in paragraph (1)(e), subparagraph (1)(f)(i) and paragraph (1)(g) are to be expressed in decimal degrees to four decimal places rounded to the nearest ten-thousandth of a degree and, if the latitude or longitude is equidistant between two ten-thousandths of a degree, to the higher of them.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Electronic report</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The identification report must be sent electronically in the form and format specified by the Minister of the Environment and must bear the electronic signature of the owner or operator, or their duly authorized representative. The identification report must be sent</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>by May 15, 2013, if the wastewater system is in operation on January 1, 2013; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>within 45 days after the wastewater system comes into operation, in any other case.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Paper report</MarginalNote><Label>(5)</Label><Text>If the Minister of the Environment has not specified an electronic form and format or if it is not feasible to send the report electronically in accordance with subsection (4) because of circumstances beyond the owner’s or operator’s control, the report must be sent on paper, signed by the owner or operator, or their duly authorized representative, and in the form and format specified by the Minister of the Environment. However, if no form and format have been specified, it may be in any form and format.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Change of information</MarginalNote><Label>(6)</Label><Text>If the information provided in the identification report changes, the owner or operator must send a notice that provides the updated information to the authorization officer no later than 45 days after the change.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Decommissioning</MarginalNote><Label>(7)</Label><Text>An owner or operator of a wastewater system must, at least 45 days before the planned decommissioning of the wastewater system, send a notice to the authorization officer setting out the planned date of the decommissioning and information specifying the place, including the civic address, if any, of that place, where the identification report is to be kept.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Monitoring Report</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Information</MarginalNote><Label>19</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a wastewater system must send, within 45 days after the end of the period referred to in subsection (2), to the authorization officer a monitoring report that contains the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>if applicable, a statement that indicates that effluent was not deposited during that period; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in any other case,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>if applicable, a statement that indicates any month in that period during which effluent was not deposited,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the number of days during which effluent was deposited,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>the volume of effluent that was deposited, expressed in m<Sup>3</Sup>,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>the average carbonaceous biochemical oxygen demand due to the quantity of CBOD matter in the effluent,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(v)</Label><Text>the average concentration of suspended solids in the effluent;</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(vi)</Label><Text>the maximum concentration of un-ionized ammonia in the effluent, if the period ends on or before June 30, 2014,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(vii)</Label><Text>if the owner or operator holds a temporary authorization issued under subsection <XRefInternal>36</XRefInternal>(1),</Text><Clause><Label>(A)</Label><Text>the result of each determination referred to in clause <XRefInternal>17</XRefInternal>(g)(i)(A) and the date on which the sample used to make that determination was taken, and</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(B)</Label><Text>if the period includes an August, the result of the determination referred to in subparagraph <XRefInternal>17</XRefInternal>(g)(ii) for that August, and</Text></Clause></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(viii)</Label><Text>for each sample for which a determination of acute lethality was made in accordance with section <XRefInternal>15</XRefInternal>, a statement that indicates</Text><Clause><Label>(A)</Label><Text>the date on which the sample was taken,</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(B)</Label><Text>each procedure referred to in section <XRefInternal>15</XRefInternal> that was used to determine the sample’s acute lethality, and</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(C)</Label><Text>whether the sample was acutely lethal or not.</Text></Clause></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Period</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>For the purpose of subsection (1), the period is</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a calendar year, if the wastewater system deposited an average daily volume of effluent via the final discharge point during the previous calendar year in respect of that calendar year of</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>less than or equal to 17 500 m<Sup>3</Sup>, for an intermittent wastewater system, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>less than or equal to 2 500 m<Sup>3</Sup>, for a continuous wastewater system with a hydraulic retention time of five or more days; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a quarter, in any other case.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Period for which information reported</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The information referred to in subsection (1) is to be reported</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for the period referred to in subsection (2), if that period is a calendar year or a quarter; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each month during that period, if that period is a quarter and the average daily volume of effluent deposited via the final discharge point during the previous calendar year in respect of that quarter was greater than 17 500 m<Sup>3</Sup>.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Electronic report</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The report must be sent electronically in the form and format specified by the Minister of the Environment and must bear the electronic signature of the owner or operator, or their duly authorized representative.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Paper report</MarginalNote><Label>(5)</Label><Text>If the Minister of the Environment has not specified an electronic form and format or if it is not feasible to send the report electronically in accordance with subsection (4) because of circumstances beyond the owner’s or operator’s control, the report must be sent on paper, signed by the owner or operator, or their duly authorized representative, and in the form and format specified by the Minister of the Environment. However, if no form and format have been specified, it may be in any form and format.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Combined Sewer Overflow Report</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Information</MarginalNote><Label>20</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a wastewater system that includes at least one combined sewer overflow point must, in accordance with subsections <XRefInternal>19</XRefInternal>(4) and (5), send to the authorization officer a combined sewer overflow report in respect of each calendar year by February 15 of the following calendar year and the report must contain the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for each month of the calendar year during which effluent was deposited via a combined sewer overflow point, the information referred to in subparagraphs <XRefInternal>17</XRefInternal>(b)(iii) and (iv); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each month of the calendar year during which effluent was not deposited via a combined sewer overflow point, a statement indicating that no effluent was deposited via an overflow point during the month.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Record Making and Retention of Documents</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>When records made</MarginalNote><Label>21</Label><Text>Records must be made without delay after the information to be recorded becomes available.</Text></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Retention of records</MarginalNote><Label>22</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>An owner or operator of a wastewater system must keep a report referred to in section <XRefInternal>17</XRefInternal>, as well as a record and a copy of a report required to be sent under these Regulations — along with any supporting documents — for at least five years after the day on which the record or report, as the case may be, was made.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Place of retention</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The report referred to in section <XRefInternal>17</XRefInternal>, the record and the copy must be kept at the wastewater system or at any other place in Canada where it can be inspected. If that report, record or copy is kept at one of those other places, the owner or operator must provide the authorization officer with information specifying that other place, including its civic address, if any.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Information on monitoring equipment and identification report</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Despite subsection (1), the information referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>17</XRefInternal>(c) must be kept for at least five years after the day on which the monitoring equipment ceased to be used, and the identification report, as it may be updated from time to time, referred to in section <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal> must be kept for at least five years after the wastewater system is decommissioned.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 2</Label><TitleText>Transitional and Temporary Authorizations to Deposit</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Purpose</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Paragraph 36(4)(b) of the Act</MarginalNote><Label>23</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>For the purpose of paragraph 36(4)(b) of the Act, an owner or operator of a wastewater system may deposit or permit the deposit of effluent that contains any of the deleterious substances prescribed in section <XRefInternal>5</XRefInternal> via the final discharge point in any water or place referred to in subsection 36(3) of the Act, if the deposit is made in accordance with an authorization issued under this Part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Definition of <DefinedTermEn>deposit</DefinedTermEn></MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>For the purposes of sections <XRefInternal>24</XRefInternal> to <XRefInternal>49</XRefInternal>, <DefinedTermEn>deposit</DefinedTermEn>, in relation to effluent, includes to permit the deposit of the effluent.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Transitional Authorization</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Requirements and Duration</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Transitional authorization</MarginalNote><Label>24</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a wastewater system may, on or before June 30, 2014, apply to an authorization officer for a transitional authorization to deposit via the final discharge point effluent that contains a deleterious substance prescribed in section <XRefInternal>5</XRefInternal>, or any combination of those substances, if the average referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(1)(a) or (b), as determined in accordance with subsection <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(3), exceeded 25 mg/L during the following periods:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any period of 12 consecutive months during the 15 months immediately before the day on which the application is made, if the wastewater system deposited, during the previous calendar year in respect of that period of 12 consecutive months, an average daily volume of effluent via its final discharge point of</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>less than or equal to 17 500 m<Sup>3</Sup>, for an intermittent wastewater system, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>less than or equal to 2 500 m<Sup>3</Sup>, for a continuous wastewater system with a hydraulic retention time of five or more days;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any three consecutive months in any of those periods of 12 consecutive months, if the wastewater system deposited, during the previous calendar year in respect of that period of 12 consecutive months, an average daily volume of effluent via its final discharge point of</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>greater than 2 500 m<Sup>3</Sup> and less than or equal to 17 500 m<Sup>3</Sup>, for a continuous wastewater system with a hydraulic retention time of five or more days, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>less than or equal to 17 500 m<Sup>3</Sup>, for any other continuous wastewater system; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>any three months in any of those periods of 12 consecutive months, if the wastewater system deposited, during the previous calendar year in respect of that period of 12 consecutive months, an average daily volume of effluent via its final discharge point of greater than 17 500 m<Sup>3</Sup>.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Duration of authorization — point system in Schedules 2 and 3</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The duration, set out in subsection <XRefInternal>26</XRefInternal>(2), of a transitional authorization is based on the system for the allocation of points related to the final discharge point set out in the table to Schedule 2 and, if applicable, related to the system’s combined sewer overflow points set out in Schedule 3.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Required information</MarginalNote><Label>25</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>An application for a transitional authorization in respect of a wastewater system must contain the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the owner’s and the operator’s name, civic and postal addresses, telephone number and, if any, email address and fax number;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the name, title, civic and postal addresses, telephone number and, if any, email address and fax number of a contact person;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>if any, the wastewater system’s name and civic address;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the period of 12 consecutive months referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>24</XRefInternal>(1) upon which the application is based;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>information that establishes that at the time of the application</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the condition for the authorization set out in paragraph <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(1)(a) or (b) is not met,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the condition was not met because of the design characteristics of the wastewater system, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>it was not technically or economically feasible before the time of the application to have modified the wastewater system, including its processes, in order to meet that condition;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>a plan for the modifications to be made to the wastewater system, including a description of the modifications to be made to its processes, so that the effluent deposited via its final discharge point is not acutely lethal and meets the conditions for authorization set out in paragraphs <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(1)(a) and (b), along with a schedule for implementation of the plan;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>the latitude and longitude of the final discharge point expressed in decimal degrees in accordance with subsection <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(3);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>the number of points allocated under the table to Schedule 2;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>a statement as to which of the waters set out in paragraphs 5(a) to (g), column 2, of the table to Schedule 2 describes the water where the effluent is deposited, or may enter from the place where the effluent is deposited, via the final discharge point and, among the points set out in column 3 for those waters, the highest number of points;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(j)</Label><Text>the average daily volume of effluent deposited via the final discharge point, as determined in accordance with section <XRefInternal>7</XRefInternal>, for the period of 12 consecutive months referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>24</XRefInternal>(1) upon which the application is based, and the number of points set out in item 1, column 3, of the table to Schedule 2 that applies to that volume based on the ranges of volume set out in column 2;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(k)</Label><Text>the averages referred to in paragraphs <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(1)(a) and (b), as determined in accordance with subsection <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(3), over</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the period of 12 consecutive months referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>24</XRefInternal>(1)(a) upon which the application is based, if paragraph <XRefInternal>24</XRefInternal>(1)(a) applies, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>each month of the period of 12 consecutive months referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>24</XRefInternal>(1)(b) or (c), as the case may be, upon which the application is based, if paragraph <XRefInternal>24</XRefInternal>(1)(b) or (c) applies;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(l)</Label><Text>the number of points determined in accordance with the formula set out in item 2, column 2, of the table to Schedule 2 when using in that formula, as the case may be, the averages</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>determined under paragraph (k) over the period referred to in subparagraph (k)(i), or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>obtained by taking the sum of the averages determined under paragraph (k) for each month referred to in subparagraph (k)(ii) and dividing that number by 12;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(m)</Label><Text>each of the averages that were summed under subparagraph (l)(ii);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(n)</Label><Text>where chlorine, or one of its compounds, was used in the treatment of wastewater in the wastewater system, the number of points set out in item 3, column 3, of the table to Schedule 2 if</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the average concentration of total residual chlorine in the effluent deposited via the final discharge point — for the period of 12 consecutive months referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>24</XRefInternal>(1) upon which the application is based — exceeded 0.02 mg/L, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the wastewater system’s effluent is not dechlorinated before it is deposited via the final discharge point;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(o)</Label><Text>the maximum concentration of un-ionized ammonia in the effluent, expressed in mg/L as nitrogen (N), at 15°C ± 1°C, as determined in accordance with subsection <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(3), over</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the period of 12 consecutive months referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>24</XRefInternal>(1)(a) upon which the application is based, if paragraph <XRefInternal>24</XRefInternal>(1)(a) applies, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>each month of the period of 12 consecutive months referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>24</XRefInternal>(1)(b) or (c), as the case may be, upon which the application is based, if paragraph <XRefInternal>24</XRefInternal>(1)(b) or (c) applies;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(p)</Label><Text>if, as the case may be, the maximum concentration referred to in subparagraph (o)(i) or any of the maximum concentrations referred to in subparagraph (o)(ii) was greater than or equal to 1.25 mg/L, expressed as nitrogen (N) at 15°C ± 1°C, the number of points set out in item 4, column 3, of the table to Schedule 2;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(q)</Label><Text>if the duration of the transitional authorization sought in the application relies on an allocation of points under Schedule 3, in addition to points allocated under the table to Schedule 2, for any combined sewer overflow point that is, under Schedule 3, allocated a number of points greater than or equal to the number of points allocated under the table to Schedule 2 to the final discharge point</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the percentage referred to in item 1, column 1, of Schedule 3 that is described in whichever of paragraphs 1(a) to (d), column 2, of that Schedule that applies,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the number of deposits referred to in item 2, column 1, of Schedule 3 that are described in whichever of paragraphs 2(a) to (d), column 2, of that Schedule that applies, for the period of 12 consecutive months referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>24</XRefInternal>(1) upon which the application is based,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>a statement as to which of the waters set out in paragraphs 3(a) to (c), column 2, of Schedule 3 describes the water where the effluent is deposited, or may enter from the place where the effluent is deposited, via that combined sewer overflow point, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>the number of points set out in column 3 of Schedule 3 for the applicable paragraph set out in column 2 of that Schedule as determined for the purposes of subparagraphs (i) and (ii) and the number of those points that applies for each statement referred to in subparagraph (iii);</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(r)</Label><Text>the information set out in subparagraph <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(1)(g)(i) for the combined sewer overflow point referred to in paragraph (q);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(s)</Label><Text>for an application referred to in paragraph (q), a plan that describes the modifications to be made to the wastewater system, and any other measure to be taken, to reduce, after the expiry of the period for which the transitional authorization is sought, the quantity of deleterious substances prescribed in section <XRefInternal>5</XRefInternal> in the effluent deposited via overflow points of a combined sewer and a schedule for implementation of the plan; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(t)</Label><Text>a statement signed and dated by the owner or operator, or their duly authorized representative, that certifies that information provided in the application is true, accurate and complete</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>in the case of information that was prepared by the owner or operator, to the best of the owner’s or operator’s information and belief, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>in the case of information that was prepared by other persons with sufficient knowledge to evaluate that information, to the best of the owner’s or operator’s information and belief, based on representations made to them by those persons.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Required information — fictional consolidated wastewater system</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Despite subsection (1), an application for a transitional authorization made by an owner or operator of a fictional consolidated wastewater system must, instead of the plan referred to in paragraph (1)(f), contain a copy of the consolidation plan referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>4</XRefInternal>(1).</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Conditions of Issuance</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Required information</MarginalNote><Label>26</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (3), the authorization officer must issue the transitional authorization if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the application contains the information required by subsection <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1) or (2), as the case may be;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the information referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1)(e) can reasonably be regarded as establishing that at the time of the application</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the condition for the authorization set out in paragraph <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(1)(a) or (b) was not met,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>that condition was not met because of the design of the wastewater system, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>it was not technically or economically feasible before the time of the application to have modified the wastewater system, including its processes, in order to meet that condition; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the schedule to implement the plan referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1)(f) or subsection <XRefInternal>4</XRefInternal>(1), as the case may be, and, if applicable, paragraph <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1)(s) can reasonably be regarded as feasible for the purpose of meeting the requirements, as the case may be, referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1)(f) or paragraph <XRefInternal>4</XRefInternal>(3)(a) and, if applicable, achieve the reduction referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1)(s).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Duration of transitional authorization</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The transitional authorization must be issued for the following period:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>from January 1, 2015 to December 31, 2020, if the final discharge point is, under the table to Schedule 2, allocated 70 or more points and, if the wastewater system has combined sewer overflow points for which points are allocated under Schedule 3, each combined sewer overflow point of the wastewater system is allocated less points than the number of points allocated under the table to Schedule 2 to the final discharge point;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>from January 1, 2015 to December 31, 2030, if the final discharge point is, under the table to Schedule 2, allocated 50 or more points but less than 70 points and, if the wastewater system has combined sewer overflow points for which points are allocated under Schedule 3, each combined sewer overflow point of the wastewater system is allocated less points than the number of points allocated under the table to Schedule 2 to the final discharge point; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>from January 1, 2015 to December 31, 2040,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>if the final discharge point is, under the table to Schedule 2, allocated less than 50 points, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>if the final discharge point is, under the table to Schedule 2, allocated 50 or more points and the wastewater system has combined sewer overflow points for which points are allocated under Schedule 3, there is at least one combined sewer overflow point that is, under Schedule 3, allocated a number of points that is greater than or equal to the number of points allocated under the table to Schedule 2 to the final discharge point.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Refusal</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The authorization officer must refuse to issue the transitional authorization if they have reasonable grounds to believe that the information contained in, or provided in support of, the application is false or misleading in a material respect.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Change of plan</MarginalNote><Label>27</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A holder of a transitional authorization who changes a plan referred in paragraph <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1)(f), subsection <XRefInternal>4</XRefInternal>(1) or paragraph <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1)(s) must, without delay, provide the authorization officer with the changed plan, along with a schedule to implement it.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Approval of changed plan</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The authorization officer must approve the changed plan and the schedule to implement it, if the requirements referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>26</XRefInternal>(1)(c) are satisfied. With that approval, the transitional authorization, based on that changed plan and that schedule, continues to be in force.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Original plan if no approval</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>If that changed plan and that schedule are not approved, the transitional authorization continues to be in force only if the holder respects the original plan and the original schedule for its implementation.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Conditions on Transitional Authorizations</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Authorized deposits — transitional authorization</MarginalNote><Label>28</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A holder of a transitional authorization in respect of a wastewater system is authorized — during a given calendar year, quarter or month, determined in accordance with subsection <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(2), in the period of authorization — to deposit effluent that contains any of the deleterious substances prescribed in section <XRefInternal>5</XRefInternal> via the final discharge point if — during the previous calendar year, previous quarter or previous month — the effluent met the following conditions:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the average carbonaceous biochemical oxygen demand due to the quantity of CBOD matter in the effluent referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(1)(a), determined in accordance with subsections <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(2) and (3), did not exceed</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>1.25 times the average determined for the carbonaceous biochemical oxygen demand due to the quantity of CBOD matter referred to in subparagraph <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1)(k)(i) or the greatest of those averages referred to in subparagraph <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1)(k)(ii), as the case may be, if the product resulting from that multiplication is greater than 25 mg/L, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>25 mg/L, in any other case;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the average concentration of suspended solids in the effluent referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(1)(b), determined in accordance with subsections <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(2) and (3), did not exceed</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>1.25 times the average concentration of suspended solids referred to in subparagraph <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1)(k)(i) or the greatest of those averages referred to in subparagraph <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1)(k)(ii), as the case may be, if the product resulting from that multiplication is greater than 25 mg/L, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>25 mg/L, in any other case;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the average concentration of total residual chlorine in the effluent referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(1)(c), determined in accordance with subsections <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(2) and (3), did not exceed 0.02 mg/L, if chlorine, or one of its compounds, was used in the treatment of wastewater; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the maximum concentration of un-ionized ammonia in the effluent referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(1)(d), determined in accordance with subsections <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(2) and (3), was less than</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>1.25 times the maximum concentration referred to in subparagraph <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1)(o)(i) or the greatest of those maximum concentrations referred to in subparagraph <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1)(o)(ii), as the case may be, if the product resulting from that multiplication is greater than or equal to 1.25 mg/L, expressed as nitrogen (N), at 15°C ± 1°C, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>1.25 mg/L, expressed as nitrogen (N), at 15°C ± 1°C, in any other case.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Authorized deposits — fictional consolidated wastewater system</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A holder of a transitional authorization in respect of a fictional consolidated wastewater system is, in addition, authorized, during the given calendar year, quarter or month referred to in subsection (1), to deposit effluent that contains any of the deleterious substances prescribed in section <XRefInternal>5</XRefInternal> via the final discharge point of each of the original wastewater systems that constitute the fictional consolidated wastewater system — other than the final discharge point for the fictional consolidated wastewater system referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>4</XRefInternal>(2) — if the effluent deposited via the final discharge point of each of those original wastewater systems — during the previous calendar year, previous quarter or previous month — met the conditions set out in subsection (1).</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Compliance Obligations</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>General requirements</MarginalNote><Label>29</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A holder of a transitional authorization in respect of a wastewater system must, during the period of authorization,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>comply with sections <XRefInternal>7</XRefInternal> to <XRefInternal>10</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>12</XRefInternal> to <XRefInternal>14</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>16</XRefInternal> to <XRefInternal>22</XRefInternal> and <XRefInternal>48</XRefInternal>; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>respect the plan referred to in, as the case may be, subsection <XRefInternal>4</XRefInternal>(1) or paragraph <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1)(f) and, if applicable, paragraph <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1)(s) — or, if applicable, that plan as approved with changes under subsection <XRefInternal>27</XRefInternal>(2) — and respect its schedule for implementation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Progress reports</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The holder of a transitional authorization must, within 90 days before the following dates, send to the authorization officer a progress report on the steps taken to implement the plan referred to in, as the case may be, subsection <XRefInternal>4</XRefInternal>(1) or paragraph <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1)(f) and, if applicable, paragraph <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1)(s) — or, if applicable, that plan as approved with changes under subsection <XRefInternal>27</XRefInternal>(2):</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>July 1, 2017, if the period of authorization ends on December 31, 2020;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>July 1, 2020 and July 1, 2025, if the period of authorization ends on December 31, 2030; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>July 1, 2020, July 1, 2025, July 1, 2030 and July 1, 2035, if the period of authorization ends on December 31, 2040.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Scope of Transitional Authorization and Revocation</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Content of transitional authorization</MarginalNote><Label>30</Label><Text>A transitional authorization must be in the form set out in Schedule 4 and contain the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the information referred to in paragraphs <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1)(a) and (c);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the latitude and longitude of the final discharge point;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the date of issuance;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the period of authorization; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the following averages and maximum concentration of the deleterious substances prescribed in section <XRefInternal>5</XRefInternal> that are authorized to be contained in effluent that is deposited via the final discharge point during a given calendar year, quarter or month referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>28</XRefInternal>(1):</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>for the average carbonaceous biochemical oxygen demand due to the quantity of CBOD matter, the average referred to in, as the case may be, subparagraph <XRefInternal>28</XRefInternal>(1)(a)(i) or (ii),</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>for the average concentration of suspended solids, the average referred to in, as the case may be, subparagraph <XRefInternal>28</XRefInternal>(1)(b)(i) or (ii),</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>for the average concentration of total residual chlorine, the average referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>28</XRefInternal>(1)(c), and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>for the maximum concentration of un-ionized ammonia, the maximum concentration referred to in, as the case may be, subparagraph <XRefInternal>28</XRefInternal>(1)(d)(i) or (ii).</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Correction of information</MarginalNote><Label>31</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>If the owner or operator becomes aware that the information provided in an application for a transitional authorization contains errors, they must, without delay, send a notice to the authorization officer, which indicates the reason for the errors and provides corrections, and make the certification under paragraph <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1)(t) with respect to the corrected application.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Corrected transitional authorization</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>On receipt of a notice that provides corrections that, if provided with the application, would have affected the scope of the information referred to in section <XRefInternal>30</XRefInternal> contained in the transitional authorization, the authorization officer must issue a corrected transitional authorization as if the corrections together with the remaining information originally provided in the application were an application under section <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Revocation</MarginalNote><Label>32</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The authorization officer may revoke a transitional authorization if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the information referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1) or (2), as the case may be, contained in the application or the information provided in a progress report referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>29</XRefInternal>(2) is false or misleading in a material respect;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the holder has, during the period of authorization, failed to comply with any condition set out in section <XRefInternal>28</XRefInternal> or any provision referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>29</XRefInternal>(1);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>new information indicates that a deposit authorized under section <XRefInternal>28</XRefInternal> has had or is likely to have an effect on fish, fish habitat or the use by man of fish that is more adverse than the worst of the effects that were anticipated when that authorization was issued;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the holder has not sent a progress report in accordance with subsection <XRefInternal>29</XRefInternal>(2); or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the authorization officer, based on a progress report referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>29</XRefInternal>(2), has reasonable grounds to believe that the plan — referred to in, as the case may be, subsection <XRefInternal>4</XRefInternal>(1) or paragraph <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1)(f) and, if applicable, paragraph <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1)(s) — or, if applicable, that plan as approved with changes under subsection <XRefInternal>27</XRefInternal>(2) — cannot be fully implemented before the end of the period of authorization.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Considerations</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>When determining whether to revoke a transitional authorization, the authorization officer must consider, as applicable, whether the holder of a transitional authorization</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>has a history of non-compliance with any condition or provision referred to in paragraph (1)(b);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>has provided a reasonable justification for not sending a progress report in accordance with subsection <XRefInternal>29</XRefInternal>(2); or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>has carried out, or signed an undertaking to carry out, specified corrective measures to ensure compliance with any condition or provision referred to in paragraph (1)(b) or to prevent or mitigate a more adverse effect referred to in paragraph (1)(c).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Representations</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The authorization officer is not permitted to revoke a transitional authorization unless they have provided the holder with</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>written reasons for the proposed revocation; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>an opportunity to be heard, by written representation, in respect of the proposed revocation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Early expiry</MarginalNote><Label>33</Label><Text>Despite subsections <XRefInternal>24</XRefInternal>(2) and <XRefInternal>26</XRefInternal>(2), a transitional authorization expires at the end of a given calendar year, quarter or month determined in accordance with subsection <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(2), if the effluent deposited via the final discharge point of the wastewater system was not acutely lethal and met the conditions for the authorization set out in paragraphs <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(1)(a) and (b) during</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>that given calendar year;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>that given quarter and the three quarters immediately before that given quarter during which effluent was deposited via the final discharge point; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>that given month and each of the 11 months immediately before that given month during which effluent was deposited via the final discharge point.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Temporary Authorization to Deposit Un-ionized Ammonia</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Requirements and Duration</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Requirements</MarginalNote><Label>34</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a wastewater system whose effluent deposited via its final discharge point is acutely lethal because of the concentration of un-ionized ammonia in it may apply to an authorization officer for a temporary authorization to deposit effluent that contains un-ionized ammonia via the final discharge point if the concentration of un-ionized ammonia in the water, determined in accordance with subsection (3), at any point that is 100 m from the point of entry where effluent is deposited in that water via the final discharge point is less than or equal to 0.016 mg/L, expressed as nitrogen (N), and if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the acute lethality of the effluent — as determined in accordance with Reference Method EPS 1/RM/13 using the procedure set out in section 6 of that Method and the Procedure for pH Stabilization EPS 1/RM/50 — is primarily because of the concentration of un-ionized ammonia in the effluent; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the effluent is acutely lethal because the concentration of un-ionized ammonia in the effluent deposited via the final discharge point is greater than or equal to 1.25 mg/L, expressed as nitrogen (N) at 15°C ± 1°C, determined in accordance with section <XRefInternal>14</XRefInternal>.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Samples</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The determination referred to in paragraph (1)(b) must</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for an intermittent wastewater system, be based on at least one sample of effluent; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for a continuous wastewater system, be based on at least two samples of effluent taken 7 days apart.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Determination of NH<Sub>3</Sub> concentration in water</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The concentration of un-ionized ammonia in the water referred to in subsection (1) must be determined in accordance with the following formula:</Text><FormulaGroup><Formula><FormulaText>total ammonia × <Fraction><Numerator>1</Numerator><Denominator>1 +<MSup><Base>10</Base><Superscript>pKa – pH</Superscript></MSup></Denominator></Fraction></FormulaText></Formula><FormulaConnector>where</FormulaConnector><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>total ammonia</FormulaTerm><Text>is the concentration of total ammonia in that water — namely, un-ionized ammonia (NH<Sub>3</Sub>) plus ionized ammonia (NH<Sub>4</Sub><Sup>+</Sup>) — determined in accordance with subsection (4), expressed in mg/L as nitrogen (N);</Text></FormulaDefinition><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>pKa</FormulaTerm><Text>is 0.09018 + 2729.92/T, where T is the ambient water temperature in kelvin; and</Text></FormulaDefinition><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>pH</FormulaTerm><Text>is the pH of that water.</Text></FormulaDefinition></FormulaGroup></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Determination of concentration of total ammonia in water</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The concentration of total ammonia in the water referred to in subsection (3) must be determined</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>using a total ammonia test; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>using a method of estimation that is based on generally accepted engineering practices.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Periods for application</MarginalNote><Label>(5)</Label><Text>An initial application for a temporary authorization to deposit effluent that contains un-ionized ammonia must be made within 30 days after, as the case may be, the determination referred to in paragraph (1)(a) or (b) has been made. Applications to extend the temporary authorization must be made at least 90 days before the expiry of the authorization.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Required information</MarginalNote><Label>35</Label><Text>An application for a temporary authorization to deposit effluent that contains un-ionized ammonia in respect of a wastewater system must contain the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the owner’s and the operator’s name, civic and postal addresses, telephone number and, if any, email address and fax number;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the name, title, civic and postal addresses, telephone number and, if any, email address and fax number, of a contact person;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>if any, the wastewater system’s name and civic address;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the latitude and longitude of the final discharge point expressed in decimal degrees in accordance with subsection <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(3);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>in relation to the determination of the acute lethality of the effluent</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>if that determination is the one referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>34</XRefInternal>(1)(a),</Text><Clause><Label>(A)</Label><Text>the result of that determination, including, for each sample on which that determination was based, the information referred to in section 8.1 of Reference Method EPS 1/RM/13 and section 3 of the Procedure for pH Stabilization EPS 1/RM/50, and</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(B)</Label><Text>information establishing that, when that determination was made, any acute lethality of the effluent was primarily because of the concentration of the un-ionized ammonia in the effluent, or</Text></Clause></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>if that determination is the one referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>34</XRefInternal>(1)(b), the concentration of un-ionized ammonia in each of the samples referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>34</XRefInternal>(2);</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>information that establishes that, when the application was made, the concentration of un-ionized ammonia in the water, determined in accordance with subsection <XRefInternal>34</XRefInternal>(3), at any point that is 100 m from the point of entry where effluent is deposited in that water via the final discharge point was less than or equal to 0.016 mg/L, expressed as nitrogen (N); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>a statement signed and dated by the owner or operator, or their duly authorized representative, that certifies that information provided in the application is true, accurate and complete</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>in the case of information that was prepared by the owner or operator, to the best of the owner’s or operator’s information and belief, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>in the case of information that was that was prepared by other persons with sufficient knowledge to evaluate that information, to the best of the owner’s or operator’s information and belief, based on representations made to them by those persons.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Conditions of Issuance</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Required information</MarginalNote><Label>36</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (2), the authorization officer must issue the temporary authorization to deposit effluent that contains un-ionized ammonia for a period of three years from January 1, 2015, or the date of issuance if that date is later, if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the application contains the information required under section <XRefInternal>35</XRefInternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the information referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>35</XRefInternal>(e) has established that the effluent was, at the time of the application, acutely lethal because of the concentration of un-ionized ammonia in it; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the information referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>35</XRefInternal>(f) has established that the concentration of un-ionized ammonia in the water, determined in accordance with subsection <XRefInternal>34</XRefInternal>(3), at any point that is 100 m from the point of entry where effluent was deposited in that water via the final discharge point was less than or equal to 0.016 mg/L, expressed as nitrogen (N).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Refusal</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The authorization officer must refuse to issue the temporary authorization if they have reasonable grounds to believe that the information contained in, or provided in support of, the application is false or misleading in a material respect.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Conditions on Temporary Authorization</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Authorized deposits</MarginalNote><Label>37</Label><Text>A holder of a temporary authorization to deposit effluent that contains un-ionized ammonia in respect of a wastewater system is authorized to deposit, via the final discharge point, effluent</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>that satisfies the conditions set out in paragraphs <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(1)(a) to (c); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>that results in a concentration of un-ionized ammonia in the water, determined in accordance with subsection <XRefInternal>34</XRefInternal>(3), at any point that is 100 m from the point of entry where effluent is deposited in that water via the final discharge point that is less than or equal to 0.016 mg/L, expressed as nitrogen (N).</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Compliance Obligations</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>General requirements</MarginalNote><Label>38</Label><Text>The holder of a temporary authorization to deposit effluent that contains un-ionized ammonia in respect of a wastewater system must during the period of authorization</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>comply with sections <XRefInternal>7</XRefInternal> to <XRefInternal>10</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>12</XRefInternal> to <XRefInternal>14</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>16</XRefInternal> to <XRefInternal>22</XRefInternal> and <XRefInternal>48</XRefInternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each sample taken under subsection <XRefInternal>10</XRefInternal>(1), (2) or (3), determine, or cause the determination of, the concentration of un-ionized ammonia in the effluent, in accordance with section <XRefInternal>14</XRefInternal>; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>once each August, determine, or cause the determination of, the concentration of un-ionized ammonia in the water referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>37</XRefInternal>(b).</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Scope of Temporary Authorization and Revocation</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Period and content</MarginalNote><Label>39</Label><Text>A temporary authorization, and any extension of it, to deposit effluent that contains un-ionized ammonia must be in the form set out in Schedule 5 and contain the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the information referred to in paragraphs <XRefInternal>35</XRefInternal>(a) and (c);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the latitude and longitude of the final discharge point;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the date of issuance of the temporary authorization and of any extension of it;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the period of authorization; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>a statement that the concentration of un-ionized ammonia in the water, determined in accordance with subsection <XRefInternal>34</XRefInternal>(3), at any point that is 100 m from the point of entry where effluent is deposited in that water via the final discharge point must be less than or equal to 0.016 mg/L, expressed as nitrogen (N).</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Extension</MarginalNote><Label>40</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A temporary authorization may, on application, be extended for successive periods of three years. If that application is based on a determination of the acute lethality of effluent referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>34</XRefInternal>(1)(a), it must contain the information referred to in subparagraph <XRefInternal>35</XRefInternal>(e)(i).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Issuance</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The authorization officer must — based on the information contained in the application for the extension, the monitoring reports sent under subsection <XRefInternal>19</XRefInternal>(1) and the original application for the temporary authorization referred to in section <XRefInternal>35</XRefInternal> — extend the authorization if it is established that, when the application for an extension was made,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the effluent was acutely lethal because of the concentration of un-ionized ammonia in it; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the concentration of un-ionized ammonia in the water, determined in accordance with subsection <XRefInternal>34</XRefInternal>(3), at any point that is 100 m from the point of entry where effluent was deposited in that water via the final discharge point was less than or equal to 0.016 mg/L, expressed as nitrogen (N).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Correction of information</MarginalNote><Label>41</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>If the owner or operator becomes aware that the information provided in an application for a temporary authorization, or for an extension of a temporary authorization, contains errors, they must, without delay, send a notice to the authorization officer, which indicates the reason for the errors and provides corrections, and make the certification under paragraph <XRefInternal>35</XRefInternal>(g) with respect to the corrected application.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Corrected temporary authorization</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>On receipt of a notice that provides corrections that, if provided with the application, would have affected the scope of the information referred to in section <XRefInternal>39</XRefInternal>, the authorization officer must issue a corrected temporary authorization or corrected extension of a temporary authorization, as the case may be, as if the corrections together with the remaining information originally provided in the application were an application under section <XRefInternal>35</XRefInternal> or <XRefInternal>40</XRefInternal>.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Revocation</MarginalNote><Label>42</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The authorization officer may revoke a temporary authorization, or an extended temporary authorization, to deposit effluent that contains un-ionized ammonia if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the information contained in, as the case may be, the application for the temporary authorization referred to in section <XRefInternal>35</XRefInternal> or the application for the extended temporary authorization referred to in <XRefInternal>40</XRefInternal> is false or misleading in a material respect;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the holder has, during the period of authorization, failed to comply with paragraph <XRefInternal>37</XRefInternal>(a) or (b), any section referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>38</XRefInternal>(a), or paragraph <XRefInternal>38</XRefInternal>(b) or (c); or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>new information indicates that a deposit under the temporary authorization or the extended temporary authorization has had or is likely to have an effect on fish, fish habitat or the use by man of fish that is more adverse than the worst of those effects that were anticipated when that authorization was issued.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Considerations</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>When determining whether to revoke a temporary authorization or an extended temporary authorization, the authorization officer must consider, as applicable, whether the holder</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>has a history of non-compliance with any provision referred to in paragraph (1)(b); or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>has carried out, or signed an undertaking to carry out, specified corrective measures to ensure compliance with any provision referred to in paragraph (1)(b) or to prevent or mitigate a more adverse effect referred to in paragraph (1)(c).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Representations</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The authorization officer is not permitted to revoke a temporary authorization or an extended temporary authorization unless they have provided the holder with</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>written reasons for the proposed revocation; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>an opportunity to be heard, by written representation, in respect of the proposed revocation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Temporary Bypass Authorization</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Requirements</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Deposit without or with partial treatment</MarginalNote><Label>43</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>An owner or operator of a wastewater system may apply to an authorization officer for a temporary authorization to bypass at least one of the treatment processes normally applied to wastewater in the system and, as a result, to deposit effluent that contains any deleterious substance prescribed in section <XRefInternal>5</XRefInternal>.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Conditions precedent</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>An application for a temporary bypass authorization is not to be made unless</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the requirement to bypass those treatment processes arises from</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>construction work to make changes to the system,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the maintenance of the system, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>the response to an anticipated event that is beyond the control of the owner or operator of the system; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the bypass is designed, within the constraints of technical and economic feasibility, to minimize the volume of effluent deposited and the concentration of deleterious substances prescribed in section <XRefInternal>5</XRefInternal> in the effluent deposited.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Period for application</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>An application for a temporary bypass authorization must be made at least 45 days before the day on which the requirement referred to in paragraph (2)(a) is to arise.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Required information</MarginalNote><Label>44</Label><Text>An application for a temporary bypass authorization must contain the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the owner’s and the operator’s name, civic and postal addresses, telephone number and, if any, email address and fax number;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the name, title, civic and postal addresses, telephone number and, if any, email address and fax number, of a contact person;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>if any, the wastewater system’s name and civic address;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>an explanation of how the bypass is designed to minimize the volume of effluent deposited and the concentration of deleterious substances prescribed in section <XRefInternal>5</XRefInternal> in the effluent deposited during the construction work, the maintenance of the system or the response referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>43</XRefInternal>(2)(a), including a description of, and a schedule for, all steps that are to be taken to achieve that minimization;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the latitude and longitude, expressed in decimal degrees in accordance with subsection <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(3), of</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the final discharge point, if the bypass results in the deposit of effluent via the system’s final discharge point, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the overflow point, if the bypass results in wastewater being diverted to an overflow point of the wastewater system for deposit in any water or place referred to in subsection 36(3) of the Act;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>the period for which the bypass is required in order to allow for the construction work, for the maintenance of the system or for the response referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>43</XRefInternal>(2)(a);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>the approximate duration, expressed in hours, of the deposits referred to in subparagraph (e)(i) or (ii) or both;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>the estimated volume, expressed in m<Sup>3</Sup>, of those deposits; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>a statement signed and dated by the owner or operator, or their duly authorized representative, that certifies that information provided in the application is true, accurate and complete</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>in the case of information that was prepared by the owner or operator, to the best of the owner’s or operator’s information and belief, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>in the case of information that was that was prepared by other persons with sufficient knowledge to evaluate that information, to the best of the owner’s or operator’s information and belief, based on representations made to them by those persons.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Conditions of Issuance</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Required information</MarginalNote><Label>45</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (3), the authorization officer must issue a temporary bypass authorization if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the authorization officer has reasonable grounds to believe that the conditions set out in paragraphs <XRefInternal>43</XRefInternal>(2)(a) and (b) are satisfied; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the application contains the information required under section <XRefInternal>44</XRefInternal>.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Duration of temporary bypass authorization</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The temporary bypass authorization is to be issued for the period that, in the authorization officer’s opinion,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>is required in order to allow for the construction work, for the maintenance of the system or for the response referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>43</XRefInternal>(2)(a); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>will mitigate any adverse effects on fish, fish habitat or the use by man of fish to the extent possible given the requirement referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>43</XRefInternal>(2)(a) for which the bypass authorization arises.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Refusal — adverse effects</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The authorization officer may refuse to issue the temporary authorization if they have reasonable grounds to believe that its issuance, for any period, would result in adverse effects on fish, fish habitat or the use by man of fish that cannot be mitigated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Refusal — false or misleading information</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The authorization officer must refuse to issue the temporary authorization if they have reasonable grounds to believe that the information contained in, or provided in support of, the application is false or misleading in a material respect.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Issuance</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Content of authorization</MarginalNote><Label>46</Label><Text>A temporary bypass authorization is to be issued for a period that is sufficient to allow for the construction work, for the maintenance of the system or for the response referred to in paragraph <XRefInternal>43</XRefInternal>(2)(a) and the authorization must be in the form set out in Schedule 6 and contain the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the information referred to in paragraphs <XRefInternal>44</XRefInternal>(a), (c) and (e);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the date of issuance; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the period of authorization.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Correction of information</MarginalNote><Label>47</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>If the owner or operator becomes aware that the information provided in an application for a temporary bypass authorization contains errors, they must, without delay, send a notice to the authorization officer, which indicates the reason for the errors and provides corrections, and make the certification under paragraph <XRefInternal>44</XRefInternal>(i) with respect to the corrected application.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Corrected authorization</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>On receipt of a notice that provides corrections that, if provided with the application, would have affected the scope of the information referred to in section <XRefInternal>46</XRefInternal> contained in the temporary bypass authorization, the authorization officer must issue a corrected temporary bypass authorization as if the corrections together with the remaining information originally provided in the application were an application under section <XRefInternal>44</XRefInternal>.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Electronic applications</MarginalNote><Label>48</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>An application for a transitional authorization or a temporary authorization must be sent electronically in the form and format specified by the Minister of the Environment and must bear the electronic signature of the owner or operator, or their duly authorized representative.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Paper</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>If the Minister of the Environment has not specified an electronic form and format or if it is not feasible to send the application electronically in accordance with subsection (1) because of circumstances beyond the control of the owner or operator, or their duly authorized representative, the application must be sent on paper, signed by the owner or operator, or their duly authorized representative, and in the form and format specified by the Minister of the Environment. However, if no form and format have been so specified, it may be in any form and format.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Registry of authorizations</MarginalNote><Label>49</Label><Text>The Minister of the Environment must maintain a registry, for examination by the public, that contains a copy of each transitional authorization, each temporary authorization to deposit effluent that contains un-ionized ammonia and each temporary bypass authorization that has been issued under this Part, as they may be modified from time to time, and that has not been revoked.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>On registration</MarginalNote><Label>50</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsections (2) to (4), these Regulations come into force on the day on which they are registered.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>January 1, 2013</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Subsections <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(2) to (6), sections <XRefInternal>7</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>8</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>10</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>12</XRefInternal> to <XRefInternal>14</XRefInternal> and <XRefInternal>16</XRefInternal>, paragraphs <XRefInternal>17</XRefInternal>(a), (b) and (d) to (g) and sections <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal> to <XRefInternal>20</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>23</XRefInternal> to <XRefInternal>27</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>30</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>31</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>34</XRefInternal> to <XRefInternal>36</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>39</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>41</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>48</XRefInternal> and <XRefInternal>49</XRefInternal> come into force on January 1, 2013.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>January 1, 2015</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Subsections <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(1) and (7), sections <XRefInternal>11</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>15</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>28</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>29</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>32</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>33</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>37</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>38</XRefInternal>, <XRefInternal>40</XRefInternal> and <XRefInternal>42</XRefInternal> to <XRefInternal>47</XRefInternal> come into force on January 1, 2015.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>January 1, 2021 — paragraphs <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(1)(c) and <XRefInternal>28</XRefInternal>(1)(c) in relation to certain owners or operators</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Despite subsection (3), paragraphs <XRefInternal>6</XRefInternal>(1)(c) and <XRefInternal>28</XRefInternal>(1)(c) come into force on January 1, 2021 in relation to an owner or operator of a wastewater system that has, on the day on which these Regulations are registered, an average daily volume of effluent deposited annually via its final discharge point of less than 5 000 m<Sup>3</Sup>, determined on the basis of its average design rate of flow of influent.</Text></Subsection></Section></Body><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 1</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 1)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><TableGroup pointsize="7" topmarginspacing="10"><table frame="topbot"><title>Authorization Officers</title><tgroup cols="4" align="left"><colspec colname="COLSPEC6" colwidth="16.32*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="42.98*" /><colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="59.80*" /><colspec colname="3" colwidth="54.15*" /><thead><row rowsep="0" topdouble="yes"><entry morerows="1" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Item</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" valign="top">Column 1</entry><entry colsep="0" valign="top">Column 2</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" valign="top">Column 3</entry></row><row rowsep="1" valign="bottom"><entry colname="2" colsep="0">Province</entry><entry colsep="0">Owner</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0">Position</entry></row></thead><tbody><row rowsep="0"><entry morerows="2" colsep="0">1</entry><entry rowheader="yes" morerows="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Ontario</entry><entry colsep="0">Her Majesty in right of Canada, another federal body or an Aboriginal organization referred to in clause <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(1)(d)(iii)(D) of these Regulations</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Manager, Wastewater Section</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>Environment Stewardship Branch</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Her Majesty in right of Ontario or another Ontario body or municipality or another local authority in Ontario</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>The holder of a position that is designated as an authorization officer for the purpose of these Regulations for Ontario in a written agreement between the governments of Canada and Ontario related to the administration of these Regulations that is published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the absence of such an agreement, Manager, Wastewater Section, Environmental Stewardship Branch, Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Entity referred to in clause <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(1)(d)(iii)(E) of these Regulations</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>The holder of a position that is designated as an authorization officer for the purpose of these Regulations for Ontario in a written agreement between the governments of Canada and Ontario related to the administration of these Regulations that is published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the absence of such an agreement, Manager, Wastewater Section, Environmental Stewardship Branch, Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry morerows="2" colsep="0">2</entry><entry rowheader="yes" morerows="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Quebec</entry><entry colsep="0">Her Majesty in right of Canada, another federal body or an Aboriginal organization referred to in clause <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(1)(d)(iii)(D) of these Regulations</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Manager, Wastewater Section</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>Environment Stewardship Branch</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Her Majesty in right of Quebec or another Quebec body or municipality or another local authority in Quebec</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>The holder of a position that is designated as an authorization officer for the purpose of these Regulations for Quebec in a written agreement between the governments of Canada and Quebec related to the administration of these Regulations that is published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the absence of such an agreement, Manager, Wastewater Section, Environmental Stewardship Branch, Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Entity referred to in clause <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(1)(d)(iii)(E) of these Regulations</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>The holder of a position that is designated as an authorization officer for the purpose of these Regulations for Quebec in a written agreement between the governments of Canada and Quebec related to the administration of these Regulations that is published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the absence of such an agreement, Manager, Wastewater Section, Environmental Stewardship Branch, Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry morerows="2" colsep="0">3</entry><entry rowheader="yes" morerows="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Nova Scotia</entry><entry colsep="0">Her Majesty in right of Canada, another federal body or an Aboriginal organization referred to in clause <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(1)(d)(iii)(D) of these Regulations</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Manager, Wastewater Section</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>Environment Stewardship Branch</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Her Majesty in right of Nova Scotia or another Nova Scotia body or municipality or another local authority in Nova Scotia</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>The holder of a position that is designated as an authorization officer for the purpose of these Regulations for Nova Scotia in a written agreement between the governments of Canada and Nova Scotia related to the administration of these Regulations that is published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the absence of such an agreement, Manager, Wastewater Section, Environmental Stewardship Branch, Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Entity referred to in clause <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(1)(d)(iii)(E) of these Regulations</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>The holder of a position that is designated as an authorization officer for the purpose of these Regulations for Nova Scotia in a written agreement between the governments of Canada and Nova Scotia related to the administration of these Regulations that is published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the absence of such an agreement, Manager, Wastewater Section, Environmental Stewardship Branch, Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry morerows="2" colsep="0">4</entry><entry rowheader="yes" morerows="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">New Brunswick</entry><entry colsep="0">Her Majesty in right of Canada, another federal body or an Aboriginal organization referred to in clause <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(1)(d)(iii)(D) of these Regulations</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Manager, Wastewater Section</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>Environment Stewardship Branch</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Her Majesty in right of a New Brunswick or another New Brunswick body or municipality or another local authority in New Brunswick</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>The holder of a position that is designated as an authorization officer for the purpose of these Regulations for New Brunswick in a written agreement between the governments of Canada and New Brunswick related to the administration of these Regulations that is published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the absence of such an agreement, Manager, Wastewater Section, Environmental Stewardship Branch, Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Entity referred to in clause <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(1)(d)(iii)(E) of these Regulations</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>The holder of a position that is designated as an authorization officer for the purpose of these Regulations for New Brunswick in a written agreement between the governments of Canada and New Brunswick related to the administration of these Regulations that is published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the absence of such an agreement, Manager, Wastewater Section, Environmental Stewardship Branch, Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry morerows="2" colsep="0">5</entry><entry rowheader="yes" morerows="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Manitoba</entry><entry colsep="0">Her Majesty in right of Canada, another federal body or an Aboriginal organization referred to in clause <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(1)(d)(iii)(D) of these Regulations</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Manager, Wastewater Section</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>Environment Stewardship Branch</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Her Majesty in right of Manitoba or another Manitoba body or municipality or another local authority in Manitoba</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>The holder of a position that is designated as an authorization officer for the purpose of these Regulations for Manitoba in a written agreement between the governments of Canada and Manitoba related to the administration of these Regulations that is published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the absence of such an agreement, Manager, Wastewater Section, Environmental Stewardship Branch, Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Entity referred to in clause <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(1)(d)(iii)(E) of these Regulations</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>The holder of a position that is designated as an authorization officer for the purpose of these Regulations for Manitoba in a written agreement between the governments of Canada and Manitoba related to the administration of these Regulations that is published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the absence of such an agreement, Manager, Wastewater Section, Environmental Stewardship Branch, Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry morerows="2" colsep="0">6</entry><entry rowheader="yes" morerows="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">British Columbia</entry><entry colsep="0">Her Majesty in right of Canada, another federal body or an Aboriginal organization referred to in clause <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(1)(d)(iii)(D) of these Regulations</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Manager, Wastewater Section</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>Environment Stewardship Branch</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Her Majesty in right of British Columbia or another British Columbia body or municipality or another local authority in British Columbia</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>The holder of a position that is designated as an authorization officer for the purpose of these Regulations for British Columbia in a written agreement between the governments of Canada and British Columbia related to the administration of these Regulations that is published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the absence of such an agreement, Manager, Wastewater Section, Environmental Stewardship Branch, Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Entity referred to in clause <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(1)(d)(iii)(E) of these Regulations</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>The holder of a position that is designated as an authorization officer for the purpose of these Regulations for British Columbia in a written agreement between the governments of Canada and British Columbia related to the administration of these Regulations that is published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the absence of such an agreement, Manager, Wastewater Section, Environmental Stewardship Branch, Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></entry></row><row><entry morerows="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0">7</entry><entry rowheader="yes" morerows="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0">Prince Edward Island</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Her Majesty in right of Canada, another federal body or an Aboriginal organization referred to in clause <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(1)(d)(iii)(D) of these Regulations</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Manager, Wastewater Section</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>Environment Stewardship Branch</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Her Majesty in right of Prince Edward Island or another Prince Edward Island body or municipality or another local authority in Prince Edward Island</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>The holder of a position that is designated as an authorization officer for the purpose of these Regulations for Prince Edward Island in a written agreement between the governments of Canada and Prince Edward Island related to the administration of these Regulations that is published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the absence of such an agreement, Manager, Wastewater Section, Environmental Stewardship Branch, Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Entity referred to in clause <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(1)(d)(iii)(E) of these Regulations</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>The holder of a position that is designated as an authorization officer for the purpose of these Regulations for Prince Edward Island in a written agreement between the governments of Canada and Prince Edward Island related to the administration of these Regulations that is published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the absence of such an agreement, Manager, Wastewater Section, Environmental Stewardship Branch, Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry morerows="2" colsep="0">8</entry><entry rowheader="yes" morerows="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Saskatchewan</entry><entry colsep="0">Her Majesty in right of Canada, another federal body or an Aboriginal organization referred to in clause <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(1)(d)(iii)(D) of these Regulations</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Manager, Wastewater Section</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>Environment Stewardship Branch</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Her Majesty in right of Saskatchewan or another Saskatchewan body or municipality or another local authority in Saskatchewan</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>The holder of a position that is designated as an authorization officer for the purpose of these Regulations for Saskatchewan in a written agreement between the governments of Canada and Saskatchewan related to the administration of these Regulations that is published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the absence of such an agreement, Manager, Wastewater Section, Environmental Stewardship Branch, Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Entity referred to in clause <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(1)(d)(iii)(E) of these Regulations</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>The holder of a position that is designated as an authorization officer for the purpose of these Regulations for Saskatchewan in a written agreement between the governments of Canada and Saskatchewan related to the administration of these Regulations that is published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the absence of such an agreement, Manager, Wastewater Section, Environmental Stewardship Branch, Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry morerows="2" colsep="0">9</entry><entry rowheader="yes" morerows="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Alberta</entry><entry colsep="0">Her Majesty in right of Canada, another federal body or an Aboriginal organization referred to in clause <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(1)(d)(iii)(D) of these Regulations</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Manager, Wastewater Section</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>Environment Stewardship Branch</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Her Majesty in right of Alberta or another Alberta body or municipality or another local authority in Alberta</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>The holder of a position that is designated as an authorization officer for the purpose of these Regulations for Alberta in a written agreement between the governments of Canada and Alberta related to the administration of these Regulations that is published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the absence of such an agreement, Manager, Wastewater Section, Environmental Stewardship Branch, Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Entity referred to in clause <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(1)(d)(iii)(E) of these Regulations</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>The holder of a position that is designated as an authorization officer for the purpose of these Regulations for Alberta in a written agreement between the governments of Canada and Alberta related to the administration of these Regulations that is published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the absence of such an agreement, Manager, Wastewater Section, Environmental Stewardship Branch, Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry morerows="2" colsep="0">10</entry><entry rowheader="yes" morerows="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Newfoundland and Labrador</entry><entry colsep="0">Her Majesty in right of Canada, another federal body or an Aboriginal organization referred to in clause <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(1)(d)(iii)(D) of these Regulations</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Manager, Wastewater Section</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>Environment Stewardship Branch</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Her Majesty in right of Newfoundland and Labrador or another Newfoundland and Labrador body or municipality or another local authority in Newfoundland and Labrador</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>The holder of a position that is designated as an authorization officer for the purpose of these Regulations for Newfoundland and Labrador in a written agreement between the governments of Canada and Newfoundland and Labrador related to the administration of these Regulations that is published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the absence of such an agreement, Manager, Wastewater Section, Environmental Stewardship Branch, Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Entity referred to in clause <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(1)(d)(iii)(E) of these Regulations</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>The holder of a position that is designated as an authorization officer for the purpose of these Regulations for Newfoundland and Labrador in a written agreement between the governments of Canada and Newfoundland and Labrador related to the administration of these Regulations that is published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the absence of such an agreement, Manager, Wastewater Section, Environmental Stewardship Branch, Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></entry></row><row><entry morerows="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0">11</entry><entry rowheader="yes" morerows="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0">Yukon</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Her Majesty in right of Canada, another federal body or an Aboriginal organization referred to in clause <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(1)(d)(iii)(D) of these Regulations</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Manager, Wastewater Section</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>Environment Stewardship Branch</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Government of Yukon or another Yukon body or municipality or another local authority in Yukon</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>The holder of a position that is designated as an authorization officer for the purpose of these Regulations for Yukon in a written agreement between the governments of Canada and Yukon related to the administration of these Regulations that is published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the absence of such an agreement, Manager, Wastewater Section, Environmental Stewardship Branch, Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Entity referred to in clause <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(1)(d)(iii)(E) of these Regulations</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>The holder of a position that is designated as an authorization officer for the purpose of these Regulations for Yukon in a written agreement between the governments of Canada and Yukon related to the administration of these Regulations that is published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the absence of such an agreement, Manager, Wastewater Section, Environmental Stewardship Branch, Department of the Environment (Canada)</Text></Provision></entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Schedule><Schedule><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 2</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section <XRefInternal>4</XRefInternal>, subsections <XRefInternal>18</XRefInternal>(1), <XRefInternal>24</XRefInternal>(2), <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1) and <XRefInternal>26</XRefInternal>(2))</OriginatingRef><TitleText>System of Points — Final Discharge Point</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><RegulationPiece><Section><MarginalNote>Definitions</MarginalNote><Label>1</Label><Text>The following definitions apply in this Schedule.</Text><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>bulk flow ratio</DefinedTermEn> means the ratio of the average rate of flow of a watercourse during a year to the average rate of flow of effluent that is deposited in that watercourse during that year. (<DefinedTermFr>coefficient de débit brut</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>marine port waters</DefinedTermEn> means the waters of a well-flushing sea port. (<DefinedTermFr>eaux d’un port maritime</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>open marine waters</DefinedTermEn>, in relation to a final discharge point, means salt waters in an area defined by an arc of 135° extending 20 km from the point of entry in relation to the final discharge point, if there is no land within that area. (<DefinedTermFr>eaux libres en milieu marin</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><TableGroup pointsize="8" topmarginspacing="10"><Caption position="over">TABLE</Caption><table frame="topbot"><tgroup cols="4"><colspec colname="COLSPEC1" colwidth="15.47*" /><colspec colname="1" colwidth="62.05*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="52.90*" /><colspec colname="3" colwidth="32.08*" /><thead><row rowsep="1" topdouble="yes"><entry morerows="1" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Item</entry><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 1</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 2</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 3</entry></row><row rowsep="0" height="10pt"><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Conditions and Water</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Criteria</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Points</entry></row></thead><tbody><row rowsep="0"><entry morerows="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1</entry><entry rowheader="yes" colname="1" morerows="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Average daily volume of effluent, expressed in m<Sup>3</Sup>, deposited during the period of 12 consecutive months referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>24</XRefInternal>(1) of these Regulations upon which the application is based</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>&gt; 100 and ≤ 500</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">5 points</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>&gt; 500 and ≤ 2 500</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">10 points</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>&gt; 2 500 and ≤ 17 500</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">15 points</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(d)</Label><Text>&gt; 17 500 and ≤ 50 000</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">25 points</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(e)</Label><Text>&gt; 50 000</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">35 points</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">2</entry><entry rowheader="yes" colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">The average carbonaceous biochemical oxygen demand (CBOD<Sub>A</Sub>) due to the quantity of CBOD matter in the effluent and the average concentration of suspended solids (SS<Sub>A</Sub>) in the effluent, both expressed in mg/L, during the period of 12 consecutive months referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>24</XRefInternal>(1) of these Regulations upon which the application is based</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">(CBOD<Sub>A</Sub> + SS<Sub>A</Sub>)/5</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">points as per formula in column 2</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry morerows="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0">3</entry><entry rowheader="yes" colname="1" morerows="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">If, during the period of 12 consecutive months referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>24</XRefInternal>(1) of these Regulations upon which the application is based, chlorine, or one of its compounds, was used in the treatment of wastewater in the wastewater system, as applicable, paragraph (a) or (b) of Column 2</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>average concentration of total residual chlorine in the effluent deposited via the final discharge point is &gt; 0.02 mg/L</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">10 points</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>effluent is not dechlorinated before it is deposited</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">10 points</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">4</entry><entry rowheader="yes" colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">The maximum concentration of un-ionized ammonia, expressed in mg/L as nitrogen (N), in the effluent deposited during the period of 12 consecutive months referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>24</XRefInternal>(1) of these Regulations upon which the application is based</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">≥ 1.25 at 15°C ± 1°C</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">20 points</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry morerows="6" colsep="0" rowsep="0">5</entry><entry rowheader="yes" colname="1" morerows="6" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Water where effluent is deposited via the final discharge point (highest value that applies)</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>open marine waters</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">5 points</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>marine port waters</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">10 points</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>lake, natural wetland, reservoir, estuary, enclosed bay</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">20 points</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(d)</Label><Text>watercourse with bulk flow ratio &gt;100</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">15 points</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(e)</Label><Text>watercourse with bulk flow ratio ≥10 and ≤100</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">20 points</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(f)</Label><Text>watercourse with bulk flow ratio &lt;10</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">25 points</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(g)</Label><Text>shellfish harvesting area within 500 m of the point of entry where effluent is deposited in the water via the final discharge point</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">20 points</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Section></RegulationPiece></Schedule><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 3</Label><OriginatingRef>(Subsections <XRefInternal>24</XRefInternal>(2), <XRefInternal>25</XRefInternal>(1) and <XRefInternal>26</XRefInternal>(2))</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><TableGroup pointsize="8" topmarginspacing="10"><table frame="topbot"><title>System of Points — Combined Sewer Overflow Points</title><tgroup cols="4"><colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="16.75*" /><colspec colname="1" colwidth="67.63*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="60.90*" /><colspec colname="3" colwidth="31.91*" /><thead><row rowsep="1" topdouble="yes"><entry morerows="1" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Item</entry><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 1</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 2</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 3</entry></row><row rowsep="0" height="10pt"><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="top">Factors</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="top">Criteria</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="top">Points</entry></row></thead><tbody><row rowsep="0"><entry morerows="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0">1</entry><entry rowheader="yes" colname="1" morerows="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">The ratio — during the period of 12 consecutive months referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>24</XRefInternal>(1) of these Regulations upon which the application is based — of the estimated average dry weather flow that circulates in the combined sewer at the overflow point to the estimated average dry weather flow that is deposited via the final discharge point, expressed as a percentage</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>≥ 50%</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">35 points</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>≥ 25% and &lt; 50%</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">25 points</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>≥ 10% and &lt; 25%</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">15 points</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(d)</Label><Text>&lt; 10%</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">10 points</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry morerows="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0">2</entry><entry rowheader="yes" morerows="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">The number of deposits via the overflow point during the period of 12 consecutive months referred to in subsection <XRefInternal>24</XRefInternal>(1) of these Regulations upon which the application is based</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>&gt; 25 deposits</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">35 points</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>&gt; 15 deposits and ≤ 25 deposits</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">25 points</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>&gt; 5 deposits and ≤ 15 deposits</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">15 points</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(d)</Label><Text>5 deposits or less</Text></Provision></entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">5 points</entry></row><row><entry morerows="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0">3</entry><entry rowheader="yes" morerows="2" colsep="0" rowsep="1">Water where effluent is deposited via each overflow point (the sum of points for all that apply)</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>shellfish harvesting area within 500 m of any point of entry where effluent is deposited in the water via the overflow point</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">20 points</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>an area where an aquatic species that is a protected species frequents or is found, or that is a fish spawning area is, within 500 m of any point of entry where effluent is deposited in the water via the overflow point</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">10 points</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>lake, natural wetland, reservoir, estuary, or enclosed bay</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">10 points</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Schedule><Schedule><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 4</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section <XRefInternal>30</XRefInternal>)</OriginatingRef><TitleText>Transitional Authorization</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>[<Emphasis style="italic">Name and address of owner or operator</Emphasis>]</Text><TableGroup pointsize="9" topmarginspacing="4"><table frame="all"><tgroup cols="1"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="16.90*" /><tbody><row rowsep="1" height="20pt"><entry colsep="0">Name of owner:</entry></row><row rowsep="1" valign="top" height="20pt"><entry colsep="0">Address of owner:</entry></row><row valign="top" height="20pt"><entry colsep="0">Name of operator:</entry></row><row valign="top" height="20pt"><entry colsep="0">Address of operator:</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" bottommarginspacing="48"><Text>in respect of [<Emphasis style="italic">name and address of wastewater system</Emphasis>]</Text><TableGroup pointsize="9" topmarginspacing="4"><table frame="all"><tgroup cols="1"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="16.90*" /><tbody><row rowsep="1" height="20pt"><entry colsep="0">Name of wastewater system:</entry></row><row valign="top" height="20pt"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Address of wastewater system:</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>is (are) hereby authorized as of January 1, 2015 to deposit effluent that contains the deleterious substances set out below until [<Emphasis style="italic">expiry date</Emphasis>]<FootnoteRef idref="footnotestar">*</FootnoteRef><Leader leader="solid" length="6pc" /> from [<Emphasis style="italic">identify final discharge point and, in the case of a fictional consolidated wastewater system, identify the final discharge point for each of the original wastewater systems</Emphasis>] <Leader leader="solid" length="6pc" />.</Text><TableGroup pointsize="9" topmarginspacing="4"><table frame="all"><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="27.20*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="31.43*" /><colspec colname="3" colwidth="34.87*" /><thead><row><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="bottom"><Emphasis style="bold">Deleterious Substance</Emphasis></entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" valign="bottom"><Emphasis style="bold">Average Concentration over the Calendar Year, Quarter or Month</Emphasis></entry><entry rowsep="1" align="center" valign="bottom"><Emphasis style="bold">Maximum Concentration over the Calendar Year, Quarter or Month</Emphasis></entry></row></thead><tbody><row topdouble="yes"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1">CBOD matter</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1">mg/L of carbonaceous biochemical oxygen demand</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1">not applicable</entry></row><row><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1">suspended solids (SS)</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1">mg/L</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1">not applicable</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colname="1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">un-ionized ammonia (NH<Sub>3</Sub>)</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">not applicable</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">mg/L, as nitrogen (N) at 15°C ± 1°C</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>is (are) authorized as of [<Emphasis style="italic">January 1, 2015</Emphasis> or <Emphasis style="italic">January 1, 2021</Emphasis>] <Leader leader="solid" length="6pc" /> to deposit effluent whose average concentration of total residual chlorine does not exceed 0.02 mg/L until [<Emphasis style="italic">expiry date</Emphasis>]<FootnoteRef idref="footnotestar">*</FootnoteRef><Leader leader="solid" length="6pc" /> from [<Emphasis style="italic">identify final discharge point and, in the case of a fictional consolidated wastewater system, identify the final discharge point for each of the original wastewater systems</Emphasis>] <Leader leader="solid" length="6pc" />. [<Emphasis style="italic">if chlorine, or one of its compounds, was used in the treatment of wastewater in the wastewater system</Emphasis>]</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>IMPORTANT: Please refer to section <XRefInternal>28</XRefInternal> of these Regulations for the conditions related to this authorization and section <XRefInternal>29</XRefInternal> of these Regulations for the compliance obligations for this authorization. In addition, please note that this authorization may be revoked under section <XRefInternal>32</XRefInternal> of these Regulations.</Text><Footnote id="footnotestar" placement="section" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>This authorization may expire in accordance with section <XRefInternal>33</XRefInternal> of these Regulations on a date earlier than the date indicated above as the expiry date.</Text></Footnote></Provision><TableGroup pointsize="9" topmarginspacing="4"><table frame="none"><tgroup cols="2"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="20.84*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="14.87*" /><tbody><row height="15pt"><entry namest="1" nameend="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0">Authorization Officer:</entry></row><row height="15pt"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>[<Emphasis style="italic">Signature</Emphasis>]</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="12" bottommarginspacing="12"><Text>[<Emphasis style="italic">Name</Emphasis>]</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>[<Emphasis style="italic">Title</Emphasis>]</Text></Provision></entry><entry rowsep="0">Date:</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Provision></Schedule><Schedule><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 5</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section <XRefInternal>39</XRefInternal>)</OriginatingRef><TitleText>Temporary Authorization To Deposit Effluent That Contains Un-Ionized Ammonia</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>[<Emphasis style="italic">Name and address of owner or operator</Emphasis>]</Text><TableGroup pointsize="9" topmarginspacing="4"><table frame="all"><tgroup cols="1"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="16.90*" /><tbody><row rowsep="1" height="20pt"><entry colsep="0">Name of owner:</entry></row><row rowsep="1" height="20pt"><entry colsep="0">Address of owner:</entry></row><row rowsep="1" valign="top" height="20pt"><entry colsep="0">Name of operator:</entry></row><row valign="top" height="20pt"><entry colsep="0">Address of operator:</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" bottommarginspacing="48"><Text>in respect of [<Emphasis style="italic">name and address of wastewater system</Emphasis>]</Text><TableGroup pointsize="9" topmarginspacing="4"><table frame="all"><tgroup cols="1"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="16.90*" /><tbody><row rowsep="1" height="20pt"><entry colsep="0">Name of wastewater system:</entry></row><row valign="top" height="20pt"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Address of wastewater system:</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>is (are) authorized, as of [<Emphasis style="italic">date</Emphasis>] <Leader leader="solid" length="6pc" />, to deposit effluent that contains un-ionized ammonia until [<Emphasis style="italic">date</Emphasis>] <Leader leader="solid" length="6pc" /> from [<Emphasis style="italic">identify final discharge point</Emphasis>] <Leader leader="solid" length="6pc" /> if the concentration of un-ionized ammonia in the water at any point that is 100 m from the point of entry where effluent is deposited in that water via the final discharge point is less than or equal to 0.016 mg/L, expressed as nitrogen (N).</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>IMPORTANT: Please refer to section <XRefInternal>38</XRefInternal> of these Regulations for the compliance obligations for this authorization. In addition, please note that this authorization may be revoked under section <XRefInternal>42</XRefInternal> of the Regulations.</Text><TableGroup pointsize="9" topmarginspacing="4"><table frame="none"><tgroup cols="2"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="20.81*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="14.90*" /><tbody><row height="15pt"><entry namest="1" nameend="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0">Authorization Officer:</entry></row><row height="15pt"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>[<Emphasis style="italic">Signature</Emphasis>]</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="12" bottommarginspacing="12"><Text>[<Emphasis style="italic">Name</Emphasis>]</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>[<Emphasis style="italic">Title</Emphasis>]</Text></Provision></entry><entry rowsep="0">Date:</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Provision></Provision></Schedule><Schedule><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 6</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section <XRefInternal>46</XRefInternal>)</OriginatingRef><TitleText>Temporary Bypass Authorization</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>[<Emphasis style="italic">Name and address of owner or operator</Emphasis>]</Text><TableGroup pointsize="9" topmarginspacing="4"><table frame="all"><tgroup cols="1"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="16.90*" /><tbody><row rowsep="1" height="20pt"><entry colsep="0">Name of owner:</entry></row><row rowsep="1" height="20pt"><entry colsep="0">Address of owner:</entry></row><row rowsep="1" valign="top" height="20pt"><entry colsep="0">Name of operator:</entry></row><row valign="top" height="20pt"><entry colsep="0">Address of operator:</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" bottommarginspacing="48"><Text>in respect of [<Emphasis style="italic">name and address of wastewater system</Emphasis>]</Text><TableGroup pointsize="9" topmarginspacing="4"><table frame="all"><tgroup cols="1"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="16.90*" /><tbody><row rowsep="1" height="20pt"><entry colsep="0">Name of wastewater system:</entry></row><row valign="top" height="20pt"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Address of wastewater system:</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>is (are) authorized, as of [<Emphasis style="italic">date</Emphasis>] <Leader leader="solid" length="6pc" /> for [<Emphasis style="italic">number of hours</Emphasis>] <Leader leader="solid" length="6pc" /> until [<Emphasis style="italic">date</Emphasis>] <Leader leader="solid" length="6pc" /> to deposit effluent from [<Emphasis style="italic">identify discharge point</Emphasis>] <Leader leader="solid" length="6pc" />.</Text><TableGroup pointsize="9" topmarginspacing="4"><table frame="none"><tgroup cols="2"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="20.81*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="14.90*" /><tbody><row height="15pt"><entry namest="1" nameend="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0">Authorization Officer:</entry></row><row height="15pt"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>[<Emphasis style="italic">Signature</Emphasis>]</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" topmarginspacing="12" bottommarginspacing="12"><Text>[<Emphasis style="italic">Name</Emphasis>]</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>[<Emphasis style="italic">Title</Emphasis>]</Text></Provision></entry><entry rowsep="0">Date:</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Provision></Schedule></Regulation>