<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2002-222</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2002</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>6</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2006</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>17</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">FISHERIES ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Metal and Diamond Mining Effluent Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2002-987</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>2002</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>6</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Fisheries and Oceans, pursuant to subsections 34(2), 36(5) and 38(9) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Fisheries Act</XRefExternal>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Metal Mining Effluent Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 1</Label><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The following definitions apply in these Regulations.</Text><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Fisheries Act</XRefExternal>. (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>acute lethality test</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>acutely lethal</DefinedTermEn>, in respect of an effluent, means that the effluent at 100% concentration kills</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>more than 50% of the rainbow trout subjected to it for a period of 96 hours, when tested in accordance with the acute lethality test set out in section 14.1; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>more than 50% of the threespine stickleback subjected to it for a period of 96 hours, when tested in accordance with the acute lethality test set out in section 14.2. (<DefinedTermFr>létalité aiguë</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>acutely lethal effluent</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>authorization officer</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>commercial operation</DefinedTermEn>, in respect of a mine, means an average rate of production equal to or greater than 10% of the design-rated capacity of the mine over a period of 90 consecutive days. (<DefinedTermFr>exploitation commerciale</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>composite sample</DefinedTermEn> means</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a quantity of effluent consisting of not less than three equal volumes or three volumes proportionate to flow that have been collected at approximately equal time intervals over a sampling period of not less than seven hours and not more than 24 hours; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a quantity of effluent collected continuously at a constant rate or at a rate proportionate to the rate of flow of the effluent over a sampling period of not less than seven hours and not more than 24 hours. (<DefinedTermFr>échantillon composite</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Daphnia magna monitoring test</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>deleterious substance</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>diamond mine</DefinedTermEn> means any work or undertaking that is designed or is used, or has been used, in connection with a mining or milling activity to produce a diamond or an ore from which a diamond may be produced. It includes any cleared or disturbed area that is adjacent to such a work or undertaking. (<DefinedTermFr>mine de diamants</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>effluent</DefinedTermEn> means any of the following:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>hydrometallurgical facility effluent, milling facility effluent, mine water effluent, tailings impoundment area effluent, treatment pond effluent or treatment facility effluent other than effluent from a sewage treatment facility; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any seepage or surface runoff containing any deleterious substance that flows over, through or out of the site of a mine. (<DefinedTermFr>effluent</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>final discharge point</DefinedTermEn>, in respect of an effluent, means an identifiable discharge point of a mine beyond which the operator of the mine no longer exercises control over the quality of the effluent. (<DefinedTermFr>point de rejet final</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>grab sample</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>hydrometallurgical facility effluent</DefinedTermEn> means effluent from the acidic leaching, solution concentration and recovery of metals by means of aqueous chemical methods, tailings slurries, and all other effluents deposited from a hydrometallurgical facility. (<DefinedTermFr>effluent d’installations d’hydrométallurgie</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>hydrometallurgy</DefinedTermEn> means the production of a metal by means of aqueous chemical methods for acidic leaching, solution concentration and recovery of metals from metal-bearing minerals other than metal-bearing minerals that have been thermally pre-treated or blended with metal-bearing minerals that have been thermally pre-treated. (<DefinedTermFr>hydrométallurgie</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>metal mine</DefinedTermEn> means any work or undertaking that is designed or is used, or has been used, in connection with a mining, milling or hydrometallurgical activity to produce a metal or a metal concentrate or an ore from which a metal or a metal concentrate may be produced, as well as any cleared or disturbed area that is adjacent to such a work or undertaking. It includes any work or undertaking, such as a smelter, pelletizing plant, sintering plant, refinery or acid plant, if its effluent is combined with the effluent from a mining, milling or hydrometallurgical activity whose purpose is to produce a metal or a metal concentrate or an ore from which a metal or a metal concentrate may be produced. (<DefinedTermFr>mine de métaux</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>milling</DefinedTermEn> means any of the following activities for the purpose of producing a diamond, metal or metal concentrate:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the crushing or grinding of ore or kimberlite;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the processing of uranium ore or uranium enriched solution; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the processing of tailings. (<DefinedTermFr>préparation du minerai</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>milling facility effluent</DefinedTermEn> means tailing slurries, heap leaching effluent, solution mining effluent and all other effluent deposited from a milling facility. (<DefinedTermFr>effluent d’installations de préparation du minerai</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>mine</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>mine under development</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>mine water effluent</DefinedTermEn> means, in respect of mining activities, water that is pumped from or flows out of any underground works, solution chambers or open pits. (<DefinedTermFr>effluent d’eau de mine</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>monthly mean concentration</DefinedTermEn> means the average value of the concentrations measured in all composite or grab samples collected from each final discharge point during each month when a deleterious substance is deposited. (<DefinedTermFr>concentration moyenne mensuelle</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>new mine</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>operations area</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>operator</DefinedTermEn> means any person who operates, has control or custody of or is in charge of a mine. (<DefinedTermFr>exploitant</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>placer mining</DefinedTermEn> means a mining operation that extracts minerals or metals from stream sediments by gravity or magnetic separation. (<DefinedTermFr>exploitation des placers</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>recognized closed mine</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Reference Method EPS 1/RM/10</DefinedTermEn> means <XRefExternal reference-type="standard">Biological Test Method: Reference Method for Determining Acute Lethality Using Threespine Stickleback</XRefExternal>, published in December 2017 by the Department of the Environment, as amended from time to time. (<DefinedTermFr>méthode de référence SPE 1/RM/10</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Reference Method EPS 1/RM/13</DefinedTermEn> means <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Biological Test Method: Reference Method for Determining Acute Lethality of Effluents to Rainbow Trout</XRefExternal> (Reference Method EPS 1/RM/13), July 1990, published by the Department of the Environment, as amended in December 2000, and as may be further amended from time to time. (<DefinedTermFr>méthode de référence SPE 1/RM/13</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Reference Method EPS 1/RM/14</DefinedTermEn> means <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Biological Test Method: Reference Method for Determining Acute Lethality of Effluents to Daphnia magna</XRefExternal> (Reference Method EPS 1/RM/14), July 1990, published by the Department of the Environment, as amended in December 2000, and as may be further amended from time to time. (<DefinedTermFr>méthode de référence SPE 1/RM/14</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>reopened mine</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>surface drainage</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>suspended solids</DefinedTermEn> means any solid matter contained in an effluent that is retained on a 1.5 micron pore filter paper when the effluent is tested in compliance with the analytical requirements set out in Table 1 of Schedule 3. (<DefinedTermFr>matières en suspension</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>tailings impoundment area</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2006-239, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>total suspended solids</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>transitional authorization</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>treatment facility effluent</DefinedTermEn> means water from a polishing pond, treatment pond, settling pond or water treatment plant or from any mine effluent treatment facility. (<DefinedTermFr>effluent d’installations de traitement</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2006-239, s. 1; SOR/2009-156, s. 1; SOR/2012-22, s. 1; SOR/2018-99, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>These Regulations apply in respect of the following mines:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>metal mines that, at any time on or after June 6, 2002,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>exceed an effluent flow rate of 50 m<Sup>3</Sup> per day, based on the effluent deposited from all the final discharge points of the mine, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>deposit a deleterious substance in any water or place referred to in subsection 36(3) of the Act; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>diamond mines that, at any time on or after June 1, 2018,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>exceed an effluent flow rate of 50 m<Sup>3</Sup> per day, based on the effluent deposited from all the final discharge points of the mine, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>deposit a deleterious substance in any water or place referred to in subsection 36(3) of the Act.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>However, these Regulations do not apply in respect of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>placer mining;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a metal mine that stopped commercial operation before June 6, 2002, unless it returns to commercial operation on or after that date; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a diamond mine that stopped commercial operation before June 1, 2018, unless it returns to commercial operation on or after that date.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Despite subsection (1), sections 4 to 31 do not apply in respect of a mine that is a recognized closed mine under subsection 32(2) unless it returns to commercial operation, in which case it ceases to be a recognized closed mine.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2012-22, s. 2; SOR/2018-99, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Prescribed Deleterious Substances</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>For the purpose of the definition <DefinitionRef>deleterious substance</DefinitionRef> in subsection 34(1) of the Act, the following substances or classes of substances are prescribed as deleterious substances:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>arsenic;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>copper;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>cyanide;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>lead;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>nickel;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>zinc;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>suspended solids; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>radium 226.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2018-99, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Authority to Deposit in Water or Place Referred to in Subsection 36(3) of Act</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>For the purposes of paragraph 36(4)(b) of the Act, the owner or operator of a mine is authorized to deposit, or to permit the deposit of, an effluent containing any deleterious substance that is prescribed in section 3 in any water or place referred to in subsection 36(3) of the Act if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the concentration of the deleterious substance in the effluent does not exceed the maximum authorized concentrations that are set out in columns 2, 3 and 4 of Schedule 4;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the pH of the effluent is equal to or greater than 6.0 but is not greater than 9.5; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the effluent is not acutely lethal.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The authority in subsection (1) is conditional on the owner or operator complying with sections 6 to 27.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2018-99, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Authority to Deposit in Tailings Impoundment Areas</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Despite section 4, the owner or operator of a mine may deposit or permit the deposit of waste rock, acutely lethal effluent or effluent of any pH and containing any concentration of a deleterious substance that is prescribed in section 3 into a tailings impoundment area that is either</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a water or place set out in Schedule 2; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a disposal area that is confined by anthropogenic or natural structures or by both, other than a disposal area that is, or is part of, a natural water body that is frequented by fish.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The authority in subsection (1) is conditional on the owner or operator complying with sections 7 to 28.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>For the purposes of this section, any acutely lethal effluent is prescribed as a deleterious substance.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2006-239, s. 2; SOR/2018-99, s. 5.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 2</Label><TitleText>Conditions Governing Authority to Deposit</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><Label>DIVISION 1</Label><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Prohibition on Diluting Effluent</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine shall not combine effluent with water or any other effluent for the purpose of diluting effluent before it is deposited.</Text></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Environmental Effects Monitoring</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>7</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine shall conduct environmental effects monitoring studies in accordance with the requirements and within the periods set out in Schedule 5.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The studies shall be conducted using documented and validated methods, and their results interpreted and reported on in accordance with generally accepted standards of good scientific practice at the time that the studies are conducted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The owner or operator shall record the results of the studies and submit to the Minister of the Environment, in accordance with the requirements set out in Schedule 5, the reports and information required by that Schedule.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2006-239, s. 3; SOR/2018-99, s. 6.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Identifying Information</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>8</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine shall submit in writing to the Minister of the Environment the information referred to in subsection (2) not later than 60 days after the day on which any of the following occur:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the mine becomes subject to these Regulations;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>ownership of the mine is transferred; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the mine returns to commercial operation after it has become a recognized closed mine.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The information that shall be submitted is</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the name and address of both the owner and the operator of the mine;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the name and address of any parent company of the owner and the operator; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the design-rated capacity of the mine, expressed as tonnes per year, and a description and rationale of how the design-rated capacity was determined.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The owner or operator shall submit in writing to the Minister of the Environment any change in the information not later than 60 days after the change occurs.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2018-99, ss. 7, 36.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Final Discharge Points</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>9</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine shall identify each final discharge point and submit in writing to the Minister of the Environment, not later than 60 days after the day on which the mine becomes subject to these Regulations, the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>plans, specifications and a general description of each final discharge point together with its location by latitude and longitude;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a description of how each final discharge point is designed and maintained in respect of the deposit of deleterious substances; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the name of the receiving body of water, if there is a name.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2006-239, s. 4; SOR/2018-99, ss. 8, 36.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>10</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine shall submit in writing to the Minister of the Environment the information required by section 9, for</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any final discharge point that is identified by an inspector, and that was not identified as required by section 9, within 30 days after the discharge point is identified; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>each new final discharge point, at least 60 days before depositing effluent from that new final discharge point.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The owner or operator shall submit in writing to the Minister of the Environment the information on any proposed change to a final discharge point at least 60 days before the change is to be made.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2018-99, s. 36.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Monitoring Equipment Information</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>11</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine shall keep records relating to effluent monitoring equipment that contain</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a description of the equipment and, if applicable, the manufacturer’s specifications and the year and model number of the equipment; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the results of the calibration tests of the equipment.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><Label>DIVISION 2</Label><TitleText>Effluent Monitoring Conditions</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Deleterious Substance and pH Testing</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>12</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine shall, not less than once per week and at least 24 hours apart, collect from each final discharge point a grab sample or composite sample of effluent and record the pH of the sample at the time of its collection and record, without delay after collecting the sample, the concentrations of the deleterious substances prescribed in section 3.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Testing conducted under subsection (1) shall comply with the analytical requirements set out in Table 1 of Schedule 3 and shall be done in accordance with generally accepted standards of good scientific practice at the time of the sampling using documented and validated methods.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Despite subsection (1), the owner or operator of a mine is not required to collect samples for the purpose of recording the concentrations of cyanide if cyanide has never been used as a process reagent at the mine.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2006-239, s. 5; SOR/2018-99, s. 9.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>13</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine may reduce the frequency of conducting tests relating to the concentrations of arsenic, copper, cyanide, lead, nickel or zinc at a final discharge point to not less than once in each calendar quarter, each test being conducted at least one month apart, if that substance’s monthly mean concentration at that final discharge point is less than 10% of the value set out in column 2 of Schedule 4 for 12 consecutive months.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine, other than an uranium mine, may reduce the frequency of conducting tests relating to the concentration of radium 226 at a final discharge point to not less than once in each calendar quarter, each test being conducted at least one month apart, if the concentration of radium 226 at that final discharge point is less than 0.037 Bq/L for 10 consecutive weeks.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine shall increase the frequency of conducting tests relating to the concentration of a deleterious substance at a final discharge point to the frequency prescribed in section 12</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in the case of a deleterious substance mentioned in subsection (1), if that substance’s monthly mean concentration at that final discharge point is equal to or greater than 10% of the value set out in column 2 of Schedule 4; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the case of radium 226, if the concentration of radium 226 at that final discharge point is equal to or greater than 0.037 Bq/L.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine shall increase the frequency of conducting tests relating to the concentration of a deleterious substance at all final discharge points to the frequency prescribed in section 12 for all the substances mentioned in subsections (1) and (2) if the owner or operator</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>fails to perform a test required under those subsections in accordance with the prescribed frequency; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>fails to submit a report required under subsection 21(1) or section 22 within the prescribed time.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>If the owner or operator of a mine changes the location of a final discharge point, the owner or operator shall increase the frequency of conducting tests relating to the concentration of a deleterious substance at that final discharge point to the frequency prescribed in section 12 for all the deleterious substances mentioned in subsections (1) and (2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(6)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine who reduces the frequency of conducting tests under subsection (1) or (2) shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>notify the Minister of the Environment, in writing, at least 30 days in advance, of that fact;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>select and record the sampling dates not less than 30 days in advance of collecting the samples of effluent; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>collect the sample on the selected day except if, owing to unforeseen circumstances, they cannot sample on that day, in which case, they shall do so as soon as practicable after that day.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2006-239, s. 6; SOR/2018-99, s. 9.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Acute Lethality Testing</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="4"><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>14</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to section 15, the owner or operator of a mine shall collect, once a month, a grab sample of effluent from each final discharge point and determine whether the effluent is acutely lethal by conducting acute lethality tests on aliquots of each effluent sample in accordance with sections 14.1 and 14.2.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>For the purposes of subsection (1), the owner or operator of a mine</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>shall select and record the sampling date not less than 30 days in advance of collecting the grab sample;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>shall collect the sample on the selected day except if, owing to unforeseen circumstances, they cannot sample on that day, in which case, they shall do so as soon as practicable after that day; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>shall collect the grab samples not less than 15 days apart.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>When collecting a grab sample of effluent for the purposes of subsection (1), the owner or operator of a mine shall collect a sufficient volume of effluent to enable the owner or operator to comply with paragraph 15(1)(a).</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2006-239, s. 7; SOR/2011-92, s. 4; SOR/2012-22, s. 3; SOR/2018-99, s. 10.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Acute Lethality Test — Rainbow Trout</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>14.1</Label><Text>Unless the salinity value of the effluent is equal to or greater than ten parts per thousand and the effluent is deposited into marine waters, the owner or operator of a mine shall determine whether the effluent is acutely lethal by conducting an acute lethality test in accordance with the procedures set out in section 5 or 6 of Reference Method EPS 1/RM/13.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2018-99, s. 10.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Acute Lethality Test — Threespine Stickleback</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>14.2</Label><Text>If the salinity value of the effluent is equal to or greater than ten parts per thousand and the effluent is deposited into marine waters, the owner or operator of a mine shall determine whether the effluent is acutely lethal by conducting an acute lethality test in accordance with the procedures set out in section 5 or 6 of Reference Method EPS 1/RM/10.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2018-99, s. 10.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Increased Frequency of Acute Lethality Testing</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>15</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>If an effluent sample is determined to be acutely lethal by an acute lethality test, the owner or operator of a mine shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>without delay, conduct the effluent characterization set out in subsection 4(1) of Schedule 5 on the aliquot of each grab sample collected under subsection 14(1) and record the concentrations of the deleterious substances prescribed in section 3;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>collect, from the final discharge point from which the effluent sample that was determined to be acutely lethal was collected, a grab sample twice a month and, without delay after collecting the sample, conduct the acute lethality test that determined the effluent sample to be acutely lethal on each grab sample in accordance with the procedure set out in section 6 of the applicable reference method and, if the sample is determined to be acutely lethal, then conduct the effluent characterization set out in subsection 4(1) of Schedule 5 and record the concentrations of the deleterious substances prescribed in section 3; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>collect the grab samples not less than seven days apart.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The owner or operator may resume sampling and testing at the frequency prescribed in section 14 if the effluent is determined not to be acutely lethal in three consecutive tests conducted under paragraph (1)(b).</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2006-239, s. 8; SOR/2018-99, s. 12.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Reduced Frequency of Acute Lethality Testing</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>16</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine may reduce the frequency of conducting an acute lethality test at a final discharge point to once in each calendar quarter if the effluent from that final discharge point is determined not to be acutely lethal by that acute lethality test for 12 consecutive months.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>For the purpose of determining whether that effluent is acutely lethal for the 12-month period referred to in subsection (1), the owner or operator of a mine shall use the results of the acute lethality tests conducted under subsection 14(1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine shall notify the Minister of the Environment in writing at least 30 days before the reduction of the frequency of acute lethality testing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The owner or operator who reduces the frequency of conducting acute lethality testing under subsection (1) shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>select and record the sampling date not less than 30 days in advance of collecting the grab samples; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>collect the grab samples not less than 45 days apart.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>If a grab sample is determined to be acutely lethal by an acute lethality test when the owner or operator of a mine is testing at the frequency prescribed in subsection (1), the owner or operator shall increase the frequency of conducting that test to the frequency prescribed in section 15 and conduct that test in accordance with that section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(6)</Label><Text>If the location of a final discharge point is changed, the owner or operator of a mine shall, at that final discharge point, increase the frequency of conducting all the acute lethality tests to the frequency prescribed in subsection 14(1) and conduct those tests in accordance with that subsection.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2012-22, s. 4; SOR/2018-99, s. 14.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText><Language xml:lang="la">Daphnia magna</Language> Monitoring Tests</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>17</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Unless the salinity value of the effluent is equal to or greater than four parts per thousand and the effluent is deposited into marine waters, the owner or operator of a mine shall conduct <Language xml:lang="la">Daphnia magna</Language> monitoring tests in accordance with the procedure set out in section 5 or 6 of Reference Method EPS 1/RM/14 at the same time that the acute lethality tests are conducted under section 14, 15 or 16 of these Regulations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The owner or operator shall conduct <Language xml:lang="la">Daphnia magna</Language> monitoring tests on the aliquots of each effluent sample collected for the acute lethality tests.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2018-99, s. 15.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Obligation to Record All Test Results</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>18</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine shall record without delay the data referred to in section 9.1 of Reference Method EPS 1/RM/10, section 8.1 of Reference Method EPS 1/RM/13 and section 8.1 of Reference Method EPS 1/RM/14 for all acute lethality tests and <Language xml:lang="la">Daphnia magna</Language> monitoring tests that are conducted to monitor deposits from final discharge points.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2018-99, s. 16.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Volume of Effluent</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>19</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine shall record, in cubic metres, the total monthly volume of effluent deposited from each final discharge point for each month during which there was a deposit.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The total monthly volume of effluent deposited shall be either</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>determined on the basis of the average of the flow rates, expressed in cubic metres per day, measured and calculated as follows:</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>by measuring the flow rate at the same time as samples are collected under section 12,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>by calculating the average monthly flow rate by adding the flow rate measurements taken during the month and dividing the total by the number of times the flow rate was measured, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>by multiplying the average monthly flow rate by the number of days during the month that effluent was deposited; or</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>determined by using a monitoring system that provides a continuous measure of the volume of effluent deposited.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The owner or operator shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>measure the flow rate or volume of effluent deposited by using a monitoring system that is accurate to within 15% of measured flow rate or volume; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>maintain and calibrate the monitoring system at least once in each year and record the results, as well as the date on which and the manner in which the requirement to maintain and calibrate has been met.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2006-239, s. 9; SOR/2012-22, s. 5; SOR/2018-99, s. 17.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Calculation of Monthly Mean Concentration and Loading</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>19.1</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>With respect to the deleterious substances that are contained in the effluent deposited from each final discharge point, the owner or operator of a mine shall, for each month during which there is a deposit and during which samples are collected, record the monthly mean concentration</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in mg/L for deleterious substances referred to in paragraphs 3(a) to (g); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in Bq/L for a deleterious substance referred to in paragraph 3(h).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>If the analytical result from any test conducted under section 12 or 13 is less than the method detection limit used for that test, the test result shall be considered to be equal to one half of the detection limit used for the purpose of calculating the monthly mean concentration.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2006-239, s. 9; SOR/2018-99, s. 18.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>20</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>With respect to the deleterious substances that are contained in the effluent deposited from each final discharge point, the owner or operator of a mine shall, for each month and for each calendar quarter during which there was a deposit and during which a sample is collected, record the loading</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in kg for deleterious substances referred to in paragraphs 3(a) to (g); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in MBq for a deleterious substance referred to in paragraph 3(h).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The owner or operator shall determine the loading for each month using the following formula:</Text><FormulaGroup><Formula><FormulaText>ML = C × V / 1,000</FormulaText></Formula><FormulaConnector>where</FormulaConnector><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>ML</FormulaTerm><Text>is the loading for a month;</Text></FormulaDefinition><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>C</FormulaTerm><Text>is the monthly mean concentration of the deleterious substance, recorded under section 19.1; and</Text></FormulaDefinition><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>V</FormulaTerm><Text>is the total monthly volume of effluent deposited from each final discharge point, recorded under section 19.</Text></FormulaDefinition></FormulaGroup></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The owner or operator shall determine the loading for each calendar quarter using the following formula:</Text><FormulaGroup><Formula><FormulaText>QL = C × V / 1,000</FormulaText></Formula><FormulaConnector>where</FormulaConnector><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>QL</FormulaTerm><Text>is the loading for a calendar quarter;</Text></FormulaDefinition><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>C</FormulaTerm><Text>is the mean of the monthly mean concentrations of the deleterious substance for that calendar quarter, recorded under section 19.1; and</Text></FormulaDefinition><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>V</FormulaTerm><Text>is the total volume of effluent deposited from each final discharge point during that calendar quarter, based on the sum of the total monthly volumes of effluent deposited from each final discharge point, recorded under section 19.</Text></FormulaDefinition></FormulaGroup></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2006-239, s. 9; SOR/2018-99, s. 19.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Reporting Monitoring Results</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>21</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine shall submit to the Minister of the Environment an effluent monitoring report for all tests and monitoring conducted during each calendar quarter not later than 45 days after the end of the quarter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (3), the effluent monitoring report shall include</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the data referred to in section 9.1 of Reference Method EPS 1/RM/10, section 8.1 of Reference Method EPS 1/RM/13 and section 8.1 of Reference Method EPS 1/RM/14 as required by section 18;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the concentration and monthly mean concentration of each deleterious substance prescribed in section 3 that is contained in the effluent samples collected under subsection 12(1) and the concentrations of such deleterious substances contained in the effluent samples collected under subsection 13(1) or (2);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the pH of the effluent samples as required by subsection 12(1);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>whether a composite or grab sample collection method was used for each effluent sample as required by subsection 12(1);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d.1)</Label><Text>for each month of the calendar quarter, the number of days that effluent was deposited;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the total volume of effluent deposited during each month of the reporting quarter as recorded under section 19;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>the mass loading of the deleterious substances prescribed in section 3 as recorded under section 20; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>the results of the effluent characterization conducted under paragraph 15(1)(a).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>If no effluent is deposited in a calendar quarter, the report shall only include a statement to that effect.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2006-239, s. 10; SOR/2018-99, ss. 20, 36.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>22</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine shall submit to the Minister of the Environment, not later than March 31 in each year, a report in the form set out in Schedule 6, that shall include the following:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the identifying information set out in Part 1 of that Schedule;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the effluent monitoring results for the previous calendar year, including</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>test results respecting each final discharge point, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the results of acute lethality tests; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the following information regarding non-compliance:</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>if the results of any effluent monitoring tests indicate that the maximum authorized concentrations set out in Schedule 4 were exceeded or that the pH of the effluent is less than 6.0 or greater than 9.5, the causes of that non-compliance and the remedial measures that are planned or that have been implemented, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>if the results of any acute lethality tests indicate that an effluent sample was determined to be acutely lethal, the remedial measures that are planned or that have been implemented.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2006-239, s. 11; SOR/2018-99, s. 21.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>23</Label><Text>Any report or information referred to in sections 7, 21 and 22 shall be submitted electronically in the format provided by the Department of the Environment, but the report or information shall be submitted in writing if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>no such format has been provided; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>it is, owing to circumstances beyond the control of either the owner or the operator, impracticable to submit the report or information electronically in the format provided.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2006-239, s. 11; SOR/2018-99, s. 22.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>24</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine shall notify an inspector without delay if the results of the effluent monitoring tests conducted under section 12 or 13, subsection 14(1) or section 15 or 16 indicate that</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the limits set out in Schedule 4 are being or have been exceeded;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the pH of the effluent is less than 6.0 or greater than 9.5; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>an effluent is acutely lethal.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The owner or operator shall provide a written report of the test results to the inspector within 30 days after the tests have been completed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 23]</Repealed></Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2006-239, s. 12; SOR/2018-99, s. 23.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Relief</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>25</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Any time period specified for collecting samples of effluent referred to in this Division may be extended if</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>unforeseen circumstances cause safety concerns or access problems and render the collection of samples of effluent impracticable; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the owner or operator of a mine notifies an inspector, without delay, of the circumstances and indicates when they expect to be able to collect the samples.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The owner or operator shall collect the samples of effluent without delay when the circumstances permit.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2006-239, s. 13.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><Label>DIVISION 3</Label><TitleText>Notice, Records and Other Documents</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>End of Commercial Operation Notice</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>26</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine shall notify the Minister of the Environment in writing of the day on which the mine has stopped commercial operation not later than 90 days after the end of commercial operation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The owner or operator shall notify the Minister of the Environment in writing without delay if the mine returns to commercial operation.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2018-99, s. 36.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Records, Books of Account or Other Documents</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>27</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine shall keep all records, books of account or other documents required by these Regulations at the mine for a period of not less than five years, beginning on the day on which they are made, including</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>records relating to all final discharge points, including any changes to those records;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>records relating to effluent monitoring equipment, including the calibration of that equipment;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>records relating to the data referred to in section 9.1 of Reference Method EPS 1/RM/10, section 8.1 of Reference Method EPS 1/RM/13 and section 8.1 of Reference Method EPS 1/RM/14;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>compensation plans;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>emergency response plans, including each update to the plan;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>reports on any unauthorized deposits;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>reports or other documents prepared and data collected for the purposes of environmental effects monitoring studies; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>records and reports of measurements with respect to the pH, temperature and concentration of any deleterious substance prescribed in section 3.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2018-99, s. 24.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><Label>DIVISION 4</Label><TitleText>Tailings Impoundment Areas</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Compensation Plan</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>27.1</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine shall, before depositing a deleterious substance into a tailings impoundment area that is set out in Schedule 2, submit to the Minister of the Environment a compensation plan that includes the information described in subsection (2) and obtain that Minister’s approval of the plan.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The purpose of the compensation plan is to offset the loss of fish habitat resulting from the deposit of any deleterious substance into the tailings impoundment area. It shall contain the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a description of the location of the tailings impoundment area and of fish habitat that will be affected by the deposit;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a quantitative impact assessment of the deposit on fish habitat;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a description of the measures to be taken to offset the loss of fish habitat;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a description of the measures to be taken during the planning and implementation of the compensation plan to mitigate any potential adverse effects on fish habitat that could result from the plan’s implementation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>a description of the measures to be taken to monitor the plan’s implementation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>a description of the measures to be taken to verify the extent to which the plan’s purpose has been achieved;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>the time required to implement the plan that allows for the achievement of the plan’s purpose within a reasonable time; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>an estimate of the cost of implementing each element of the plan.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine shall submit with the compensation plan an irrevocable letter of credit to cover the plan’s implementation costs, which letter of credit shall be payable upon demand on the declining balance of the implementation costs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The Minister of the Environment shall approve the compensation plan if it meets the requirements of subsection (2) and the owner or operator of a mine has complied with subsection (3).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine shall ensure that the compensation plan approved by the Minister of the Environment is implemented and, if the compensation plan’s purpose is not being achieved, the owner or operator shall inform the Minister of the Environment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(6)</Label><Text>If the compensation plan’s purpose is not being achieved, the owner or operator of a mine shall, as soon as practicable in the circumstances, identify and implement all necessary remedial measures to ensure that the purpose is achieved.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2006-239, s. 14; SOR/2018-99, s. 24.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Deposits from Tailings Impoundment Areas</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>28</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine shall deposit effluent from a tailings impoundment area only through a final discharge point that is monitored and reported on in accordance with the requirements of these Regulations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine shall comply with section 6 and the conditions prescribed in paragraphs 4(1)(a) to (c) for all effluent that exits a tailing impoundment area.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 3</Label><TitleText>Unauthorized Deposits</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>29</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 25]</Repealed></Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Emergency Response Plan</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>30</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine shall prepare an emergency response plan that describes the measures to be taken in respect of a deleterious substance within the meaning of subsection 34(1) of the Act to prevent any unauthorized deposit of such a substance or to mitigate the effects of such a deposit.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The emergency response plan shall include the following elements:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the identification of any unauthorized deposit that can reasonably be expected to occur at the mine and that can reasonably be expected to result in damage or danger to fish habitat or fish or the use by man of fish, and the identification of the damage or danger;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a description of the measures to be used to prevent, prepare for, respond to and recover from a deposit identified under paragraph (a);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a list of the individuals who are to implement the plan in the event of an unauthorized deposit, and a description of their roles and responsibilities;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the identification of the emergency response training required for each of the individuals listed under paragraph (c);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>a list of the emergency response equipment included as part of the plan, and the equipment’s location; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>alerting and notification procedures including the measures to be taken to notify members of the public who may be adversely affected by a deposit identified under paragraph (a).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The owner or operator shall complete the emergency response plan and have it available for inspection no later than 60 days after the mine becomes subject to this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The owner or operator shall update and test the emergency response plan at least once each year to ensure that the plan continues to meet the requirements of subsection (2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4.1)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine shall, each time the emergency response plan is tested, record the following information and keep the record for at least five years:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a summary of the test;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the test results; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>any modifications that are made to the plan as a consequence of the test.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4.2)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine shall ensure that a copy of the most recent version of the emergency response plan is kept at the mine in a location that is readily available to the individuals who are responsible for implementing the plan.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>If a mine has not been subject to the requirements of this section for more than one year, a new emergency response plan shall be prepared and completed no later than 60 days after the day on which the mine again becomes subject to this section.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2006-239, s. 16; SOR/2012-22, s. 6(F); SOR/2018-99, s. 26.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Reporting</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>31</Label><Text>A report required by subsection 38(7) of the Act in respect of the unauthorized deposit of a deleterious substance shall contain the following information:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the name, description and concentration of the deleterious substance deposited;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the estimated quantity of the deposit and how the estimate was achieved;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the day on which, and hour at which, the deposit occurred;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the quantity of the deleterious substance that was deposited at a place other than through a final discharge point and the identification of that place, including the location by latitude and longitude and, if applicable, the civic address;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the quantity of the deleterious substance that was deposited through a final discharge point and the identification of that discharge point;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>the name of the receiving body of water, if there is a name, and the location by latitude and longitude where the deleterious substance entered the receiving body of water;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>the results of the acute lethality tests conducted under subsection 31.1(1) or a statement indicating that acute lethality tests were not conducted but that notification was given under subsection 31.1(2);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>the circumstances of the deposit, the measures that were taken to mitigate the effects of the deposit and, if the emergency response plan was implemented, details concerning its implementation; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the measures that were taken, or that are intended to be taken, to prevent any similar occurrence of an unauthorized deposit.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2006-239, s. 17; SOR/2011-92, s. 6; SOR/2018-99, s. 27.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Acute Lethality Testing</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>31.1</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>If an unauthorized deposit of a deleterious substance occurs, the owner or operator of a mine shall, without delay, collect a grab sample of effluent at the place where the deposit occurred and determine whether the effluent is acutely lethal by conducting tests on aliquots of each effluent sample in accordance with sections 14.1 and 14.2.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Despite subsection (1), the owner or operator of a mine is not required to conduct those tests if they notify an inspector, without delay, that the deposit is an acutely lethal effluent.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2018-99, s. 27.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 4</Label><TitleText>Recognized Closed Mines</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Requirements</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>32</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>An owner or operator who intends to close a mine shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>provide written notice of that intention to the Minister of the Environment;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>maintain the mine’s rate of production at less than 10% of its design-rated capacity for a continuous period of three years starting on the day on which the written notice is received by the Minister of the Environment; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>conduct a biological monitoring study during the three-year period referred to in paragraph (b) in accordance with Division 3 of Part 2 of Schedule 5.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>If the owner or operator has complied with all of the requirements set out in paragraphs (1)(a) to (c), the mine becomes a recognized closed mine after the expiry of the three-year period referred to in subsection (1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The owner or operator shall notify the Minister of the Environment in writing at least 60 days before reopening the recognized closed mine.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The owner or operator referred to in this section shall keep at any place in Canada all records, books of account or other documents required by these Regulations for a period of not less than five years beginning on the day they are made, and shall notify the Minister of the Environment in writing of their location.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2006-239, s. 18; SOR/2018-99, ss. 28, 36.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Identifying Information</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>33</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a recognized closed mine shall submit in writing to the Minister of the Environment the information referred to in subsection (2) not later than 60 days after the day on which</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the recognized closed mine becomes subject to these Regulations; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>ownership of the recognized closed mine is transferred.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The information that shall be submitted is the name and address of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>both the owner and the operator of the recognized closed mine; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any parent company of the owner or the operator.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The owner or operator shall notify the Minister of the Environment of any change in the information not later than 60 days after the change occurs.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2018-99, s. 36.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>34</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 29]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>35</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 29]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>36</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 29]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>37</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 29]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>38</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 29]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>39</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 29]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>40</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 29]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>41</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 29]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>42</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 29]</Repealed></Text></Section></Body><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 1</Label></ScheduleFormHeading><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 30]</Repealed></Schedule><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 2</Label><OriginatingRef>(Subsections 5(1) and 27.1(1))</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><TableGroup pointsize="7" topmarginspacing="10"><table frame="topbot"><title justification="left">Tailings Impoundment Areas</title><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="60.54*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="224.98*" /><colspec colname="COLSPEC1" colwidth="434.57*" /><thead><row valign="bottom" topdouble="yes"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="bottom" /><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="bottom">Column 1</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Column 2</entry></row><row valign="bottom"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Item</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Water or Place</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Description</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Anderson Lake, Manitoba</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Anderson Lake located at 54°51′ north latitude and 100°0′ west longitude near the town of Snow Lake, Manitoba. More precisely, the area bounded by</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the contour of elevation around Anderson Lake at the 285-m level, and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the control dam built at the east end of Anderson Lake.</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Garrow Lake, Nunavut</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Garrow Lake located at 75°23′ north latitude and 97°48′ west longitude near the south end of Little Cornwallis Island, Nunavut.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">3</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">South Kemess Creek, British Columbia</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>That part of South Kemess Creek being within the watershed of that tributary of South Kemess Creek</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>extending eastwards and upstream from the centre of a tailings dam constructed at 57°1′ north latitude and 126°41′ west longitude, and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>below the crest of the dam at an elevation of 1515 m.</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">4</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Albino Lake, British Columbia</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Albino Lake located at 56°39.4′ north latitude and 130°29.4′ west longitude near the Eskay Creek Mine in British Columbia. More precisely, the area bounded by</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the contour of elevation around Albino Lake at the 1040-m level, and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the outlet of Albino Lake.</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">5</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Tom MacKay Lake, British Columbia</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Tom MacKay Lake located at 56°39′ north latitude and 130°34′ west longitude near the Eskay Creek Mine in British Columbia. More precisely, the area bounded by</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the contour of elevation around Tom MacKay Lake at the 1078-m level, and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the outlet of Tom MacKay Lake.</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">6</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Trout Pond, Newfoundland and Labrador</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Trout Pond located at 48°39′0.81882″ north latitude and 56°29′19.704984″ west longitude in west-central Newfoundland. More precisely, the area bounded by</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the contour of elevation around Trout Pond at the 270 m level, and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the outlet of Trout Pond.</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">7</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">The headwater pond of a tributary to Gill’s Pond Brook, Newfoundland and Labrador</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>The headwater pond of a tributary to Gill’s Pond Brook, located at 48°38′29.599584″ north latitude and 56°30′15.560676″ west longitude in west-central Newfoundland. More precisely, the area bounded by</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the contour of elevation around the pond at the 260 m level, and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the outlet of the pond.</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">8</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">The northwest arm of Second Portage Lake, Nunavut</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>That portion of the northwest arm of Second Portage Lake, located at 65°1′39.29″ north latitude and 96°3′43″ west longitude, approximately 80 km north of the town of Baker Lake, Nunavut. More precisely, the area bounded by</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the contour of elevation around the arm at the 146 m level, and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the dam built at the southeast end of the arm.</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">9</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Tail Lake, Nunavut</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Tail Lake, located at 68°7′25.8″ north latitude and 106°33′31.2″ west longitude, approximately 125 km southwest of the town of Cambridge Bay, Nunavut. More precisely, the area bounded by</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the contour of elevation around Tail Lake at the 33.5 m level, and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the dams built at the south and north ends of the lake.</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">10</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of Wabush Lake, Newfoundland and Labrador</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>That portion of Wabush Lake near the towns of Labrador City and Wabush in western Labrador. More precisely, the area bounded by</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the southern limit, extending from 53° north latitude, 66°50′24″ west longitude to 53° north latitude, 66°52′57″ west longitude, and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the outlet of Wabush Lake, extending from 53°09′4.7″ north latitude, 66°47′3.5″ west longitude to 53°08′57.5″ north latitude, 66°47′2.9″ west longitude.</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">11</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Flora Lake, Newfoundland and Labrador</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Flora Lake located at 52°55′ north latitude, 66°49′ west longitude, near the towns of Labrador City and Wabush in western Labrador.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">12</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed tributary stream to Flora Lake, Newfoundland and Labrador</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed tributary stream to Flora Lake, Newfoundland and Labrador. More precisely, an area extending from the mouth of the stream (52°52′9.94″ north latitude, 66°47′14.26″ west longitude) for a distance of 75 m upstream from Flora Lake.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">13</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed tributary stream to Flora Lake, Newfoundland and Labrador</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed tributary stream to Flora Lake, Newfoundland and Labrador. More precisely, an area extending from the mouth of the stream (52°52′10.70″ north latitude, 66°47′6.49″ west longitude) for a distance of 580 m upstream from Flora Lake.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">14</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed tributary stream to Flora Lake, Newfoundland and Labrador</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed tributary stream to Flora Lake, Newfoundland and Labrador. More precisely, an area extending from the mouth of the stream (52°52′57.45″ north latitude, 66°47′25.23″ west longitude) for a distance of 256 m upstream from Flora Lake.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">15</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Sandy Pond, Newfoundland and Labrador</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Sandy Pond, located at 47°25′33″ north latitude and 53°46′52″ west longitude, on the Avalon Peninsula, approximately 3 km east southeast of the town of Long Harbour-Mount Arlington Heights, Newfoundland and Labrador. More precisely, the area bounded by</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the contour of elevation around Sandy Pond at the 137 m level, and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the dams built at the north end of Sandy Pond.</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">16</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of King Richard Creek, British Columbia</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of King Richard Creek, located approximately 60 km southwest of the town of Mackenzie, British Columbia. More precisely, a 3.3 km portion of the creek extending northwards and upstream from the centre of a dam constructed at 55°06′42″ north latitude and 123°59′29″ west longitude, to the centre of a dam constructed at 55°07′52″ north latitude and 124°00′50″ west longitude.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">17</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed tributary to Alpine Lake, British Columbia</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed tributary to Alpine Lake, located approximately 60 km southwest of the town of Mackenzie, British Columbia. More precisely, a 900 m portion of the tributary extending southwards and upstream from the centre of a dam constructed at 55°08′19″ north latitude and 124°00′27″ west longitude, to the centre of a dam constructed at 55°07′59″ north latitude and 124°01′00″ west longitude.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">18</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed tributary to Alpine Lake, British Columbia</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed tributary to Alpine Lake, located approximately 60 km southwest of the town of Mackenzie, British Columbia. More precisely, a 590 m portion of the tributary extending southwards and upstream from the centre of a dam constructed at 55°08′18″ north latitude and 124°00′41″ west longitude, to the centre of a dam constructed at 55°08′09″ north latitude and 124°01′08″ west longitude.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">19</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Mallard Lake, Saskatchewan</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Mallard Lake, located at 56°00′32″ north latitude and 104°16′38″ west longitude, approximately 120 km northeast of the town of La Ronge, Saskatchewan. More precisely, the area bounded by</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the contour of elevation around Mallard Lake at the 490 m level, and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the dam built at the south end of Mallard Lake.</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">20</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">The unnamed headwater pond of an unnamed tributary of East Creek, Ontario</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">An unnamed headwater pond of an unnamed tributary of East Creek, located at 50°02′17″ north latitude and 79°40′57″ west longitude, approximately 145 km northeast of the town of Cochrane, Ontario.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">21</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed tributary to East Creek, Ontario</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed tributary to East Creek, Ontario, located approximately 145 km northeast of the town of Cochrane, Ontario. More precisely, a 2.3-km portion of the tributary extending northwards and downstream from the outlet of the unnamed headwater pond referred to in item 20, to the centre of a dam constructed at 50°02′43″ north latitude and 79°40′20″ west longitude.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">22</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed tributary to Linden Creek, Ontario</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed tributary to Linden Creek, Ontario, located approximately 145 km northeast of the town of Cochrane, Ontario. More precisely, a 1.8-km portion of the tributary extending southwards and downstream from the northern perimeter of a waste rock disposal area at 50°00′17″ north latitude and 79°43′37″ west longitude to the southern perimeter of the waste rock disposal area at 49°59′30″ north latitude and 79°43′07″ west longitude.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">23</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed tributary to an unnamed lake in the Linden Creek watershed, Ontario</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed tributary to an unnamed lake in the Linden Creek watershed, Ontario, located approximately 145 km northeast of the town of Cochrane, Ontario. More precisely, a 1.4-km portion of the tributary extending southwards and downstream from the headwaters of the tributary at 50°00′17″ north latitude and 79°42′39″ west longitude to the southern perimeter of a waste rock disposal area at 49°59′25″ north latitude and 79°42′27″ west longitude.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">24</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of Trail Creek, British Columbia</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of Trail Creek, located approximately 20 km southeast of the community of Iskut, British Columbia. More precisely, a 0.6 km portion of the creek extending southwards and downstream from a natural barrier located at 57°42′59″ north latitude and 129°44′10″ west longitude, to the centre of a dam constructed at 57°42′43″ north latitude and 129°44′20″ west longitude.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">25</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Lake Hesse, Quebec</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Lake Hesse, located at 52°46′21″ north latitude and 67°20′58″ west longitude, approximately 15 km west of the town of Fermont, Quebec. More precisely, the area bounded by</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the contour of elevation around Lake Hesse at the 620 m level,</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the dam built at the north end of Lake Hesse, and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the control dam built at the south end of Lake Hesse.</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">26</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">An unnamed lake approximately 20 km west of Fermont, Quebec and a portion of its outlet</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>An unnamed lake, located at 52°49′43″ north latitude and 67°22′23″ west longitude, approximately 20 km west of the town of Fermont, Quebec, and a portion of its outlet. More precisely, the area bounded by</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the contour of elevation around the lake at the 660 m level, and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the outlet of the lake extending from the mouth of an outlet stream at 52°49′33″ north latitude and 67°22′18″ west longitude for a distance of 30 m downstream from that mouth.</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">27</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed stream discharging waters from an unnamed lake, other than the one referred to in item 26, approximately 20 km west of Fermont, Quebec</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed stream discharging waters from an unnamed lake, other than the one referred to in item 26, approximately 20 km west of the town of Fermont, Quebec. More precisely, the 1815 m portion of the stream that extends southwards and downstream from the point located at 52°50′02″ north latitude and 67°21′29″ west longitude to the point located at 52°49′20″ north latitude and 67°21′39″ west longitude.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">28</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of South Teigen Creek, British Columbia</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of South Teigen Creek, located approximately 65 km northwest of Stewart, British Columbia. More precisely, an 8.1‑km portion of the creek extending northwestwards and downstream from the point located at 56°37′53″ north latitude and 129°54′44″ west longitude to the centre of a dam located at 56°40′11.57″ north latitude and 129°58′20.92″ west longitude.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">29</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of North Treaty Creek, British Columbia</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of North Treaty Creek, located approximately 65 km northwest of Stewart, British Columbia. More precisely, a 3.3‑km portion of the creek extending southwards and downstream from the headwaters of the creek located at 56°37′34″ north latitude and 129°54′50″ west longitude to the centre of a dam located at 56°35′54.24″ north latitude and 129°51′25.31″ west longitude.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">30</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">An unnamed watercourse that is a tributary to Lake Jean, located approximately 25 km southeast of Chibougamau, Quebec</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">The unnamed watercourse that is a tributary to Lake Jean, located approximately 25 km southeast of the town of Chibougamau, Quebec, beginning at the unnamed pond located at 49°47′58″ north latitude and 74°01′38″ west longitude and extending northwards and downstream for a distance of 6.4 km to the centre of the dam constructed at 49°49′29″ north latitude and 74°03′07″ west longitude.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">31</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed watercourse that is a tributary to the watercourse referred to in item 30</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed watercourse beginning at that watercourse’s point of confluence with the watercourse referred to in item 30, which confluence is located at 49°47′57″ north latitude and 74°03′25″ west longitude, and extending for a distance of 1 km northwards and upstream from that point.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">32</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed watercourse that is a tributary to the watercourse referred to in item 30</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed watercourse beginning at a point located at 49°48′06″ north latitude and 74°03′41″ west longitude and extending for a distance of 740 m northwards and downstream from that point to the point of confluence with the watercourse referred to in item 30, which confluence is located at 49°48′25″ north latitude and 74°03′25″ west longitude.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">33</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">An unnamed pond east of Lake Bernadette, Quebec, and a portion of its outlet</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">An unnamed pond located at 49°48′43″ north latitude and 74°04′01″ west longitude and a portion of its outlet extending from the mouth of the outlet located at 49°48′47″ north latitude and 74°03′59″ west longitude for a distance of 190 m northwards and downstream from that mouth.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">34</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed creek (locally known as Loslo Creek), and of its unnamed tributaries, that is tributary to Pinewood River, Ontario</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed creek (locally known as Loslo Creek), and of its unnamed tributaries, that is tributary to Pinewood River, located approximately 65 km northwest of the town of Fort Frances, Ontario. More precisely, the portion extending southwards and downstream from the northernmost point of the creek at 48°53′6″ north latitude and 94°2′43″ west longitude to the point located at 48°50′24″ north latitude and 94°3′36″ west longitude.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">35</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed creek (locally known as Marr Creek), and of its unnamed tributaries, that is tributary to Pinewood River, Ontario</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed creek (locally known as Marr Creek), and of its unnamed tributaries, that is tributary to Pinewood River, located approximately 65 km northwest of the town of Fort Frances, Ontario. More precisely, the portion extending southwards and downstream from the northernmost point of the creek at 48°52′12″ north latitude and 94°1′49″ west longitude to the point located at 48°51′18″ north latitude and 94°2′25″ west longitude.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">36</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed creek (locally known as Marr Creek), other than the portion referred to in item 35, that is tributary to Pinewood River, Ontario</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed creek (locally known as Marr Creek), other than the portion referred to in item 35, that is tributary to Pinewood River, located approximately 65 km northwest of the town of Fort Frances, Ontario. More precisely, the portion extending southwards and downstream from the point located at 48°50′52″ north latitude and 94°2′11″ west longitude, for a distance of 1.85 km, to the point located at 48°49′53″ north latitude and 94°2′24″ west longitude.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">37</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed stream and its unnamed tributaries located approximately 25 km northwest of the town of Amos, Quebec</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed stream and its unnamed tributaries located approximately 25 km northwest of the town of Amos, Quebec. More precisely, the 4.6 km portion of the stream extending from the point located at 48°40ˊ44.00˝ north latitude and 78°29ˊ12.68˝ west longitude to the point located at 48°40ˊ7.19˝north latitude and 78°28ˊ1.52˝ west longitude and covering an area of 3.4 ha.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">38</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed tributary to Petit lac du Portage, Quebec</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of an unnamed tributary to Petit lac du Portage located approximately 15 km northwest of the town of Sept-Îles, Quebec. More precisely, the 465 m portion of the tributary to Petit lac du Portage extending southwest and upstream from the point located at 50°16ˊ00.90˝ north latitude and 66°33ˊ42.71˝ west longitude to the point located at 50°16ˊ06.00˝ north latitude and 66°33ˊ31.55˝ west longitude and covering an area of 0.233 ha.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">39</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">An unnamed headwater pond of ruisseau Clet and its unnamed tributaries, Quebec</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>An unnamed headwater pond of ruisseau Clet located at 50°15ˊ15.82˝ north latitude and 66°33ˊ13.6˝ west longitude and covering an area of 2.486 ha, approximately 15 km northwest of the town of Sept-Îles, Quebec, and</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a 471 m portion of its unnamed tributary extending upstream from the point located at 50°15ˊ18.37˝ north latitude and 66°33ˊ24.01˝ west longitude to the point located at 50°15ˊ20.27˝ north latitude and 66°33ˊ13.51˝ west longitude and covering an area of 0.117 ha; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a 76 m portion of its unnamed tributary extending upstream from the point located at 50°15ˊ11.97˝ north latitude and 66°33ˊ22.57˝ west longitude to the point located at 50°15ˊ12.82˝ north latitude and 66°33ˊ20.66˝ west longitude and covering an area of 0.033 ha.</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">40</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of ruisseau Clet and its unnamed tributaries, Quebec</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">A portion of ruisseau Clet, and its unnamed tributaries, located approximately 15 km northwest of the town of Sept-Îles, Quebec. More precisely, the 1897 m portion of ruisseau Clet extending southeast and downstream from the outlet of the unnamed headwater pond referred to in item 39 to the point on ruisseau Clet located at 50°15ˊ11.26˝ north latitude and 66°32ˊ15.99˝ west longitude and covering an area of 0.850 ha.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">41</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">An unnamed watercourse that is a tributary to Rivière Hall, Quebec</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">An unnamed watercourse that is composed of interconnected streams and ponds and is a tributary to Rivière Hall and located approximately 15 km northwest of the town of Sept-Îles, Quebec. More precisely, the 910 m portion of the unnamed watercourse extending downstream from the point located at 50°14ˊ52.33˝ north latitude and 66°33ˊ27.75˝ west longitude to the point located at 50°14ˊ39.67˝ north latitude and 66°32ˊ45.74˝ west longitude and covering an area of 3.619 ha.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">42</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Portions of an unnamed creek, Quebec</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Two portions of an unnamed creek located approximately 15 km northwest of the town of Sept-Îles, Quebec. More precisely,</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the west portion of the creek extending for a distance of 253 m from the point located at 50°15ˊ18.78˝ north latitude and 66°29′52.43˝ west longitude to the point located at 50°15′13.76˝ north latitude and 66°29′46.60˝ west longitude and covering 0.0585 ha; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the east portion of the creek extending for a distance of 267 m from the point located at 50°15ˊ19.58˝ north latitude and 66°29ˊ45.99˝ west longitude to the point located at 50°15ˊ14.18˝ north latitude and 66°29ˊ45.19˝ west longitude and covering 0.0555 ha.</Text></Provision></Provision></entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup><HistoricalNote>SOR/2006-239, ss. 21 to 23; SOR/2008-216, s. 1; SOR/2009-27, s. 1; SOR/2009-156, s. 2; SOR/2010-250, s. 1; SOR/2011-202, s. 1; SOR/2015-45, s. 1; SOR/2016-87, s. 1; SOR/2016-196, s. 1; SOR/2017-128, s. 1; SOR/2017-129, s. 1; SOR/2017-197, s. 1; SOR/2017-272, s. 1; SOR/2018-100, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Schedule><Schedule><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 3</Label><OriginatingRef>(Subsections 1(1) and 12(2) and subsection 4(2) of Schedule 5)</OriginatingRef><TitleText>Analytical Requirements for Metal or Diamond Mining Effluent</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><TableGroup pointsize="8" topmarginspacing="10"><Caption position="over">TABLE 1</Caption><table frame="topbot"><tgroup cols="5"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="42.06*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="111.70*" /><colspec colname="3" colwidth="100.71*" /><colspec colname="4" colwidth="94.35*" /><colspec colname="5" colwidth="119.23*" /><thead><row topdouble="yes"><entry colsep="0" morerows="1" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Item</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 1</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 2</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 3</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 4</entry></row><row valign="bottom"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1">Deleterious Substance/pH/temperature</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1">Precision<FootnoteRef idref="t1_e">1</FootnoteRef></entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1">Accuracy<FootnoteRef idref="t2_e">2</FootnoteRef></entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1">Method Detection Limit (MDL)</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Arsenic</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">10%</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">100 ± 10%</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.0025 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Copper</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">10%</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">100 ± 10%</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.001 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">3</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Cyanide</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">10%</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">100 ± 10%</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.005 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">4</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Lead</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">10%</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">100 ± 10%</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.0005 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">5</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Nickel</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">10%</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">100 ± 10%</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.0125 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">6</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Zinc</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">10%</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">100 ± 10%</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.010 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">7</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Suspended Solids</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">15%</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">100 ± 15%</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2.000 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">8</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Radium 226</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">10%</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">100 ± 10%</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.01 Bq/L</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">9</entry><entry colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0">Total ammonia</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">10%</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">100 ± 10%</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">0.05 mg/L expressed as nitrogen (N)</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">10</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">pH</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.1 pH unit</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.1 pH unit</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Not Applicable</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">11</entry><entry colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0">Temperature</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">10%</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">± 0.5 °C</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Not Applicable</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table><Footnote id="t1_e" placement="table"><Label>1</Label><Text>Relative standard deviation at concentrations 10 times above the MDL.</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="t2_e" placement="table"><Label>2</Label><Text>Analyte recovery at concentrations above 10 times the MDL.</Text></Footnote></TableGroup><TableGroup pointsize="8" topmarginspacing="10"><Caption position="over">TABLE 2</Caption><table frame="topbot"><tgroup cols="5"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="41.80*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="106.36*" /><colspec colname="3" colwidth="102.40*" /><colspec colname="4" colwidth="96.34*" /><colspec colname="5" colwidth="121.14*" /><thead><row topdouble="yes"><?PubTbl row rht="0.26in"?><entry colsep="0" morerows="1" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Item</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 1</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 2</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 3</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 4</entry></row><row valign="bottom"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1">Substances/hardness/alkalinity/electrical conductivity</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1">Precision<FootnoteRef idref="t1_ee">1</FootnoteRef></entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1">Accuracy<FootnoteRef idref="t2_ee">2</FootnoteRef></entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1">Method Detection Limit (MDL)</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Aluminum</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0">10%</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0">100 ± 10%</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.005 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Cadmium</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0">10%</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0">100 ± 10%</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.000045 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">3</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Chloride</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">10%</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0">100 ± 10%</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">60 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">4</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Chromium</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">10%</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0">100 ± 10%</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.00445 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">5</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Cobalt</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">10%</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0">100 ± 10%</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.00125 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">6</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Iron</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">10%</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0">100 ± 10%</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.15 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">7</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Manganese</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">10%</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0">100 ± 10%</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.005 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">8</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Mercury</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">10%</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0">100 ± 10%</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.00001 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">9</entry><entry colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0">Molybdenum</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">10%</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">100 ± 10%</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">0.0365 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">10</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Nitrate</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">10%</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0">100 ± 10%</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1.46835 mg/L, expressed as nitrogen (N)</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">11</entry><entry colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0">Phosphorus</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">10%</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">100 ± 10%</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">0.05 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">12</entry><entry colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0">Selenium</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">10%</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">100 ± 10%</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">0.0005 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">13</entry><entry colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0">Sulphate</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">10%</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">100 ± 10%</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">0.6 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">14</entry><entry colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0">Thallium</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">10%</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">100 ± 10%</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">0.0004 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">15</entry><entry colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0">Uranium</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">10%</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">100 ± 10%</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">0.0075 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">16</entry><entry colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0">Total ammonia</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">10%</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">100 ± 10%</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">0.05 mg/L expressed as nitrogen (N)</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">17</entry><entry colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0">Hardness</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">10%</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">100 ± 10%</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">1 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">18</entry><entry colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0">Alkalinity</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">10%</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">100 ± 10%</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">2 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">19</entry><entry colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0">Electrical Conductivity</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">10%</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">100 ± 10%</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">1 μS/cm</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table><Footnote id="t1_ee" placement="table"><Label>1</Label><Text>Relative standard deviation at concentrations 10 times above the MDL.</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="t2_ee" placement="table"><Label>2</Label><Text>Analyte recovery at concentrations above 10 times the MDL.</Text></Footnote></TableGroup><HistoricalNote>SOR/2006-239, s. 24; SOR/2018-99, s. 31.</HistoricalNote></Schedule><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 4</Label><OriginatingRef>(Paragraph <XRefInternal>4</XRefInternal>(1)(a), subsection <XRefInternal>13</XRefInternal>(1), paragraph <XRefInternal>13</XRefInternal>(3)(a), subparagraph <XRefInternal>22</XRefInternal>(c)(i) and paragraph <XRefInternal>24</XRefInternal>(1)(a))</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><TableGroup pointsize="7" topmarginspacing="10"><table frame="topbot"><title>Authorized Limits of Deleterious Substances</title><tgroup cols="5"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="44.15*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="102.60*" /><colspec colname="3" colwidth="107.15*" /><colspec colname="4" colwidth="110.10*" /><colspec colname="5" colwidth="104.10*" /><thead><row topdouble="yes"><entry morerows="1" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Item</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 1</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 2</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 3</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 4</entry></row><row valign="bottom"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Deleterious Substance</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Maximum Authorized Monthly Mean Concentration</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Maximum Authorized Concentration in a Composite Sample</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Maximum Authorized Concentration in a Grab Sample</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1</entry><entry rowheader="yes" colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Arsenic</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.50 mg/L</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.75 mg/L</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1.00 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2</entry><entry rowheader="yes" colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Copper</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.30 mg/L</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.45 mg/L</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.60 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">3</entry><entry rowheader="yes" colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Cyanide</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1.00 mg/L</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1.50 mg/L</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2.00 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">4</entry><entry rowheader="yes" colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Lead</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.20 mg/L</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.30 mg/L</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.40 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">5</entry><entry rowheader="yes" colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Nickel</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.50 mg/L</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.75 mg/L</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1.00 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">6</entry><entry rowheader="yes" colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Zinc</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.50 mg/L</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.75 mg/L</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1.00 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">7</entry><entry rowheader="yes" colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Total Suspended Solids</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">15.00 mg/L</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">22.50 mg/L</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">30.00 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">8</entry><entry rowheader="yes" colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Radium 226</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.37 Bq/L</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.74 Bq/L</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1.11 Bq/L</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" pointsize="8"><Text>NOTE: All concentrations are total values.</Text></Provision><HistoricalNote>SOR/2006-239, s. 25; SOR/2018-99, s. 32.</HistoricalNote></Schedule><Schedule><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 5</Label><OriginatingRef>(Subsections 7(1) and (3) and paragraphs 15(1)(a) and (b) and 32(1)(c))</OriginatingRef><TitleText>Environmental Effects Monitoring Studies</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><RegulationPiece><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The following definitions apply in this Schedule.</Text><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>biological monitoring study</DefinedTermEn> means a study referred to in section 9. (<DefinedTermFr>étude de suivi biologique</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>effect on fish tissue from mercury</DefinedTermEn> means a concentration of total mercury that exceeds 0.5 μg/g wet weight in fish tissue that is taken in an exposure area and that is statistically different from and higher than the concentration of total mercury in fish tissue that is taken in a reference area. (<DefinedTermFr>effet du mercure sur les tissus de poissons</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>effect on the benthic invertebrate community</DefinedTermEn> means a statistical difference between data referred to in subparagraph 12(1)(e)(ii) and paragraph 12(1)(f) from a study respecting the benthic invertebrate community conducted in</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>an exposure area and a reference area; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>sampling areas within an exposure area where there are gradually decreasing effluent concentrations. (<DefinedTermFr>effet sur la communauté d’invertébrés benthiques</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>effect on the fish population</DefinedTermEn> means a statistical difference between data relating to the indicators referred to in subparagraph 12(1)(e)(i) from a study respecting fish population conducted in</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>an exposure area and a reference area; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>sampling areas within an exposure area where there are gradually decreasing effluent concentrations. (<DefinedTermFr>effet sur la population de poissons</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Paragraph></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>exposure area</DefinedTermEn> means all fish habitat and waters frequented by fish that are exposed to effluent. (<DefinedTermFr>zone exposée</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>fish</DefinedTermEn> has the same meaning as in section 2 of the Act but does not include parts of fish, parts of shellfish, parts of crustaceans or parts of marine animals. (<DefinedTermFr>poisson</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>reference area</DefinedTermEn> means water frequented by fish that is not exposed to effluent and that has fish habitat that, as far as practicable, is most similar to that of the exposure area. (<DefinedTermFr>zone de référence</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>sampling area</DefinedTermEn> means the area within an exposure or reference area where representative samples are collected. (<DefinedTermFr>zone d’échantillonnage</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>For the purpose of this schedule, <DefinedTermEn>critical effect size</DefinedTermEn>, in relation to an effect indicator set out in column 1 of the following table, means the critical effect size set out in column 2:</Text><TableGroup pointsize="8" topmarginspacing="10"><table frame="topbot"><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="15.76*" /><colspec colname="1" colwidth="41.58*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="41.66*" /><thead><row rowsep="0" topdouble="yes"><entry colsep="0" valign="top" /><entry colname="1" colsep="0" valign="top">Column 1</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" valign="top">Column 2</entry></row><row rowsep="1" valign="bottom"><entry colsep="0" valign="top">Item</entry><entry colname="1" colsep="0" valign="top">Effect Indicator</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" valign="top">Critical Effect Size</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" /><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">For Fish Population</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">(% of reference mean)</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colsep="0">1</entry><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Total body weight at age</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">± 25%</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colsep="0">2</entry><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Gonad weight at total body weight</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">± 25%</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colsep="0">3</entry><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Liver weight at total body weight</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">± 25%</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colsep="0">4</entry><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Total body weight at length (condition)</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">± 10%</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colsep="0">5</entry><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Age</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">± 25%</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colsep="0" /><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">For Benthic Invertebrate Community</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">(Standard Deviation Units)</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colsep="0">6</entry><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Density</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">± 2 SD</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colsep="0">7</entry><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Simpson’s Evenness Index</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">± 2 SD</entry></row><row rowsep="0"><entry colsep="0">8</entry><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Taxa Richness</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">± 2 SD</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>Environmental effects monitoring studies consist of the effluent and water quality monitoring studies set out in Part 1 and the biological monitoring studies set out in Part 2.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 1</Label><TitleText>Effluent and Water Quality Monitoring Studies</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Required Studies</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>Effluent and water quality monitoring studies consist of effluent characterization, sublethal toxicity testing and water quality monitoring.</Text></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Effluent Characterization</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Effluent characterization is conducted by analyzing a sample of effluent and recording the hardness, alkalinity, electrical conductivity and temperature of the sample and the concentrations, in total values, of the following substances:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>aluminum;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>cadmium;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>iron;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>subject to subsection (4), mercury;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>molybdenum;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>selenium;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>nitrate (concentration in units of nitrogen);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>chloride;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>chromium;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(j)</Label><Text>cobalt;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(k)</Label><Text>sulphate;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(l)</Label><Text>thallium;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(m)</Label><Text>uranium;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(n)</Label><Text>phosphorus (concentration in units of phosphorus);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(o)</Label><Text>manganese; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(p)</Label><Text>ammonia (concentration in units of nitrogen).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The analysis shall comply with the analytical requirements set out in Table 2 of Schedule 3.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The effluent characterization shall be conducted once per calendar quarter on an aliquot of effluent sample collected under sections 12 and 13 of these Regulations from each final discharge point at least one month after the sample on which the previous characterization was conducted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The recording of the concentration of mercury in effluent referred to in paragraph (1)(d) may be discontinued if that concentration is less than 0.10 µg/L in 12 consecutive samples collected under subsection (3).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>Quality assurance and quality control measures shall be implemented that will ensure the accuracy of the effluent characterization data.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Sublethal Toxicity Testing</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Sublethal toxicity testing shall, in the case of effluent deposited into fresh waters, be conducted using the following test methodologies, as amended from time to time:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in the case of a fish species,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text><XRefExternal reference-type="other">Biological Test Method: Test of Larval Growth and Survival Using Fathead Minnows</XRefExternal> (Report EPS 1/RM/22), published by the Department of the Environment, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text><XRefExternal reference-type="other">Biological Test Method: Toxicity Tests Using Early Life Stages of Salmonid Fish (Rainbow Trout)</XRefExternal> (Reference Method EPS 1/RM/28), published by the Department of the Environment;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in the case of an invertebrate species, <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Biological Test Method: Test of Reproduction and Survival Using the Cladoceran Ceriodaphnia dubia</XRefExternal> (Report EPS 1/RM/21), published by the Department of the Environment;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>in the case of a plant species, <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Biological Test Method: Test for Measuring the Inhibition of Growth Using the Freshwater Macrophyte, Lemna minor</XRefExternal> (Reference Method EPS 1/RM/37), published by the Department of the Environment, as it applies to the biological endpoint based on the number of fronds; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>in the case of an algal species,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text><XRefExternal reference-type="other">Biological Test Method: Growth Inhibition Test Using a Freshwater Alga</XRefExternal> (Report EPS 1/RM/25), published by the Department of the Environment, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text><XRefExternal reference-type="other">Détermination de la toxicité : inhibition de la croissance chez l’algue Pseudokirchneriella subcapitata</XRefExternal>, (Méthode de référence MA 500 – P. sub. 1.0, rév. 3), published by the Centre d’expertise en analyse environnementale du Québec du ministère du Développement durable, de l’Environnement et de la Lutte contre les changements climatiques du Québec.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Sublethal toxicity testing shall, in the case of effluent deposited into marine or estuarine waters, be conducted for fish species, invertebrate species and algal species using the following test methodologies, as amended from time to time, as applicable to each species:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text><XRefExternal reference-type="other">Biological Test Method: Fertilization Assay Using Echinoids (Sea Urchins and Sand Dollars)</XRefExternal> (Report EPS 1/RM/27), published by the Department of the Environment;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text><XRefExternal reference-type="other">Short-term Methods for Estimating the Chronic Toxicity of Effluents and Receiving Waters to Marine and Estuarine Organisms</XRefExternal> (Reference Method EPA/821/R-02/014), published by the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text><XRefExternal reference-type="other">Short-term Methods for Estimating the Chronic Toxicity of Effluent and Receiving Waters to West Coast Marine and Estuarine Organisms</XRefExternal> (Reference Method EPA/600/R-95-136), published by the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The sublethal toxicity tests shall be conducted on aliquots of the same effluent sample collected for effluent characterization collected from the mine’s final discharge point that has potentially the most adverse environmental impact on the environment, taking into account</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the loading of the deleterious substances contained in the effluent as determined under subsection 20(2) of these Regulations; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the manner in which the effluent mixes within the exposure area.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>6</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The sublethal toxicity tests shall be conducted on the species referred to in subsections 5(1) and (2) two times each calendar year for three years and each test shall be conducted on an aliquot of effluent sample collected at least one month after the collection of the sample used in the previous tests.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>However, if effluent is discharged for 31 consecutive days or less in a calendar year, the tests may be conducted only once in that year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>After three years, the tests shall be conducted once per calendar quarter on the species referred to in subsection 5(1) or (2), as the case may be, whose results for all the tests conducted in accordance with subsections (1) and (2) — including such tests conducted in addition to the number required by those subsections — produce the lowest geometric mean, taking into account the inhibition concentration that produces a 25% effect or an effective concentration of 25%.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Water Quality Monitoring</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>7</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Water quality monitoring is conducted by</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>collecting samples of water from</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the exposure area surrounding the point of entry of effluent into water from each final discharge point and from the related reference areas, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the sampling areas that are selected under clauses 10(b)(i)(B) and 10(c)(i)(A);</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>recording the temperature of the water and the dissolved oxygen concentration in the water in the exposure and reference areas where the samples are collected;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>recording the concentration of the substances set out in paragraphs 4(1)(a) to (p) and,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>in the case of effluent that is deposited into fresh water, recording the pH, hardness, alkalinity and electrical conductivity of the water samples,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>in the case of effluent that is deposited into estuarine waters, recording the pH, hardness, alkalinity, electrical conductivity and salinity of the water samples, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>in the case of effluent that is deposited into marine waters, recording the salinity of the water samples;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>recording the concentration of the deleterious substances prescribed in section 3 of these Regulations, but</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>not recording the concentrations of cyanide if that substance is not used as a process reagent within the operations area, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>not recording the concentrations of radium 226 if the conditions of subsection 13(2) of these Regulations are met; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>implementing quality assurance and quality control measures that will ensure the accuracy of water quality monitoring data.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The water quality monitoring shall be conducted</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>four times per calendar year and at least one month apart on the samples of water collected, while the mine is depositing effluent, from the areas referred to in subparagraph (1)(a)(i); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>at the same time that the biological monitoring studies are conducted on samples of water collected in the areas referred to in subparagraph (1)(a)(ii).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Information Related to Effluent and Water Quality Monitoring Studies</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>8</Label><Text>The following information in relation to the effluent and water quality monitoring studies conducted during a calendar year under sections 4 to 7 shall be submitted to the Minister of the Environment not later than March 31 of the following year:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the dates on which samples were collected for effluent characterization, sublethal toxicity testing and water quality monitoring;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for each sample collected for effluent characterization, the location of the final discharge point from which samples were collected for effluent characterization;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the location of the final discharge point from which samples were collected for sublethal toxicity testing and the data used in selecting the final discharge point in accordance with subsection 5(3);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the latitude and longitude of sampling areas for water quality monitoring and a description that is sufficient to identify the location of the sampling areas;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the results of effluent characterization, sublethal toxicity testing and water quality monitoring;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>the methodologies used to conduct effluent characterization and water quality monitoring, and the related method detection limits;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>a description of the quality assurance and quality control measures that were implemented and the data related to the implementation of those measures; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>with respect to every effluent sample collected at each final discharge point, the annual mean concentration of mercury and selenium.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 2</Label><TitleText>Biological Monitoring Studies</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Required Studies</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>9</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Biological monitoring studies shall include</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a study respecting fish population, if the highest concentration of effluent in the exposure area, during a period in which there are deposits, is greater than 1% at any location that is 250 m from a point at which the effluent enters the area from a final discharge point, unless the results of the previous two biological monitoring studies indicate</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>for all effect indicators with no assigned critical effect size, no effect on the fish population, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>for all effect indicators with an assigned critical effect size, no effect on the fish population or an effect on the fish population the absolute value of the magnitude of which is less than the absolute value of its assigned critical effect size;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a study respecting the benthic invertebrate community, if the highest concentration of effluent in the exposure area, during a period in which there are deposits, is greater than 1% at any location that is 100 m from a point at which the effluent enters the area from a final discharge point, unless the results of the previous two biological monitoring studies indicate</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>for all effect indicators with no assigned critical effect size, no effect on the benthic invertebrate community, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>for all effect indicators with an assigned critical effect size, no effect on the benthic invertebrate community or an effect on the benthic invertebrate community the absolute value of the magnitude of which is less than the absolute value of its assigned critical effect size;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a study respecting fish tissue mercury, if</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>effluent characterization reveals an annual mean concentration of total mercury in the effluent that is equal to or greater than 0.10 µg/L, based on a calendar year, unless the results of the previous two biological monitoring studies indicate no effect on fish tissue from mercury, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the method detection limit used in respect of mercury for the analysis of at least two of four effluent samples in a calendar year is equal to or greater than 0.10 µg/L;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a study respecting fish tissue selenium, if</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>effluent characterization reveals a concentration of total selenium in the effluent that is equal to or greater than 10 µg/L,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>effluent characterization reveals an annual mean concentration of total selenium in the effluent that is equal to or greater than 5 µg/L, based on a calendar year, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>the method detection limit used in respect of selenium for the analysis of any effluent sample is equal to or greater than 10 µg/L, or the method detection limit used in respect of selenium for the analysis of at least two of four effluent samples in a calendar year is equal to or greater than 5 µg/L; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>if the cause of any effect on the fish population, on fish tissue from mercury or on the benthic invertebrate community is not known, a study that will be used to determine the cause of the effect if</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the results of the previous two biological monitoring studies indicate a similar type of effect, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>for an effect indicator with an assigned critical effect size, the absolute value of the magnitude of the effect is equal to or greater than the absolute value of its critical effect size in either of those studies.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>If the results of the previous two biological monitoring studies are used to lift the requirement to conduct a study under any of paragraphs (1)(a), (b), (c) or (e), the earlier of those two studies shall not be used to lift a requirement to conduct a subsequent study.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>For the purposes of subsection (1), the concentration of effluent shall be determined or the effluent characterization shall be carried out, as the case may be,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in the case of the first biological monitoring studies, beginning on the day on which the mine becomes subject to section 7 of these Regulations and ending on the day before the day on which the first study design is required to be submitted; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for any subsequent biological monitoring studies, beginning on the day on which the previous study design was required to be submitted and ending on the day before the day on which the subsequent study design is required to be submitted.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><Label>DiVISION 1</Label><TitleText>First Biological Monitoring Studies</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>First Study Design</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>10</Label><Text>A first study design shall be submitted to the Minister of the Environment not later than 12 months after the day on which a mine becomes subject to section 7 of these Regulations. It shall contain</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a site characterization that includes</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>a description of the manner in which the effluent mixes within each exposure area, during a period in which there are deposits, including an estimate of the concentration of effluent in the exposure area at 100 m and 250 m from every point at which the effluent enters the area from a final discharge point and — in respect of each calendar year — any supporting data, including raw data, for the estimate,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>a description of the exposure and reference areas where the biological monitoring studies would be conducted — whether or not they are required — that includes information on the geological, hydrological, oceanographical, limnological, chemical and biological features of those areas,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>the type of production process used by the mine and the environmental protection practices in place at the mine,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>a description of any anthropogenic, natural or other factors that are not related to the effluent but that may reasonably be expected to affect the results of any biological monitoring study, whether or not it is required, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(v)</Label><Text>any additional information that would enable a determination as to whether studies would be conducted in accordance with generally accepted standards of good scientific practice;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a description of how any required study respecting fish population, fish tissue mercury and fish tissue selenium will be conducted that includes</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>a description of and the scientific rationale for</Text><Clause><Label>(A)</Label><Text>the fish species selected, taking into account the abundance of the species most exposed to effluent,</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(B)</Label><Text>the sampling areas selected within the exposure area and the reference area,</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(C)</Label><Text>the sampling period selected,</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(D)</Label><Text>the sample size selected, and</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(E)</Label><Text>the field and laboratory methodologies selected, and</Text></Clause></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>an explanation as to how, in the case of the study respecting fish population or fish tissue mercury, the study will provide the information necessary to determine if the effluent has an effect on fish population or on fish tissue from mercury;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a description of how any required study respecting the benthic invertebrate community will be conducted that includes</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>a description of and the scientific rationale for</Text><Clause><Label>(A)</Label><Text>the sampling areas selected, taking into account the benthic invertebrate diversity and the area most exposed to effluent,</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(B)</Label><Text>the sampling period selected,</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(C)</Label><Text>the sample size selected, and</Text></Clause><Clause><Label>(D)</Label><Text>the field and laboratory methodologies selected, and</Text></Clause></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>an explanation as to how the study will provide the information necessary to determine if the effluent has an effect on the benthic invertebrate community;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the month in which the samples will be collected for each required biological monitoring study;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>a description of the quality assurance and quality control measures that will be implemented for each required biological monitoring study to ensure the validity of the data that is collected; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>a summary of the results of any studies to determine whether the effluent was causing an effect on the fish population, fish tissue from mercury or the benthic invertebrate community and of any studies in the exposure and reference areas respecting fish tissue selenium completed before the mine becomes subject to section 7 of these Regulations and any scientific data to support the results.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>First Biological Monitoring Studies</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>11</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (2), the first biological monitoring studies shall start not earlier than six months after the day on which the first study design is submitted under section 10, and shall be conducted in accordance with that study design.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>If the owner or operator is unable to follow the study design due to circumstances beyond their control, the owner or operator shall inform the Minister of the Environment without delay of those circumstances and of the changes that are made to the study.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>First Interpretative Report</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>12</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A first interpretative report shall be submitted to the Minister of the Environment not later than 36 months after the day on which the mine becomes subject to section 7 of these Regulations. It shall contain</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a description of any deviation from the study design that occurred while the biological monitoring studies were being conducted and any impact that the deviation had on the studies;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the latitude and longitude of sampling areas and a description of the sampling areas sufficient to identify the location of the sampling areas;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the dates and times when samples were collected;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the sample sizes;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the mean, median, standard deviation, standard error and minimum and maximum values in the sampling areas for</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>in the case of the study respecting fish population, effect indicators of growth, reproduction, condition and survival that include, if practicable, the length, total body weight and age of the fish, the weight of its liver or hepatopancreas and, if the fish are sexually mature, the egg weight, fecundity and gonad weight of the fish,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>in the case of the study respecting the benthic invertebrate community, effect indicators of the total benthic invertebrate density, evenness index, taxa richness and, if the study is conducted in an area where it is possible to sample sediment, total organic carbon content of sediment and particle size distribution of sediment,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>in the case of the study respecting fish tissue mercury, the effect indicator of the concentration of total mercury (wet weight) in the fish tissue, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>in the case of the study respecting fish tissue selenium, the concentration — in the muscle or whole body and, if practicable, in the ovaries or eggs — of total selenium (dry weight) reported in µg/g and the percentage of the moisture content of the sample;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>in the case of the study respecting the benthic invertebrate community, a calculation of the similarity index effect indicator;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>an identification of the sex of the fish sampled and of the presence of any lesions, tumours, parasites or other abnormalities and, in the case of the study respecting fish tissue selenium, the type of fish tissue studied and the scientific rationale for the selection of that tissue;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>a determination as to whether there is a statistically significant difference between the sampling areas for the calculations under subparagraphs (e)(i) to (iii) and paragraph (f) taking into consideration the information identified under paragraph (g), with the statistical comparison made separately and independently for each effect indicator;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>a statistical analysis of the results of the calculations under subparagraphs (e)(i) to (iii) and paragraph (g) that indicates the probability of correctly detecting an effect of a pre-defined size and the degree of confidence that can be placed in the calculations;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(j)</Label><Text>for an effect indicator referred to in paragraph (e) with an assigned critical effect size, a comparison of the magnitude of the effect — calculated in accordance with subsection (2) or (3), as the case may be — to its critical effect size;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(k)</Label><Text>any supporting data, including raw data, for the information provided under paragraphs (e) to (j);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(l)</Label><Text>a description of any quality assurance or quality control measures that were implemented and the data related to the implementation of those measures;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(m)</Label><Text>based on the information referred to in paragraphs (e) to (k), the identification of</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>any effect on the fish population,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>any effect on the benthic invertebrate community, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>any effect on fish tissue from mercury;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(n)</Label><Text>for an effect indicator with an assigned critical effect size, a statement as to whether the absolute value of the magnitude of the effect is equal to or greater than the absolute value of its critical effect size;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(o)</Label><Text>a summary of the results of effluent characterization, sublethal toxicity testing and water quality monitoring reported under paragraph 8(e) beginning on the day on which the mine becomes subject to section 7 of these Regulations;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(p)</Label><Text>the conclusions of the biological monitoring studies, and a description of how those conclusions will impact the study design for subsequent biological monitoring studies, taking into account</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the results of any studies referred to in paragraph 10(f),</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>the presence of anthropogenic, natural or other factors that are not related to the effluent under study and that may reasonably be expected to contribute to any observed effect,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>the results of the statistical analysis conducted under paragraphs (h) and (i), and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>the data referred to in paragraph (l);</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(q)</Label><Text>the month in which the next biological monitoring studies will start, if any biological monitoring studies are required; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(r)</Label><Text>the date when the next interpretative report is required to be submitted or would be required to be submitted but for the application of subsection 16(3).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>For the purpose of the study respecting fish population, the magnitude of the effect for an effect indicator is to be calculated using the following formula:</Text><FormulaGroup><Formula><FormulaText>(A – B)/B × 100</FormulaText></Formula><FormulaConnector>where</FormulaConnector><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>A</FormulaTerm><Text>is</Text><FormulaParagraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for the purpose of the age indicator, the mean value for the indicator in the exposure area, and</Text></FormulaParagraph><FormulaParagraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for the purpose of the indicators other than age, the adjusted mean value — obtained using the analysis of covariance (ANCOVA) statistical test method — for the indicator in the exposure area; and</Text></FormulaParagraph></FormulaDefinition><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>B</FormulaTerm><Text>is</Text><FormulaParagraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for the purpose of the age indicator, the mean value for the indicator in the reference area, and</Text></FormulaParagraph><FormulaParagraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>for the purpose of the indicators other than age, the adjusted mean value — obtained using the analysis of covariance (ANCOVA) statistical test method — for the indicator in the reference area.</Text></FormulaParagraph></FormulaDefinition></FormulaGroup></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>For the purposes of the study respecting the benthic invertebrate community, the magnitude of the effect for an effect indicator is to be calculated using the following formula:</Text><FormulaGroup><Formula><FormulaText>(A – B)/C</FormulaText></Formula><FormulaConnector>where</FormulaConnector><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>A</FormulaTerm><Text>is the mean value for the indicator in the exposure area;</Text></FormulaDefinition><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>B</FormulaTerm><Text>is the mean value for the indicator in the reference area; and</Text></FormulaDefinition><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>C</FormulaTerm><Text>is the standard deviation for the indicator in the reference area.</Text></FormulaDefinition></FormulaGroup></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><Label>DIVISION 2</Label><TitleText>Subsequent Biological Monitoring Studies</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Subsequent Study Designs</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>13</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Each subsequent study design shall be submitted to the Minister of the Environment</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>at least six months before the start of the biological monitoring studies that are set out in that study design; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>if no biological monitoring studies are required, not later than 12 months after the day on which the previous interpretative report was required to be submitted or would have been required to be submitted but for the application of subsection 16(3).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Each subsequent study design shall include</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a summary of the information referred to in paragraph 10(a) and a description of any changes to that information since the submission of the most recent study design, as well as — in respect of each calendar year — any supporting data, including raw data, for the estimate referred to in subparagraph 10(a)(i), whether or not the estimate has changed;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the information referred to in paragraphs 10(b) to (e);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a summary of the results of any biological monitoring studies conducted after June 6, 2002;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>if the study referred to in paragraph 9(1)(e) is required,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the month in which the study will start, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>a description of how the study will be conducted that includes any field and laboratory methodologies that will be used to determine the cause of the effect; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>if the cause of an effect on the fish population, on fish tissue from mercury or on the benthic invertebrate community is known, the cause of the effect and any supporting data, including raw data.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Conduct of Subsequent Biological Monitoring Studies</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>14</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (2), the subsequent biological monitoring studies shall be conducted in accordance with the study design submitted under section 13.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>If the owner or operator is unable to follow the study design due to circumstances beyond their control, the owner or operator shall inform the Minister of the Environment without delay of those circumstances and the changes that are made to the study.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Content of Subsequent Interpretative Reports</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>15</Label><Text>Subject to subsection 16(3), each subsequent study design shall be followed by a subsequent interpretative report that includes</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for a study referred to in paragraphs 9(1)(a) to (d), the information referred to in paragraphs 12(1)(a) to (n) and (p) to (r);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a summary of the results of effluent characterization, sublethal toxicity testing and water quality monitoring reported under paragraph 8(e) after the day on which the previous interpretative report was required to be submitted or would have been required to be submitted but for the application of subsection 16(3); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>if the study design includes the description required under paragraph 13(2)(d),</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>the cause of the effect, if determined, and any supporting data, including raw data, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>if the cause of the effect was not determined, an explanation of why and a description of any steps that need to be taken in the next study to determine that cause.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Submission of Subsequent Interpretative Reports</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>16</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (2), each subsequent interpretative report shall be submitted to the Minister of the Environment not later than 36 months after the day on which the previous interpretative report was required to be submitted or would have been required to be submitted but for the application of subsection 16(3).</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The interpretative report following a resumption of effluent discharge referred to in subsection 17(2) shall be submitted not later than 36 months after the day on which effluent discharge resumes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>An interpretative report is not required in respect of a 36-month period if no biological monitoring studies are required in respect of that period.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Cessation of Discharge</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>17</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine that has ceased discharging effluent for a period of at least 36 months is not required to conduct environmental effects monitoring studies so long as the period of cessation continues.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The requirement to conduct environmental effects monitoring studies shall resume, as the case may be, on</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the day on which effluent discharge resumes; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the day on which a notice referred to in paragraph 32(1)(a) of these Regulations is received by the Minister of the Environment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>The owner or operator shall notify the Minister of the Environment in writing without delay</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>when the period of cessation begins; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>when the mine resumes effluent discharge.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Any biological monitoring study that began before the end of the 36-month period shall be completed and followed by an interpretative report in accordance with section 15.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="2"><Label>DIVISION 3</Label><TitleText>Final Studies</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="3"><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>18</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>If an owner or operator of a mine has provided a notice referred to in paragraph 32(1)(a) of these Regulations to the Minister of the Environment, the owner or operator shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>if the notice is received before biological monitoring studies have started, conduct the biological monitoring studies and submit any interpretative report that is required in respect of those studies; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>if the notice is received after biological monitoring studies have started, in addition to submitting any interpretative report that is required in respect of those studies, submit a final study design in accordance with subsection (2), conduct final biological monitoring studies in accordance with section 19 and submit a final interpretative report in accordance with section 20.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The final study design shall be submitted to the Minister of the Environment not later than six months after the day on which the notice referred to in paragraph 32(1)(a) of these Regulations is received. It shall include the information required under subsection 13(2).</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Conduct of Final Biological Monitoring Studies</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>19</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (2), the final biological monitoring studies shall be conducted in accordance with the study design submitted under subsection 18(2) not earlier than six months after the day on which the final study design has been submitted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>If the owner or operator is unable to follow the study design due to circumstances beyond their control, the owner or operator shall inform the Minister of the Environment without delay of those circumstances and the changes that are made to the study.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="3"><TitleText>Content of Final Interpretative Report</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>20</Label><Text>The final interpretative report shall be submitted to the Minister of the Environment not later than three years after the day on which the notice referred to in paragraph 32(1)(a) of these Regulations is received and shall include the information referred to in paragraphs 15(a) to (c).</Text></Section></RegulationPiece><HistoricalNote>SOR/2006-239, ss. 26 to 33, 34(F); SOR/2012-22, ss. 10 to 17; SOR/2018-99, s. 33.</HistoricalNote></Schedule><Schedule><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 6</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 22)</OriginatingRef><TitleText>Annual Report Summarizing Effluent Monitoring Results</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 1</Label><TitleText>Identifying Information</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Label>1</Label><Text>Name of the mine</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Label>2</Label><Text>Address of the mine</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Label>3</Label><Text>Name of the operator of the mine</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Label>4</Label><Text>Operator’s telephone number and e-mail address, if any</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Label>5</Label><Text>Reporting period</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Label>6</Label><Text>Date of report</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 2</Label><TitleText>Test Results Respecting Each Final Discharge Point</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Label>1</Label><Text>Complete the following table with the monthly mean concentration for the deleterious substances set out in the table for each final discharge point and identify the location of the final discharge point.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Label>2</Label><Text>Any measurement not taken because there was no deposit from the final discharge point shall be identified by the letters “NDEP” (No Deposit).</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Label>3</Label><Text>Any measurement not taken because no measurement was required in accordance with the conditions set out in section 12 or 13 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Metal Mining Effluent Regulations</XRefExternal> shall be identified by the letters “NMR” (No Measurement Required).</Text></Provision><TableGroup pointsize="7" spanlanguages="yes" spanmarginalnotecol="yes" topmarginspacing="4"><table frame="all"><tgroup cols="12" keep-together="yes"><colspec colname="col1" colwidth="41.47*" /><colspec colname="col2" colwidth="45.09*" /><colspec colname="col3" colwidth="48.97*" /><colspec colname="col4" colwidth="47.68*" /><colspec colname="col5" colwidth="52.53*" /><colspec colname="col6" colwidth="50.20*" /><colspec colname="col7" colwidth="49.27*" /><colspec colname="col8" colwidth="45.09*" /><colspec colname="col9" colwidth="44.63*" /><colspec colname="col10" colwidth="46.49*" /><colspec colname="col11" colwidth="52.06*" /><colspec colname="col12" colwidth="52.53*" /><thead><row topdouble="yes" topmarginspacing="4" bottommarginspacing="4"><entry namest="col1" nameend="col12" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">Location of final discharge point:</entry></row><row valign="bottom"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center">Month</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>As</Text></Provision><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>(mg/L)</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>Cu</Text></Provision><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>(mg/L)</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>CN</Text></Provision><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>(mg/L)</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>Pb</Text></Provision><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>(mg/L)</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>Ni</Text></Provision><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>(mg/L)</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>Zn</Text></Provision><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>(mg/L)</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>TSS</Text></Provision><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>(mg/L)</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>Ra 226</Text></Provision><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>(Bq/L)</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>Lowest</Text></Provision><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>pH</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>Highest</Text></Provision><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>pH</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" hyphenation="no" topmarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>Effluent Volume</Text></Provision><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>(m<Sup>3</Sup>)</Text></Provision></entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry rowheader="yes" colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center">Jan</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /></row><row><entry rowheader="yes" colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center">Feb</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /></row><row><entry rowheader="yes" colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center">Mar</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /></row><row><entry rowheader="yes" colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center">Apr</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /></row><row><entry rowheader="yes" colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center">May</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /></row><row><entry rowheader="yes" colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center">June</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /></row><row><entry rowheader="yes" colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center">July</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /></row><row><entry rowheader="yes" colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center">Aug</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /></row><row><entry rowheader="yes" colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center">Sept</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /></row><row><entry rowheader="yes" colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center">Oct</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /></row><row><entry rowheader="yes" colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center">Nov</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /></row><row><entry rowheader="yes" colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center">Dec</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 3</Label><TitleText>Results of Acute Lethality Tests and <Language xml:lang="la">Daphnia Magna</Language> Monitoring Tests</TitleText></Heading><TableGroup pointsize="7" spanmarginalnotecol="yes" topmarginspacing="10"><table frame="all"><tgroup cols="4" keep-together="yes"><colspec colname="col1" colwidth="29.20*" /><colspec colname="col2" colwidth="52.44*" /><colspec colname="col3" colwidth="62.33*" /><colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="62.33*" /><thead><row topdouble="yes"><entry namest="col1" nameend="COLSPEC0" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">Location of final discharge point:</entry></row><row valign="bottom"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>Date Sample Collected</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" hyphenation="no" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>Results for Rainbow Trout Acute Lethality Tests</Text></Provision><Provision justification="center" hyphenation="no" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>(mean percentage mortality in 100% effluent test concentration)</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" hyphenation="no" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>Results for <Language xml:lang="la">Daphnia magna</Language> Monitoring Tests</Text></Provision><Provision justification="center" hyphenation="no" topmarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>(mean percentage mortality in 100% effluent test concentration)</Text></Provision></entry><entry rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" hyphenation="no" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>Results for Threespine Stickleback Acute Lethality Tests</Text></Provision><Provision justification="center" hyphenation="no" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>(mean percentage mortality in 100% effluent test concentration)</Text></Provision></entry></row></thead><tbody><row height="20pt"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry rowsep="1" /></row><row height="20pt"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry rowsep="1" /></row><row height="20pt"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry rowsep="1" /></row><row height="20pt"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry rowsep="1" /></row><row height="20pt"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry rowsep="1" /></row><row height="20pt"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry rowsep="1" /></row><row height="20pt"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry rowsep="1" /></row><row height="20pt"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry rowsep="1" /></row><row height="20pt"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry rowsep="1" /></row><row height="20pt"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry rowsep="1" /></row><row height="20pt"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry rowsep="1" /></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 4</Label><TitleText><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 34]</Repealed></TitleText></Heading><HistoricalNote>SOR/2006-239, s. 35; SOR/2018-99, s. 34.</HistoricalNote></Schedule><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 6.1</Label></ScheduleFormHeading><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 35]</Repealed></Schedule><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 7</Label></ScheduleFormHeading><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 35]</Repealed></Schedule><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 8</Label></ScheduleFormHeading><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2018-99, s. 35]</Repealed></Schedule><Schedule id="RelatedProvs"><ScheduleFormHeading type="amending"><TitleText>RELATED PROVISIONS</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><RegulationPiece><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2018-99, s. 37</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>37</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Despite subsection 8(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Metal and Diamond Mining Effluent Regulations</XRefExternal>, the owner or operator of a mine that is subject to those Regulations on the day on which this section comes into force shall submit in writing to the Minister of the Environment the information referred to in paragraph 8(2)(c) of those Regulations not later than 60 days after the day on which this section comes into force.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>During the 12‑month period beginning on the day on which this section comes into force, despite subsection 16(2) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Metal and Diamond Mining Effluent Regulations</XRefExternal>, the owner or operator of a diamond mine may, for the purposes of determining whether effluent is acutely lethal for the 12‑month period referred to in subsection 16(1) of those Regulations, use acute lethality data that was collected during any period of 12 consecutive months before the day on which this section comes into force, if the owner or operator submits a report to the Minister of the Environment that indicates that</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the tests to determine acute lethality have been conducted in accordance with the procedures set out in section 5 or 6 of Reference Method EPS 1/RM/10 or section 5 or 6 of Reference Method EPS 1/RM/13;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the data relates to effluent generated after the start of commercial operation by the mine; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the data was collected not more than 36 months before the day on which this section comes into force.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>During the 12‑month period beginning on the day on which section 14.3 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Metal and Diamond Mining Effluent Regulations</XRefExternal> comes into force, despite subsection 16(2) of those Regulations, the owner or operator of a metal mine or diamond mine may, for the purposes of determining whether effluent is acutely lethal for the 12‑month period referred to in subsection 16(1) of those Regulations, use acute lethality data that was collected during any period of 12 consecutive months before the day on which that section 14.3 comes into force, if the owner or operator submits a report to the Minister of the Environment that indicates that</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the tests to determine acute lethality have been conducted in accordance with the procedures set out in section 5 or 6 of Reference Method EPS 1/RM/14;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the data relates to effluent generated after the start of commercial operation by the mine; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the data was collected not more than 36 months before the day on which that section 14.3 comes into force.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2018-99, s. 38</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>38</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Despite section 10 of Schedule 5 to the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Metal and Diamond Mining Effluent Regulations</XRefExternal>, the first study design of a diamond mine that is subject to those Regulations on June 1, 2018 may be submitted not later than the earlier of June 1, 2021 and the day on which a document that is equivalent to a study design is required to be submitted under provincial or territorial laws.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>In the case of a diamond mine in respect of which the first study design is submitted under subsection (1), the period referred to in subsection 11(1) of Schedule 5 to the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Metal and Diamond Mining Effluent Regulations</XRefExternal> does not apply.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>In the case of a diamond mine that is subject to the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Metal and Diamond Mining Effluent Regulations</XRefExternal> on June 1, 2018, the results of any studies conducted before the day on which the first study design is submitted may be used for the purpose of determining which biological monitoring studies are required to be conducted under section 9 of Schedule 5 to those Regulations if those results can be used for the purpose of meeting the requirements of section 12 of that Schedule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>However, only information gathered — for the purpose of meeting the requirements of provincial or territorial laws — during the three-year period before the day on which the first study design is submitted may be used to determine the concentration of effluent, mercury and selenium for the application of subsections 9(1) and (2) of Schedule 5 to the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Metal and Diamond Mining Effluent Regulations</XRefExternal>. If that information is used, paragraph 9(3)(a) of that Schedule does not apply.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(5)</Label><Text>If the results of studies referred to in subsection (3) and the information referred to in subsection (4) are used in accordance with those subsections, the first study design shall include, in addition to the information referred to in section 10 of Schedule 5 to the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Metal and Diamond Mining Effluent Regulations</XRefExternal>, the information referred to in paragraph 13(2)(d) or (e), as the case may be, of that Schedule, copies of and a summary of the results of the studies and an explanation — that includes supporting information — as to how the results and information can be used for the purposes of meeting the requirements of sections 9 and 12 of that Schedule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(6)</Label><Text>In the case of a diamond mine that is subject to the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Metal and Diamond Mining Effluent Regulations</XRefExternal> on June 1, 2018, the effluent and water quality monitoring studies set out in Part 1 of Schedule 5 to those Regulations shall be started on the day on which the first study design is submitted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(7)</Label><Text>In the case of a diamond mine that is subject to the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Metal and Diamond Mining Effluent Regulations</XRefExternal> on June 1, 2018, the results of sublethal toxicity tests conducted — for the purpose of meeting the requirements of provincial or territorial laws — during the three-year period before the day on which the first study design is submitted may be used for the application of subsection 6(3) of Schedule 5 to those Regulations, as if three years had elapsed, if those tests meet the requirements of subsection 5(1) of that Schedule. If those results are used, subsections 6(1) and (2) of that Schedule do not apply.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(8)</Label><Text>If the results of sublethal toxicity tests are used in accordance with subsection (7), the information referred to in paragraphs 8(a), (c), (e) and (g) of Schedule 5 to the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Metal and Diamond Mining Effluent Regulations</XRefExternal>, in relation to those tests, shall be submitted to the Minister of the Environment not later than the day on which the first study design is submitted and shall be accompanied by a summary of the results of the tests and an explanation — that includes supporting information — as to how the results can be used for the purposes of meeting the requirements of subsection 5(1) of that Schedule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(9)</Label><Text>In the case of a diamond mine that is subject to the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Metal and Diamond Mining Effluent Regulations</XRefExternal> on June 1, 2018, the first interpretative report shall, despite subsection 12(1) of Schedule 5 to those Regulations, be submitted not later than 24 months after the day on which the first study design is submitted and shall contain, in addition to the information referred to in section 12 of that Schedule, the information referred to in paragraph 15(c) of that Schedule.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2018-99, s. 39</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>39</Label><Text>In the case of a metal mine that is subject to the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Metal and Diamond Mining Effluent Regulations</XRefExternal> on June 1, 2018,</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>sections 4 to 8 of Schedule 5 to those Regulations apply beginning on January 1, 2019 and, until that day, the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Metal Mining Effluent Regulations</XRefExternal>, as they read immediately before June 1, 2018, continue to apply to the matters referred to in those sections;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>subsections 6(1) and (2) of Schedule 5 to those Regulations do not apply and the results of sublethal toxicity tests conducted under the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Metal Mining Effluent Regulations</XRefExternal> during the three-year period before January 1, 2019 shall be used for the application of subsection 6(3) of that Schedule, as if three years had elapsed; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>biological monitoring studies started on or before June 1, 2018 shall be completed, and the corresponding interpretative report shall be submitted, in accordance with the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Metal Mining Effluent Regulations</XRefExternal>, as they read immediately before June 1, 2018.</Text></Paragraph></Section></RegulationPiece></Schedule><Schedule id="NifProvs"><ScheduleFormHeading type="amending"><TitleText>AMENDMENTS NOT IN FORCE</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><RegulationPiece><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2018-99, s. 2(4)</TitleText></Heading><Section type="amending"><Label>2</Label><Subsection type="amending"><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The definition <DefinedTermEn>acutely lethal</DefinedTermEn> in subsection 1(1) of the Regulations is amended by striking out “or” at the end of paragraph (a), by adding “or” at the end of paragraph (b) and by adding the following after paragraph (b):</Text><AmendedText><SectionPiece><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>more than 50% of the <Language xml:lang="la">Daphnia magna</Language> subjected to it for a period of 48 hours, when tested in accordance with the acute lethality test set out in section 14.3.</Text></Paragraph></SectionPiece></AmendedText></Subsection></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2018-99, s. 2(6)</TitleText></Heading><Section type="amending"><Label>2</Label><Subsection type="amending"><Label>(6)</Label><Text>Section 1 of the Regulations is amended by adding the following after subsection (1):</Text><AmendedText><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Every reference in these Regulations to column 1, 2, 3 or 4 of Schedule 4 shall be read as</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a reference to column 1, 2, 3 or 4 of Table 1 of Schedule 4, in the case of a mine to which subparagraph 4(1)(a)(i) applies; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a reference to column 1, 2, 3 or 4 of Table 2 of Schedule 4, in the case of a mine to which subparagraph 4(1)(a)(ii) applies.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></AmendedText></Subsection></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2018-99, ss. 3(2), (3)</TitleText></Heading><Section type="amending"><Label>3</Label><Subsection type="amending"><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Section 3 of the Regulations is amended by striking out “and” at the end of paragraph (g), by adding “and” at the end of paragraph (h) and by adding the following after paragraph (h):</Text><AmendedText><SectionPiece><Paragraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>un-ionized ammonia.</Text></Paragraph></SectionPiece></AmendedText></Subsection><Subsection type="amending"><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Paragraph 4(1)(a) of the Regulations is replaced by the following:</Text><AmendedText><SectionPiece><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the concentration of the deleterious substance in the effluent does not exceed the maximum authorized concentrations that are set out in columns 2, 3 and 4 of</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>Table 1 of Schedule 4, in the case of a mine in respect of which these Regulations apply for the first time on or after June 1, 2021 or in the case of a recognized closed mine that returns to commercial operation on or after June 1, 2021, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>Table 2 of Schedule 4, in any other case;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></SectionPiece></AmendedText></Subsection></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2018-99, s. 4</TitleText></Heading><Section type="amending"><Label>4</Label><Text>The Regulations are amended by adding the following after section 4:</Text><AmendedText><Section><Label>4.1</Label><Text>Paragraph 4(1)(c) does not apply in the case where the effluent is determined to be acutely lethal in accordance with the procedures set out in section 5 or 6 of Reference Method EPS 1/RM/14 when the owner or operator of a mine is testing at the frequency prescribed in subsection 14(1), unless the effluent is determined to be acutely lethal in accordance with any other acute lethality test.</Text></Section></AmendedText></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2018-99, ss. 9(2) to (4)</TitleText></Heading><Section type="amending"><Label>9</Label><Subsection type="amending"><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Subsection 12(1) of the Regulations is replaced by the following:</Text><AmendedText><Section><Label>12</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine shall, not less than once per week and at least 24 hours apart, collect from each final discharge point</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a grab sample or composite sample of effluent and record the pH of the sample at the time of its collection and record, without delay after collecting the sample, the concentrations of the deleterious substances prescribed in section 3 except un-ionized ammonia; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a grab sample of effluent and record the temperature and the pH of the sample at the time of its collection and record, without delay after collecting the sample, the concentrations of total ammonia expressed as nitrogen (N).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section></AmendedText></Subsection><Subsection type="amending"><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Section 12 of the Regulations is amended by adding the following after subsection (3):</Text><AmendedText><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine shall determine and record the concentration of un-ionized ammonia, using the temperature, pH and concentration of total ammonia recorded under paragraph (1)(b), in accordance with the following formula:</Text><FormulaGroup><Formula><FormulaText>A (1/(1 + 10<Sup>pKa-pH</Sup>))</FormulaText></Formula><FormulaConnector>where</FormulaConnector><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>A</FormulaTerm><Text>is the concentration of total ammonia — which is the sum of un-ionized ammonia (NH<Sub>3</Sub>) and ionized ammonia (NH<Sub>4</Sub><Sup>+</Sup>) — expressed in mg/L as nitrogen (N);</Text></FormulaDefinition><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>pH</FormulaTerm><Text>is the pH of the effluent sample; and</Text></FormulaDefinition><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>pKa</FormulaTerm><Text>is a dissociation constant calculated in accordance with the following formula:</Text><FormulaGroup><Formula><FormulaText>0.09018 + 2729.92/T</FormulaText></Formula><FormulaConnector>where</FormulaConnector><FormulaDefinition><FormulaTerm>T</FormulaTerm><Text>is the temperature of the effluent sample in kelvin.</Text></FormulaDefinition></FormulaGroup></FormulaDefinition></FormulaGroup></Subsection></AmendedText></Subsection><Subsection type="amending"><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Subsection 13(1) of the Regulations is replaced by the following:</Text><AmendedText><Section><Label>13</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine may reduce the frequency of conducting tests relating to the concentrations of arsenic, copper, cyanide, lead, nickel, zinc or un-ionized ammonia at a final discharge point to not less than once in each calendar quarter, each test being conducted at least one month apart, if that substance’s monthly mean concentration at that final discharge point is less than 10% of the value set out in column 2 of Schedule 4 for 12 consecutive months.</Text></Subsection></Section></AmendedText></Subsection></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2018-99, ss. 10(2), (3)</TitleText></Heading><Section type="amending"><Label>10</Label><Subsection type="amending"><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Subsection 14(1) of the Regulations is replaced by the following:</Text><AmendedText><Section><Label>14</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to section 15, the owner or operator of a mine shall collect, once a month, a grab sample of effluent from each final discharge point and determine whether the effluent is acutely lethal by conducting acute lethality tests on aliquots of each effluent sample in accordance with sections 14.1 to 14.3.</Text></Subsection></Section></AmendedText></Subsection><Subsection type="amending"><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Subsection 14(3) of the Regulations is replaced by the following:</Text><AmendedText><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>When collecting a grab sample of effluent for the purposes of subsection (1), the owner or operator of a mine shall</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>collect a sufficient volume of effluent to enable the owner or operator to comply with paragraph 15(1)(a); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>record the temperature and the pH of each grab sample of effluent at the time of the sample’s collection.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></AmendedText></Subsection></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2018-99, s. 11</TitleText></Heading><Section type="amending"><Label>11</Label><Text>The Regulations are amended by adding the following after section 14.2:</Text><AmendedText><Heading level="4"><TitleText>Acute Lethality Test — <Language xml:lang="la">Daphnia Magna</Language></TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>14.3</Label><Text>Unless the salinity value of the effluent is equal to or greater than four parts per thousand and the effluent is deposited into marine waters, the owner or operator of a mine shall, in addition to conducting the acute lethality test set out in section 14.1, determine whether the effluent is acutely lethal by conducting an acute lethality test in accordance with the procedures set out in section 5 or 6 of Reference Method EPS 1/RM/14.</Text></Section></AmendedText></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2018-99, s. 12(2)</TitleText></Heading><Section type="amending"><Label>12</Label><Subsection type="amending"><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Paragraphs 15(1)(a) and (b) of the Regulations are replaced by the following:</Text><AmendedText><SectionPiece><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>without delay,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>conduct the effluent characterization set out in subsection 4(1) of Schedule 5 on the aliquot of each grab sample collected under subsection 14(1),</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>record the concentration of total ammonia and, using that concentration and using the temperature and pH recorded under paragraph 14(3)(b), determine the concentration of un-ionized ammonia in accordance with the formula set out in subsection 12(4), and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>record the concentrations of the deleterious substances prescribed in section 3;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>collect a grab sample twice a month from the final discharge point from which the effluent sample determined to be acutely lethal was collected, record the temperature and the pH of each sample at the time of its collection and, without delay, conduct the acute lethality test that determined the effluent sample to be acutely lethal on each grab sample in accordance with the procedure set out in section 6 of the applicable reference method and, if the sample is determined to be acutely lethal, without delay,</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>conduct the effluent characterization set out in subsection 4(1) of Schedule 5 on the aliquot of each grab sample,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>record the concentration of total ammonia and, using that concentration and using the temperature and pH recorded under this paragraph, determine the concentration of un-ionized ammonia in accordance with the formula set out in subsection 12(4), and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>record the concentrations of the deleterious substances prescribed in section 3; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></SectionPiece></AmendedText></Subsection></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2018-99, s. 13</TitleText></Heading><Section type="amending"><Label>13</Label><Text>The Regulations are amended by adding the following after section 15:</Text><AmendedText><Section><Label>15.1</Label><Text>Despite paragraph 15(1)(c), if an effluent sample is determined to be acutely lethal when tested using the acute lethality test set out in section 14.3, the owner or operator of a mine shall, without delay, collect the first grab sample required by paragraph 15(1)(b) and comply with the requirements of that paragraph.</Text></Section></AmendedText></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2018-99, s. 15(2)</TitleText></Heading><Section type="amending"><Label>15</Label><Subsection type="amending"><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Section 17 of the Regulations and the heading before it are repealed.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2018-99, s. 16(2)</TitleText></Heading><Section type="amending"><Label>16</Label><Subsection type="amending"><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Section 18 of the Regulations is replaced by the following:</Text><AmendedText><Section><Label>18</Label><Text>The owner or operator of a mine shall record without delay the data referred to in section 9.1 of Reference Method EPS 1/RM/10, section 8.1 of Reference Method EPS 1/RM/13 and section 8.1 of Reference Method EPS 1/RM/14 for all acute lethality tests that are conducted to monitor deposits from final discharge points.</Text></Section></AmendedText></Subsection></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2018-99, s. 18(2)</TitleText></Heading><Section type="amending"><Label>18</Label><Subsection type="amending"><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Paragraph 19.1(1)(a) of the Regulations is replaced by the following:</Text><AmendedText><SectionPiece><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in mg/L for deleterious substances referred to in paragraphs 3(a) to (g) and (i); and</Text></Paragraph></SectionPiece></AmendedText></Subsection></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2018-99, s. 19(2)</TitleText></Heading><Section type="amending"><Label>19</Label><Subsection type="amending"><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Paragraph 20(1)(a) of the Regulations is replaced by the following:</Text><AmendedText><SectionPiece><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in kg for deleterious substances referred to paragraphs 3(a) to (g) and (i); and</Text></Paragraph></SectionPiece></AmendedText></Subsection></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2018-99, s. 27(2)</TitleText></Heading><Section type="amending"><Label>27</Label><Subsection type="amending"><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Subsection 31.1(1) of the Regulations is replaced by the following:</Text><AmendedText><Section><Label>31.1</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>If an unauthorized deposit of a deleterious substance occurs, the owner or operator of a mine shall, without delay, collect a grab sample of effluent at the place where the deposit occurred and determine whether the effluent is acutely lethal by conducting tests on aliquots of each effluent sample in accordance with sections 14.1 to 14.3.</Text></Subsection></Section></AmendedText></Subsection></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2018-99, s. 32(2)</TitleText></Heading><Section type="amending"><Label>32</Label><Subsection type="amending"><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Schedule 4 to the Regulations is replaced by the Schedule 4 set out in Schedule 2 to these Regulations.</Text><AmendedText><Schedule><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE 4</Label><OriginatingRef>(Subsection 1(2), subparagraphs 4(1)(a)(i) and (ii), subsection 13(1), paragraph 13(3)(a), subparagraph 22(c)(i) and paragraph 24(1)(a))</OriginatingRef><TitleText>Maximum Authorized Concentrations of Prescribed Deleterious Substances</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><TableGroup pointsize="8" spanlanguages="yes" topmarginspacing="10"><Caption position="over">TABLE 1</Caption><table frame="topbot"><tgroup cols="5"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="44.76*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="102.45*" /><colspec colname="3" colwidth="107.05*" /><colspec colname="4" colwidth="109.86*" /><colspec colname="5" colwidth="103.98*" /><thead><row topdouble="yes"><entry colsep="0" morerows="1" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Item</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 1</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 2</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 3</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 4</entry></row><row valign="bottom"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Deleterious Substance</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Maximum Authorized Monthly Mean Concentration</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Maximum Authorized Concentration in a Composite Sample</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Maximum Authorized Concentration in a Grab Sample</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Arsenic</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.10 mg/L</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.15 mg/L</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.20 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Copper</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.10 mg/L</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.15 mg/L</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.20 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">3</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Cyanide</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.50 mg/L</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.75 mg/L</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1.00 mg/L</entry></row><row><?PubTbl row rht="0.28in"?><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">4</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Lead</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.08 mg/L</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.12 mg/L</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.16 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">5</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Nickel</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.25 mg/L</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.38 mg/L</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.50 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">6</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Zinc</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.40 mg/L</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.60 mg/L</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.80 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">7</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Suspended Solids</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">15.00 mg/L</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">22.50 mg/L</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">30.00 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">8</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Radium 226</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.37 Bq/L</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.74 Bq/L</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1.11 Bq/L</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">9</entry><entry colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0">Un-ionized ammonia</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">0.50 mg/L expressed as nitrogen (N)</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Not applicable</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">1.00 mg/L expressed as nitrogen (N)</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" pointsize="8"><Text>NOTE: The concentrations for items 1 to 8 are total values.</Text></Provision><TableGroup pointsize="8" spanlanguages="yes" topmarginspacing="10"><Caption position="over">TABLE 2</Caption><table frame="topbot"><tgroup cols="5"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="44.15*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="102.60*" /><colspec colname="3" colwidth="107.15*" /><colspec colname="4" colwidth="110.10*" /><colspec colname="5" colwidth="104.10*" /><thead><row topdouble="yes"><?PubTbl row rht="0.28in"?><entry colsep="0" morerows="1" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Item</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 1</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 2</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 3</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">Column 4</entry></row><row valign="bottom"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Deleterious Substance</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Maximum Authorized Monthly Mean Concentration</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Maximum Authorized Concentration in a Composite Sample</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Maximum Authorized Concentration in a Grab Sample</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Arsenic</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.30 mg/L</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.45 mg/L</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.60 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">2</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Copper</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.30 mg/L</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.45 mg/L</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.60 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">3</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Cyanide</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.50 mg/L</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.75 mg/L</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1.00 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">4</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Lead</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.10 mg/L</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.15 mg/L</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.20 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">5</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Nickel</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.50 mg/L</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.75 mg/L</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1.00 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">6</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Zinc</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.50 mg/L</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.75 mg/L</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1.00 mg/L</entry></row><row><?PubTbl row rht="0.28in"?><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">7</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Suspended Solids</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">15.00 mg/L</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">22.50 mg/L</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">30.00 mg/L</entry></row><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">8</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0" valign="top">Radium 226</entry><entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.37 Bq/L</entry><entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">0.74 Bq/L</entry><entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1.11 Bq/L</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">9</entry><entry colsep="0" rowheader="yes" rowsep="0">Un-ionized ammonia</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">0.50 mg/L expressed as nitrogen (N)</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Not applicable</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">1.00 mg/L expressed as nitrogen (N)</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" pointsize="8"><Text>NOTE: The concentrations for items 1 to 8 are total values.</Text></Provision></Schedule></AmendedText></Subsection></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2018-99, ss. 33(2), (3)</TitleText></Heading><Section type="amending"><Label>33</Label><Subsection type="amending"><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Schedule 5 to the Regulations is amended by replacing the references after the heading “Schedule 5” with the following:</Text><AmendedText><OriginatingRef>(Subsections <XRefInternal>7</XRefInternal>(1) and (3), subparagraphs <XRefInternal>15</XRefInternal>(1)(a)(i) and (b)(i) and paragraph <XRefInternal>32</XRefInternal>(1)(c))</OriginatingRef></AmendedText></Subsection><Subsection type="amending"><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Subsection 4(1) of Schedule 5 to the Regulations is amended by adding “and” at the end of paragraph (n), by striking out “and” at the end of paragraph (o) and by repealing paragraph (p).</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2018-99, s. 34(1)</TitleText></Heading><Section type="amending"><Label>34</Label><Subsection type="amending"><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Part 2 of Schedule 6 to the Regulations is replaced by the following:</Text><AmendedText><Schedule><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 2</Label><TitleText>Test Results Respecting Each Final Discharge Point</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Label>1</Label><Text>Complete the following table with the monthly mean concentration for the deleterious substances set out in the table for each final discharge point and identify the location of the final discharge point.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Label>2</Label><Text>Any measurement not taken because there was no deposit from the final discharge point shall be identified by the letters “NDEP” (No Deposit).</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Label>3</Label><Text>Any measurement not taken because no measurement was required in accordance with the conditions set out in section 12 or 13 of these Regulations shall be identified by the letters “NMR” (No Measurement Required).</Text></Provision><TableGroup pointsize="7" spanlanguages="yes" spanmarginalnotecol="yes" topmarginspacing="10"><table frame="all"><tgroup cols="13" keep-together="yes"><colspec colname="col1" colwidth="41.47*" /><colspec colname="col2" colwidth="45.09*" /><colspec colname="col3" colwidth="48.97*" /><colspec colname="col4" colwidth="47.68*" /><colspec colname="col5" colwidth="52.53*" /><colspec colname="col6" colwidth="50.20*" /><colspec colname="col7" colwidth="49.27*" /><colspec colname="col8" colwidth="45.09*" /><colspec colname="col9" colwidth="44.63*" /><colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="44.63*" /><colspec colname="col10" colwidth="46.49*" /><colspec colname="col11" colwidth="52.06*" /><colspec colname="col12" colwidth="52.53*" /><thead><row topdouble="yes" topmarginspacing="4" bottommarginspacing="4"><entry namest="col1" nameend="col12" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">Location of final discharge point:</entry></row><row valign="bottom"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center">Month</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>As</Text></Provision><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>(mg/L)</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>Cu</Text></Provision><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>(mg/L)</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>CN</Text></Provision><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>(mg/L)</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>Pb</Text></Provision><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>(mg/L)</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>Ni</Text></Provision><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>(mg/L)</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>Zn</Text></Provision><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>(mg/L)</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>SS</Text></Provision><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>(mg/L)</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>Ra 226</Text></Provision><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>(Bq/L)</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision><Text>Un-ionized ammonia (mg/L, expressed as Nitrogen (N))</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>Lowest</Text></Provision><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>pH</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>Highest</Text></Provision><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>pH</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" hyphenation="no" topmarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>Effluent Volume</Text></Provision><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>(m<Sup>3</Sup>)</Text></Provision></entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry rowheader="yes" colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center">Jan.</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /></row><row><entry rowheader="yes" colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center">Feb.</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /></row><row><entry rowheader="yes" colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center">Mar.</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /></row><row><entry rowheader="yes" colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center">Apr.</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /></row><row><entry rowheader="yes" colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center">May</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /></row><row><entry rowheader="yes" colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center">June</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /></row><row><entry rowheader="yes" colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center">July</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /></row><row><entry rowheader="yes" colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center">Aug.</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /></row><row><entry rowheader="yes" colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center">Sept.</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /></row><row><entry rowheader="yes" colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center">Oct.</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /></row><row><entry rowheader="yes" colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center">Nov.</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /></row><row><entry rowheader="yes" colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center">Dec.</entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" /></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Schedule></AmendedText></Subsection></Section><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2018-99, s. 34(3)</TitleText></Heading><Section type="amending"><Label>34</Label><Subsection type="amending"><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Part 3 of Schedule 6 to the Regulations is replaced by the following:</Text><AmendedText><Schedule><Heading level="1"><Label>PART 3</Label><TitleText>Results of Acute Lethality Tests</TitleText></Heading><TableGroup pointsize="7" spanmarginalnotecol="yes" topmarginspacing="10"><table frame="all"><tgroup cols="4" keep-together="yes"><colspec colname="col1" colwidth="29.20*" /><colspec colname="col2" colwidth="52.44*" /><colspec colname="col3" colwidth="62.33*" /><colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="62.33*" /><thead><row topdouble="yes"><entry namest="col1" nameend="COLSPEC0" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top">Location of final discharge point:</entry></row><row valign="bottom"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" topmarginspacing="0"><Text>Date Sample Collected</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" hyphenation="no" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>Results for Rainbow Trout Acute Lethality Tests</Text></Provision><Provision justification="center" hyphenation="no" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>(mean percentage mortality in 100% effluent test concentration)</Text></Provision></entry><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" hyphenation="no" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>Results for <Language xml:lang="la">Daphnia magna</Language> Acute Lethality Tests</Text></Provision><Provision justification="center" hyphenation="no" topmarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>(mean percentage mortality in 100% effluent test concentration)</Text></Provision></entry><entry rowsep="1" align="center"><Provision justification="center" hyphenation="no" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>Results for Threespine Stickleback Acute Lethality Tests</Text></Provision><Provision justification="center" hyphenation="no" topmarginspacing="0" bottommarginspacing="0" list-item="no"><Text>(mean percentage mortality in 100% effluent test concentration)</Text></Provision></entry></row></thead><tbody><row height="20pt"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry rowsep="1" /></row><row height="20pt"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry rowsep="1" /></row><row height="20pt"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry rowsep="1" /></row><row height="20pt"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry rowsep="1" /></row><row height="20pt"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry rowsep="1" /></row><row height="20pt"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry rowsep="1" /></row><row height="20pt"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry rowsep="1" /></row><row height="20pt"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry rowsep="1" /></row><row height="20pt"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry rowsep="1" /></row><row height="20pt"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry rowsep="1" /></row><row height="20pt"><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry colsep="1" rowsep="1" /><entry rowsep="1" /></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup></Schedule></AmendedText></Subsection></Section></RegulationPiece></Schedule></Regulation>