<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en" in-force="yes"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2012-148</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2012</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>6</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2012</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>25</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CANADIAN ENVIRONMENTAL ASSESSMENT ACT, 2012</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Prescribed Information for the Description of a Designated Project Regulations</LongTitle></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>The Minister of the Environment, pursuant to paragraph 84(b) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canadian Environmental Assessment Act, 2012</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_81000-2-1256-E_hq_12156">a</FootnoteRef>, makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Prescribed Information for the Description of a Designated Project Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fn_81000-2-1256-E_hq_12156" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 2012, c. 19, s. 52</Text></Footnote></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Ottawa, July 6, 2012</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><SignatureBlock justification="right" width="15pc"><SignatureName justification="right">PETER KENT</SignatureName><SignatureTitle justification="right"><Emphasis style="italic">Minister of the Environment</Emphasis></SignatureTitle></SignatureBlock></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Information</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Required information</MarginalNote><Label>1</Label><Text>The information set out in the schedule is prescribed for the purposes of subsection 8(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canadian Environmental Assessment Act, 2012</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Amendment to These Regulations</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>[Amendment]</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section type="transitional"><MarginalNote>S.C. 2012, c. 19</MarginalNote><Label><FootnoteRef idref="fn_IndF732_hq_13006">*</FootnoteRef>3</Label><Subsection type="transitional"><Label>(1)</Label><Text>These Regulations, other than section 2, come into force on the day on which section 52 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Jobs, Growth and Long-term Prosperity Act</XRefExternal>, chapter 19 of the Statutes of Canada, 2012, comes into force.</Text></Subsection><Subsection type="transitional"><MarginalNote>S.C. 2012, c. 19</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Section 2 comes into force on the first day on which both sections 52 and 141 of that Act are in force.</Text></Subsection><Footnote id="fn_IndF732_hq_13006" placement="section" status="editorial"><Label>*</Label><Text>[Note: Regulations, other than section 2, in force July 6, 2012, <Emphasis style="italic">see</Emphasis> SI/2012-56; section 2 in force November 25, 2013, <Emphasis style="italic">see</Emphasis> SI/2013-116.]</Text></Footnote></Section></Body><Schedule><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 1)</OriginatingRef><TitleText>Prescribed Information for the Description of a Designated Project</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><RegulationPiece><Heading level="1"><TitleText>General Information</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>The project’s name, nature and proposed location.</Text></Section><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>The proponent’s name and contact information and the name and contact information of their primary representative for the purpose of the description of the project.</Text></Section><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>A description of and the results of any consultations undertaken with any jurisdictions and other parties including Aboriginal peoples and the public.</Text></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>The environmental assessment and regulatory requirements of other jurisdictions.</Text></Section><Section><Label>4.1</Label><Text>A description of any environmental study that is being or has been conducted of the region where the project is to be carried out.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Project Information</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>A description of the project’s context and objectives.</Text></Section><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>The provisions in the schedule to the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations Designating Physical Activities</XRefExternal> describing the project in whole or in part.</Text></Section><Section><Label>7</Label><Text>A description of the physical works that are related to the project including their purpose, size and capacity.</Text></Section><Section><Label>8</Label><Text>The anticipated production capacity of the project and a description of the production processes to be used, the associated infrastructure and any permanent or temporary structures.</Text></Section><Section><Label>9</Label><Text>A description of all activities to be performed in relation to the project.</Text></Section><Section><Label>10</Label><Text>A description of any waste that is likely to be generated during any phase of the project and of a plan to manage that waste.</Text></Section><Section><Label>11</Label><Text>A description of the anticipated phases of and the schedule for the project’s construction, operation, decommissioning and abandonment.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Project Location Information</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>12</Label><Text>A description of the project’s location, including</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>its geographic coordinates;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>site maps produced at an appropriate scale in order to determine the project’s overall location and the spatial relationship of the project components;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the legal description of land to be used for the project, including the title, deed or document and any authorization relating to a water lot;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the project’s proximity to any permanent, seasonal or temporary residences;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the project’s proximity to reserves, traditional territories as well as lands and resources currently used for traditional purposes by Aboriginal peoples; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>the project’s proximity to any federal lands.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Federal Involvement</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>13</Label><Text>A description of any financial support that federal authorities are, or may be, providing to the project.</Text></Section><Section><Label>14</Label><Text>A description of any federal land that may be used for the purpose of carrying out the project.</Text></Section><Section><Label>15</Label><Text>A list of the permits, licences or other authorizations that may be required under any Act of Parliament to carry out the project.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Environmental Effects</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>16</Label><Text>A description of the physical and biological setting.</Text></Section><Section><Label>17</Label><Text>A description of any changes that may be caused, as a result of carrying out the project, to</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>fish and fish habitat as defined in subsection 2(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Fisheries Act</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>aquatic species, as defined in subsection 2(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Species at Risk Act</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>migratory birds, as defined in subsection 2(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Migratory Birds Convention Act, 1994</XRefExternal>.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>18</Label><Text>A description of any changes to the environment that may occur, as a result of carrying out the project, on federal lands, in a province other than the province in which the project is proposed to be carried out or outside of Canada.</Text></Section><Section><Label>19</Label><Text>Information on the effects on Aboriginal peoples of any changes to the environment that may be caused as a result of carrying out the project, including effects on health and socio-economic conditions, physical and cultural heritage, the current use of lands and resources for traditional purposes or on any structure, site or thing that is of historical, archaeological, paleontological or architectural significance.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Summary</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>20</Label><Text>A summary of the information required under sections 1 to 19.</Text></Section></RegulationPiece><HistoricalNote>SOR/2012-148, s. 2; SOR/2014-5, ss. 1 to 3.</HistoricalNote></Schedule></Regulation>