<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/91-101</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1991</YYYY><MM>1</MM><DD>17</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2011</YYYY><MM>8</MM><DD>25</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AERONAUTICS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Rimouski Airport Zoning Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting Zoning at Rimouski Airport</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1991-35</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1991</YYYY><MM>1</MM><DD>17</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Whereas, pursuant to section 5.5<FootnoteRef idref="footnote1star_e">*</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Aeronautics Act</XRefExternal>, a copy of the proposed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Zoning Regulations respecting Rimouski Airport</XRefExternal>, substantially in the form set out in the schedule hereto, was published in two successive issues of the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal> Part I on October 1st and 8th, 1988, and in two successive issues of <Emphasis style="italic"><Language xml:lang="fr">Le Rimouskois</Language></Emphasis> on February 7th and 14th, 1989, and in two successive issues of the <Emphasis style="italic"><Language xml:lang="fr">Progrès-Echo</Language></Emphasis> on February 8th and 15th, 1989, and a reasonable opportunity was thereby afforded to interested persons to make representations to the Minister of Transport with respect thereto;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Therefore, His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Transport, pursuant to section 5.4<FootnoteRef idref="footnote1star_e">*</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Aeronautics Act</XRefExternal>, is pleased hereby to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting zoning at Rimouski Airport</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision><Footnote id="footnote1star_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>R.S. 1985, c. 33 (1st Supp.)</Text></Footnote></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Rimouski Airport Zoning Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>airport</DefinedTermEn> means the Rimouski Airport in the Village of Rimouski-Est, in the Province of Quebec; (<DefinedTermFr>aéroport</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>airport reference point</DefinedTermEn> means the point described in Part I of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>point de repère de l’aéroport</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>approach surface</DefinedTermEn> means an imaginary inclined plane that extends upward and outward from each end of a strip, which approach surface is more particularly described in Part II of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>surface d’approche</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Minister</DefinedTermEn> means the Minister of Transport; (<DefinedTermFr>ministre</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>outer surface</DefinedTermEn> means an imaginary surface located above and in the immediate vicinity of the airport, which outer surface is more particularly described in Part III of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>surface extérieure</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>strip</DefinedTermEn> means the rectangular portion of the landing area of the airport, including the runway, prepared for the take-off and landing of aircraft in a particular direction, which strip is more particularly described in Part IV of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>bande</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>transitional surface</DefinedTermEn> means an imaginary inclined plane that extends upward and outward from the lateral limits of a strip and its approach surfaces, which transitional surface is more particularly described in Part V of the schedule. (<DefinedTermFr>surface de transition</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>For the purposes of these Regulations, the elevation of the airport reference point is 22.2 m above sea level.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>These Regulations apply to all the lands in the vicinity of the airport, which lands are found within the limits described in Part VI of the Schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>No person shall erect or construct on any land to which these Regulations apply, any building, structure or object or any addition to any existing building, structure or object, the highest point of which will exceed in elevation at the location of that point</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the approach surfaces;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the outer surface; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the transitional surfaces.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Natural Growth</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>Where an object of natural growth on any land to which these Regulations apply exceeds in elevation any of the surfaces referred to in paragraphs 4(a) to (c), the Minister may require that the owner or occupier of the land on which that object is growing remove the excessive growth.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Disposal of Waste</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>No owner or occupier of any land to which these Regulations apply shall permit such land or any part of it to be used for the disposal of any waste that is edible by or attractive to birds.</Text></Section></Body><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label><OriginatingRef>(Sections 2 and 3)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><Heading level="1"><Label>PART I</Label><TitleText>Description of the Airport Reference Point</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The airport reference point, shown on Rimouski Airport Zoning Plan No. MM-87-6620 dated February 2, 1987 is situated at the centre of runway 07-25, the said airport reference point having coordinates of Northing (N) 5,371,265.968 and Easting (E) 231,094.041, and the said coordinates are of the S.CO.P.Q. system, zone number 6, central meridian 67°30′.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART II</Label><TitleText>Description of the Approach Surfaces</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The approach surfaces, shown on Rimouski Airport Zoning Plan No. MM-87-6620 dated February 2, 1987, are surfaces abutting each end of the strip associated with the runway designated 07-25 and are described as follows:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a surface abutting the end of the strip associated with runway approach 07 consisting of an inclined plane having a ratio of 1 m measured vertically to 40 m measured horizontally rising to an imaginary horizontal line drawn at right angles to the projected centre line of the strip and distant 1 778.4 m measured horizontally from the end of the strip; the outer ends of the imaginary horizontal line being 341.76 m from the projected centre line; said imaginary horizontal line being 44.46 m above the elevation at the end of the strip; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a surface abutting the end of the strip associated with runway approach 25 consisting of an inclined plane having a ratio of 1 m measured vertically to 40 m measured horizontally rising to an imaginary horizontal line drawn at right angles to the projected centre line of the strip and distant 1 822 m measured horizontally from the end of the strip; the outer ends of the imaginary horizontal line being 348.3 m from the projected centre line; said imaginary horizontal line being 45.55 m above the elevation at the end of the strip.</Text></Provision></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART III</Label><TitleText>Description of the Outer Surface</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The outer surface, shown on Rimouski Airport Zoning Plan No. MM-87-6620 dated February 2, 1987, is an imaginary surface located at a common plane established at a constant elevation of 45 m above the elevation of the airport reference point, except that, where that common plane is less than 9 m above the surface of the ground, outer surface is an imaginary surface located at 9 m above the surface of the ground.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART IV</Label><TitleText>Description of the Strip</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The strip associated with runway 07-25 shown on Rimouski Airport Zoning Plan No. MM-87-6620 dated February 2, 1987, is described as being 150 m in width, 75 m being on each side of the centre line of the runway, and 1 521.58 m in length.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART V</Label><TitleText>Description of Each Transitional Surface</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Each transitional surface, shown on Rimouski Airport Zoning Plan No. MM-87-6620 dated February 2, 1987, is a surface consisting of an inclined plane rising at a ratio of 1 m measured vertically to 7 m measured horizontally at right angles to the centre line and projected centre line of the strip and extending upward and outward from the lateral limits of the strip and its approach surfaces to an intersection with the outer surface.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART VI</Label><TitleText>Description of the Outer Limits of Land</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The boundary of the outer limits of lands, shown on Rimouski Airport Zoning Plan No. MM-87-6620, dated February 2, 1987, is described as follows:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Commencing at a point, the coordinates of which are N 5,367,380.712 m and E 230,142.835 m, being located at the intersection of a line situated at two thousand three hundred metres (2 300 m) and parallel to the centre line of runway 07-25 with a circle having a radius of four thousand metres (4 000 m), the centre of which is the Airport Reference Point; thence following an arc of a circle having a radius of four thousand metres (4 000 m), the centre of which is the Airport Reference Point, a distance of seventeen thousand four hundred and sixty-seven metres and twenty hundredths (17 467.20 m) to a point, the coordinates of which are N 5,371,687.131 and E 235,071.806; thence following a line having an azimuth of 228°51′23″, a distance of six thousand five hundred and forty-five metres and twenty-three hundredths (6 545.23 m) to the point of commencement.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>All the coordinates, distances and azimuths mentioned in this description are in reference with the S.CO.P.Q. system, zone number 6, central meridian 67°30′; all the dimensions are given in the international measurement system (SI).</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The lands found within the above described limits form part of the Cadastre of the Parish of Saint-Germain-de-Rimouski, the Town of Saint-Germain-de-Rimouski and the Parish of Saint-Anaclet, Registry Division of Rimouski, Province of Quebec.</Text></Provision></Provision><HistoricalNote>SOR/91-502, s. 1(F).</HistoricalNote></Schedule></Regulation>