<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/74-431</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1974</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>22</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2006</YYYY><MM>10</MM><DD>26</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">APPROPRIATION ACT NO. 9, 1966</XRefExternal><XRefExternal reference-type="act">APPROPRIATION ACTS</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Teslin Exploration Limited Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Authorizing the Minister of Indian Affairs and Northern Development to Consent to the Transfer of Certain Territorial Coal Licences and to Postpone the Repayment of Amounts Payable Under the Northern Mineral Exploration Assistance Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber> 1974-1561</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1974</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>16</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>His Excellency the Administrator in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Indian Affairs and Northern Development, pursuant to Vote No. 7a of <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Appropriation Act No. 9, 1966</XRefExternal>, is pleased hereby to make the annexed Order authorizing the Minister of Indian Affairs and Northern Development to consent to the transfer of certain Territorial Coal Licences and to postpone the repayment of amounts payable under the Northern Mineral Exploration assistance regulations.</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Teslin Exploration Limited Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In this Order,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Minister</DefinedTermEn> means the Minister of Indian Affairs and Northern Development; (<DefinedTermFr>Ministre</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Regulations</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Northern Mineral Exploration Assistance Regulations</XRefExternal>. (<DefinedTermFr>règlement</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Consent to Transfer</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>Notwithstanding paragraph 11(c) of the Regulations, the Minister may consent to the transfer by Teslin Exploration Limited of Territorial Coal Licences numbered 10, 11 and 12 to Vittorio Ghitti.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Postponement of Repayment</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>Notwithstanding paragraph 11(e) of the Regulations, and subject to section 5 of this Order, the obligation to repay to Her Majesty in right of Canada the balance of the grant paid to Teslin Exploration Limited pursuant to the Regulations together with simple interest thereon at the rate of 10 per cent per annum is postponed until the disposition of Territorial Coal Licences numbered 10, 11, 12, 15, 16 and 17.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Undertaking</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>Teslin Exploration Limited shall give a written undertaking to repay to Her Majesty in right of Canada the balance of the grant owing under the Regulations together with simple interest thereon at the rate of 10 per cent per annum out of any of Territorial Coal Licences numbered 10, 11, 12, 15, 16 and 17.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>