<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/93-74</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1993</YYYY><MM>2</MM><DD>11</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2011</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>13</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AERONAUTICS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Gore Bay Airport Zoning Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting Zoning at Gore Bay Airport</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1993-262</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1993</YYYY><MM>2</MM><DD>11</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Whereas, pursuant to section 5.5 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Aeronautics Act</XRefExternal>, a copy of the proposed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting Gore Bay Airport</XRefExternal>, substantially in the form set out in the schedule hereto, was published in two successive issues of the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal> Part I on March 7th and 14th, 1992, and in two successive issues of the Manitoulin Expositor on April 22nd and 29th, 1992, and in two successive issues of the Manitoulin Recorder on March 25th and April 1st, 1992, and a reasonable opportunity was thereby afforded to interested persons to make representations to the Minister of Transport with respect thereto;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Therefore, His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Transport, pursuant to section 5.4 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Aeronautics Act</XRefExternal>, is pleased hereby to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting zoning at Gore Bay Airport</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Gore Bay Airport Zoning Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>airport</DefinedTermEn> means the Gore Bay Airport, in the Townships of Gordon and Barrie in the District of Manitoulin, in the Province of Ontario; (<DefinedTermFr>aéroport</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>airport reference point</DefinedTermEn> means the point described in Part I of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>point de repère de l’aéroport</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>approach surfaces</DefinedTermEn> means the imaginary inclined planes that extend upward and outward from each end of a strip, which planes are more particularly described in Part II of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>surfaces d’approche</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>outer surface</DefinedTermEn> means the imaginary plane located above and in the immediate vicinity of the airport, which plane is more particularly described in Part III of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>surface extérieure</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>strip</DefinedTermEn> means the rectangular portion of the landing area of the airport, including the runway, prepared for the take-off and landing of aircraft in a particular direction, which portion is more particularly described in Part IV of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>bande</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>transitional surfaces</DefinedTermEn> means the imaginary inclined planes that extend upward and outward from the lateral limits of a strip and its approach surfaces, which planes are more particularly described in Part V of the schedule. (<DefinedTermFr>surfaces de transition</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>For the purposes of these Regulations, the elevation of the airport reference point is 183.5 m above sea level.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/94-375, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>These Regulations apply to all land, including public road allowances, that is adjacent to or in the vicinity of the airport, which land is more particularly described in Part VI of the schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>No person shall erect or construct, on any land to which these Regulations apply, any building, structure or object or any addition to any existing building, structure or object, the highest point of which will exceed in elevation at the location of that point</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the approach surfaces;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the outer surface; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the transitional surfaces.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Aeronautical Facilities</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>No owner or lessee of any land to which these Regulations apply shall permit any part of that land to be used or developed in a manner that causes interference with any signals or communications to and from any aircraft or to and from any facilities used to provide services relating to aeronautics.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/94-375, s. 2(F).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Natural Growth</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>Where an object of natural growth that is on any land to which these Regulations apply grows to a height that exceeds in elevation at the location of the object any of the surfaces referred to in section 4, the Minister may require that the owner or lessee of the land remove the excessive growth.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Disposal of Waste</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>7</Label><Text>No owner or lessee of any land to which these Regulations apply shall permit any part of that land to be used for the disposal of any waste that is edible by or attractive to birds.</Text></Section></Body><Schedule bilingual="no" spanlanguages="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label><OriginatingRef>(Sections 2 and 3)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><Heading level="1"><Label>PART I</Label><TitleText>Description of the Airport Reference Point</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The airport reference point, shown on Gore Bay Airport Zoning Plan No. 52-024 86-288, Sheet 5, dated September 4, 1990, is a point which may be located by:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>COMMENCING at Button 29 being the easterly end of runway 11-29 at Gore Bay Airport, having Universal Transverse Mercator coordinates of 5 081 764.25 N and 379 127.00 E;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE northwesterly along the centre line of said runway 11-29, 855.17 m to a point;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE northeasterly and perpendicular to the centre line of said runway 11-29, 428.26 m to the airport reference point, having Universal Mercator coordinates of 5 082 304.86 N and 378 338.33 E.</Text></Provision></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART II</Label><TitleText>Description of the Approach Surfaces</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The approach surfaces, shown on Gore Bay Airport Zoning Plan No. 52-024 86-228, Sheets 4, 5 and 6, dated September 4, 1990, are planes abutting each end of the strip associated with runway 11-29 and are described as follows:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>an inclined plane abutting the end of the strip associated with runway approach 11 having a ratio of 1 m measured vertically to 50 m measured horizontally rising to an imaginary horizontal line drawn at right angles to the projected centre line of the strip and distant 2 240 m measured horizontally from the end of the strip; the outer ends of the imaginary horizontal line being 486 m from the projected centre line; said imaginary horizontal line being 44.8 m above the elevation at the end of the strip; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>an inclined plane abutting the end of the strip associated with runway approach 29 having a ratio of 1 m measured vertically to 50 m measured horizontally rising to an imaginary horizontal line drawn at right angles to the projected centre line of the strip and distant 2 095 m measured horizontally from the end of the strip; the outer ends of the imaginary horizontal line being 464.25 m from the projected centre line; said imaginary horizontal line being 41.9 m above the elevation at the end of the strip.</Text></Provision></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART III</Label><TitleText>Description of the Outer Surface</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The outer surface, shown on Gore Bay Airport Zoning Plan No. 52-024 86-228, Sheets 1 to 9 inclusive, dated September 4, 1990, is an imaginary plane established at a constant elevation of 45 m above the elevation of the airport reference point, except that, where that plane is less than 9 m above the surface of the ground, the outer surface is located at 9 m above the surface of the ground.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART IV</Label><TitleText>Description of the Strip</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The strip associated with runway 11-29, shown on Gore Bay Airport Zoning Plan No. 52-024 86-228, Sheet 5, dated September 4, 1990, is 300 m in width, 150 m being on each side of the centre line of the runway and 1 619.57 m in length.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART V</Label><TitleText>Description of the Transitional Surfaces</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Each transitional surface, shown on Gore Bay Airport Zoning Plan No. 52-024 86-228, Sheets 4, 5 and 6, dated September 4, 1990, is an inclined plane rising at a ratio of 1 m measured vertically to 7 m measured horizontally at right angles to the centre line and projected centre line of the strip, extending upward and outward from the lateral limits of the strip and its approach surfaces to an intersection with the outer surface.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART VI</Label><TitleText>Description of the Land to Which These Regulations Apply</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The outer boundary of the land to which these Regulations apply, shown on Gore Bay Airport Zoning Plan No. 52-024 86-228, Sheets 1 to 9 inclusive, dated September 4, 1990, is described as follows:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>ALL AND SINGULAR those certain parcels or tracts of land situate lying and being in the Township of Gordon, the Township of Barrie Island and islands in Bayfield Sound adjacent to the Townships of Gordon and Barrie Island, all in the District of Manitoulin, in the Province of Ontario;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>COMMENCING at the northeast corner of Lot 18 Concession 9 in the Township of Gordon;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE southerly along the easterly limit of Lot 18 to the southeast corner of the said lot;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE southerly in a straight line across the road allowance between Concessions 8 and 9 to the northwest corner of Lot 17 Concession 8;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE easterly along the northerly boundary of the said Lot 17 to the northeast corner thereof;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE southerly along the easterly boundary of Lot 17 through Concessions 8 and 7 to the southeast corner of Lot 17 Concession 7;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE westerly along the southerly boundary of Lot 17 Concession 7 to the southwest corner thereof;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE southerly in a straight line across the road allowance between Concessions 6 and 7 to the northeast corner of Lot 18 Concession 6;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE southerly along the easterly boundary of Lot 18 Concession 6 to the southeast corner thereof;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE westerly along the southerly limit of Lot 18 Concession 6 to the northeast corner of Lot 19 Concession 5;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE southerly along the easterly limit of Lot 19 Concession 5 to the southeast corner thereof;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE westerly along the southerly limit of Concession 5 across Lots 19 and 20 to the southwest corner of Lot 20 Concession 5;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE southerly in a straight line across the road allowance between Concessions 4 and 5 to the northeast corner of Lot 21 Concession 4;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE southerly along the easterly limit of Lot 21 Concession 4 to the southeast corner of Lot 21 Concession 4, being on the inner limit of the road allowance around Lake Wolsey;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE southerly on the production of the easterly limit of the said Lot 21 Concession 4 across the said road allowance to the high water mark of Lake Wolsey;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE southwesterly along the said high water mark of Lake Wolsey in front of Lots 21 and 22 and the road allowance between Lots 21 and 22 to a point on the easterly production of the southerly limit of Lot 22 Concession 4;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE westerly in a straight line to the most southeasterly corner of Lot 22 Concession 4;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE westerly along the southerly limit of Concession 4 through Lots 22 and 23 to the southwest corner of the said Lot 23, being the inner limit of the road allowance around Bayfield Sound on Lake Huron;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE continuing westerly on the production of the said southerly limit of Concession 4 to the high water mark of Bayfield Sound on Lake Huron;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE northerly along the westerly limit of the road allowance around Bayfield Sound to its intersection with an arc drawn on a radius of 4 000 m measured from the airport reference point, the coordinates of which are 5 082 304.86 N and 378 338.33 E;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE westerly, northwesterly and northerly along the said arc to its intersection with the southerly limit of the road allowance south of Lot 8 Concession 3 in the Township of Barrie Island being on the high water mark of Bayfield Sound;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE easterly along the said southerly limit of the road allowance to its intersection with the southerly production of the westerly limit of Lot 7 Concession 3 in the said Township of Barrie Island;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE northerly in a straight line across the road allowance to the southwest corner of Lot 7 Concession 3;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE northerly along the westerly limit of Lot 7 Concession 3 to the northwest corner thereof;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE easterly along the northerly limits of Lots 7 and 6 to the northeast corner of Lot 6 Concession 3;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE easterly in a straight line across the road allowance between Lots 5 and 6 to the northwest corner of Lot 5 Concession 3;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE easterly along the northerly limit of Lots 5 and 4 to the northeast corner of Lot 4 Concession 3;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE northerly in a straight line across the road allowance between Concessions 3 and 4 to the southwest corner of Lot 3 Concession 4;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE northerly along the westerly limit of Lot 3 Concession 4 to the northwest corner thereof;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE easterly along the northerly limit of the said Lot 3 Concession 4 to the northeast corner thereof, being a point in the westerly limit of Lot 2 Concession 5;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE northerly along the westerly limit of Lot 2 Concession 5 to the northwest corner thereof;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE easterly along the northerly limit of Lots 2 and 1 Concession 5 to the northeast corner of Lot 1 Concession 5, being a point in the inner limit of the road allowance around the Township of Barrie Island;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE continuing easterly in a straight line on the production of the said northerly limit of Lot 1 Concession 5 across the said road allowance to the high water mark of Julia Bay on Lake Huron, being the easterly limit of the said road allowance;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE southerly along the easterly limit of the road allowance to its intersection with an arc drawn on a radius of 4 000 m measured from the airport reference point, the coordinates of which are 5 082 304.86 N and 378 338.33 E;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE easterly and southeasterly along the said arc to its intersection with the road allowance in front of Lot 19 Concession 9 in the Township of Gordon;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE easterly along the northerly limit of the said road allowance to a point in the northerly production of the easterly limit of Lot 18 Concession 9 in the Township of Gordon;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE southerly in a straight line across the said road allowance to the northeast corner of the said Lot 18 Concession 9, being the POINT OF COMMENCEMENT.</Text></Provision></Provision><HistoricalNote>SOR/94-375, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Schedule></Regulation>