<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/98-36</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1997</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>29</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>10</MM><DD>27</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CUSTOMS TARIFF</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Commonwealth Caribbean Countries Tariff Rules of Origin Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1997-2007 </OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1997</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>29</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Finance, pursuant to subsection 16(2) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fna_e">a</FootnoteRef>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Commonwealth Caribbean Countries Tariff Rules of Origin Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fna_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 1997, c. 36</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>In these Regulations, <DefinedTermEn>beneficiary country</DefinedTermEn> means a country that is a beneficiary of the Commonwealth Caribbean Countries Tariff.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Originating Goods</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A good originates in a beneficiary country if the good is</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a mineral good extracted from the soil or the seabed of the country;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a vegetable good harvested in the country;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a live animal born and raised in the country;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a good obtained in the country from a live animal;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>a good obtained by hunting or fishing in the country;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>a good derived from sea fishing or other marine goods taken from the sea by a vessel of the country;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>a product made on board a factory ship of the country exclusively from products referred to in paragraph (f);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>waste and scrap derived from manufacturing facilities of the country;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>used goods of the country imported into Canada for use only for the recovery of raw materials; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(j)</Label><Text>goods produced in the country exclusively from a product referred to in any of paragraphs (a) to (h).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Goods originate in a beneficiary country if the value of the materials, parts or products originating outside the beneficiary country or in an undetermined location and used in the manufacture or production of the goods amounts to not more than 40% of the ex-factory price of the goods as packed for shipment to Canada.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>For the purposes of subsection (2), the following are deemed to have originated in the beneficiary country</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any materials, parts or products used in the manufacture or production of the goods referred to in that subsection and originating in any other beneficiary country or from Canada, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any packing required for the transportation of the goods, excluding packing in which the goods are ordinarily sold for consumption in the beneficiary country.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>For the purpose of determining the origin of goods, each good in a shipment shall be considered separately, except that</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>if a group, set or assembly of goods is classified in one item, the group, set or assembly shall be considered to be one good, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>tools, parts and accessories</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>that are imported with a good,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>that constitute the standard equipment customarily included in the sale of a good of that kind, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>the price of which is included in the price of the good and for which no separate charge is made,</Text></Subparagraph><ContinuedParagraph><Text>shall be considered as forming a whole with the good.</Text></ContinuedParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>An unassembled good that is imported in more than one shipment because it is not feasible for transport or production reasons to import it in one shipment shall be considered to be one good.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Direct Shipment</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>Goods are entitled to the Commonwealth Caribbean Countries Tariff only if the goods are shipped directly to Canada, with or without transhipment, from a beneficiary country.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Repeal</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>[Repeal]</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section type="transitional"><Label>6</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on January 1, 1998.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>