<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/99-298</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1999</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>23</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2006</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>11</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">TERRITORIAL LANDS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Order Authorizing Federal Employees to Acquire Interests in Certain Lands in the Northwest Territories (Order No. 1, 1999)</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1999-1204 </OrderNumber><Date><YYYY> 1999</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>23</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Indian Affairs and Northern Development, pursuant to paragraph 29(1)(a) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Territorial Lands Act</XRefExternal>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Order Authorizing Federal Employees to Acquire Interests in Certain Lands in the Northwest Territories (Order No. 1, 1999)</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Purpose</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>The purpose of this Order is to authorize certain employees of the Government of Canada to acquire interest in territorial lands in the Northwest Territories.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Authorization</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>The employee of the Government of Canada named in the schedule is hereby authorized to acquire interests in territorial lands in the Northwest Territories as described in the schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section type="transitional"><Label>3</Label><Text>This Order comes into force on the day on which it is registered.</Text></Section></Body><Schedule bilingual="no" spanlanguages="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label></ScheduleFormHeading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>To Roselle Marie Scott, of the City of Yellowknife in the Northwest Territories, a Postal Clerk employee of the Canada Post Corporation, to lease, for a seasonal dwelling, the whole of Lot Numbered 1015, on the southerly shore of Prelude Lake, in Quad 85 I/12, in the Northwest Territories, as said Lot is shown on plan of survey of Record Number 65767, in the Canada Lands Surveys Record at Ottawa, a copy of which is filed in the Land Titles Office for the Northwest Territories Land Registration District at Yellowknife, under number 1316, saving and excepting therefrom and reserving thereout all mines and minerals, including hydrocarbons, whether solid, liquid or gaseous and the right to work them.</Text></Provision></Schedule></Regulation>