<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2002-148</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2002</YYYY><MM>4</MM><DD>11</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>3</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">PRECLEARANCE ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Regulations Designating Persons and Categories of Persons — Other Than Travellers Destined for the United States — Who May Enter a Preclearance Area</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2002-546 </OrderNumber><Date><YYYY> 2002</YYYY><MM>4</MM><DD>11</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Foreign Affairs, pursuant to paragraph 38(1)(b) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Preclearance Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-2002-148_e_hq_5852">a</FootnoteRef>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations Designating Persons and Categories of Persons — Other Than Travellers Destined for the United States — Who May Enter a Preclearance Area</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fn_SOR-2002-148_e_hq_5852" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 1999, c. 20</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>The following definitions apply in these Regulations.</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>airport operator</DefinedTermEn> means the holder of a Canadian aviation document issued under Part I of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Aeronautics Act</XRefExternal> in respect of the airport, or the person in charge of the airport. (<DefinedTermFr>exploitant de l’aéroport</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>restricted area pass</DefinedTermEn> means a restricted area pass as defined in section 1 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Canadian Aviation Security Regulations</XRefExternal>, but only if it is issued by an airport operator and only if it entitles the holder to have access during a specified period to the preclearance area in the airport governed by the airport operator. (<DefinedTermFr>laissez-passer de zone réglementée</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Designation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>For the purposes of subsection 8(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Preclearance Act</XRefExternal>, the following persons and categories of persons may enter the preclearance area at an airport:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the holder of a restricted area pass for that airport who is required to enter the preclearance area in order to perform functions of their employment at the airport or functions under a contract that the holder has with the airport operator;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a person who is required to enter the preclearance area in order to perform maintenance or repair of the airport facilities or emergency services at the airport, if they are under constant surveillance by the airport operator, either electronically or by way of personal escort, while they are in the preclearance area; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>any other person who</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>is the holder of a restricted area pass for that airport and has a legitimate requirement to enter the preclearance area at the time in question, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>has permission to enter the preclearance area from the airport operator and is under constant surveillance by the airport operator by way of personal escort while in the preclearance area.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label><FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-2002-148_e_hq_5853">*</FootnoteRef>3</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on the day on which section 38 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Preclearance Act</XRefExternal>, being chapter 20 of the Statutes of Canada, 1999, comes into force.</Text><Footnote id="fn_SOR-2002-148_e_hq_5853" placement="section" status="editorial"><Label>*</Label><Text>[Note: Regulations in force May 1, 2002, <Emphasis style="italic">see</Emphasis> SI/2002-73.]</Text></Footnote></Section></Body></Regulation>