<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/88-101</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1988</YYYY><MM>1</MM><DD>14</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2006</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>26</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CANADA SHIPPING ACT, 2001</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Anchorage Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting the Anchoring of Ships in Certain Prohibited Waters</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1988-43</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1988</YYYY><MM>1</MM><DD>14</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Transport, pursuant to sections 635 and 730<FootnoteRef idref="fn_1e">*</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Shipping Act</XRefExternal>, is pleased hereby to revoke the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Conception Bay Anchorage Regulations</XRefExternal>, C.R.C., c. 1417, the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Northumberland Strait Anchorage Regulations</XRefExternal>, C.R.C., c. 1453, the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Parry Bay Anchorage Regulations</XRefExternal>, C.R.C., c. 1455, the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Random Sound Anchorage Regulations</XRefExternal>, C.R.C., c. 1462, and the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Welland Canal Entrances Anchorage Regulations</XRefExternal>, C.R.C., c. 1499, and to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting the anchoring of ships in certain prohibited waters</XRefExternal> in substitution therefor.</Text><Footnote id="fn_1e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>R.S.C. 1970, c. 27 (2nd Supp.), s. 3</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Anchorage Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations, <DefinedTermEn>prohibited waters</DefinedTermEn> means the waters described in the schedule. (<DefinedTermFr>eaux interdites</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Prohibition</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>No person shall anchor a ship within prohibited waters.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Contravention</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>Every person who contravenes section is liable, on summary conviction, to a fine not exceeding $500.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Instructions and Directions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>Every ship within prohibited waters shall take into consideration any instruction or direction relating to any navigation limitation or prohibition or other shipping measure contained in Notices to Mariners published by the Canadian Coast Guard or Notices to Shipping broadcast or published by the Canadian Coast Guard.</Text></Section></Body><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 2)</OriginatingRef><TitleText>Prohibited Waters</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Label>1</Label><Text>Conception Bay — Province of Newfoundland</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Beginning at the lighted cable sign in Broad Cove, Newfoundland, in the position Latitude 47°35′45″N., Longitude 52°53′10″W., as shown on Canadian Hydrographic Service Chart 4566, edition dated November 23, 1962; THENCE in a straight line to the position Latitude 47°35′45″N., Longitude 52°53′37″W.; THENCE in a straight line to the position Latitude 47°37′12″N., Longitude 52°55′44″W.; THENCE in a straight line to the cable landing at Bell Island, Newfoundland, in position Latitude 47°37′37″N., Longitude 52°56′00″W.; THENCE in a straight line to the position Latitude 47°37′37″N., Longitude 52°55′16″W.; THENCE in a straight line to the position on the shore Latitude 47°36′09″N., Longitude 52°53′06″W.; THENCE following the high water mark in a southwesterly direction to the point of beginning.</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Label>2</Label><Text>Random Sound — Province of Newfoundland</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Beginning at a point on the high water mark at the easterly extremity of East Random Head, as shown on Canadian Hydrographic Service Charts 4545 and 4546, editions dated May 6, 1983 and January 24, 1964, respectively; THENCE in a straight line to a point on the high water mark at the easterly extremity of West Random Head; THENCE following the high water mark in a westerly direction to a point on the shore at Latitude 48°03′04″N., Longitude 53°38′42″W.; THENCE in a straight line to a point on the high water mark of Middle Cliff at Latitude 48°03′54″N., Longitude 53°40′26″W.; THENCE following the high water mark in a westerly and northerly direction to the easterly extremity of Red Point; THENCE in a straight line to a point on the high water mark at the westerly extremity of Brown Mead; THENCE following the high water mark in a southerly and easterly direction to the point of beginning.</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Label>3</Label><Text>Northumberland Strait — Between the Provinces of New Brunswick and Prince Edward Island</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Beginning at a point on the high water mark at Cape Bruin, N.B., located at Latitude 46°10′58″N., Longitude 63°58′42″W., as shown on Canadian Hydrographic Service Chart 4406, edition dated July 12, 1985; THENCE in a straight line to a point on the high water mark at Fernwood, P.E.I., Latitude 46°19′15″N., Longitude 63°48′55″W.; THENCE following the high water mark in a southerly and easterly direction to a point on the shore at Latitude 46°18′30″N., Longitude 63°46′09″W.; THENCE in a straight line to a point on the high water mark at Botsford, N.B., Latitude 46°10′01″N., Longitude 63°56′00″W.; THENCE following the high water mark in a northwesterly direction to the point of beginning.</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Label>4</Label><Text>Welland Canal Entrances — Province of Ontario</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" keep-with-previous="yes" list-item="no"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>Lake Ontario: beginning at a point north of the Port Weller Entrance to the Welland Canal located at Latitude 43°14′40″N., Longitude 79°13′40″W., as shown on Canadian Hydrographic Service Chart 2063, edition dated December 2, 1983; THENCE in a 090° direction for approximately 0.9 nautical miles to a position located at Latitude 43°14′40″N., Longitude 79°12′28″W.; THENCE in a 009° direction for approximately 2.6 nautical miles to a position located at Latitude 43°17′16″N., Longitude 79°11′50″W.; THENCE in a 270° direction for approximately 1.7 nautical miles to a position located at Latitude 43°17′16″N., Longitude 79°14′15″W.; THENCE in a 171° direction for approximately 2.6 nautical miles to the point of beginning; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>Lake Erie: beginning at a point south of the Port Colborne Entrance to the Welland Canal located at Latitude 42°51′55″N., Longitude 79°15′53″W., as shown on Canadian Hydrographic Service Chart 2120, edition dated March 7, 1986; THENCE in a 110° direction for approximately 0.9 nautical miles to a position located at Latitude 42°51′37″N., Longitude 79°14′44″W.; THENCE in a 191° direction for approximately 2.6 nautical miles to a position located at Latitude 42°49′3″N., Longitude 79°15′24″W.; THENCE in a 290° direction for approximately 1.7 nautical miles to a position located at Latitude 42°49′38″N., Longitude 79°17′36″W.; THENCE in a 029° direction for approximately 2.6 nautical miles to the point of beginning.</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Label>5</Label><Text>Parry Bay — Province of British Columbia</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Beginning at a point on the high water mark of Albert Head located at Latitude 48°23′05″N., Longitude 123°28′48″W., as shown on Canadian Hydrographic Service Chart 3440, edition dated March 11, 1983; THENCE in a straight line to a point at Latitude 48°21′12″N., Longitude 123°30′54″W.; THENCE in a straight line to a point on the high water mark at Latitude 48°21′51″N., Longitude 123°31′57″W.; THENCE in a northerly and easterly direction along the high water mark of Parry Bay to the point of beginning.</Text></Provision></Provision></Schedule></Regulation>