<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/99-335</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1999</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>28</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2007</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>13</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CANADA SHIPPING ACT, 2001</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Private Buoy Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Private Buoy Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1999-1364 </OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1999</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>28</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Transport and the Minister of Fisheries and Oceans, pursuant to sections 519 and 562<FootnoteRef idref="footnotea_e">a</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Shipping Act</XRefExternal>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Private Buoy Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="footnotea_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>R.S., c. 6 (3rd Supp.), s. 77</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>In these Regulations, <DefinedTermEn>private buoy</DefinedTermEn>means a buoy that is not owned by the federal government, a provincial government or a government agency.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>These Regulations apply to every private buoy other than private buoys used to mark fishing gear.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Placement Requirements</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>No person shall place in any Canadian waters a private buoy that interferes with or is likely to interfere with the navigation of any vessel, or that misleads or is likely to mislead the operator of any vessel.</Text></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>No person shall place a private buoy in any Canadian waters unless</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the part of the buoy that shows above the surface of the water is at least 15.25 cm wide and at least 30.5 cm high;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the buoy displays, on opposite sides, the capital letters “PRIV” that are</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>as large as is practical for the size of the buoy, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>white when the background colour is red, green or black;</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>black when the background colour is white or yellow;</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the buoy complies with the requirements set out in <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canadian Aids to Navigation</XRefExternal> (TP 968) published by the Canadian Coast Guard in 1995, as amended from time to time;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>the buoy displays, in a conspicuous location and in a permanent and legible manner, the name, address and telephone number of its owner;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the buoy is constructed and maintained in a manner and with materials that ensure that it remains in position and retains the characteristics specified in paragraphs (a) to (d); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>the buoy’s anchor is constructed and maintained in a manner and with materials that ensure that it remains in position.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>The owner of a private buoy placed in any Canadian waters shall ensure that the information required by paragraph (1)(d) is accurate at all times.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>If there is a need for increased visibility or better identification of a buoy for safety and the prevention of accidents, the Minister of Transport may order the owner of the buoy to modify it according to the requirements set out in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Procedures Manual for Design and Review of Short-range Aids to Navigation Systems</XRefExternal> (TP 9677), published in March 1989 by the Canadian Coast Guard, as amended from time to time.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2002-19, s. 1; SOR/2010-27, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>No person shall place in any Canadian waters a private buoy that has a light unless the light remains lit throughout the night and meets the requirements referred to in paragraph 4(1)(c).</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Removal</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>7</Label><Text>The Minister of Transport may remove from any Canadian waters a private buoy that does not comply with these Regulations.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2010-27, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Repeal</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>8</Label><Text>[Repeal]</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section type="transitional"><Label>9</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on the date on which they are registered.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>