<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en" in-force="yes"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2008-116</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>4</MM><DD>17</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>5</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">LOBBYING ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Lobbyists Registration Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2008-769</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>4</MM><DD>17</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the President of the Treasury Board, pursuant to section 12<FootnoteRef idref="fn_608777-e_hq_2923">a</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Lobbying Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_608777-e_hq_2924">b</FootnoteRef>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Lobbyists Registration Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fn_608777-e_hq_2923" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 2006, c. 9, s. 79 and ss. 81(g)</Text></Footnote><Footnote id="fn_608777-e_hq_2924" placement="page" status="official"><Label>b</Label><Text>R.S., c. 44 (4th Supp.); S.C. 2006, c. 9, s. 66</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>The following definitions apply in these Regulations.</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Lobbying Act</XRefExternal>. (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Commissioner</DefinedTermEn> means the Commissioner of Lobbying appointed under subsection 4.1(1) of the Act. (<DefinedTermFr>commissaire</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>consultant lobbyist</DefinedTermEn> means an individual who is required to file a return under subsection 5(1) of the Act. (<DefinedTermFr>lobbyiste-conseil</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>in-house lobbyist</DefinedTermEn> means an employee of a corporation or organization who is named in the return filed under subsection 7(1) of the Act. (<DefinedTermFr>lobbyiste salarié</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>member of a transition team</DefinedTermEn> means any person referred to in subsection 2(3) of the Act. (<DefinedTermFr>membre d’une équipe de transition</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Filing of Returns</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to subsection (2), a return shall be filed electronically.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A return may be filed in paper format if the person filing the return</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>has difficulty filing the return electronically because of a disability; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>does not have access to a computer system that allows them to file it electronically.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A return referred to in section 5 of the Act that is filed in paper format shall be in Form 1 of the schedule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A return referred to in section 7 of the Act that is filed in paper format on behalf of a corporation shall be in Form 2 of the schedule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>A return referred to in section 7 of the Act that is filed in paper format on behalf of an organization shall be in Form 3 of the schedule.</Text></Subsection></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A return that is filed in paper format must be delivered to the Commissioner’s office by mail, by facsimile transmission or by hand.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>A return is deemed to have been received</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>on the date of receipt stamped on the document by the Commissioner’s office, if the return is delivered by mail or by hand;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>on the date indicated by the receiving apparatus, if the return is sent by facsimile transmission; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>on the date that it enters the registry of the Commissioner’s office, if the return is filed electronically.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>A facsimile copy of the return is deemed to be the original.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2012-88, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Registration of Consultant Lobbyists</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Initial Return</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>A consultant lobbyist shall, with respect to a return filed under subsection 5(1) of the Act, include, in addition to the information required under subsection 5(2) of the Act, the following:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>if the client is a corporation, whether the consultant lobbyist is a member of the board of directors of the corporation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>if the client is an organization, whether the consultant lobbyist is a member of, or a member of the board of directors of, the organization;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>if the consultant lobbyist ceases to hold a designated public office on or after July 2, 2008 and they file the return less than five years after ceasing to hold the designated public office, whether they are subject to the five-year prohibition on lobbying set out in section 10.11 of the Act and, if not, the reason that they are not subject to it; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>if the consultant lobbyist ceased to be a transition team member on or after January 24, 2006 and they file the return less than five years after ceasing to carry out those functions, whether they are subject to the five-year prohibition on lobbying set out in section 10.11 of the Act and, if not, the reason that they are not subject to it; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>the name and title of the client’s principal representative with whom the consultant lobbyist deals.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Monthly Return</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>For the purposes of paragraph 5(3)(a) of the Act, the following types of communication are prescribed if made orally and arranged in advance of the communication:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a communication referred to in any of subparagraphs 5(1)(a)(i) to (vi) of the Act that is initiated by a person other than a public office holder; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a communication referred to in either subparagraph 5(1)(a)(v) or (vi) that is initiated by a public office holder.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>7</Label><Text>The consultant lobbyist shall, with respect to a return filed under subsection 5(3) of the Act, include, in addition to the information required under paragraph 5(3)(a) of the Act, the following:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the position title of the designated public office holder; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the name of the branch or unit and the name of the department or other governmental institution in which the designated public office holder is employed or serves at the time of the communication.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Registration of In-house Lobbyists (Corporations and Organizations)</TitleText></Heading><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Initial Return</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>8</Label><Text>The officer responsible shall, with respect to a return filed under subsection 7(1) of the Act, include, in addition to the information required under subsection 7(3) of the Act, the following:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>if an in-house lobbyist ceases to hold a designated public office on or after July 2, 2008 but less than five years before the return is filed, whether they are subject to the five-year prohibition on lobbying under section 10.11 of the Act and, if not, the reason why they are not subject to it; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>if an in-house lobbyist ceases to be a transition team member on or after January 24, 2006 but less than five years before the return is filed, whether they are subject to the five-year prohibition on lobbying under section 10.11 of the Act and, if not, the reason why they are not subject to it.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="2"><TitleText>Monthly Return</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>9</Label><Text>For the purposes of subsection 7(4) of the Act, the following types of communication are prescribed if made orally and arranged in advance of the communication:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a communication referred to in any of subparagraphs 7(1)(a)(i) to (v) of the Act that is initiated by a person other than a public office holder; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a communication referred to in subparagraph 7(1)(a)(v) of the Act that is initiated by a public office holder.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Section><Label>10</Label><Text>The officer responsible for filing shall, with respect to a return filed under subsection 7(4) of the Act, include, in addition to the information required under paragraph 7(4)(a) of the Act, the following:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the position title of the designated public office holder; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the name of the branch or unit and the name of the department or other governmental institution in which the designated public office holder is employed or serves at the time of the communication.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Clarification or Correction of Returns</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>11</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Any clarification to a return requested by the Commissioner under subsection 9(3.1) of the Act shall be provided by the individual who submitted the return, not later than 30 days after the day on which the request is made.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Any correction to a return requested by the Commissioner under subsection 9(3.1) of the Act shall be provided by the individual who submitted the return, not later than 10 days after the day on which the request is made.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>A request made by the Commissioner is deemed to have been made</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>on the date that it is post marked, if the request is mailed;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>on the date that it is delivered, if the request is delivered by hand;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>on the date indicated by the receiving apparatus, if the request is sent by facsimile transmission; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>on the date of transmission, if the request is sent by electronic mail.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(4)</Label><Text>A clarification or correction to a return is deemed to have been received</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>on the date of receipt stamped on the document by the Commissioner’s office, if the clarification or correction to the return is delivered by mail or by hand;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>on the date indicated by the receiving apparatus, if the clarification or correction to the return is sent by facsimile transmission; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>on the date of transmission, if the clarification or correction to the return is sent by electronic mail.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2012-88, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Repeal</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>12</Label><Text>[Repeal]</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section type="transitional"><Label>13</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on July 2, 2008.</Text></Section></Body><Schedule spanlanguages="yes"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 3)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><ImageGroup width="39pc"><AlternateText>Form 1 Return for Consultant Lobbyist - Consultant Lobbyist Registration Form</AlternateText><Image source="SOR-2008-116img\SOR-2008-116_e001.png" /></ImageGroup><ImageGroup width="40pc"><AlternateText>Continued Form 1 Return for Consultant Lobbyist - Consultant Lobbyist Registration Form</AlternateText><Image source="SOR-2008-116img\SOR-2008-116_e002.png" /></ImageGroup><ImageGroup width="40pc"><AlternateText>Continued Form 1 Return for Consultant Lobbyist - Consultant Lobbyist Registration Form</AlternateText><Image source="SOR-2008-116img\SOR-2008-116_e003.png" /></ImageGroup><ImageGroup width="40pc"><AlternateText>Continued Form 1 Return for Consultant Lobbyist - Consultant Lobbyist Registration Form</AlternateText><Image source="SOR-2008-116img\SOR-2008-116_e004.png" /></ImageGroup><ImageGroup width="40pc"><AlternateText>Continued Form 1 Return for Consultant Lobbyist - Consultant Lobbyist Registration Form</AlternateText><Image source="SOR-2008-116img\SOR-2008-116_e005.png" /></ImageGroup><ImageGroup width="40pc"><AlternateText>Form 2 Return for In-house Lobbyists (Corporation) - In-house Lobbyists (Corporation) Registration Form</AlternateText><Image source="SOR-2008-116img\SOR-2008-116_e006.png" /></ImageGroup><ImageGroup width="40pc"><AlternateText>Continued Form 2 Return for In-house Lobbyists (Corporation) - In-house Lobbyists (Corporation) Registration Form</AlternateText><Image source="SOR-2008-116img\SOR-2008-116_e007.png" /></ImageGroup><ImageGroup width="40pc"><AlternateText>Continued Form 2 Return for In-house Lobbyists (Corporation) - In-house Lobbyists (Corporation) Registration Form</AlternateText><Image source="SOR-2008-116img\SOR-2008-116_e008.png" /></ImageGroup><ImageGroup width="40pc"><AlternateText>Continued Form 2 Return for In-house Lobbyists (Corporation) - In-house Lobbyists (Corporation) Registration Form</AlternateText><Image source="SOR-2008-116img\SOR-2008-116_e009.png" /></ImageGroup><ImageGroup width="40pc"><AlternateText>Continued Form 2 Return for In-house Lobbyists (Corporation) - In-house Lobbyists (Corporation) Registration Form</AlternateText><Image source="SOR-2008-116img\SOR-2008-116_e010.png" /></ImageGroup><ImageGroup width="40pc"><AlternateText>Form 3 Return for In-house Lobbyists (Organization) - In-house Lobbyists (Organization) Registration Form</AlternateText><Image source="SOR-2008-116img\SOR-2008-116_e011.png" /></ImageGroup><ImageGroup width="40pc"><AlternateText>Continued Form 3 Return for In-house Lobbyists (Organization) - In-house Lobbyists (Organization) Registration Form</AlternateText><Image source="SOR-2008-116img\SOR-2008-116_e012.png" /></ImageGroup><ImageGroup width="40pc"><AlternateText>Continued Form 3 Return for In-house Lobbyists (Organization) - In-house Lobbyists (Organization) Registration Form</AlternateText><Image source="SOR-2008-116img\SOR-2008-116_e013.png" /></ImageGroup><ImageGroup width="40pc"><AlternateText>Continued Form 3 Return for In-house Lobbyists (Organization) - In-house Lobbyists (Organization) Registration Form</AlternateText><Image source="SOR-2008-116img\SOR-2008-116_e014.png" /></ImageGroup><HistoricalNote>SOR/2012-88, s. 3(F).</HistoricalNote></Schedule></Regulation>