<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/85-730</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1985</YYYY><MM>8</MM><DD>8</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2010</YYYY><MM>9</MM><DD>23</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Racing Products Transfer and Loan Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting the Transfer or Loan of Racing Photographic or Video Products</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1985-2417</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1985</YYYY><MM>8</MM><DD>7</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Agriculture and the Treasury Board, pursuant to section 52 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Financial Administration Act</XRefExternal>, is pleased hereby to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting the transfer or loan of racing photographic or video products</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Racing Products Transfer and Loan Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>agreement</DefinedTermEn> means an agreement referred to in subsection 3(1); (<DefinedTermFr>accord</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>association</DefinedTermEn> means an association as defined in subsection 188(9) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Criminal Code</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>association</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>contractor</DefinedTermEn> means a person who has contracted with the Minister to produce a product; (<DefinedTermFr>entrepreneur</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Director</DefinedTermEn> means the Director of the Race Track Division of the Department of Agriculture and includes any person designated by him to act on his behalf for the purposes of these Regulations; (<DefinedTermFr>directeur</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Minister</DefinedTermEn> means the Minister of Agriculture; (<DefinedTermFr>ministre</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>officer</DefinedTermEn> means a person appointed by the Minister pursuant to subsection 188(3) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Criminal Code</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>fonctionnaire</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>product</DefinedTermEn> means any photographic material, video material or video signal that relates to a horse race and that is produced for the Minister by a contractor by means of a photo-finish or video camera during the running of the race; (<DefinedTermFr>matériel</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>product user</DefinedTermEn> means a contractor or an association. (<DefinedTermFr>utilisateur</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Transfer or Loan</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to these Regulations, the Director is hereby authorized to transfer or loan products to product users and, for such purpose, to enter into an agreement in writing with any product user.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>An agreement may provide for the transfer or loan of products to the product user from time to time in accordance with the agreement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>An agreement shall provide</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>that the Director may at any time terminate the agreement if any product that has been transferred or loaned pursuant thereto is used by the product user contrary to the condition set out in section 4; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>that, where a product user to whom a product has been loaned pursuant to the agreement uses the product contrary to the condition set out in section 4, the product user shall deliver up the product to an officer forthwith after the Director requests the product user to do so.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/86-388, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Conditions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>The Director shall not transfer or loan a product pursuant to section 3 except subject to the condition that the product transferred or loaned will be used only for viewing or reproduction, or for both viewing and reproduction, for one or more of the following purposes:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>promoting the horse racing industry;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>compiling personal records for persons who participate in horse racing;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>assisting in informing legal telephone account bettors about horse races;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>informing legal telephone account bettors about horse races in conjunction with the distribution of pre-race or post-race betting information by an association; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>providing the public with general information about horse racing.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/86-388, s. 2(F).</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>The Director shall not loan a product to a product user unless the product user has entered into an agreement that complies with subsection 3(3).</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/86-388, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>6</Label><Text><Repealed>[Revoked, SOR/86-388, s. 3]</Repealed></Text></Section></Body></Regulation>