<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/87-603</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1987</YYYY><MM>10</MM><DD>15</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2011</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>27</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AERONAUTICS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>La Ronge Airport Zoning Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting Zoning at La Ronge Airport</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1987-2148</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1987</YYYY><MM>10</MM><DD>15</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas, pursuant to section 4.5 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Aeronautics Act</XRefExternal>, a copy of the proposed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Zoning Regulations respecting La Ronge Airport</XRefExternal>, substantially in the form set out in the schedule hereto, was published in two successive issues of the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal> Part I on May 16th and 23rd, 1987, and in two successive issues of The Northerner La Ronge on July 8th and 15th, 1987, and a reasonable opportunity was thereby afforded to interested persons to make representations to the Minister of Transport with respect thereto.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Therefore, Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Transport, pursuant to section 4.4 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Aeronautics Act</XRefExternal>, is pleased hereby to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting zoning at La Ronge Airport</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">La Ronge Airport Zoning Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>airport</DefinedTermEn> means the La Ronge Airport, in the vicinity of La Ronge, in the Province of Saskatchewan; (<DefinedTermFr>aéroport</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>airport reference point</DefinedTermEn> means the point described in Part I of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>point de repère de l’aéroport</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>approach surface</DefinedTermEn> means an imaginary inclined plane that extends upward and outward from each end of a strip, which approach surface is more particularly described in Part II of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>surface d’approche</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Minister</DefinedTermEn> means the Minister of Transport; (<DefinedTermFr>ministre</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>outer surface</DefinedTermEn> means an imaginary surface located above and in the immediate vicinity of the airport, which outer surface is more particularly described in Part III of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>surface extérieure</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>strip</DefinedTermEn> means the rectangular portion of the landing area of the airport, including the runway, prepared for the take-off and landing of aircraft in a particular direction, which strip is more particularly described in Part IV of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>bande</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>transitional surface</DefinedTermEn> means an imaginary inclined plane that extends upward and outward from the lateral limits of a strip and its approach surfaces, which transitional surface is more particularly described in Part V of the schedule. (<DefinedTermFr>surface de transition</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>For the purposes of these Regulations, the elevation of the airport reference point is 372 m above sea level.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-87, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>These Regulations apply to all the lands, including public road allowances, adjacent to or in the vicinity of the airport, which lands are more particularly described as follows:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the lands within the outer limits of lands described in Part VI of the schedule; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the lands directly under that portion of the approach surfaces that extend beyond the said outer limits.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-87, s. 2(F).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>No person shall erect or construct on any land to which these Regulations apply, any building, structure or object or any addition to any existing building, structure or object, the highest point of which will exceed in elevation at the location of that point</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the approach surfaces;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the outer surface; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the transitional surfaces.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-87, s. 3(F).</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Natural Growth</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>Where an object of natural growth on any land to which these Regulations apply exceeds in elevation any of the surfaces referred to in paragraphs 4(a) to (c), the Minister may require that the owner or occupier of the land on which that object is growing remove the growth or the excessive portion thereof.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Disposal of Waste</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>No owner or occupier of any land to which these Regulations apply shall permit that land or any part of it to be used for the disposal of any waste that is edible by or attractive to birds.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-87, s. 4(F).</HistoricalNote></Section></Body><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label><OriginatingRef>(Sections 2 and 3)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><Heading level="1"><Label>PART I</Label><TitleText>Description of the Airport Reference Point</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The airport reference point, shown on Public Works Canada La Ronge Airport Zoning Plan No. E.1882 dated July 5, 1985, is a point located on the centre line of runway 17-35 distant 762 m southerly from the 17 end of the said runway.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART II</Label><TitleText>Description of the Approach Surfaces</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The approach surfaces, shown on Public Works Canada La Ronge Airport Zoning Plan No. E.1882 dated July 5, 1985, are surfaces abutting each end of the strip associated with the runways designated 17-35 and 10-28 and are described as follows:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a surface abutting the end of the strip associated with runway approach 35, consisting of an inclined plane having a ratio of 1 m measured vertically to 60 m measured horizontally, rising to an intersection with the outer surface, thence said approach surface shall slope upward at a ratio of 1 m measured vertically to 50 m measured horizontally rising to an imaginary horizontal line drawn at right angles to the projected centre line of the strip and distant 15 000 m measured horizontally from the end of the strip; the outer ends of the imaginary horizontal line being 2 400 m from the projected centre line; said imaginary horizontal line being 291.5 m measured vertically above the elevation at the end of the strip;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a surface abutting the end of the strip associated with runway approach 17, consisting of an inclined plane having a ratio of 1 m measured vertically to 60 m measured horizontally, rising to an intersection with the outer surface, thence said approach surface shall slope upward at a ratio of 1 m measured vertically to 50 m measured horizontally rising to an imaginary horizontal line drawn at right angles to the projected centre line of the strip and distant 15 000 m measured horizontally from the end of the strip; the outer ends of the imaginary horizontal line being 2 400 m from the projected centre line; said imaginary horizontal line being 292.3 m measured vertically above the elevation at the end of the strip;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a surface abutting the end of the strip associated with runway approach 10, consisting of an inclined plane having a ratio of 1 m measured vertically to 40 m measured horizontally, rising to an imaginary horizontal line drawn at right angles to the projected centre line of the strip and distant 2 500 m measured horizontally from the end of the strip; the outer ends of the imaginary horizontal line being 280.5 m from the projected centre line; said imaginary horizontal line being 62.5 m measured vertically above the elevation at the end of the strip; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a surface abutting the end of the strip associated with runway approach 28, consisting of an inclined plane having a ratio of 1 m measured vertically to 40 m measured horizontally, rising to an imaginary horizontal line drawn at right angles to the projected centre line of the strip and distant 2 500 m measured horizontally from the end of the strip; the outer ends of the imaginary horizontal line being 280.5 m from the projected centre line; said imaginary horizontal line being 62.5 m measured vertically above the elevation at the end of the strip.</Text></Provision></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART III</Label><TitleText>Description of the Outer Surface</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The outer surface, shown on Public Works Canada La Ronge Airport Zoning Plan No. E.1882 dated July 5, 1985, is an imaginary surface located at a common plane established at a constant elevation of 45 m above the elevation of the airport reference point, except that, where that common plane is less than 9 m above the surface of the ground, the outer surface is an imaginary surface located at 9 m above the surface of the ground.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART IV</Label><TitleText>Description of the Strips</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The strips, shown on Public Works Canada La Ronge Airport Zoning Plan No. E.1882 dated July 5, 1985, are described as follows:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the strip associated with runway 17-35 is 300 m in width, 150 m on each side of the centre line of the runway and 1 949 m in length; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the strip associated with runway 10-28 is 61 m in width, 30.5 m on each side of the centre line of the runway and 974 m in length.</Text></Provision></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART V</Label><TitleText>Description of the Transitional Surfaces</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The transitional surfaces, shown on Public Works Canada La Ronge Airport Zoning Plan No. E.1882 dated July 5, 1985, are described as follows:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the transitional surface associated with runway 17-35 is a surface consisting of an inclined plane rising at a ratio of 1 m measured vertically to 7 m measured horizontally at right angles to the centre line and projected centre line of the strip extending upward and outward from the lateral limits of the strip and its approach surfaces to an intersection with the outer surface or another transitional surface of an adjoining strip; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the transitional surface associated with runway 10-28 is a surface consisting of an inclined plane rising at a ratio of 1 m measured vertically to 5 m measured horizontally at right angles to the centre line and projected centre line of the strip extending upward and outward from the lateral limits of the strip and its approach surfaces to an intersection with the outer surface or another transitional surface of an adjoining strip.</Text></Provision></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART VI</Label><TitleText>Description of the Lands to Which These Regulations Apply</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The boundary of the outer limits of lands, shown on Public Works Canada La Ronge Airport Zoning Plan No. E.1882, dated July 5, 1985, is described as follows:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>COMMENCING at a point on the southeasterly limit of Public Reserve R5, Registered Plan 78PA07498 where it is intersected by the circumference of a circle having a radius of 4 000 meters and centered at the airport reference point as described in Part I of the schedule;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE, in an easterly direction following the circumference of the said circle counterclockwise to a point where it intersects the northwesterly limit of Poirier Street Registered Plan 76PA24040;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE, southwesterly along the said northwesterly limit to its intersection with the production northwesterly of the northeasterly limit of Lot 23, Block 29, Registered Plan 80PA03018;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE, southeasterly across Poirier Street and along the northeasterly limit of the said Lot 23 to the westerly corner of Lot 25, Block 29, Registered Plan 80PA13345;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE, northeasterly along the northwesterly limits of Lots 25, 26 and 27, Block 29 to the northerly corner of Lot 27;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE, southeasterly along the northeasterly limit of Lot 27 and its production across Finlayson Street and Parcel J, Registered Plan 70PA08594 to its intersection with the northwesterly limit of Block 38, Registered Plan 80PA19051;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE, northeasterly along the northwesterly limit Block 38 to the northerly corner of Lot 17;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE, southeasterly along the northeasterly limit of Lot 17, Block 38, to the easterly corner of Lot 17, Block 38;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE, northerly, easterly and southeasterly along the easterly, southerly and southwesterly limits of Lots 16 to 2 inclusive, Block 38, Registered Plan 78PA20750 and the intervening lane to the most southerly corner of the said Lot 2, Block 38;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE, northeasterly along the southeasterly limits of Lots 2 and 1, Block 38 to the easterly corner of Lot 1, Block 38;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE, southeasterly across Studer Street and along the northeasterly limit of Lot 2, Block 36, Registered Plan 78PA20750, to the easterly corner of Lot 2, Block 36;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE, northeasterly along the southeasterly limit of Block 36 to the most easterly corner of Lot 9, across Mowery Crescent and continuing northeasterly and easterly along the southeasterly and southerly limits of Block 18, Registered Plan 76PA24039 to the southeast corner of Lot 8, Block 18;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE, southeasterly across Parcel J, Registered Plan 70PA08594 to the northwest corner of Lot 6, Registered Plan 76PA24039;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE, southeasterly along the southwesterly limits of Blocks 18, 12 and across the intervening Mowery Crescent to the southerly corner of Lot 50, Block 12;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE, northeasterly along the southeasterly limit of Lot 50 and its production across Studer Street to the northeasterly limit of Studer Street;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE, southeasterly along the northeasterly limit of Studer Street to the northwesterly limit of Bedford Drive;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>THENCE, northeasterly along the northwesterly limit of Bedford Drive and Public Reserve R.5 to the point of commencement.</Text></Provision></Provision><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-87, ss. 5(F), 6(E), 7(E) and 8.</HistoricalNote></Schedule></Regulation>