<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/93-420</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1993</YYYY><MM>8</MM><DD>6</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>9</MM><DD>27</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">BROADCASTING ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Broadcasting Information Regulations, 1993</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting Broadcasting Information Requirements</LongTitle></Identification><Order><Provision language-align="yes" format-ref="indent-0-0" list-item="no"><Text>Whereas, pursuant to subsection 10(3) of the Broadcasting Act<FootnoteRef idref="footnote1star_e">*</FootnoteRef>, a copy of the proposed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting broadcasting information requirements</XRefExternal>, substantially in the form annexed hereto, was published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal> Part I on July 3, 1993 and a reasonable opportunity was thereby given to licensees and other interested persons to make representations to the Canadian Radio-television and Telecommunications Commission with respect thereto;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>Therefore, the Canadian Radio-television and Telecommunications Commission, pursuant to subsection 10(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Broadcasting Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="footnote1star_e">*</FootnoteRef>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting broadcasting information requirements</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Text>Hull, Quebec, August 5, 1993</Text><Footnote id="footnote1star_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>S.C. 1991, c. 11</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Broadcasting Information Regulations, 1993</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Submission of Information</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Subject to section 3, on or before November 30 of each year, a licensee that charges a fee to subscribers or to another licensee that charges a fee to subscribers shall submit to the Commission a statement of accounts, on the annual return of broadcasting licensee form, for the year ending on the previous August 31.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>At the request of the Commission, a licensee shall respond to</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any complaint or request for resolution of a dispute filed by any person or any request for information regarding the programming originated or distributed by the licensee or regarding the licensee’s technical operations, subscribership, financial affairs or ownership; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any request for information regarding the licensee’s adherence to the conditions of its licence, the Act, these Regulations, industry standards, practices or codes or any other self-regulatory mechanism of the industry.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>In this section, <DefinedTermEn>subscriber</DefinedTermEn> means</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a household of one or more persons, whether occupying a single-unit dwelling or a unit in a multiple-unit dwelling, to which service is provided directly or indirectly by the holder of a licence, as defined in section 2 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Broadcasting Act</XRefExternal>; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the owner or operator of any hotel, hospital, nursing home or other commercial or institutional premises to which service is provided by the holder of a licence, as defined in section 2 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Broadcasting Act</XRefExternal>.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/96-414, s. 1; SOR/2011-147, s. 12.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>Any licensee that is required by any other regulation made under the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Broadcasting Act</XRefExternal> to submit to the Commission any information requested on the form referred to in subsection 2(1) or on any matter referred to in subsection 2(2) is not required to submit the information to the Commission pursuant to that subsection.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>