<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2002-195</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2002</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>23</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>3</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">FOREIGN MISSIONS AND INTERNATIONAL ORGANIZATIONS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Regulations Clarifying the Application of Provisions of the Convention on the Privileges and Immunities of the United Nations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2002-827 </OrderNumber><Date><YYYY> 2002</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>23</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Whereas the Governor General in Council considers it necessary to clarify, in relation to section 5 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Foreign Missions and International Organizations Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-2002-195_e_hq_5854">a</FootnoteRef>, the application of the Convention on the Privileges and Immunities of the United Nations.</Text><Footnote id="fn_SOR-2002-195_e_hq_5854" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 2000, c. 12, s. 119</Text></Footnote></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Therefore, Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Foreign Affairs, pursuant to section 13<FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-2002-195_e_hq_5855">b</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Foreign Missions and International Organizations Act</XRefExternal>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations Clarifying the Application of Provisions of the Convention on the Privileges and Immunities of the United Nations</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fn_SOR-2002-195_e_hq_5855" placement="page" status="official"><Label>b</Label><Text>S.C. 1991, c. 41</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>The following definitions apply in these Regulations.</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Foreign Missions and International Organizations Act</XRefExternal>. (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>common-law partner</DefinedTermEn> means, in relation to an individual, a person who is cohabiting with the individual in a conjugal relationship, having so cohabited for a period of at least one year. (<DefinedTermFr>conjoint de fait</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Convention</DefinedTermEn> means the Convention on the Privileges and Immunities of the United Nations set out in Schedule III to the Act. (<DefinedTermFr>Convention</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Clarification</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>For the purpose of clarifying, in relation to section 5 of the Act, the application of provisions of the Convention, in particular paragraphs 11(d) and 18(d) and (f) and section 19, the Convention shall be applied in Canada in a manner that extends to common-law partners the treatment afforded to spouses.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>For the purpose of clarifying, in relation to section 5 of the Act, the application of provisions of the Convention, the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Organization of American States Privileges and Immunities in Canada Order</XRefExternal>, the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">International Telecommunication Union Privileges and Immunities Order</XRefExternal> and subsection 5(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Agence de la Francophonie and the Institut de l’énergie et de l’environnement de la Francophonie Privileges and Immunities Order</XRefExternal>, the privileges and immunities accorded under paragraphs 11(d) and 18(d) and (f) and section 19 of the Convention are extended to the spouses and common-law partners of the persons referred to in those provisions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(3)</Label><Text>For the purpose of clarifying, in relation to section 5 of the Act, the application of provisions of the Convention, in particular section 19, the Convention shall be applied in Canada in a manner that extends, to the minor children of a spouse or common-law partner of the persons referred to in that section, the treatment afforded to the minor children of those persons.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on the day on which they are registered.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>