<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2007-285</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2007</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>13</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>1</MM><DD>3</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">SPECIAL ECONOMIC MEASURES ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Special Economic Measures (Burma) Regulations</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2007-1913</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>2007</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>13</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas the Governor in Council is of the opinion that the situation in Burma constitutes a grave breach of international peace and security that has resulted or is likely to result in a serious international crisis;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Text>Therefore, Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Foreign Affairs, pursuant to subsections 4(1) to (3) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Special Economic Measures Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_610627-E_hq_3215">a</FootnoteRef>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Special Economic Measures (Burma) Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fn_610627-E_hq_3215" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 1992, c. 17</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>The following definitions apply in these Regulations.</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><MarginalNote><DefinedTermEn>arms and related material</DefinedTermEn></MarginalNote><MarginalNote><DefinedTermFr>armes et matériel connexe</DefinedTermFr></MarginalNote><Text><DefinedTermEn>arms and related material</DefinedTermEn> means any type of weapon, ammunition, military vehicle or military or paramilitary equipment, and includes their spare parts.</Text></Definition><Definition><MarginalNote><DefinedTermEn>Burma</DefinedTermEn></MarginalNote><MarginalNote><DefinedTermFr>Birmanie</DefinedTermFr></MarginalNote><Text><DefinedTermEn>Burma</DefinedTermEn> means Myanmar, and includes</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any political subdivision of Myanmar;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the government, and any department of Myanmar or of a political subdivision of Myanmar; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>any agency of Myanmar or of a political subdivision of Myanmar.</Text></Paragraph></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>controlling interest</DefinedTermEn><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2012-85, s. 1]</Repealed></Text></Definition><Definition><MarginalNote><DefinedTermEn>designated person</DefinedTermEn></MarginalNote><MarginalNote><DefinedTermFr>personne designée</DefinedTermFr></MarginalNote><Text><DefinedTermEn>designated person</DefinedTermEn> means a person whose name is listed on the schedule in accordance with section 2.</Text></Definition><Definition><MarginalNote><DefinedTermEn>Minister</DefinedTermEn></MarginalNote><MarginalNote><DefinedTermFr>ministre</DefinedTermFr></MarginalNote><Text><DefinedTermEn>Minister</DefinedTermEn> means the Minister of Foreign Affairs.</Text></Definition><Definition><MarginalNote><DefinedTermEn>pension</DefinedTermEn></MarginalNote><MarginalNote><DefinedTermFr>pension</DefinedTermFr></MarginalNote><Text><DefinedTermEn>pension</DefinedTermEn> means a benefit paid under the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Old Age Security Act</XRefExternal>, the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Pension Plan</XRefExternal> or an <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Act respecting the Quebec Pension Plan</XRefExternal>, R.S.Q. c. R-9, any superannuation, pension or benefit paid under or in respect of any retirement savings plan or under any retirement plan, any amount paid under or in respect of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Garnishment, Attachment and Pension Diversion Act</XRefExternal> or the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Pension Benefits Division Act</XRefExternal>, and any other payment made in respect of disability.</Text></Definition><HistoricalNote>SOR/2012-85, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>List</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Designated person</MarginalNote><Label>2</Label><Text>A person whose name is listed in the schedule is a person in respect of whom the Governor in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister, is satisfied that there are reasonable grounds to believe is</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a former or current senior official of the Government of Burma, the State Peace and Development Council of Burma, the Union Solidarity and Development Association of Burma or a successor to any of the foregoing;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>an associate or family member of a person set out in paragraph (a);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>an entity owned, controlled or acting on behalf of a person set out in paragraphs (a) or (b); or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>an entity owned or controlled or acting on behalf of the Government of Burma, the State Peace and Development Council of Burma, the Union Solidarity and Development Association of Burma or a successor to any of the foregoing.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Prohibitions</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Asset freeze</MarginalNote><Label>3</Label><Text>Subject to section 18, it is prohibited for any person in Canada and any Canadian outside Canada to</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>deal in any property, wherever situated, held by or on behalf of a designated person;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>enter into or facilitate any transaction related to a dealing referred to in paragraph (a);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>provide any financial or related service in respect of a dealing referred to in paragraph (a);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>make any goods, wherever situated, available to a designated person; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>provide any financial or related service to or for the benefit of a designated person.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2012-85, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Restricted or prohibited activities</MarginalNote><Label>4</Label><Text>Subject to section 19, it is prohibited for any person in Canada and any Canadian outside Canada to</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>export, sell, supply, ship, transport or otherwise deal in arms and related material, wherever situated, destined for Burma or any person in Burma;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>import, purchase, acquire, ship, transport or otherwise deal in arms and related material, wherever situated, that are exported from Burma after December 13, 2007;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>transfer, provide or communicate technical data related to military activities or to the provision, manufacture, maintenance or use of arms and related material to Burma or any person in Burma; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>provide or acquire financial or other services related to military activities or to the provision, manufacture, maintenance or use of arms and related material to, from or for the benefit of or on the direction or order of Burma or any person in Burma.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2012-85, s. 2.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>5</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2012-85, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>6</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2012-85, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>7</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2012-85, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>8</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2012-85, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>9</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2012-85, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>10</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2012-85, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>11</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2012-85, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><Label>12</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2012-85, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Prohibition</MarginalNote><Label>13</Label><Text>No person in Canada and no Canadian outside Canada shall do anything that causes, assists or promotes, or is intended to cause, assist or promote, any act or thing prohibited by section 3 or 4.</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/2012-85, s. 3.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Duty to Determine</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Determination</MarginalNote><Label>14</Label><Text>Each of the following entities must determine on a continuing basis whether it is in possession or control of property owned or controlled by or on behalf of a designated person:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>authorized foreign banks, as defined in section 2 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Bank Act</XRefExternal>, in respect of their business in Canada or banks to which that Act applies;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>cooperative credit societies, savings and credit unions and caisses populaires regulated by a provincial Act and associations regulated by the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Cooperative Credit Associations Act</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>foreign companies, as defined in subsection 2(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Insurance Companies Act</XRefExternal>, in respect of their insurance business in Canada;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>companies, provincial companies and societies, as those terms are defined in subsection 2(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Insurance Companies Act</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>fraternal benefit societies regulated by a provincial Act in respect of their insurance activities and insurance companies and other entities engaged in the business of insuring risks that are regulated by a provincial Act;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(f)</Label><Text>companies to which the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Trust and Loan Companies Act</XRefExternal> applies;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(g)</Label><Text>trust companies regulated by a provincial Act;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(h)</Label><Text>loan companies regulated by a provincial Act;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>entities authorized under provincial legislation to engage in the business of dealing in securities, or to provide portfolio management or investment counselling services; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(j)</Label><Text>entities that engage in any activity described in paragraph 5(h) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Proceeds of Crime (Money Laundering) and Terrorist Financing Act</XRefExternal> if the activity involves the opening of an account for a client.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2012-85, s. 4.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Disclosure</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Report</MarginalNote><Label>15</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Every person in Canada and every Canadian outside Canada shall disclose without delay to the Commissioner of the Royal Canadian Mounted Police</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the existence of property in their possession or control that they have reason to believe is owned or controlled, directly or indirectly, by a designated person or by an entity owned or controlled by a designated person; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>information about a transaction or proposed transaction in respect of property referred to in paragraph (a).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Immunity</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>No person contravenes subsection (1) by disclosing in good faith under that subsection.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application to No Longer Be a Designated Person</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Petition</MarginalNote><Label>16</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A designated person may apply to the Minister in writing to have their name removed from the schedule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Decision</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>On receipt of an application, the Minister shall decide whether there are reasonable grounds to recommend to the Governor in Council that the applicant’s name be removed from the schedule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Presumption</MarginalNote><Label>(3)</Label><Text>If the Minister does not make a decision on the application within 90 days after the day on which the application is received, the Minister is deemed to have decided to recommend that the applicant remain a designated person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Notice</MarginalNote><Label>(4)</Label><Text>The Minister shall give notice without delay to the applicant of any decision taken or deemed to have been taken.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>New application</MarginalNote><Label>(5)</Label><Text>If there has been a material change in circumstances since the last petition was submitted, a person may submit another application under subsection (1).</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/2012-85, s. 5.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application for a Certificate</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Mistaken identity</MarginalNote><Label>17</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>A person claiming not to be a designated person may apply to the Minister for a certificate stating that they are not the person who has been designated under section 2.</Text></Subsection><Subsection><MarginalNote>Certificate — time frame</MarginalNote><Label>(2)</Label><Text>If it is established that the person is not a designated person, the Minister shall issue a certificate to the applicant within 15 days after the day on which the application is received.</Text></Subsection></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Exclusions</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Exceptions to section 3</MarginalNote><Label>18</Label><Text>Section 3 does not apply in respect of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any activity engaged in under an agreement or arrangement between Canada and Burma;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any payment made by or on behalf of a designated person that is due under a contract entered into before the person became a designated person, provided that the payment is not made to or for the benefit of a designated person;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>any goods made available, or services provided, to or by any of the following entities for the purpose of safeguarding human life, disaster relief, democratization, stabilization or providing food, medicine, medical supplies or equipment or development assistance:</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>an international organization with diplomatic status,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>a United Nations agency,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>the International Red Cross and Red Crescent Movement, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iv)</Label><Text>a non-governmental organization that has entered into a grant or contribution agreement with the Department of Foreign Affairs and International Trade or the Canadian International Development Agency; and</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>any transaction necessary for a Canadian to transfer any existing accounts, funds or investments of a Canadian held with a designated person to a person other than a designated person.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2012-85, s. 6.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><MarginalNote>Exceptions to section 4</MarginalNote><Label>19</Label><Text>Section 4 does not apply in respect of</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>protective clothing and equipment, including flak jackets and military helmets, for the personal use of United Nations personnel, human rights monitors, representatives of the media and humanitarian and development workers and associated personnel;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>non-lethal military equipment intended solely for humanitarian, human rights monitoring or protective use, and related technical assistance and training; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>members of the Canadian Forces who are in or travel to Burma in the performance of official duties, including providing security to Canadian diplomatic staff, providing humanitarian assistance, or engaging in other activities authorized by the Chief of the Defence Staff.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/2012-85, s. 6.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application Prior to Publication</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Application</MarginalNote><Label>20</Label><Text>For the purpose of paragraph 11(2)(a) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Statutory Instruments Act</XRefExternal>, these Regulations apply according to their terms before they are published in the Canada Gazette.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Registration</MarginalNote><Label>21</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on the day on which they are registered.</Text></Section></Body><Schedule><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 2)</OriginatingRef><TitleText>Persons</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><Heading level="1" style="listcaption"><Label>PART 1</Label><TitleText>Entities</TitleText></Heading><List first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2"><Item><Label>1</Label><Text>Air Bagan (also known among other names as Air Bagan Holdings Pte. Ltd. and Air Bagan Limited)</Text></Item><Item><Label>2</Label><Text>Bandoola Transportation Co. Ltd.</Text></Item><Item><Label>3</Label><Text>Berger Paint Manufacturing Co. Ltd.</Text></Item><Item><Label>4</Label><Text>Dagon Brewery</Text></Item><Item><Label>5</Label><Text>Granite Tile Factory (Kyaikto)</Text></Item><Item><Label>6</Label><Text>Hantha Waddy Golf Resort and Myodaw (City) Club Ltd.</Text></Item><Item><Label>7</Label><Text>Htoo Furniture (also known among other names as Htoo Wood, Htoo Wood Products, Htoo Wood Products Pte. Limited and Htoo Wood-Based Industry)</Text></Item><Item><Label>8</Label><Text>Htoo Group of Companies (also known among other names as Htoo Trading Company Limited and Htoo Trading Group Company)</Text></Item><Item><Label>9</Label><Text>Innwa Bank</Text></Item><Item><Label>10</Label><Text>MEC Disposable Syringe Factory</Text></Item><Item><Label>11</Label><Text>MEC Marble Mine</Text></Item><Item><Label>12</Label><Text>MEC Marble Tiles Factory</Text></Item><Item><Label>13</Label><Text>MEC Burma Cable Wire Factory</Text></Item><Item><Label>14</Label><Text>MEC Oxygen and Gases Factory</Text></Item><Item><Label>15</Label><Text>MEC Ship Breaking Service</Text></Item><Item><Label>16</Label><Text>MEC Steel Mills (Hmaw Bi/Pyi/Ywama)</Text></Item><Item><Label>17</Label><Text>MICB (also known among other names as Myanma Investment and Commercial Bank and Burma Investment and Commercial Bank)</Text></Item><Item><Label>18</Label><Text>Myaing Galay (Rhino Brand) Cement Factory</Text></Item><Item><Label>19</Label><Text>Myanma Economic Bank (also known among other names as Burma Economic Bank)</Text></Item><Item><Label>20</Label><Text>Myanma Economic Corporation (MEC)</Text></Item><Item><Label>21</Label><Text>Myanma Foreign Trade Bank (also known among other names as Burma Foreign Trade Bank)</Text></Item><Item><Label>22</Label><Text>Burma Ar (Power) Construction Services</Text></Item><Item><Label>23</Label><Text>Burma Brewery Ltd.</Text></Item><Item><Label>24</Label><Text>Burma Daewoo International</Text></Item><Item><Label>25</Label><Text>Burma Imperial Jade Co. Ltd.</Text></Item><Item><Label>26</Label><Text>Burma Nouveau Steel Co. Ltd.</Text></Item><Item><Label>27</Label><Text>Burma Posco Steel Co. Ltd.</Text></Item><Item><Label>28</Label><Text>Burma Rubber Wood Co. Ltd.</Text></Item><Item><Label>29</Label><Text>Burma Ruby Enterprise</Text></Item><Item><Label>30</Label><Text>Burma Segal International Ltd.</Text></Item><Item><Label>31</Label><Text>Myawaddy Bank Ltd.</Text></Item><Item><Label>32</Label><Text>Myawaddy Trading Ltd.</Text></Item><Item><Label>33</Label><Text>Myawaddy Travel Services</Text></Item><Item><Label>34</Label><Text>National Development Corp.</Text></Item><Item><Label>35</Label><Text>Nawaday Hotel and Travel Services</Text></Item><Item><Label>36</Label><Text>Ngwe Pin Le (Silver Sea) Livestock Breeding and Fishery Co.</Text></Item><Item><Label>37</Label><Text>Pavo Trading Pte. Ltd.</Text></Item><Item><Label>38</Label><Text>Rothman of Pall Mall Burma Private Ltd.</Text></Item><Item><Label>39</Label><Text>Sin Min (King Elephants) Cement Factory (Kyaukse)</Text></Item><Item><Label>40</Label><Text>Soap Factory (Paung)</Text></Item><Item><Label>41</Label><Text>The First Automotive Co. Ltd.</Text></Item><Item><Label>42</Label><Text>Union of Burma Economic Holding Ltd.</Text></Item><Item><Label>43</Label><Text>Yuzana Company Limited (also known among other names as Yuzana Construction)</Text></Item><Item><Label>44</Label><Text>Zay Gabar Company (also known among other names as Zaykabar Company)</Text></Item></List><Heading level="1" style="listcaption"><Label>PART 2</Label><TitleText>Individuals</TitleText></Heading><List first-line-indent="0" subsequent-line-indent="2"><Item><Label>1</Label><Text>Than Shwe, born February 2, 1933</Text></Item><Item><Label>2</Label><Text>Maung Aye, born December 25, 1937</Text></Item><Item><Label>3</Label><Text>Khin Lay Thet, born June 19, 1947</Text></Item><Item><Label>4</Label><Text>Aung Thet Mann, born June 19, 1977 (also known among other names as Shwe Mann Ko Ko)</Text></Item><Item><Label>5</Label><Text>Toe Naing Mann, born June 29, 1978</Text></Item><Item><Label>6</Label><Text>Zay Zin Latt, born March 24, 1981</Text></Item><Item><Label>7</Label><Text>Tin Aung Myint Oo, born May 27, 1950</Text></Item><Item><Label>8</Label><Text>Kyaw Win, born January 3, 1944</Text></Item><Item><Label>9</Label><Text>Ye Myint, born October 21, 1943</Text></Item><Item><Label>10</Label><Text>Tin Lin Myint, born January 25, 1947</Text></Item><Item><Label>11</Label><Text>Aung Htwe, born February 1, 1943</Text></Item><Item><Label>12</Label><Text>Maung Bo, born February 16, 1945</Text></Item><Item><Label>13</Label><Text>Tin Naing Thein, born 1955</Text></Item><Item><Label>14</Label><Text>Saw Tun, born May 8, 1935</Text></Item><Item><Label>15</Label><Text>Chan Nyein, born 1944 (also known among other names as Chang Nyein)</Text></Item><Item><Label>16</Label><Text>Zaw Min, born January 10, 1949</Text></Item><Item><Label>17</Label><Text>Lun Thi, born July 18, 1940</Text></Item><Item><Label>18</Label><Text>Hla Tun, born July 11, 1951</Text></Item><Item><Label>19</Label><Text>Nyan Win, born January 22, 1953</Text></Item><Item><Label>20</Label><Text>Kyaw Myint, born 1940</Text></Item><Item><Label>21</Label><Text>Maung Oo, born 1952</Text></Item><Item><Label>22</Label><Text>Saw Lwin, born 1939</Text></Item><Item><Label>23</Label><Text>Soe Tha, born 1945</Text></Item><Item><Label>24</Label><Text>Thaung, born July 6, 1937</Text></Item><Item><Label>25</Label><Text>Thein Zaw, born October 20, 1951</Text></Item><Item><Label>26</Label><Text>Kyaw Thu, born August 15, 1949</Text></Item><Item><Label>27</Label><Text>Mya Oo, born January 25, 1940</Text></Item><Item><Label>28</Label><Text>Myint Swe, born May 24, 1951</Text></Item><Item><Label>29</Label><Text>Hsan Hsint, born 1951</Text></Item><Item><Label>30</Label><Text>Than Sein, born February 1, 1946</Text></Item><Item><Label>31</Label><Text>Tay Za, born July 8, 1964</Text></Item><Item><Label>32</Label><Text>Thidar Zaw, born February 24, 1964</Text></Item><Item><Label>33</Label><Text>Pye Phyo Tay Za, born January 29, 1987</Text></Item><Item><Label>34</Label><Text>Thiha, born June 24, 1960</Text></Item><Item><Label>35</Label><Text>Khin Shwe, born January 21, 1952</Text></Item><Item><Label>36</Label><Text>Zay Thiha, born January 1, 1977</Text></Item><Item><Label>37</Label><Text>Khin Nyunt, born October 11, 1939</Text></Item><Item><Label>38</Label><Text>Khin Win Shwe, born October 6, 1940</Text></Item></List><HistoricalNote>SOR/2012-85, s. 7.</HistoricalNote></Schedule><Schedule id="RelatedProvs"><ScheduleFormHeading type="amending"><TitleText>RELATED PROVISIONS</TitleText></ScheduleFormHeading><RegulationPiece><Heading level="5" style="nifrp"><TitleText>
                    — SOR/2012-85, s. 8</TitleText></Heading><Section><MarginalNote>Application</MarginalNote><Label>8.</Label><Text>For the purpose of paragraph 11(2)(a) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Statutory Instruments Act</XRefExternal>, these Regulations apply according to their terms before they are published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section></RegulationPiece></Schedule></Regulation>