<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/88-397</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1988</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>24</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">ROYAL CANADIAN MOUNTED POLICE ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Royal Canadian Mounted Police External Review Committee Security and Confidentiality Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting the Security and Confidentiality of Information to which Members of the Royal Canadian Mounted Police External Review Committee and Persons Employed by the Royal Canadian Mounted Police External Review Committee May Have Access in the Performance of their Duties</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1988-1478</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1988</YYYY><MM>7</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Solicitor General of Canada, pursuant to subsection 21(1)<FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-88-397_e_hq_6242">*</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Royal Canadian Mounted Police Act</XRefExternal>, is pleased hereby to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting the security and confidentiality of information to which members of the Royal Canadian Mounted Police External Review Committee and persons employed by the Royal Canadian Mounted Police External Review Committee may have access in the performance of their duties</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fn_SOR-88-397_e_hq_6242" placement="page" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>S.C. 1986, c. 11, s. 11</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Royal Canadian Mounted Police External Review Committee Security and Confidentiality Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Security Requirements</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>Every member of the Committee and every person employed by the Committee who is required to receive or obtain information relating to any matter under the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Royal Canadian Mounted Police Act</XRefExternal> shall, in the performance of their duties, comply with any security and confidentiality requirements applicable to individuals who normally have access to and use of that information and shall take the oath of secrecy or the affirmation of secrecy set out in the schedule.</Text></Section></Body><Schedule bilingual="no" spanlanguages="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label><OriginatingRef>(Section 2)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Oath of Secrecy</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>I, <Leader leader="solid" length="10pc" />, solemnly swear that I will not, without due authority, disclose or make known to any person not legally entitled thereto any information acquired by me by reason of the duties performed by me on behalf of or under the direction of the Royal Canadian Mounted Police External Review Committee or by reason of any office or employment held by me pursuant to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Royal Canadian Mounted Police Act</XRefExternal>. So help me God.</Text><SignatureBlock justification="right" width="10pc"><SignatureLine justification="left"><Leader leader="solid" length="10pc" /></SignatureLine><SignatureName justification="left">Signature</SignatureName></SignatureBlock></Provision><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Affirmation of Secrecy</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>I, <Leader leader="solid" length="10pc" />, solemnly affirm that I will not, without due authority, disclose or make known to any person not legally entitled thereto any information acquired by me by reason of the duties performed by me on behalf of or under the direction of the Royal Canadian Mounted Police External Review Committee or by reason of any office or employment held by me pursuant to the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Royal Canadian Mounted Police Act</XRefExternal>.</Text><SignatureBlock justification="right" width="10pc"><SignatureLine justification="left"><Leader leader="solid" length="10pc" /></SignatureLine><SignatureName justification="left">Signature</SignatureName></SignatureBlock></Provision></Schedule></Regulation>