<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/91-714</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1991</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>5</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>17</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">PETRO-CANADA PUBLIC PARTICIPATION ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Petro-Canada Limited Pension Protection Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting Pension Protection for Employees of Petro-Canada Limited</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1991-2406 </OrderNumber><Date><YYYY> 1991</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>5</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of State (Finance and Privatization) and the President of the Treasury Board, pursuant to section 17 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Petro-Canada Public Participation Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-91-714_e_hq_6177">*</FootnoteRef>, is pleased hereby to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting pension protection for employees of Petro-Canada Limited</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fn_SOR-91-714_e_hq_6177" placement="page" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>S.C. 1991, c. 10</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Petro-Canada Limited Pension Protection Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Applicable Enactments</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>The <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Superannuation Act</XRefExternal> and the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Supplementary Retirement Benefits Act</XRefExternal> and the regulations made under those Acts apply to a person who makes an election under paragraph 17(1)(d) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Petro-Canada Limited Public Participation Act</XRefExternal> except as provided in sections 3 and 4.</Text><HistoricalNote>1991, c. 10, s. 19.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Adapted Provisions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>For the purposes of section 17 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Petro-Canada Limited Public Participation Act</XRefExternal>, subparagraphs 10(9)(b)(i) and (ii) and sections 12 and 13 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Superannuation Act</XRefExternal> are adapted as follows:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in subparagraphs 10(9)(b)(i) and (ii) of that Act, the year in which a person ceased to be employed in the Public Service is the year in which the person ceased to be employed by Petro-Canada Limited; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in sections 12 and 13 of that Act</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>except for the purpose of subsection 12(4) of that Act, the number of years of pensionable service and any period of employment of a person includes any such service or employment with Petro-Canada Limited during the period beginning on the day that the person ceased to be employed in the Public Service and ending on the day preceding the day on which the person ceased to be employed by Petro-Canada Limited, and</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>except for the purposes of subparagraph (i), the day on which a person ceased to be employed in the Public Service is the day on which that person ceased to be employed by Petro-Canada Limited.</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>1991, c. 10, s. 19.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>For the purposes of section 17 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Petro-Canada Limited Public Participation Act</XRefExternal>, subsection 4(5) and subparagraphs 6(2)(b)(i) and (ii) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Supplementary Retirement Benefits Act</XRefExternal> are adapted as follows:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>in subsection 4(5) of that Act, the retirement year or retirement month of a person is 1991 or July 1991, as the case may be; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>in subparagraphs 6(2)(b)(i) and (ii) of that Act, the year in which a person ceased to contribute in respect of current service to the Supplementary Retirement Benefits Account is the year in which that person ceased to be employed by Petro-Canada Limited.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>1991, c. 10, s. 19.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>These Regulations shall come into force, or be deemed to have come into force, on November 29, 1991.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>