<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/2005-392</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>28</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2006</YYYY><MM>3</MM><DD>17</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CUSTOMS TARIFF</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Stainless Steel Round Wire Products Anti-dumping Duty Remission Order</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>2005-2212</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>2005</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>28</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Finance, pursuant to section 115 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Tariff</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="footnotea_e">a</FootnoteRef>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Stainless Steel Round Wire Products Anti-dumping Duty Remission Order</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="footnotea_e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 1997, c. 36</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>The following definitions apply in this Order.</Text><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>Agency</DefinedTermEn> means the Canada Border Services Agency. (<DefinedTermFr>Agence</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition><Text><DefinedTermEn>stainless steel round wire products</DefinedTermEn> means</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>stainless steel belting wire used in the production of conveyor belts; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>stainless steel wire line used in the oil and gas industry</Text><Subparagraph><Label>(i)</Label><Text>to run specialized tools in and out of wells in order to open up the oil and gas zones or wells,</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(ii)</Label><Text>to log, or</Text></Subparagraph><Subparagraph><Label>(iii)</Label><Text>to do regular pressure- and temperature-type work. (<DefinedTermFr>produits de fils ronds en acier inoxydable</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Subparagraph></Paragraph></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Remission</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>Subject to section 3, remission is hereby granted for the portion, if any, of the anti-dumping duties paid or payable under the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Special Import Measures Act</XRefExternal> on or after April 2, 2004, in respect of stainless steel round wire products, in excess of the amount equal to 35 per cent of the export price, within the meaning of subsection 2(1) of that Act, of those products.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Conditions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>Remission is granted on the following conditions:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a claim for remission is made by the importer to the Minister of Public Safety and Emergency Preparedness within two years after the day on which the stainless steel round wire products were accounted for under section 32 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Act</XRefExternal>;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>on request by the Agency, the importer files with the Agency the evidence that the Agency requires to determine eligibility for the remission;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the importer agrees that it shall be subject at any time, including after the remission, to audit by the Agency for the purpose of verifying whether the information supplied by the importer under paragraph (a) or (b) is accurate and complete and whether the facts on which the Agency relied or intends to rely, as applicable, to determine eligibility for remission remain unchanged in all material respects; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>at the time when the Agency elects to conduct the audit referred to in paragraph (c), the Agency is able to conclude that the information supplied remains accurate and complete and that the facts remain unchanged in all material respects.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section type="transitional"><Label>4</Label><Text>This Order comes into force on the day on which it is registered.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>