<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/99-300</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1999</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>23</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>10</MM><DD>28</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">FOREIGN PUBLISHERS ADVERTISING SERVICES ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><LongTitle>Regulations Defining Certain Expressions for the Purpose of Section 21.1 of the Foreign Publishers Advertising Services Act</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1999-1217 </OrderNumber><Date><YYYY> 1999</YYYY><MM>6</MM><DD>23</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Canadian Heritage, pursuant to section 20.1 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Foreign Publishers Advertising Services Act</XRefExternal><FootnoteRef idref="fn_SOR-99-300_e_hq_5617">a</FootnoteRef>, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations Defining Certain Expressions for the Purpose of Section 21.1 of the Foreign Publishers Advertising Services Act</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fn_SOR-99-300_e_hq_5617" placement="page" status="official"><Label>a</Label><Text>S.C. 1999, c. 23</Text></Footnote></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Expressions Defined</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>For the purpose of section 21.1 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Foreign Publishers Advertising Services Act</XRefExternal>, the following expressions are defined.</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>revenues generated by the supply of advertising services directed at the Canadian market</DefinedTermEn>, in respect of an issue of a periodical and any material accompanying the periodical whether it is attached or not, means the total amount of space on a page or any part of a page or any lines on a page dedicated to paid advertisements that are placed by a Canadian advertiser, or a person acting on their behalf, and that are directed at the Canadian market. (<DefinedTermFr>revenus qui proviennent des services publicitaires destinés au marché canadien</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>revenues generated by the total supply of advertising services</DefinedTermEn>, in respect of an issue of a periodical and any material accompanying the periodical whether it is attached or not, means the total amount of space on a page or any part of a page or any lines on a page dedicated to paid advertisements. (<DefinedTermFr>revenus publicitaires totaux</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Coming into Force</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>These Regulations come into force on July 1, 1999.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>