<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/78-444</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1978</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>12</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2010</YYYY><MM>9</MM><DD>7</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS MARKETING ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>British Columbia Mushroom Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Granting Authority to Regulate the Marketing of Mushrooms in British Columbia</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1978-1544</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1978</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>11</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Agriculture, pursuant to section 2 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Agricultural Products Marketing Act</XRefExternal>, is pleased hereby to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Order granting authority to regulate the marketing of mushrooms in British Columbia</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">British Columbia Mushroom Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In this Order,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Act</DefinedTermEn> means the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Natural Products Marketing (British Columbia) Act</XRefExternal>; (<DefinedTermFr>Loi</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Commodity Board</DefinedTermEn> means the British Columbia Mushroom Marketing Board established pursuant to the Act; (<DefinedTermFr>Office</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>mushrooms</DefinedTermEn> means mushrooms grown in the Province of British Columbia; (<DefinedTermFr>Champignons</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Plan</DefinedTermEn> means the British Columbia Mushroom Scheme established and amended from time to time pursuant to the Act and any Regulations made thereunder to give effect to the Scheme. (<DefinedTermFr>Plan</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interprovincial and Export Trade</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>The Commodity Board is authorized to regulate the marketing of mushrooms in interprovincial and export trade and for such purposes may, by order or regulation, with respect to persons and property situated within the Province of British Columbia, exercise all or any powers like the powers exercisable by it in relation to the marketing of mushrooms locally within that Province under the Act and the Plan.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Levies</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>The Commodity Board is authorized in relation to the powers granted to it by section 3 with respect to the marketing of mushrooms in interprovincial and export trade to make orders fixing, imposing and collecting levies or charges from persons situated in the Province of British Columbia who are engaged in the production or marketing of mushrooms and for such purposes to classify such persons into groups and fix the levies or charges payable by the members of the different groups in different amounts and the Commodity Board may use such levies or charges for its purposes including the creation of reserves and the payment of expenses and losses resulting from the sale or disposal of mushrooms and the equalization or adjustment among producers of mushrooms of moneys realized from the sale thereof during such period or periods of time as it may determine.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>