<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/82-361a</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1982</YYYY><MM>3</MM><DD>26</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2011</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>18</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">PUBLIC SERVICE EMPLOYMENT ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Non-Public Funds Staff Exclusion Approval Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Approving the Exclusion by the Public Service Commission of all Positions and Employees of the Staff of the Non-Public Funds, Canadian Forces from the Operation of the Public Service Employment Act</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1982-942</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1982</YYYY><MM>3</MM><DD>25</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas the Public Service Commission has decided that it is not practicable nor in the best interests of the Public Service to apply the provisions of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal> to positions and employees of the Staff of the Non-Public Funds, Canadian Forces;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>And Whereas the Public Service Commission has further decided that it is desirable to make the annexed Regulations prescribing how such positions and employees shall be dealt with.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Therefore, His Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Public Service Commission, is pleased hereby</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>pursuant to section 39 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal>, to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Order approving the exclusion by the Public Service Commission of all positions and employees of the Staff of the Non-Public Funds, Canadian Forces from the operation of the Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal>; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>pursuant to subsection 35(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal> to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting the appointment of persons to the Staff of the Non-Public Funds, Canadian Forces</XRefExternal>.</Text></Provision></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Non-Public Funds Staff Exclusion Approval Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Approval</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>The exclusion by the Public Service Commission of all positions and employees of the Staff of the Non-Public Funds, Canadian Forces, from the operation of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Public Service Employment Act</XRefExternal> is hereby approved.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>