<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/87-602</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1987</YYYY><MM>10</MM><DD>15</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2011</YYYY><MM>5</MM><DD>27</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AERONAUTICS ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Sarnia Airport Zoning Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting Zoning at Sarnia Airport</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1987-2147</OrderNumber><Date><YYYY>1987</YYYY><MM>10</MM><DD>15</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Whereas, pursuant to section 4.5 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Aeronautics Act</XRefExternal>, a copy of the proposed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Zoning Regulations respecting Sarnia Airport</XRefExternal>, substantially in the form set out in the schedule hereto, was published in two successive issues of the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal> Part I on June 13th and 20th, 1987, and in two successive issues of The Sarnia Observer on June 13th and 17th, 1987, and a reasonable opportunity was thereby afforded to interested persons to make representations to the Minister of Transport with respect thereto.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Therefore, Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Transport, pursuant to section 4.4 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Aeronautics Act</XRefExternal>, is pleased hereby to revoke the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Sarnia Airport Zoning Regulations</XRefExternal>, C.R.C., c. 107, and to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting zoning at Sarnia Airport</XRefExternal>, in substitution therefor.</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Sarnia Airport Zoning Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Subsection><Label>(1)</Label><Text>In these Regulations,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>airport</DefinedTermEn> means the Sarnia Airport in the Township of Sarnia, in the Province of Ontario; (<DefinedTermFr>aéroport</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>airport reference point</DefinedTermEn> means the point described in Part I of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>point de repère de l’aéroport</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>approach surface</DefinedTermEn> means an imaginary inclined plane that extends upward and outward from each end of a strip, which approach surface is more particularly described in Part II of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>surface d’approche</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>Minister</DefinedTermEn> means the Minister of Transport; (<DefinedTermFr>ministre</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>outer surface</DefinedTermEn> means an imaginary surface located above and in the immediate vicinity of the airport, which outer surface is more particularly described in Part III of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>surface extérieure</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>strip</DefinedTermEn> means the rectangular portion of the landing area of the airport, including the runway, prepared for the take-off and landing of aircraft in a particular direction, which strip is more particularly described in Part IV of the schedule; (<DefinedTermFr>bande</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>transitional surface</DefinedTermEn> means an imaginary inclined plane that extends upward and outward from the lateral limits of a strip and its approach surfaces, which transitional surface is more particularly described in Part V of the schedule. (<DefinedTermFr>surface de transition</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Subsection><Subsection><Label>(2)</Label><Text>For the purposes of these Regulations, the elevation of the airport reference point is 179.5 m above sea level.</Text></Subsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-85, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>These Regulations apply to all the lands, including public road allowances, adjacent to or in the vicinity of the airport, which lands are more particularly described in Part VI of the schedule.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>General</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>No person shall erect or construct on any land to which these Regulations apply, any building, structure or object or any addition to any existing building, structure or object, the highest point of which will exceed in elevation at the location of that point</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the approach surfaces;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the outer surface; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>the transitional surfaces.</Text></Paragraph></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Natural Growth</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>Where an object of natural growth on any land to which these Regulations apply exceeds in elevation any of the surfaces referred to in paragraphs 4(a) to (c), the Minister may require that the owner or occupier of the land on which that object is growing remove the growth or the excessive portion thereof.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Disposal of Waste</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>No owner or occupier of any land to which these Regulations apply shall permit that land or any part of it to be used for the disposal of any waste edible by or attractive to birds.</Text></Section></Body><Schedule bilingual="no" spanlanguages="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label><OriginatingRef>(Sections 2 and 3)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><Heading level="1"><Label>PART I</Label><TitleText>Description of Airport Reference Point</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The Airport Reference Point, shown on Sarnia Airport Zoning Plan No. 38-028-84-133, Sheet 5, dated March 17, 1986, is a point distant 76.20 m measured northeasterly at right angles to the centre line of runway 14-32, from a point distant 898.06 m measured northwesterly along the said centre line from the southeasterly end of strip 14-32.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART II</Label><TitleText>Description of the Approach Surfaces</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The approach surfaces, shown on Sarnia Airport Zoning Plan No. 38-028-84-133, Sheets 2 to 8 inclusive and 10 to 13 inclusive, dated March 17, 1986, are surfaces abutting each end of the strips associated with runways designated 05-23 and 14-32 and are described as follows:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>a surface abutting the end of the strip associated with runway approach 05 consisting of an inclined plane having a ratio of 1 m measured vertically to 25 m measured horizontally rising to an imaginary horizontal line drawn at right angles to the projected centre line of the strip and distant 1 110 m measured horizontally from the end of the strip; the outer ends of the imaginary horizontal line being 141 m from the projected centre line; said imaginary horizontal line being 44.4 m above the elevation at the end of the strip;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a surface abutting the end of the strip associated with runway approach 23 consisting of an inclined plane having a ratio of 1 m measured vertically to 25 m measured horizontally rising to an imaginary horizontal line drawn at right angles to the projected centre line of the strip and distant 1 115 m measured horizontally from the end of the strip; the outer ends of the imaginary horizontal line being 141.5 m from the projected centre line; said imaginary horizontal line being 44.6 m above the elevation at the end of the strip;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>a surface abutting the end of the strip associated with runway approach 14 consisting of an inclined plane having a ratio of 1 m measured vertically to 50 m measured horizontally rising to an imaginary line coinciding with the International Boundary and distant 8 614.7 m measured horizontally along the projected centre line of the strip from the end of the strip; the outer ends of the imaginary line coincident with the International Boundary being 1 747.5 m northeasterly and 1 506.6 m southwesterly from the point of intersection of the projected centre line of the strip and the International Boundary; the elevation at that point of intersection being 172.6 m above the elevation at the end of the strip; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(d)</Label><Text>a surface abutting the end of the strip associated with runway approach 32 consisting of an inclined plane having a ratio of 1 m measured vertically to 50 m measured horizontally rising to an imaginary horizontal line drawn at right angles to the projected centre line of the strip and distant 15 000 m measured horizontally from the end of the strip; the outer ends of the imaginary horizontal line being 2 400 m from the projected centre line; said imaginary horizontal line being 300 m above the elevation at the end of the strip.</Text></Provision></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART III</Label><TitleText>Description of the Outer Surface</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The outer surface, shown on Sarnia Airport Zoning plan No. 38-028-84-133, Sheets 1 to 9 inclusive and 11 and 12, dated March 17, 1986 is an imaginary surface located at a common plane established at a constant elevation of 45 m above the elevation of the airport reference point, except that, where that common plane is less than 9 m above the surface of the ground, the outer surface is an imaginary surface located at 9 m above the surface of the ground.</Text></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART IV</Label><TitleText>Description of the Strips</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The strips shown on Sarnia Airport Zoning Plan No. 38-028-84-133, Sheet 5, dated March 17, 1986, are described as follows:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the strip associated with runway 05-23 being 60 m in width, 30 m on each side of the centre line of the runway, and 1 030.72 m in length; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the strip associated with runway 14-32, being 300 m in width, 150 m on each side of the centre line of the runway, and 1 675.78 m in length.</Text></Provision></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART V</Label><TitleText>Description of Each Transitional Surface</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Each transitional surface, shown on Sarnia Airport Zoning Plan No. 38-028-84-133, Sheets 2, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 11 and 12, dated March 17, 1986, is described as follows:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the transitional surface associated with runway 05-23 is a surface consisting of an inclined plane rising at a ratio of 1 m measured vertically to 5 m measured horizontally at right angles to the centre line and projected centre line of the strip extending upward and outward from the lateral limits of the strip and its approach surfaces to an intersection with the outer surface or another transitional surface of an adjoining strip; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1" language-align="no" list-item="no"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the transitional surface associated with runway 14-32 is a surface consisting of an inclined plane rising at a ratio of 1 m measured vertically to 7 m measured horizontally at right angles to the centre line and projected centre line of the strip extending upward and outward from the lateral limits of the strip and its approach surfaces to an intersection with the outer surface or another transitional surface of an adjoining strip.</Text></Provision></Provision><Heading level="1"><Label>PART VI</Label><TitleText>Description of the Lands to Which These Regulations Apply</TitleText></Heading><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>The boundary of the outer limits of lands, shown on Sarnia Airport Zoning Plan No. 38-028-84-133, Sheets 1 to 4 inclusive and 6 to 14 inclusive, dated March 17, 1986, are described as follows:</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Commencing at the intersection of the water’s edge of Lake Huron with the production northerly of the eastern boundary of Lot 13, in the Front Concession in the Township of Sarnia;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence southerly along the said production northerly of the eastern boundary of Lot 13 and along the said boundary to the intersection thereof with the north-western boundary of Westgate Crescent according to a plan registered in the Registry Office for the Registry Division of Lambton as No. 650;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence south-westerly and southerly along the north-western and western boundary of said Westgate Crescent to the intersection thereof with the northern boundary of Hamilton Street according to said registered plan No. 650;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence southerly in a straight line across said Hamilton Street to the most northerly corner of Lot 58 according to said registered plan No. 650;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence south-westerly along the south-eastern boundary of Hamilton Street being also the north-western boundary of said Lot 58 to the most westerly corner of said Lot 58;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence south-easterly along the south-western boundary of Lots 58 and 83 according to said registered plan No. 650 to the most southerly corner of said Lot 83;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence southerly along the western boundary of Winslow Crescent to the most easterly corner of Lot 94, according to said registered plan No. 650;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence southerly along the eastern boundary of said Lot 94 to the south-easterly corner thereof;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence westerly along the southern boundary of said Lot 94 to the north-easterly corner of Lot 40 according to said registered plan No. 650;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence southerly along the eastern boundary of said Lot 40 to the south-easterly corner thereof;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence southerly in a straight line across Kaymar Crescent to the north-easterly corner of Lot 18, according to said registered plan No. 650;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence southerly along the eastern boundary of said Lot 18 and along the production southerly of the said eastern boundary to the intersection thereof with the southern boundary of Block F according to said registered plan No. 650, the said southern boundary being also the northern limit of County Road No. 7 (New Lakeshore Road) as shown on a plan deposited in the said Registry Office as No. 319;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence easterly along the northern limit of said County Road No. 7 to the intersection thereof with the eastern boundary of Lot 13, Front Concession in the said Township of Sarnia;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence southerly along the said eastern boundary of Lot 13, to the south-easterly corner thereof, being also the north-easterly corner of Lot 5, in the Gore Concession in the said Township;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence southerly along the eastern boundary of said Lot 5, Gore Concession to the south-easterly corner thereof;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence southerly in a straight line across the allowance for road between the Gore Concession and Concession 8 to the north-easterly corner of Lot 5 in Concession 8;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence southerly along the eastern boundary of Lot 5 in Concession 8 to the south-easterly corner thereof, being also the north-easterly corner of Lot 5, in Concession 7;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence southerly along the eastern boundary of Lot 5 in Concession 7 to the intersection thereof with the northern limit of the King’s Highway No. 7, as widened, and shown on Ministry of Transport and Communications Plan P2039-1, deposited in the said Registry Office as Number 144;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence westerly along the said northern limit of the King’s Highway No. 7 to the intersection thereof with the western boundary of said Lot 5, Concession 7;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence southerly in a straight line across the King’s Highway No. 7 to the intersection of the southern limit of the said Highway, as widened, and shown on the said Plan P2039-1, with the eastern boundary of Lot 6, Concession 6;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence southerly along the said eastern boundary of Lot 6, Concession 6 to the intersection thereof with the north-easterly limit of approach surface 32;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence south-easterly along the said north-easterly limit of Approach Surface 32 on an azimuth of 129°14′00″ to the most easterly corner thereof, the U.T.M. co-ordinates of which are 4,751,281.802 North, 405,683.838 East;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence south-westerly along the south-easterly limit of Approach Surface 32 on an azimuth of 227°45′51″ the most southerly corner thereof, the U.T.M. co-ordinates of which are 4,748,056.259 North, 402,131.021 East;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence north-westerly along the south-westerly limit of Approach Surface 32, on an azimuth of 326°17′41″ to the intersection thereof with the northern boundary of Lot 7, Concession 5 in the said Township of Sarnia;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence westerly along the said northern boundary of Lot 7, Concession 5 to the north-westerly corner thereof;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence southerly along the western boundary of the said Lot 7, Concession 5 to the south-westerly corner thereof;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence westerly along the southern boundaries of Lots 8 and 9, in Concession 5 to the south-westerly corner of the said Lot 9, Concession 5;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence westerly in a straight line across the allowance for road between Lots 9 and 10 in Concession 5 to the south-easterly corner of the said Lot 10, Concession 5;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence westerly along the southern boundaries of Lots 10, 11 and 12, in Concession 5 to the south-westerly corner of the said Lot 12, Concession 5;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence westerly in a straight line across the allowance for road between Lots 12 and 13 in Concession 5 to the south-easterly corner of the said Lot 13, Concession 5;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence westerly along the southern boundaries of Lots 13 and 14 in Concession 5 to the south-westerly corner of the said Lot 14, Concession 5;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence northerly along the western boundary of said Lot 14, Concession 5 to the north-westerly corner thereof, being also the south-easterly corner of Lot 15, Concession 6;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence westerly along the southern boundary of said Lot 15, Concession 6 to the south-westerly corner thereof;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence westerly in a straight line across the allowance for road between Lots 15 and 16, Concession 6 to the south-easterly corner of the said Lot 16, Concession 6;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence westerly along the southern boundary of said Lot 16, Concession 6 to the south-westerly corner thereof;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence northerly along the western boundary of Lot 16, Concession 6 to the north-westerly corner thereof;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence westerly along the northern boundary of Lot 17, Concession 6 to the north-westerly corner thereof;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence northerly in a straight line across the allowance for road between Concession 6 and Concession 7 to the south-westerly corner of Lot 17, Concession 7;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence northerly along the western boundary of said Lot 17, Concession 7 and continuing northerly along the western boundary of Lot 17, Concession 8 to the north-westerly corner of said Lot 17, Concession 8;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence northerly in a straight line across the allowance for road between Concession 8 and Front Concession to the south-westerly corner of Lot 51 in said Front Concession;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence northerly along the western boundary of said Lot 51, Front Concession to the intersection with the southern boundary of Block V according to a plan registered in the said Registry Office as No. 632;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence northerly along the western boundary of said Block V and continuing northerly along the western boundary of Douglas Drive according to said registered plan No. 632 to the intersection with the southern boundary of Esser Crescent, registered plan No. 632;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence westerly and northerly along the southern and western boundary of said Esser Crescent and the northerly extension thereof to the intersection with the southern limit of Errol Road, registered plan No. 632;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence northerly in a straight line across said Errol Road to the intersection of the northern boundary of said Errol Road with the western boundary of Concordia Court according to said registered plan No. 632;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence northerly along the western boundary of Concordia Court to the south-easterly corner of Lot 342 according to said registered plan No. 632;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence northerly along the eastern boundaries of Lots 342 and 328 according to said registered plan No. 632 to the north-easterly corner of said Lot 328;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence northerly in a straight line across McAlpine Crescent to the south-westerly corner of Lot 292 according to said registered plan No. 632;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence northerly along the western boundary of said Lot 292 to the north-westerly corner thereof;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence easterly along the northern boundaries of Lots 292 and 293 according to said registered plan No. 632, also being the southern boundaries of Lots 12 and 13 according to a plan registered in the said Registry Office as No. 482, to the southeasterly corner of the said Lot 13;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence northerly along the eastern boundary of the said Lot 13, registered plan No. 482 to the intersection thereof with the southern boundary of Cathcart Boulevard;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence easterly along the said southern boundary of Cathcart Boulevard to the north-easterly corner of Lot 23 according to said registered plan No. 482;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence northerly in a straight line across the said Cathcart Boulevard to the intersection of the northern boundary thereof with the eastern boundary of Rutherglen Close according to a plan registered in the said Registry Office as No. 317;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence northerly along the most eastern boundary of Rutherglen Close to the intersection thereof with the southern boundary of Lakeshore Road as widened by said registered plan No. 317;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence northerly in a straight line across said Lakeshore Road to the intersection of the northern boundary thereof with the eastern boundary of Rutherglen Drive according to a plan registered in the said Registry Office as No. 499;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence northerly along the said eastern boundaries of Rutherglen Drive and the One Foot Reserve at the northerly end thereof to the intersection with the northern boundary of the said registered plan No. 499;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence westerly along the said northern boundary of registered plan No. 499 to the intersection thereof with the western boundary of Lot 50, Front Concession in the said Township of Sarnia;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence northerly along the said western boundary of Lot 50 in the Front Concession to the intersection with the water’s edge of Lake Huron;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence easterly along the said water’s edge of Lake Huron to the intersection with the south-westerly limit of Approach Surface 14;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence north-westerly along the said south-westerly limit of Approach Surface 14 on an azimuth of 309°14′00″ to the intersection thereof with the International Boundary between Canada and the United States of America, the U.T.M. co-ordinates of which said intersection are 4,766,982.055 North, 386,372.856 East;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence north-easterly along the said International Boundary to the intersection thereof with the north-easterly limit of said Approach Surface 14, the U.T.M. co-ordinates of which said intersection are 4,770,019.249 North, 387,538.551 East;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence south-easterly along the said north-easterly limit of Approach Surface 14 on an azimuth of 146°17′41″ to the intersection thereof with the north-easterly limit of the Transitional Surface which line has an azimuth of 138°20′14″, the U.T.M. co-ordinates of which said intersection are 4,763,997.076 North, 391,555.649 East;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence south-easterly along said north-easterly limit of Transitional Surface on an azimuth of 138°20′14″ to the intersection thereof with the water’s edge of Lake Huron; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Thence easterly along the said water’s edge of Lake Huron to the Point of Commencement.</Text></Provision></Provision><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-85, ss. 2(E), 3(E) and 4(F).</HistoricalNote></Schedule></Regulation>