<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/90-10</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1989</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>14</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2006</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>20</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">CANADA POST CORPORATION ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Non-mailable Matter Regulations</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Regulations Respecting Non-mailable Matter</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1989-2452 </OrderNumber><Date><YYYY> 1989</YYYY><MM>12</MM><DD>14</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Whereas, pursuant to section 20 of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Post Corporation Act</XRefExternal>, a copy of the proposed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting non-mailable matter</XRefExternal>, substantially in the form set out in the schedule hereto, was published in the <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal> Part I on July 22, 1989 and a reasonable opportunity was thereby afforded to interested persons to make representations to the Minister of Regional Industrial Expansion with respect thereto;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" list-item="no" language-align="yes"><Text>Therefore, Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of Regional Industrial Expansion, pursuant to subsection 19(1) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Post Corporation Act</XRefExternal>, is pleased hereby to approve the revocation of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Prohibited Mail Regulations</XRefExternal>, C.R.C., c. 1289, and to approve the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Regulations respecting non-mailable matter</XRefExternal>, made by the Canada Post Corporation, effective January 1, 1990.</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>These Regulations may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Non-mailable Matter Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In these Regulations, <DefinedTermEn>letter-post item</DefinedTermEn> has the same meaning as in the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">International Letter-post Items Regulations</XRefExternal>. (<Emphasis style="italic">envoi de la poste aux lettres</Emphasis>)</Text><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-799, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Non-mailable Matter</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>For the purposes of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Post Corporation Act</XRefExternal> and the regulations under that Act, the items set out in the schedule are non-mailable matter.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Disposition of Non-mailable Matter</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>Any non-mailable matter found in course of post, other than non-mailable matter that is seized under the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Customs Act</XRefExternal>, shall be disposed of as follows:</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>any non-mailable matter included in item 1 or 7 of the schedule shall be destroyed or disposed of in a manner that does not expose any person or property or the environment to danger;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>any non-mailable matter included in item 2 of the schedule shall be delivered to an association for the protection of animals or any other facility that shelters or looks after animals;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(c)</Label><Text>any non-mailable matter included in item 3 of the schedule shall, where its outside cover bears a return address, be returned to the sender or, where its outside cover does not bear a return address, be destroyed;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(d)</Label><Text>any non-mailable matter included in item 4 of the schedule shall be delivered to a police officer, a peace officer or the competent authority, as applicable; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(e)</Label><Text>any non-mailable matter included in item 5 or 8 of the schedule shall, where its outside cover bears a return address, be returned to the sender or, where its outside cover does not bear a return address, be disposed of in accordance with the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Undeliverable and Redirected Mail Regulations</XRefExternal>.</Text></Paragraph><HistoricalNote>SOR/98-557, s. 1; SOR/2006-220, s. 1; SOR/2008-200, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>5</Label><Text>Where any non-mailable matter is returned to the Corporation by a customs officer, it shall be held by the Corporation</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>for 30 days, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>where legal proceedings in which the non-mailable matter may be required are commenced before and continued after the expiration of the 30 days referred to in paragraph (a), until the final disposition of those proceedings,</Text></Paragraph><ContinuedSectionSubsection><Text>and thereafter shall be disposed of in accordance with section 4.</Text></ContinuedSectionSubsection><HistoricalNote>SOR/92-695, s. 1(F); SOR/2002-166, s. 1.</HistoricalNote></Section><Section><Label>6</Label><Text>Where any non-mailable matter that contains an intoxicating beverage is returned to the Corporation by a customs officer, it shall be</Text><Paragraph><Label>(a)</Label><Text>returned to the country of origin where the addressee so requests and pays the return postage therefor; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph><Label>(b)</Label><Text>held for 30 days and thereafter destroyed, unless within that time the addressee requests that it be returned to the country of origin and pays the return postage therefor.</Text></Paragraph></Section></Body><Schedule spanlanguages="no" bilingual="no"><ScheduleFormHeading><Label>SCHEDULE</Label><OriginatingRef>(Sections 3 to 5)</OriginatingRef></ScheduleFormHeading><TableGroup pointsize="7" rowbreak="yes" topmarginspacing="4"><Caption position="over">NON-MAILABLE MATTER</Caption><table frame="topbot"><tgroup cols="2"><colspec colname="1" colwidth="11.05*" /><colspec colname="2" colwidth="92.22*" /><thead><row valign="bottom" topdouble="yes"><entry colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Item</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="1" valign="bottom">Non-mailable Matter</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top">1</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" valign="top"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Dangerous goods as defined in the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Transportation of Dangerous Goods Act</XRefExternal> or the regulations made thereunder, except where, in accordance with that Act and those regulations,</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the sender of the dangerous goods offers them to the Corporation for transport; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the Corporation is capable of handling and transporting the dangerous goods.</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Items that, because of the manner in which they are packed, may expose a person to danger or may damage mail or postal equipment.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Letter-post items or parcels that contain dangerous or perishable items prohibited by article 18 of the Universal Postal Convention (25th Congress, 2012) and by articles VII and VIII of the Final Protocol of that Convention.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Items that may soil mail or postal equipment.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(5)</Label><Text>Items that emit offensive odours.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(6)</Label><Text>Fish, game, meat, fruit, vegetables, perishable biological substances or other perishable items that are not prepared for posting in accordance with the applicable requirements of the current <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Postal Guide — Guide des postes du Canada</XRefExternal>, published by the Corporation.</Text></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">2</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Live animals, other than live animals that are accepted for transmission by post pursuant to an agreement with the Corporation or that are referred to in the current <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Postal Guide — Guide des postes du Canada</XRefExternal>, published by the Corporation and are prepared for posting in accordance with the applicable requirements set out in that guide.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Letter-post items or parcels that contain live animals prohibited by article 18 of the Universal Postal Convention (25th Congress, 2012).</Text></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">3</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(1)</Label><Text>Items that have on their outside cover</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>anything written or printed or attached thereto, other than the name and address of the addressee and of the sender or endorsements or attachments that are authorized by or under applicable regulations or by the Corporation;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>on the address side thereof, a stamp of a charity or some other non-postal stamp indicating value;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>in the space reserved for postage stamps, stamps or stickers of private manufacture;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(d)</Label><Text>hand-stamped or printed facsimiles of postal cancelling or franking stamps; or</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(e)</Label><Text>successive addresses.</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Envelopes with windows, unless</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>each window has a transparent covering; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>the longest sides of the window through which the address is visible are parallel to the longest sides of the envelope.</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(2.1)</Label><Text>Letter-post items in wholly transparent envelopes, unless</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>the envelopes are constructed in such a way that they can be easily handled while in the course of transmission by post; and</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>a label is securely attached to the outer surface of the envelope and the label has sufficient space to include the name and address of the addressee, the postage and any applicable service instructions.</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(3)</Label><Text><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2002-166, s. 2]</Repealed></Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(4)</Label><Text>Letter-post items or parcels, other than those referred to in subitems 1(3) and 2(2), that contain matter prohibited by article 18 of the Universal Postal Convention (25th Congress, 2012) and by articles VII and VIII of the Final Protocol of that Convention.</Text></Provision></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">4</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0">Any item transmitted by post in contravention of an Act or a regulation of Canada.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">5</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0">Gold bullion, gold dust and non-manufactured precious metals unless accepted for transmission by post pursuant to an agreement with the Corporation.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">6</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Repealed>[Repealed, SOR/2010-289, s. 1]</Repealed></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">7</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0">Replica or inert munitions, as well as other devices that simulate explosive devices or munitions, including replica or inert grenades or other simulated military munitions, whether or not such items are for display purposes.</entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">8</entry><entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0"><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(1)</Label><Text>For the purposes of subitems (2) and (3), sexually explicit material that is sent as addressed admail or unaddressed admail means</Text><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(a)</Label><Text>images or representations of nudity that are suggestive of sexual activity;</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(b)</Label><Text>images or representations of sexual intercourse, with no suggestion of violence or degradation; or</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-1-1"><Label>(c)</Label><Text>written text that describes sexual acts in a way that is more than purely technical, with no suggestion of violence or degradation.</Text></Provision></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(2)</Label><Text>Sexually explicit material that is not in an opaque envelope with the words “adult material” or a similar warning.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0"><Label>(3)</Label><Text>Sexually explicit material that is on the outside of an envelope.</Text></Provision></entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></TableGroup><HistoricalNote>SOR/90-799, ss. 2 to 4; SOR/92-695, ss. 2, 3, 4(F); SOR/94-201, ss. 1, 2; SOR/95-309, ss. 1, 2; SOR/98-557, ss. 2, 3; SOR/2000-199, ss. 29, 30; SOR/2002-166, s. 2; SOR/2003-382, ss. 23 to 25; SOR/2006-220, s. 2; SOR/2006-345, s. 4; SOR/2008-200, s. 2; SOR/2008-285, s. 8(F); SOR/2009-335, ss. 3 to 5; SOR/2010-289, s. 1; SOR/2014-53, ss. 3 to 5.</HistoricalNote></Schedule></Regulation>