<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/89-538</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1989</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>9</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2008</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>12</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Medical High Technology International Inc. Shares Acquisition Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Authorizing Theratronics International Limited to Acquire and Hold Shares of Medical High Technology International Inc.</LongTitle><RegulationMakerOrder><RegulationMaker>P.C.</RegulationMaker><OrderNumber>1989-2234 </OrderNumber><Date><YYYY> 1989</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>9</DD></Date></RegulationMakerOrder></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Whereas the Governor in Council, pursuant to subsection 91(6) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Financial Administration Act</XRefExternal>, is satisfied that Theratronics International Limited, as a corporation incorporated under the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Canada Business Corporations Act</XRefExternal>, is empowered to undertake the transaction described in the annexed Order.</Text></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes" list-item="no"><Text>Therefore, Her Excellency the Governor General in Council, on the recommendation of the Minister of State (Privatization and Regulatory Affairs) and the Treasury Board, pursuant to paragraph 91(1)(b) of the <XRefExternal reference-type="act">Financial Administration Act</XRefExternal>, is pleased hereby to make the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Order authorizing Theratronics International Limited to acquire and hold shares of Medical High Technology International Inc.</XRefExternal></Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Medical High Technology International Inc. Shares Acquisition Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Authorized Transactions</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>Theratronics International Limited is hereby authorized to acquire, on or before March 31, 1990, shares having an aggregate value not exceeding US$250,000 of Medical High Technology International Inc. of Clearwater, Florida, U.S.A., that, on acquisition, will be held by, on behalf of or in trust for Theratronics International Limited.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>