<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE Regulation PUBLIC "-//Justice Canada//DTD Regulation v1.2.2//EN" "Dtd/Regulations/Version_1.2.2/regulation.dtd"><Regulation gazette-part="II" regulation-type="SOR" xml:lang="en"><Identification><InstrumentNumber>SOR/88-465</InstrumentNumber><RegistrationDate><Date><YYYY>1988</YYYY><MM>8</MM><DD>30</DD></Date></RegistrationDate><ConsolidationDate><Date><YYYY>2018</YYYY><MM>06</MM><DD>21</DD></Date></ConsolidationDate><LastModifiedDate><Date><YYYY>2010</YYYY><MM>11</MM><DD>30</DD></Date></LastModifiedDate><EnablingAuthority><XRefExternal reference-type="act">AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS MARKETING ACT</XRefExternal></EnablingAuthority><ShortTitle>Manitoba Chicken Marketing (Interprovincial and Export) Order</ShortTitle><LongTitle>Order Respecting the Marketing in Interprovincial and Export Trade of Chicken Produced in Manitoba</LongTitle></Identification><Order><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>The Manitoba Chicken Broiler Producers’ Marketing Board, pursuant to section 3<FootnoteRef idref="fn_1e">*</FootnoteRef> of the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Manitoba Chicken Order</XRefExternal>, C.R.C., c. 152, hereby makes the annexed <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Order respecting the marketing in interprovincial and export trade of chicken produced in Manitoba</XRefExternal>.</Text><Footnote id="fn_1e" placement="page" status="official"><Label>*</Label><Text>SOR/82-668, 1982 <XRefExternal reference-type="other">Canada Gazette</XRefExternal> Part II, p. 2550</Text></Footnote></Provision><Provision format-ref="indent-0-0" language-align="yes"><Text>Dated at Winnipeg, Manitoba this 23rd day of August, 1988</Text></Provision></Order><Body><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Short Title</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>1</Label><Text>This Order may be cited as the <XRefExternal reference-type="regulation">Manitoba Chicken Marketing (Interprovincial and Export) Order</XRefExternal>.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Interpretation</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>2</Label><Text>In this Order,</Text><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>chicken</DefinedTermEn> means a chicken of any variety, grade or class that is not more than five months of age and that is raised or kept within the Province of Manitoba for a purpose other than egg production, and includes broiler, fryer and roasting chickens; (<DefinedTermFr>poulet</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>marketing</DefinedTermEn> means selling or offering for sale, processing, buying, purchasing or offering to buy or purchase and includes advertising, packing, storing, shipping and transporting but does not include packing and storing by a producer on the producer’s premises; (<DefinedTermFr>vente</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition><Definition generate-in-text="no"><Text><DefinedTermEn>producer</DefinedTermEn> means any person who raises, keeps, prepares for slaughter, or slaughters chicken within the Province of Manitoba and includes the employer of any such person, a person who under any lease or agreement is entitled to a share of the chicken raised or kept by any such person, and a person who takes possession of any chicken from any such person under any form of security for a debt. (<DefinedTermFr>producteur</DefinedTermFr>)</Text></Definition></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Application</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>3</Label><Text>This Order applies in respect of the marketing of chicken in interprovincial and export trade and, in relation to such marketing, to persons and property situated in the Province of Manitoba.</Text></Section><Heading level="1"><TitleText>Prohibition</TitleText></Heading><Section><Label>4</Label><Text>No producer shall market chicken in interprovincial or export trade, unless exempted from this section by order of the Manitoba Chicken Broiler Producers’ Marketing Board.</Text></Section></Body></Regulation>